<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Guida Spirituale on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/guida_spirituale/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Guida Spirituale on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/guida_spirituale/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 Go Placidly</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/guida_spirituale/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/guida_spirituale/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
Go Placidly
26 August 1980 am in Buddha Hall
HEAR THEN THE WISDOM OF THE WISE: “GO PLACIDLY AMID THE NOISE AND THE HASTE, AND REMEMBER WHAT PEACE THERE MAY BE IN SILENCE.
“AS FAR AS POSSIBLE, WITHOUT SURRENDER, BE ON GOOD TERMS WITH ALL PERSONS.
SPEAK YOUR TRUTH QUIETLY AND CLEARLY; AND LISTEN TO OTHERS, EVEN TO THE DULL AND THE IGNORANT; THEY TOO HAVE THEIR STORY.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Doubt is a Sword</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/guida_spirituale/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/guida_spirituale/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
Doubt is a Sword
4 September 1980 am in Buddha Hall
The first question Question 1 OSHO
WHEN MY CHILDREN KNEW I WAS COMING TO SEE YOU, THERE WAS NO REQUEST FOR GIFTS. THERE WAS ONLY ONE THING THEY WANTED FOR ME TO BRING BACK SOME OF YOUR JOKES. THEY TOLD ME THAT ALL THE STUFF BETWEEN THE JOKES WAS GOOD FOR GROWN-UPS, BUT FOR THEM JUST THE JOKES.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 Beliefs are Lies</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/guida_spirituale/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/guida_spirituale/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
Beliefs are Lies
5 September 1980 am in Buddha Hall
The first question Question 1 OSHO,
IS THERE QUALITY IN NOTHINGNESS?
Anudeya,
NOTHINGNESS CAN EITHER BE just emptiness or it can be a tremendous fullness. It can be negative, it can be positive. If it is negative it is like death, darkness. Religions have called it hell. It is hell because there is no joy in it, no song in it, there is no heartbeat, no dance.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 The Total Man</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/guida_spirituale/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/guida_spirituale/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
The Total Man
6 September 1980 am in Buddha Hall
The first question Question 1 OSHO,
IN REFERENCE TO YOUR ADVISING INDIRA GANDHI TO IMPOSE A STRICTER EMERGENCY AND SUSPEND ELECTIONS FOR FIFTEEN YEARS, Mid-Day CARRIES THE HEADLINE: “STICK TO YOUR RELIGIOUS PURSUITS, MR. RAJNEESH!”
DO YOU HAVE ANY RESPONSE, OSHO?
Krishna Prem,
I TEACH THE TOTAL MAN. One of the greatest problems that humanity is facing today is the fragmentary man.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 Child of the Universe</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/guida_spirituale/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/guida_spirituale/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
Child of the Universe
7 September 1980 am in Buddha Hall
“BEYOND A WHOLESOME DISCIPLINE, BE GENTLE WITH YOURSELF. YOU ARE A CHILD OF THE UNIVERSE NO LESS THAN THE TREES AND THE STARS; YOU HAVE A RIGHT TO BE HERE. AND WHETHER OR NOT IT IS CLEAR TO YOU, NO DOUBT THE UNIVERSE IS UNFOLDING AS IT SHOULD.
“THEREFORE BE AT PEACE WITH GOD, WHATEVER YOU CONCEIVE HIM TO BE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 The Only Miracle</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/guida_spirituale/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/guida_spirituale/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
The Only Miracle
8 September 1980 am in Buddha Hall
The first question Question 1 OSHO,
WHAT IS SURRENDER? I USED TO THINK I KNEW. NOW IT IS A MYSTERY.
Prem Prabhat,
THE FALSE KNOWLEDGE de-mystifies existence; the true knowledge re-mystifies it. Knowing, if authentic, makes life more of a mystery than it has ever been before. Knowledge certainly covers your eyes with dark clouds, creates a wall of thick smoke, and you start feeling you know.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 Kiss or Kill</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/guida_spirituale/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/guida_spirituale/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
Kiss or Kill
9 September 1980 am in Buddha Hall
The first question Question 1 OSHO,
THERE IS DEEP IN MYSELF A YEARNING FOR THE PERMANENCY OF LOVE. IS THAT STUPID?
Prem Anna,
LOVE CAN EXIST in two dimensions: either as horizontal or as vertical. We are acquainted with the love which is horizontal. That is also the dimension of time; the vertical is the dimension of eternity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 Surprise Me!</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/guida_spirituale/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/guida_spirituale/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 16
Surprise Me!
10 September 1980 am in Buddha Hall
The first question Question 1 OSHO,
WHO NEEDS GOD WHEN WE ARE BLESSED WITH THE BEAUTIFUL FEET OF A BEAUTIFUL MASTER TO SIT UNDER?
Sheela,
YOU FOOL! That is the surest way to find God – one cannot miss. The Master is only a window. The Master simply opens into God, just as the window opens into the sky.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Going Essential</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/guida_spirituale/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/guida_spirituale/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
Going Essential
27 August 1980 am in Buddha Hall
The first question Osho,
Question 1
CAN YOU TELL US MORE ABOUT THE ESSENTIAL?
Prem Samadhi,
Man is also a seed, a possibility, a potential, a hop, a promise. But the seed is not yet the flower. In essence it has the capacity of millions of flowers, but not in reality. Those flowers have to be actualized.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 The Feel of It</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/guida_spirituale/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/guida_spirituale/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
The Feel of It
28 August 1980 am in Buddha Hall
Question 1
OSHO, MY PROBLEM IS THAT I THINK THERE IS SOMETHING WRONG WITH ME. IF I THINK THAT I HAVE A PROBLEM THEN I REALLY DO HAVE ONE. IN FACT, THINKING SEEMS TO BE JUST THE MAKING UP OF PROBLEMS. WHAT DO YOU THINK?
Deva Saguna,
I don’t think at all!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Don\&#39;t Compare</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/guida_spirituale/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/guida_spirituale/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
Don’t Compare
29 August 1980 am in Buddha Hall
The first question Osho,
Question 1
SITTING NEAR YOU I INCREASINGLY FEEL DEEP SILENCE AND WHAT SEEMS TO BE EMPTINESS, BUT THERE IS NO BLISS IN IT. I TEND TO REGARD THIS AS AN INDICATION THAT SOMETHING IS WRONG, ESPECIALLY AT DARSHAN WHERE SO MANY PEOPLE ARE SO BLISSFUL. I DON’T SEEM TO HAVE ANY IDEA WHETHER I AM ON THE RIGHT TRACK OR NOT.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 God Never Repeats</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/guida_spirituale/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/guida_spirituale/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
God Never Repeats
30 August 1980 am in Buddha Hall
“AVOID LOUD AND AGGRESSIVE PERSONS; THEY ARE VEXATIOUS TO THE SPIRIT.
“IF YOU COMPARE YOURSELF WITH OTHERS, YOU MAY BECOME VAIN OR BITTER, FOR ALWAYS THERE WILL BE GREATER AND LESSER PERSONS THAN YOURSELF.
“ENJOY YOUR ACHIEVEMENTS AS WELL AS YOUR PLANS.
“KEEP INTERESTED IN YOUR OWN CAREER, HOWEVER HUMBLE; IT IS A REAL POSSESSION IN THE CHANGING FORTUNES OF TIME.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 The Virtuous Circle</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/guida_spirituale/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/guida_spirituale/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
The Virtuous Circle
31 August 1980 am in Buddha Hall
The first question Question 1
OSHO, IS MY NAME AN ESSENTIAL OR SOMETHING NON-ESSENTIAL?
Premananda,
Existence is nameless. We are all nameless, but the name has a certain utility; without it life will be impossible. When the child is born he comes as a nobody, as pure nothingness – that’s the beauty of a child – but it is a necessity that he should be given a name.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Create a Context</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/guida_spirituale/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/guida_spirituale/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
Create a Context
1 September 1980 am in Buddha Hall
The first question Question 1
OSHO, I WELCOME YOUR STERN STEPS TO GUIDE A COUNTRY LIKE INDIA FROM SLAVERY AND POVERTY, ETC. HOWEVER, I FEEL VERY SORRY TO HEAR YOU QUOTED AS SAYING: “FOR FIFTEEN YEARS THIS COUNTRY NEEDS NO DEMOCRACY. IT HAS NOT THAT MUCH INTELLIGENCE.” PLEASE EXPLAIN WHAT YOU MEAN BY THIS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 I say, Rejoice!</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/guida_spirituale/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/guida_spirituale/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
I say, Rejoice!
2 September 1980 am in Buddha Hall
The first question Question 1 OSHO,
WHAT IS YOUR MESSAGE?
Pritam,
MY MESSAGE IS VERY SIMPLE Live life as dangerously as possible. Live life totally, intensely, passionately, because except for life there is no other God.
Friedrich Nietzsche says God is dead. That is wrong because God has never been there in the first place.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 Be Yourself</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/guida_spirituale/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/guida_spirituale/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
Be Yourself
3 September 1980 am in Buddha Hall
“BE YOURSELF.
ESPECIALLY DO NOT FEIGN AFFECTION. NEITHER BE CYNICAL ABOUT LOVE; FOR IN THE FACE OF ALL ARIDITY AND DISENCHANTMENT, IT IS AS PERENNIAL AS THE GRASS.
“TAKE KINDLY THE COUNSEL OF THE YEARS, GRACEFULLY SURRENDERING THE THINGS OF YOUTH.
“NURTURE STRENGTH OF SPIRIT TO SHIELD YOU IN SUDDEN MISFORTUNE. BUT DO NOT DISTRESS YOURSELF WITH DARK IMAGININGS.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
