<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Yoga, The Alpha and the Omega - Vol 1 on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/yoga_the_alpha_and_the_omega__vol_1/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Yoga, The Alpha and the Omega - Vol 1 on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/yoga_the_alpha_and_the_omega__vol_1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 Introduction to the path of Yoga</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/yoga_the_alpha_and_the_omega__vol_1/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/yoga_the_alpha_and_the_omega__vol_1/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
Introduction to the path of Yoga
25 December 1973 pm in
NOW THE DISCIPLINE OF YOGA. YOGA IS THE CESSATION OF MIND.
THEN THE WITNESS IS ESTABLISHED IN ITSELF.
IN THE OTHER STATES THERE IS IDENTIFICATION WITH THE MODIFICATIONS OF THE MIND.
We live in a deep illusion – the illusion of hope, of future, of tomorrow. As man is, man cannot exist without self-deceptions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 The cause of your misery</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/yoga_the_alpha_and_the_omega__vol_1/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/yoga_the_alpha_and_the_omega__vol_1/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 10
The cause of your misery
4 January 1974 pm in
The first question:
Question 1
HOW IS IT THAT YOU DESCRIBE THE LIFE THAT IS REALLY OURS, AND WHICH YOU HAVE TRANSCENDED, SO CORRECTLY AND IN EVERY DETAIL, WHILE WE REMAIN SO IGNORANT OF IT? IS IT NOT PARADOXICAL?
It looks paradoxical, it is not – because you can understand only when you have transcended.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 The desireless path of yoga</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/yoga_the_alpha_and_the_omega__vol_1/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/yoga_the_alpha_and_the_omega__vol_1/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
The desireless path of yoga
26 December 1973 pm in
The first question:
Question 1
YOU SAID LAST NIGHT THAT TOTAL DESPAIR, FRUSTRATION AND HOPELESSNESS IS THE BEGINNING GROUND FOR YOGA. THIS GIVES YOGA A PESSIMISTIC LOOK. IS THIS PESSIMISTIC STATE REALLY NECESSARY TO BEGIN THE PATH OF YOGA? DOES AN OPTIMIST ALSO BEGIN WITH THE PATH OF YOGA?
It is neither.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Five modifications of mind</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/yoga_the_alpha_and_the_omega__vol_1/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/yoga_the_alpha_and_the_omega__vol_1/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
Five modifications of mind
27 December 1973 pm in
THE MODIFICATIONS OF THE MIND ARE FIVE. THEY CAN BE EITHER A SOURCE OF ANGUISH OR OF NON-ANGUISH.
THEY ARE RIGHT KNOWLEDGE, WRONG KNOWLEDGE, IMAGINATION, SLEEP AND MEMORY.
Mind can be either the source of bondage or the source of freedom. Mind becomes the gate for this world, the entry; it can also become the exit.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Beyond mind to awareness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/yoga_the_alpha_and_the_omega__vol_1/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/yoga_the_alpha_and_the_omega__vol_1/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
Beyond mind to awareness
28 December 1973 pm in
The first question:
Question 1
YOU SAID THAT THERE ARE ONLY TWO ALTERNATIVES FOR MEN, EITHER MADNESS OR MEDITATION, BUT MILLIONS OF PEOPLE ON THE EARTH HAVE NOT REACHED TO EITHER OF THE TWO. DO YOU THINK THEY WILL?
They have reached! They have not reached to meditation, but they have reached to madness!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Right and wrong knowledge</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/yoga_the_alpha_and_the_omega__vol_1/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/yoga_the_alpha_and_the_omega__vol_1/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
Right and wrong knowledge
29 December 1973 pm in
RIGHT KNOWLEDGE HAS THREE SOURCES: DIRECT COGNITION, INFERENCE AND THE WORDS OF THE AWAKENED ONES.
WRONG KNOWLEDGE IS A FALSE CONCEPTION NOT CORRESPONDING TO THE THING AS IT IS.
AN IMAGE CONJURED UP BY WORDS WITHOUT ANY SUBSTANCE BEHIND IT IS VIKALPA – IMAGINATION.
THE MODIFICATION OF THE MIND WHICH IS BASED ON THE ABSENCE OF ANY CONTENT IN IT IS SLEEP.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 The purity of yoga</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/yoga_the_alpha_and_the_omega__vol_1/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/yoga_the_alpha_and_the_omega__vol_1/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
The purity of yoga
30 December 1973 pm in
The first question:
Question 1
YOU SAID THAT PATANJALI’S YOGA IS AN EXACT SCIENCE, ABSOLUTELY LOGICAL, IN WHICH THE RESULT IS AS CERTAIN AS TWO PLUS TWO MAKE FOUR. IF THE ATTAINMENT OF THE UNKNOWN AND INFINITE, CAN BE REDUCED TO MERE LOGIC, IS IT NOT TRUE AND AT THE SAME TIME ABSURD THAT THE INFINITE PHENOMENON IS WITHIN THE ORBIT OF THE FINITE MIND?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Constant inner practice</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/yoga_the_alpha_and_the_omega__vol_1/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/yoga_the_alpha_and_the_omega__vol_1/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
Constant inner practice
31 December 1973 pm in
THEIR CESSATION IS BROUGHT ABOUT BY PERSISTENT INNER EFFORT AND NON- ATTACHMENT.
OF THESE TWO, ABHYASA THE INNER PRACTICE IS THE EFFORT FOR BEING FIRMLY ESTABLISHED IN ONESELF.
IT BECOMES FIRMLY GROUNDED ON BEING CONTINUED FOR A LONG TIME, WITHOUT INTERRUPTION AND WITH REVERENT DEVOTION.
Man is not only his conscious mind. He has also nine times more than the conscious, the unconscious layer of the mind.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 Stop, and it is here!</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/yoga_the_alpha_and_the_omega__vol_1/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/yoga_the_alpha_and_the_omega__vol_1/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
Stop, and it is here!
1 January 1974 pm in
The first question:
Question 1
PATANJALI HAS STRESSED THE IMPORTANCE OF NON-ATTACHMENT, THAT IS, CESSATION OF DESIRES, FOR BEING ROOTED IN ONESELF. BUT IS NON-ATTACHMENT REALLY AT THE BEGINNING OF THE JOURNEY, OR AT THE VERY END?
The beginning and the end are not two things. The beginning is the end, so don’t divide them and don’t think in terms of duality.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 Practice and desirelessness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/yoga_the_alpha_and_the_omega__vol_1/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/yoga_the_alpha_and_the_omega__vol_1/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
Practice and desirelessness
3 January 1974 pm in
THE FIRST STATE OF VAIRAGYA, DESIRELESSNESS – CESSATION FROM SELF- INDULGENCE IN THE THIRST FOR SENSUOUS PLEASURES, WITH CONSCIOUS EFFORT.
THE LAST STATE OF VAIRAGYA, DESIRELESSNESS – CESSATION OF ALL DESIRING BY KNOWING THE INNERMOST NATURE OF PURUSHA, THE SUPREME SELF.
Abhyasa and vairagya – constant inner practice and desirelessness: these are the two foundation stones of Patanjali’s yoga.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
