<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Vigyan Bhairav Tantra, Vol 2 on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vigyan Bhairav Tantra, Vol 2 on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 Be a witness not a judge</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
Be a witness not a judge
25 March 1973 pm in Bombay, India
AT THE START OF SNEEZING, DURING FRIGHT, IN ANXIETY, ABOVE A CHASM, FLYING IN BATTLE, IN EXTREME CURIOSITY, AT THE BEGINNING OF HUNGER, AT THE END OF HUNGER, BE UNINTERRUPTEDLY AWARE.
THE PURITY OF OTHER TEACHINGS IS AN IMPURITY TO US. IN REALITY, KNOW NOTHING AS PURE OR IMPURE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Moving to the roots</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
Moving to the roots
23 May 1973 pm in Bombay, India
Question 1
LAST NIGHT YOU SAID THAT BY CHANGING THE OUTER, THE INNER REMAINS UNCHANGED, UNTRANSFORMED. BUT IS IT NOT TRUE THAT THE RIGHT FOOD, RIGHT LABOUR, RIGHT SLEEP, RIGHT ACTIONS AND BEHAVIORS ARE ALSO IMPORTANT FACTORS FOR INNER TRANSFORMATION? ISN’T IT A MISTAKE TO IGNORE THE OUTER COMPLETELY?
THE OUTER CANNOT CHANGE THE INNER, but the outer can help, or it can hinder.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 Come back to existence</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
Come back to existence
24 May 1973 pm in Bombay, India
IN RAIN DURING A BLACK NIGHT
ENTER THAT BLACKNESS AS THE FORM OF FORMS. WHEN A MOONLESS RAINY NIGHT IS NOT PRESENT, CLOSE EYES AND FIND BLACKNESS BEFORE YOU. OPENING EYES, SEE BLACKNESS.
SO FAULTS DISAPPEAR FOREVER. WHEREVER YOUR ATTENTION ALIGHTS, AT THIS VERY POINT,
EXPERIENCE.
Once a doctor, a very well known historian and an eminent scholar, was staying in a village.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Enter this moment</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
Enter this moment
27 May 1973 pm in Bombay, India
Question 1
THE OTHER NIGHT YOU SAID THAT PHILOSOPHIES ARE ANTI-MEDITATION. BUT ON THE OTHER HAND YOU AGREE THAT THE EASTERN PHILOSOPHIES SUCH AS TANTRA, YOGA AND VEDANT, ARE THE WRITINGS OF ENLIGHTENED SAGES. WHY DO THE ENLIGHTENED SAGES LEAVE BEHIND THEM A STRONG STRUCTURE OF PHILOSOPHICAL CONTEMPLATION, IF PHILOSOPHIES ARE ANTI-MEDITATION?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 From death to deathlessness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
From death to deathlessness
28 May 1973 pm in Bombay, India
FOCUS ON FIRE
RISING THROUGH YOUR FORM FROM THE TOES UP
UNTIL THE BODY BURNS TO ASHES BUT NOT YOU.
MEDITATE ON THE MAKE-BELIEVE WORLD AS BURNING TO ASHES AND BECOME BEING ABOVE HUMANAS,
AS SUBJECTIVELY,
LETTERS FLOW INTO WORDS AND WORDS INTO SENTENCES, AND AS, OBJECTIVELY,
CIRCLES FLOW INTO WORLDS AND WORLDS INTO PRINCIPLES, FIND AT LAST THESE CONVERGING IN OUR BEING</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 The fire of awareness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
The fire of awareness
29 May 1973 pm in Bombay, India
Question 1
A MEDITATOR WHO IS VULNERABLE, PASSIVE, OPEN AND RECEPTIVE, FEELS THAT WITH THESE CHARACTERISTICS HE SUFFERS DUE TO THE INFLUENCE OF THE NON- MEDITATIVE, NEGATIVE AND TENSE VIBRATIONS AROUND HIM. PLEASE EXPLAIN HOW HE CAN PRESERVE HIS VULNERABLE PSYCHE FROM THE HARMFUL VIBRATIONS.
If you are really vulnerable, nothing is negative for you – because the negative is your interpretation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 Only the unreal dissolves</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
Only the unreal dissolves
30 May 1973 pm in Bombay, India
FEEL: MY THOUGHT, I-NESS, INTERNAL ORGANS – ME. BEFORE DESIRE AND BEFORE KNOWING,
HOW CAN I SAY I AM?
CONSIDER. DISSOLVE IN THE BEAUTY.
Once a visitor asked many people in a small town about the mayor: ‘What type of man is your mayor?’
Said the priest, ‘He is no good.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 Discovering the emptiness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
Discovering the emptiness
31 May 1973 pm in Bombay, India
Question 1
IN MEDITATION, WHEN THE ‘I’ DROPS TEMPORARILY AND AN EMPTINESS IS CREATED WITHIN, AFTER IT A FRUSTRATION IS FELT WHEN THAT EMPTINESS IS NOT FILLED BY THE ENTRY OF THE UNKNOWN. HOW CAN ONE LEARN TO LIVE WITH THAT EMPTINESS?
Emptiness is the unknown. Don’t wait and don’t hope that something is going to fill the emptiness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 Searching for freedom</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
Searching for freedom
28 June 1973 pm in Bombay, India
TOSS ATTACHMENT FOR BODY ASIDE, REALIZING I AM EVERYWHERE.
ONE WHO IS EVERYWHERE IS JOYOUS. THINKING NO THING
WILL LIMITED-SELF UNLIMIT.
I have heard a story about an old doctor. One day his assistant phoned him because he was in very great difficulty – his patient was choking himself to death. A billiard ball was stuck in his throat, and the assistant was at a loss for what to do.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 In your hands</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
In your hands
29 June 1973 pm in Bombay, India
Question 1
TECHNIQUES ARE SHORTCUTS, REVOLUTIONS, BUT ARE NOT THESE AGAINST TAO, SWABHAV, THE NATURE?
They are. They are against tao, they are against swabhav. Any effort is against shabhav, tao; effort as such is against tao. If you can leave everything to swabhav, tao, nature, then no technique is needed, because that is the ultimate technique.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19 Watching from the hills</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
Watching from the hills
30 June 1973 pm in Bombay, India
SUPPOSE YOU CONTEMPLATE SOMETHING BEYOND PERCEPTION,
BEYOND GRASPING, BEYOND NOT BEING. – YOU.
I AM EXISTING.
THIS IS MINE.
THIS IS THIS.
OH BELOVED,
EVEN IN SUCH KNOW ILLIMITABLY.
Man is Janus-Faced – animal and divine both. Animal belongs to his past, divine belongs to his future, and this creates the difficulty.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Alertness through tantra \-- not principles</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
Alertness through tantra – not principles
26 March 1973 pm in Bombay, India
The first question:
Question 1
“IS IT NOT TRUE THAT AN IMMORAL LIFE CREATES HINDRANCES IN MEDITATION?”
What is meditation? It is not your character, it is not what you do. It is what you are. It is not the character, it is the consciousness that you bring to whatsoever you do.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 Liberation from yourself</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
Liberation from yourself
1 July 1973 pm in Bombay, India
Question 1
YOU SAY THAT RELIGION IS TOTAL FREEDOM OR MOKSHA, AND YOU ALSO STRESS THE IMPORTANCE OF SURRENDER IN RELIGION. BUT ARE NOT FREEDOM AND SURRENDER CONTRADICTORY IN TERMS?
They appear contradictory but they are not. And they appear so because of the language; existentially they are not. Try to understand two things.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 Techniques to become one with the whole</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
Techniques to become one with the whole
2 July 1973 pm in Bombay, India
EACH THING IS PERCEIVED THROUGH KNOWING. THE SELF SHINES IN SPACE THROUGH KNOWING. PERCEIVE ONE BEING AS KNOWER AND KNOWN. BELOVED,
AT THIS MOMENT
LET, MIND, KNOWING, BREATH, FORM, BE INCLUDED.
I have heard one anecdote. In a conservative party rally, Lord Mancroft was invited to speak. He came right on time, reached the rostrum and said to the public – he was looking a little flustered – he said, ‘Forgive me for shortening my speech a little, but the fact is that my house is on fire.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22 Right now is the goal</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
Right now is the goal
3 July 1973 pm in Bombay, India
Question 1
YESTERDAY YOU SAID THAT ONE SHOULD HURRY TOWARDS THE GOAL BECAUSE WHATEVER TIME WE HAVE IS VERY LITTLE. HOWEVER, SOME TIME AGO YOU ALSO SAID THAT THE WHOLE PROCESS OF ATTAINING THE GOAL SHOULD BE AN EFFORTLESS PLAY. HOW WOULD YOU RECONCILE THE TWO WORDS ‘HURRY’ AND ‘PLAY’?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23 No map to follow</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
No map to follow
4 July 1973 pm in Bombay, India
TOUCHING EYEBALLS AS A FEATHER, LIGHTNESS BETWEEN THEM OPENS INTO HEART AND THERE PERMEATES THE COSMOS.
KIND DEVI,
ENTER ETHERIC PRESENCE
PERVADING FAR ABOVE AND BELOW YOUR FORM.
Once it happened in a church that after a very long dry sermon, the minister announced that there would be a meeting, a brief meeting of the board, right after the benediction.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 Choicelessness is bliss</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 24
Choicelessness is bliss
5 July 1973 pm in Bombay, India
Question 1
IS IT THAT THERE ARE ONLY TWO ALTERNATIVES BEFORE MAN – A LIFE OF ABIDING SORROW AND SUFFERING OR ONE OF DIVINITY AND BLISS – AND THIS CHOICE LIES WITH HIM? HOW IS IT THAT MOST HAVE CHOSEN THE PATH OF SORROW AND SUFFERING?
It is a very significant question, but very delicate also.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25 Life is a mystery, not a problem</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 25
Life is a mystery, not a problem
25 July 1973 pm in Bombay, India
PUT MINDSTUFF
IN SUCH INEXPRESSIBLE FINENESS ABOVE, BELOW AND IN YOUR HEART.
CONSIDER ANY AREA OF YOUR PRESENT FORM AS LIMITLESSLY SPACIOUS.
Life is not a problem but a mystery. For science life is a problem, but for religion it is a mystery. A problem can be solved, a mystery cannot be solved – it can be lived but it cannot be solved.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26 Enlightenment \-- the most ordinary</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 26
Enlightenment – the most ordinary
26 July 1973 pm in Bombay, India
The first question:
Question 1
LAST NIGHT YOU SAID THAT WHEN THERE ARE NO THOUGHTS IN THE MIND, THE MIND BECOMES AN EMPTY SPACE AND THE DOORS TO ALL THE MYSTERIES ARE OPENED. I FEEL THIS INNER SPACE DEEPLY AND CLEARLY BUT THERE IS NOTHING SPECIAL THAT I FEEL AS MYSTERY.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27 Neither mind nor matter</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 27
Neither mind nor matter
27 July 1973 pm in Bombay, India
FEEL YOUR SUBSTANCE, BONES, FLESH, BLOOD, SATURATED WITH THE COSMIC ESSENCE.
FEEL THE FINE QUALITIES OF CREATIVITY PERMEATING YOUR BREASTS’ AND ASSUMING DELICATE CONFIGURATIONS.
Philosophers all over the world have been arguing for centuries about what basic stuff the universe is made of, what the substance is. There have been propositions, systems, that say that matter is the basic reality and mind is just an outgrowth, that matter is basic and mind is just a by-product, that mind is also material, only subtle.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28 If you get serious you lose the point</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part28/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 28
If you get serious you lose the point
28 July 1973 pm in Bombay, India
The first question:
Question 1
IT HAS BEEN SAID THAT NO DESIRE, NEITHER WORLDLY NOR RELIGIOUS, CAN LEAD TOWARDS FREEDOM. BUT A POSITIVE IMAGINATION OF HAPPINESS AND BLISS IS ALSO A SORT OF DESIRE. THEN ISN’T IT TRUE THAT IMAGINATION IS ALSO DESIRE AND HENCE CREATES TENSIONS?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>29 You are unknown to yourself</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part29/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 29
You are unknown to yourself
29 July 1973 pm in Bombay, India
ABIDE IN SOME PLACE ENDLESSLY SPACIOUS, CLEAR OF TREES, HILLS, HABITATIONS. THENCE COMES THE END OF MIND PRESSURES.
CONSIDER THE PLENUM TO BE YOUR OWN BODY OF BLISS.
Man is born alone and dies alone, but between these two points he lives in society, he lives with others.
Aloneness is his basic reality; society is just accidental.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Finding the changeless through the changing</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
Finding the changeless through the changing
27 March 1973 pm in Bombay, India
BE THE UNSAME SAME TO FRIEND AS TO STRANGER, IN HONOR AND DISHONOR.
HERE IS THE SPHERE OF CHANGE, CHANGE, CHANGE. THROUGH CHANGE CONSUME CHANGE.
Northrope says somewhere that the Western mind has been continuously searching for the theoretical component of existence – the causal link for how things happen, what is the cause, how the effect can be controlled, how man can manipulate nature.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>30 Aloneness is pain</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part30/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 30
Aloneness is pain
30 July 1973 pm in Bombay, India
The first question:
Question 1
CONFRONTATION OF ONESELF IN ALONENESS IS VERY FEARFUL, VERY PAINFUL. WHAT TO DO?
It is fearful and it is painful, and one has to suffer it. Nothing should be done to avoid it, nothing should be done to divert the mind, nothing should be done to escape form it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>31 Forget the periphery</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part31/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 31
Forget the periphery
31 July 1973 pm in Bombay, India
IN ANY POSITION GRADUALLY PERVADE AN AREA BETWEEN THE ARMPITS INTO GREAT PEACE.
FEEL YOURSELF AS PERVADING ALL DIRECTIONS, FAR, NEAR.
Life without is a cyclone – a constant conflict, turmoil, struggle. But it is only so on the surface – just as on the surface of the ocean are waves, maddening noise, constant struggle.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>32 Falling in love with an enlightened person</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part32/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part32/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 32
Falling in love with an enlightened person
1 August 1973 pm in Bombay, India
The first question:
Question 1
YOU SAID THAT LOVE IS POSSIBLE ONLY WITH DEATH. THEN WILL YOU PLEASE EXPLAIN BUDDHA’S LOVE.
For an ignorant person love is always part of hate, it always goes with hate. For the ignorant mind hate and love are just two aspects of the same coin.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>33 Fear of transformation</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part33/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part33/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 33
Fear of transformation
1 November 1973 pm in Bombay, India
THE APPRECIATION OF OBJECTS AND SUBJECTS IS THE SAME FOR AN ENLIGHTENED AS FOR AN UNENLIGHTENED PERSON. THE FORMER HAS ONE GREATNESS: HE REMAINS IN THE SUBJECTIVE MOOD, NOT LOST IN THINGS.
BELIEVE OMNISCIENT, OMNIPOTENT, PERVADING.
Many people seem to be interested in meditation, but that interest cannot be very deep because so very few are transformed through it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>34 The greater the sensitivity, the greater the detachment</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part34/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part34/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 34
The greater the sensitivity, the greater the detachment
2 November 1973 pm in Bombay, India
The first question:
Question 1
WITH DEEPENING MEDITATION, ONE BECOMES MORE AND MORE SENSITIVE TO OBJECTS, EVENTS AND PERSONS. BUT DUE TO THIS HEIGHTENED SENSITIVITY ONE FEELS A SORT OF DEEP INTIMACY WITH EVERYTHING, AND THIS USUALLY BECOMES A CAUSE OF SUBTLE ATTACHMENTS. HOW TO BE SENSITIVE AND YET DETACHED?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>35 The search for the rhythm of the opposites</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part35/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part35/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 35
The search for the rhythm of the opposites
3 November 1973 pm in Bombay, India
IMAGE SPIRIT SIMULTANEOUSLY WITHIN AND AROUND YOU UNTIL THE ENTIRE UNIVERSE SPIRITUALIZES.
WITH YOUR ENTIRE CONSCIOUSNESS IN THE VERY START OF DESIRE, OF KNOWING, KNOW.
O SHAKTI, EACH PARTICULAR PERCEPTION IS LIMITED, DISAPPEARING IN OMNIPOTENCE.
IN TRUTH FORMS ARE INSEPARATE. INSEPARATE ARE OMNIPRESENT BEING AND YOUR OWN FORM.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>36 Buddha\&#39;s inner orgasm</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part36/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part36/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 36
Buddha’s inner orgasm
4 November 1973 pm in Bombay, India
The first question:
Question 1
WE HAVE ALWAYS HEARD THAT TANTRA IS BASICALLY CONCERNED WITH SEX ENERGY AND SEX CENTER TECHNIQUES, BUT YOU SAY THAT TANTRA IS ALL-INCLUSIVE. IF THERE IS ANY TRUTH IN THE FORMER STANDPOINT, THE MAJORITY OF TECHNIQUES IN VIGYANA BHAIRAVA SEEM TO BE NON-TANTRIC. IS THIS TRUE?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>37 Become each being</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part37/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part37/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 37
Become each being
5 November 1973 pm in Bombay, India
FEEL THE CONSCIOUSNESS OF EACH PERSON AS YOUR OWN CONSCIOUSNESS. SO, LEAVING ASIDE CONCERN FOR SELF, BECOME EACH BEING.
THIS CONSCIOUSNESS EXISTS AS EACH BEING, AND NOTHING ELSE EXISTS. THIS CONSCIOUSNESS IS THE SPIRIT OF GUIDANCE OF EACH ONE. BE THIS ONE.
Existence as such is one. The human problem arises because of human self-consciousness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>38 The inner guide</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part38/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part38/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 38
The inner guide
6 November 1973 pm in Bombay, India
The first question:
Question 1
SOME OF THE TECHNIQUES IN THE ONE HUNDRED AND TWELVE METHODS SEEM TO BE END RESULTS AND NOT TECHNIQUES, SUCH AS THOSE THAT SAY TO “BECOME UNIVERSAL CONSCIOUSNESS” OR “BE THIS ONE” ETC. IT SEEMS THAT WE NEED TECHNIQUES TO ACHIEVE THESE TECHNIQUES. WERE TECHNIQUES LIKE THESE MEANT FOR VERY ADVANCED PERSONS WHO COULD JUST BECOME COSMIC AT A MERE SUGGESTION?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>39 Sunyawad \-- the philosophy of emptiness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part39/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part39/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 39
Sunyawad – the philosophy of emptiness
7 November 1973 pm in Bombay, India
SUPPOSE YOUR PASSIVE FORM TO BE AN EMPTY ROOM WITH WALLS OF SKIN – EMPTY.
GRACIOUS ONE, PLAY. THE UNIVERSE IS AN EMPTY SHELL WHEREIN YOUR MIND FROLICS INFINITELY.
SWEET HEARTED ONE, MEDITATE ON KNOWING AND NOT-KNOWING, EXISTING AND NOT- EXISTING. THEN LEAVE BOTH ASIDE THAT YOU MAY BE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Tantra\&#39;s secrets of love and liberation</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
Tantra’s secrets of love and liberation
28 March 1973 pm in Bombay, India
The first question:
Question 1
“IN REFERENCE TO YOUR STATEMENT THAT TANTRA IS A LOVE TECHNIQUE, PLEASE EXPLAIN WHY MODERN MAN AND WOMAN HAVE BECOME INCAPABLE OF LOVE.”
Love is spontaneous. It cannot be controlled. You cannot “make” love; you cannot do anything about it. And the more you do, the more you will miss it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>40 All and nothing mean the same</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part40/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part40/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 40
All and nothing mean the same
8 November 1973 pm in Bombay, India
The first question:
Question 1
YOU SAID THAT REALLY THERE IS NO ONE INSIDE US, THERE IS ONLY A VOID, AN EMPTINESS, BUT THEN WHY DO YOU OFTEN CALL IT THE BEING, THE CENTER?
Being or non-being, nothing or all – they look contradictory but they both mean the same. All and nothing mean the same.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Remaining with the real</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
Remaining with the real
29 March 1973 pm in Bombay, India
AS A HEN MOTHERS HER CHICKS, MOTHER PARTICULAR KNOWINGS, PARTICULAR DOINGS, IN REALITY.
SINCE, IN TRUTH, BONDAGE AND FREEDOM ARE RELATIVE, THESE WORDS ARE ONLY FOR THOSE TERRIFIED WITH THE UNIVERSE. THIS UNIVERSE IS A REFLECTION OF MINDS. AS YOU SEE MANY SUNS IN WATER FROM ONE SUN, SO SEE BONDAGE AND LIBERATION.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 The tantric way to freedom from desires</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
The tantric way to freedom from desires
30 March 1973 pm in Bombay, India
The first question:
Question 1
“YOU SAID YESTERDAY THAT THE MOTIVATION TOWARDS LIBERATION OR SAMADHI IS ALSO A TENSION AND A BARRIER, BUT IS IT NOT CORRECT THAT IT IS NOT A DESIRE BUT AN ASPIRATION – THE INTRINSIC THIRST OF THE HUMAN BEING?”
You must understand what desire means, and religions have confused you much about it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Tantric meditation with light techniques</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
Tantric meditation with light techniques
31 March 1973 pm in Bombay, India
CONSIDER YOUR ESSENCE AS LIGHT RAYS FROM CENTER TO CENTER UP THE VERTEBRAE, AND SO RISES “LIVINGNESS” IN YOU.
OR IN THE SPACES BETWEEN, FEEL THIS AS LIGHTNING.
FEEL THE COSMOS AS A TRANSLUCENT EVER-LIVING PRESENCE.
Man can be considered in three ways: in terms of the normal, the abnormal and the supernormal.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 The potentiality of the seed</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
The potentiality of the seed
1 April 1973 pm in Bombay, India
The first question:
Question 1
“LAST NIGHT YOU SAID THAT A KRISHNA, A CHRIST, A BUDDHA, THEY ARE THE CLIMAX OF HUMAN POSSIBILITY AND GROWTH, AND THEN YOU SAID THAT YOGIC AND TANTRIC PSYCHOLOGY PUT NO IDEAL BEFORE MAN AND THAT TO HAVE AN IDEAL IS A MISTAKE ACCORDING TO TANTRA.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 Conscious doing</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/vigyan_bhairav_tantra_vol_2/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
Conscious doing
22 May 1973 pm in Bombay, India
IN SUMMER WHEN YOU SEE THE ENTIRE SKY ENDLESSLY CLEAR ENTER SUCH CLARITY. SHAKTI,
SEE ALL SPACE AS IF ALREADY ABSORBED IN YOUR OWN HEAD IN THE BRILLIANCE.
WAKING, SLEEPING, DREAMING, KNOW YOU AS LIGHT.
AS I LOOK IN YOUR EYES I never see you there – as if you are absent. You exist absently, and this is the core of all suffering.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
