<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Satyam Shivam Sundram on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Satyam Shivam Sundram on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 Satyam, Shivam, Sundram</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
Satyam, Shivam, Sundram
7 November 1987 am in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHAT IS THE MYSTIC CONCEPTION OF ULTIMATE REALITY?
Maneesha, the mystic’s conception of the ultimate reality is the only authentic, real experience. It is not a thought or a concept, but an existential experience.
But the mystic does not deal with the mind. His whole effort is to get rid of the prison of the mind.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Only the meditators comes to know his whole being</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
Only the meditators comes to know his whole being
11 November 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
RIGVEDA SAYS, “LET NOBLE THOUGHTS COME TO US FROM EVERY SIDE.” DO YOU AGREE WITH THIS STATEMENT?
Chaitanya Kirti, I do not agree with RIGVEDA and its statement. It appears only to the intellectuals as true.
But those who know, know perfectly well that thoughts are simply thoughts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 You cannot hurt a humble man</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
You cannot hurt a humble man
12 November 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHAT IS THE DIFFERENCE BETWEEN BEING HUMBLE, BEING SHY, AND JUST HIDING OUT OF FEAR?
Anand Shantideva, the difference between being humble, being shy, and just hiding out of fear is immensely great. But man’s unawareness is such that he is not even capable of making distinctions between his own actions and responses to reality; otherwise, the difference is so clear that even to ask the question is useless.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Buts, ifs and hows</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
Buts, ifs and hows
12 November 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
HOW CAN I LEAVE MY EGO OUTSIDE THE FRONT GATE? IT FOLLOWS ME LIKE A SHADOW AND EVEN HIDES BEHIND MY BACK AND THEN I AM NOT ABLE TO SEE IT.
Anand Shantideva, the question shows you have not understood the meaning of the ego. It is not something visible or tangible; it is not even a shadow that follows you.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 A peace that passeth all misunderstanding</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
A peace that passeth all misunderstanding
13 November 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHY AM I FORCING SITUATIONS ACCORDING TO MY WILL, INSTEAD OF ACCEPTING THEM AND LETTING THEM JUST HAPPEN? I HAVE A FEELING THAT MY BODY MAKES ME AWARE OF IT, REACTING WITH HIGH FEVER.
Devam Navyo, the upbringing of man is so poisonous, so crippling, that it destroys all that is significant and valuable in you and replaces it with cruelty, violence, a desire to dominate.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 Nuclear weapons, and a cowardly soul</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
Nuclear weapons, and a cowardly soul
13 November 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
THE UNITED STATES GOVERNMENT PROUDLY PROCLAIMS ITSELF THE LAND OF THE FREE AND THE HOME OF THE BRAVE AND POINTS TO ITS CONSTITUTIONAL PROTECTIONS OF FUNDAMENTAL RIGHTS. AT THE SAME TIME IT TWISTS AND BREAKS ITS OWN LAWS TO PERSECUTE YOU WHO EMBODY FREEDOM AND TRUTH.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 Choose the flowers, leave the thorns</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
Choose the flowers, leave the thorns
14 November 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
FROM WHAT I HEARD YOU SAY, I UNDERSTOOD THAT FOR ENLIGHTENMENT TO HAPPEN, MEDITATION IS A PREPARATION, BUT ALSO AN INTENSE URGE IS REQUIRED, A REALIZATION THAT NOTHING ELSE REALLY MATTERS. I SEE MYSELF BEING INTERESTED IN ALL KINDS OF THINGS, ALL KINDS OF MIND-STORIES, MUSIC, WOMEN, SENSE PERCEPTIONS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 Going inwards, going godwards</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
Going inwards, going godwards
14 November 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHY AM I ALWAYS RUNNING SO FAST? IS THERE SOMETHING THAT I DON’T WANT TO SEE?
Prem Amita, it is not only you; almost everybody is running as fast as he can from himself. And the problem is, you cannot run away from yourself.
Wherever you go you will be yourself.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 You have to put aside your fear</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
You have to put aside your fear
15 November 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I HAVE HAD A GLIMPSE OF WHAT IT COULD BE TO JUST BE. BUT SO MUCH FEAR COMES UP ABOUT DOING NOTHING, I HAVE THIS SENSE THAT I AM STUCK. WHAT IS THIS FEAR?
Deva Tharsita, the first glimpse of one’s own being is inevitably unbelievable, firstly because you have not known it before so you cannot recognize what it is.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 The mystic rose</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
The mystic rose
15 November 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHAT IS THE SECRET OF THE MAGIC ROSE?
Milarepa, it is not a question suitable to you, but I will answer anyway. The mystic rose is an ancient symbol of tremendous importance.
Charles Darwin propounded a theory of evolution. Most of it is relevant, but he has missed something very basic.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19 A blessing from beyond</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
A blessing from beyond
16 November 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
SOMETIMES I HAVE THE FEELING THAT SEX HAS DROPPED ME, BUT IT SEEMS I HAVE NOT GOT IT YET. OR I JUST DON’T WANT TO ACCEPT THE FACT OF IT. CAN YOU HELP ME TO UNDERSTAND WHAT IS GOING ON?
Sarjano, the Western mind has completely forgotten that sex is not life; hence everyone born in the West carries in his unconscious the idea that the moment sex is finished, all is finished.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 My presence says all</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
My presence says all
7 November 1987 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
THE OTHER MORNING WHEN I HEARD YOU TALKING ABOUT SEXUAL ENERGY, AIDS AND BIRTH CONTROL, I FELT SUCH A PURE RIGHTNESS ABOUT EACH THING THAT YOU SAID. YOU ARE THE INTELLECTUAL GIANT OF THE CENTURY. THERE IS NO COMPETITION.
I ALSO FEEL THE SENSE OF URGENCY.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 The radiation of enlightenment</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
The radiation of enlightenment
16 November 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
THE OTHER DAY YOU WERE TELLING US THE EFFECTS OF RADIOACTIVE MATTER ON THE BODY. BUT I AM FEELING AND EXPERIENCING THE RADIATION OF A BUDDHA – AN ENORMOUS ENERGY RADIATING FROM YOU WHICH NOT ONLY REJUVENATES BODY-MIND CONTINUOUSLY, BUT MAKES US LAUGH, DANCE AND CELEBRATE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 Only the meditator knows there is no death</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
Only the meditator knows there is no death
17 November 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
FOR ABOUT SIX MONTHS I HAVE BEEN WAKING UP EVERY MORNING WITH A DEEP FEAR OF DEATH. I MUST BE MISSING THE MOST IMPORTANT EXPERIENCES IN MY MEDITATION TO BE SO AFRAID OF DEATH IN MY SLEEP. YEARS AGO, I WOKE UP EVERY MORNING WITH A SMILE AND DEEP HAPPINESS THAT I HAD FOUND YOU.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22 Unknown territories, unexplored skies</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
Unknown territories, unexplored skies
17 November 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
SEX SEEMS TO BE DROPPING ME. IS MUSIC NEXT?
Milarepa, sex is dropping so many people that the problem is not that sex is dropping you also, the problem is that many others may start picking it up! Dropping is okay; avoid picking up.
And I can understand your worry.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23 Jump into life\&#39;s deepest waters</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
Jump into life’s deepest waters
18 November 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHY SUCH AN ENORMOUS FEAR OF ALLOWING MYSELF TO BE REALLY ALIVE?
Veet Vishada, the fear of allowing oneself to be really alive is not the fear of life; it is a very camouflaged fear of death. If you are alive, you will die. Death is the culmination of life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 A handful of dry leaves</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 24
A handful of dry leaves
18 November 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHEN I HEAR YOU SAY THAT YOU ARE ONLY HERE FOR US, I FEEL SUCH AN URGENCY ARISING IN ME, SUCH A DEEP URGE TO MOVE DEEP INSIDE BEYOND ALL MY LITTLE PIDDLY TRIPS AND LIMITATIONS, AND YET INSIDE REALIZING SUCH A DEEP HELPLESSNESS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25 Just learn to be aware in all situations</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 25
Just learn to be aware in all situations
19 November 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
INSIDE, THERE IS SOMETHING THAT I CANNOT LOOK AT, I CAN ONLY BE IT. AND THEN I AM AT THE CENTER OF EXPERIENCING MY MIND, MY BODY, AND WHAT COMES TO MY SENSES. THIS FEELS ECSTATIC, YET IS VERY SUBTLE, AND EASILY DISAPPEARS WHEN I AGAIN IDENTIFY WITH WHAT IS EXPERIENCED.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26 This great adventure</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 26
This great adventure
19 November 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
THIS MORNING THE TOP OF MY HEAD FLEW OFF TO GREET YOU. LIKE A LIDLESS POT I SAT DRINKING YOU IN.
SUDDENLY A QUESTION POPPED UP: ALL THE HISTORICAL REBELLIONS HAVE A HUGE “NO” AT THEIR SOURCE. YOUR REBELLION OF THE SOUL IS CENTERED IN THE MYSTERY OF “YES.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27 Love: the conscious path of the ego</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 27
Love: the conscious path of the ego
20 November 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
SITTING WITH YOU, THERE ARE TWO PARTS OF ME OPERATING, ONE OPPOSING THE OTHER. ONE PART LOVES AND TRUSTS YOU MORE THAN ANY MAN I’VE EVER MET. THE OTHER IS JUST PLAIN AFRAID OF YOU – AFRAID OF YOUR UNWAVERING TRUTH AND THE AUTHORITY THAT IT GIVES YOU.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28 Become an outsider</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part28/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 28
Become an outsider
20 November 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
MORE AND MORE IT HAPPENS THAT I’M ALONE, AND I AM BEGINNING TO LOVE AND ENJOY THIS SILENT SPACE. BUT A FEAR IS COMING UP: I AM AFRAID THAT IN THIS WAY I WILL LOSE CONTACT WITH OTHERS AND I WILL BECOME A STRANGER.
I FEEL A LONGING THAT BRINGS ME TOWARDS YOU, BUT A PASSION AND DESIRE TO FALL IN LOVE WITH SOMEONE SEEMS TO BE NO MORE THERE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>29 Therapy, hypnosis and meditation</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part29/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 29
Therapy, hypnosis and meditation
21 November 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHILE USING HYPNOSIS IN THE SERVICE OF MEDITATION, I HAVE NOTICED THAT THE LINE BETWEEN THERAPY AND MEDITATION IS DISSOLVING. AS WITNESSING CAN BECOME EASY AND NATURAL IN HYPNOSIS, IT SEEMS TO PROVIDE THE GROUND FOR A QUANTUM LEAP INTO NO-MIND.
BELOVED MASTER, WOULD YOU SPEAK ON THE TRANSFORMATION OF HYPNOSIS INTO MEDITATION?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Learn the art of living with the eternal</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
Learn the art of living with the eternal
8 November 1987 am in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHY AM I NOT CURIOUS ABOUT ANYTHING ANYMORE?
Devageet, twelve hundred years ago there was a mystery school exactly like this. The mystery school belonged to one of the greatest Sufis, Mevlana Jalaluddin Rumi. The Turkish word mevlana means Beloved Master; it has never been used for anyone else.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>30 In search of the ultimate new</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part30/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 30
In search of the ultimate new
21 November 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHY IS THE NEW SO SCARY? MY WANTING AND NEED FOR RECOGNITION ARE GONE ALONG WITH THE DOING. EVEN THOUGH DEEP INSIDE I AM TREMENDOUSLY THANKFUL AND HAPPY, I FIND PART OF MYSELF FEELING GUILTY. I SEE AS WELL THAT LAZINESS IS NOT ONE OF MY QUALITIES.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 A quality which is immeasurable</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
A quality which is immeasurable
8 November 1987 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
HOW CAN I LOVE BETTER?
Indradhanu, love is enough unto itself. It needs no betterment. It is perfect as it is; it is not in any way to be more perfect. The very desire shows a misunderstanding about love and its nature. Can you have a perfect circle?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Remember the art of let go</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
Remember the art of let go
9 November 1987 am in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHY IS IT SO DIFFICULT TO BE IN A STATE OF LET-GO?
Puja Kavina, the world needs workaholics. It needs people to be slaves, to be proletariats, to be laborers and function just like machines; hence all the so-called moralists and puritans have been teaching people that work has some intrinsic value.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Every enlightened man has all the flavors of truth</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
Every enlightened man has all the flavors of truth
9 November 1987 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I DON’T UNDERSTAND WHY ENLIGHTENED MASTERS ARE CRITICAL OF EACH OTHER. ARE THEY NOT ALL WORKING TOWARDS THE HIGHER GOOD?
ARE THEY NOT DIFFERENT FLAVORS OF THE SAME TRUTH?
Anand Varuni, the question you have asked is almost impossible to answer for the simple reason that you are not enlightened yet.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 A beautiful servant, a dangerous master</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
A beautiful servant, a dangerous master
10 November 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
HOW DOES WATCHING LEAD TO NO-MIND? I AM MORE AND MORE ABLE TO WATCH MY BODY, MY THOUGHTS AND FEELINGS AND THIS FEELS BEAUTIFUL. BUT MOMENTS OF NO THOUGHTS ARE FEW AND FAR BETWEEN. WHEN I HEAR YOU SAYING “MEDITATION IS WITNESSING,” I FEEL I UNDERSTAND.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 Just learn to be yourself</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
Just learn to be yourself
10 November 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
WHY AM I SCARED TO ACCEPT MYSELF THE WAY I AM?
Kalyan Mitto, everybody is in the same situation. Everybody is scared to accept himself the way he is. This is how all the past centuries of mankind have cultivated, conditioned every child, every human being.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 The great affair</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/satyam_shivam_sundram/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
The great affair
11 November 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I FEEL AND KNOW IN MY HEART, I AM YOUR DISCIPLE. I DON’T FEEL I AM YET A DEVOTEE ALTHOUGH I ASPIRE TO BE ONE. IS IT THE NATURE OF BEING A DEVOTEE THAT ONE KNOWS ONE HAS BECOME ONE? OR DOES THE INNOCENCE OF THE DEVOTEE MAKE THE AWARENESS OF IT NOT POSSIBLE?</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
