<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>YAA-HOO! The Mystic Rose on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/</link>
    <description>Recent content in YAA-HOO! The Mystic Rose on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 I am a beginning and an end</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
I am a beginning and an end
19 March 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
MY WHOLE BEING BOWS TO YOUR FEET, BUT IT IS VERY DIFFICULT FOR ME TO TAKE MY EYES FROM YOUR BEAUTIFUL, RADIANT BEING, WHEN YOU GREET US COMING AND GOING IN THE MORNING. AM I MISSING BY PEEKING? IS THIS ATTACHMENT TO YOUR PHYSICAL PRESENCE AND FORM SOMETHING THAT HAS TO BE TRANSCENDED?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 That flame depends on you</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
That flame depends on you
28 March 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
IT SEEMS WESTERN MINDS CRAVE NEW EXPERIENCES. IF MEDITATION IS CONCERNED WITH THE EXPERIENCER, NOT THE EXPERIENCE, HOW DO THE NEW HI-TECH EXPERIENCE KITS MOVE US INTO MEDITATION?
Pradeepa, the question you have asked is very relevant, particularly because so many machines are being developed around the world, pretending that they can give you meditation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 These creatures are found everywhere</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
These creatures are found everywhere
29 March 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHEN DOES THE DISCIPLE’S FREEDOM BECOME HIS MASTER’S CONDEMNATION?
Milarepa, the authentic disciple has never condemned the master. In fact, he cannot condemn the master; the master has become his own heart and being.
To condemn the master is to condemn oneself. But yes, there are so-called disciples.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 On the flight alone</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
On the flight alone
30 March 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I HAVE READ THAT KABIR SAYS, “I LEAVE BEHIND MY CLOAK INTACT. I WORE MY CLOAK WITH GREAT CARE AND THEN PUT IT ASIDE AS I FOUND IT, WITHOUT IMPAIRING IT IN ANY WAY. OH SWAN, TAKE OFF ON THE FLIGHT ALONE.”
OSHO, WHAT IS THIS?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 Just ordinary friday</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
Just ordinary friday
1 April 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WE ARE TRYING TO LIVE IN THE HERE AND NOW – ESPECIALLY IF WE ARE IN POONA. BUT NEVERTHELESS WE SOMETIMES THINK OF THE FUTURE.
I ASK MYSELF, IF NOBODY ELSE HEARS YOUR VOICE EXCEPT US, WHAT WILL HAPPEN IN THE YEAR 2017? WHAT MORE CAN WE DO SO THAT YOU WILL BE HEARD AND THE BAD VISION OF THE YEAR 2017 THAT I HAVE WILL NOT HAPPEN?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 The way goes through</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
The way goes through
2 April 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO...
GURDJIEFF IS REPORTED TO HAVE COMMENTED: “ORDINARY MEN NEVER EXPERIENCE TRUE SUFFERING AND SORROW, FOR THEY LIVE MECHANICAL AND ROUTINE LIVES, AND THEIR TROUBLES ARE ROUTINE, AUTOMATIC AND INESCAPABLE. BUT A MAN WHO HAS WILLFULLY UNDERTAKEN THE EXTRAORDINARY AND UNNECESSARY BURDEN OF THE WORK, HE ALONE KNOWS THE TASTE OF REAL SORROW AND SICKNESS OF HEART, FOR HE WILL SUFFER PAIN AND PRESSURES THAT LIFE DOES NOT ORDINARILY REQUIRE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 Never ask, \&#34;who am i?\&#34;</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
Never ask, “who am i?”
3 April 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
IN HIS BOOK, CODEX HAMMER, LEONARDO DA VINCI HAS WRITTEN:
“IT IS IMPOSSIBLE THAT ANYTHING OF ITSELF ALONE CAN BE CAUSE OF ITS CREATION, AND THOSE THINGS WHICH ARE OF THEMSELVES ARE ETERNAL.”
WOULD YOU LIKE TO SPEAK ON THIS?
Jivan Mada, the question is one of those which has been contemplated for centuries and yet no answer exists.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 Helplessness: another name of let-go</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
Helplessness: another name of let-go
4 April 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I AM SEEING A CERTAIN HELPLESSNESS ARISING IN ME. IT IS A FEELING THAT I HAD FEARED AND ALWAYS TRIED TO AVOID IN THE PAST.
YET, AS IT BEGINS TO OVERWHELM ME, IT BRINGS A SENSE OF FREEDOM I HAVE SELDOM, IF EVER, EXPERIENCED BEFORE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 A no-return state of affairs</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
A no-return state of affairs
5 April 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHEN YOU INITIATED ME EIGHT YEARS AGO, I HAD MY OWN BUSINESS, A GREAT CAR, A NICE APARTMENT AND ALWAYS A BEAUTIFUL WOMAN AROUND. I DRESSED MYSELF IN A THREE-PIECE BUSINESS UNIFORM COMPLETE WITH BRIEFCASE.
NOW, I LIVE IN A BAMBOO HUT, DRIVE A RENTED BIKE, DRESS MYSELF IN A NEHRU SHIRT AND STRANGE COTTON PANTS; VERY RARELY DO I ALLOW A WOMAN TO COME CLOSE ANYMORE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 Love the only freedom from attachment</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
Love the only freedom from attachment
6 April 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Just read! Question 1 BELOVED OSHO, MIRDAD SAYS,
“LOVE IS THE ONLY FREEDOM FROM ATTACHMENT. WHEN YOU LOVE EVERYTHING YOU ARE ATTACHED TO NOTHING.”
AND LATER ON:
“MAN MADE PRISONER BY THE LOVE OF A WOMAN AND WOMAN MADE PRISONER BY THE LOVE OF A MAN ARE EQUALLY UNFIT FOR FREEDOM’S PRECIOUS CROWN.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19 No \&#34;I\&#34; no \&#34;you\&#34; \-- just a mirror reflecting</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
No “I” no “you” – just a mirror reflecting
7 April 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHAT EXACTLY IS THIS UNCONSCIOUS MIND WHICH IS ALSO CALLED THE DARK NIGHT OF THE SOUL? IS IT SOMETHING BELONGING TO THE PHYSICAL MONKEY BRAIN? OR IS IT SOMETHING OF THE UNIVERSAL MIND, WHICH I AM ASSUMING IS MY OWN HIGHER MIND?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Nowhere and everywhere</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
Nowhere and everywhere
20 March 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
AT THE AGE OF SIXTEEN I LEFT MY BODY AFTER A CAR ACCIDENT. WHEN I SAW THAT THE PEOPLE I LOVED COULD NOT SEE OR UNDERSTAND MY HAPPINESS, I ENTERED MY BODY, IN A STATE OF SHOCK, AND STAYED UNCONSCIOUS FOR TWO MONTHS.
FOR A FEW WEEKS I HAVE BEEN EXPERIENCING A VERY SIMILAR STATE OF BEING IN MY MEDITATION, AND SITTING IN FRONT OF YOU.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 Just a glimpse and the work is done</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
Just a glimpse and the work is done
8 April 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
IN THE TWO MINUTES OF SILENCE AND LET-GO THE OTHER NIGHT, YOU TOOK US TO THE HIGHEST LEVEL OF CONSCIOUSNESS.
THE SOUNDLESS SOUND AND INEXPRESSIBLE GRATITUDE INSIDE, EVEN THE WATCHER DISAPPEARS. I CANNOT BELIEVE HOW EASY IT IS!
BELOVED MASTER, IS THIS ENERGY ALWAYS AVAILABLE, OR ONLY CLOSE TO YOUR PHYSICAL PRESENCE?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 I have come again the storm has persuaded me</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
I have come again the storm has persuaded me
9 April 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
PLEASE ACCEPT OUR APOLOGY FOR OUR BEHAVIOR LAST NIGHT. WE ASK FOR YOUR FORGIVENESS FROM THE BOTTOM OF OUR HEARTS.
BELOVED OSHO,
LAST EVENING I HAD MY FIRST EXPERIENCE OF DEATH. YOUR ANSWER TO THE BEAUTIFUL QUESTION PUT BEFORE YOU HAD TAKEN ME SO DEEP WITHIN, SO HIGH, THAT BY THE TIME I REALIZED WHAT WAS HAPPENING – YOU WERE GONE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22 My experience is of the wordless</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
My experience is of the wordless
10 April 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
ACCORDING TO MY DICTIONARY, A CULT IS “A RELIGION REGARDED AS UNORTHODOX OR SPURIOUS” – “SPURIOUS” MEANING “OF ILLEGITIMATE BIRTH, BASTARD.”
IS IT NOT TRUE TO SAY THAT THE REAL SPIRIT OF RELIGIOUSNESS CAN NEVER BE ANYTHING BUT UNORTHODOX; AND WILL ALWAYS BE INSPIRED BY A LOVE UNION, RATHER THAN BORN OUT OF A LEGALIZED CONTRACT?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23 Enlightenment without bargaining</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
Enlightenment without bargaining
11 April 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I HAVE BEEN YOUR SANNYASIN FOR ONE YEAR. I MEDITATE, WATCH, AND DO WHATEVER LOOKS TRUE TO ME; STILL A BIG PAIN ARISES.
BELOVED OSHO, HOW LONG WILL IT TAKE TO GET ENLIGHTENED, AND DOES THIS ENLIGHTENMENT REALLY EXIST?
Yoganand, existence is not a goal; you don’t have to cover a certain mileage.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 Saying small things with big words</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 24
Saying small things with big words
13 April 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
HUANG PO, THE NINTH CENTURY ZEN MASTER SAID, “ORDINARY PEOPLE ALL INDULGE IN CONCEPTUAL THOUGHT BASED ON ENVIRONMENTAL PHENOMENA; HENCE THEY FEEL DESIRE AND HATRED. TO ELIMINATE ENVIRONMENTAL PHENOMENA JUST PUT AN END TO YOUR CONCEPTUAL THINKING. WHEN THIS CEASES, ENVIRONMENTAL PHENOMENA ARE VOID, AND WHEN THESE ARE VOID THOUGHT CEASES.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25 A great surgery in the right hands</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 25
A great surgery in the right hands
14 April 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I UNDERSTOOD FROM PAST DISCOURSES WHEN YOU HAVE TALKED ON HYPNOSIS, THAT ONE BECOMES, TO ALL INTENTS AND PURPOSES, TOTALLY UNCONSCIOUS, AWARE ONLY OF THE HYPNOTIST’S VOICE.
I HAVE NOT EXPERIENCED THIS STATE, BUT SOMETHING MORE AKIN TO WHAT I FEEL IN DISCOURSE, EXCEPT MORE SO: I FEEL MENTALLY AND PHYSICALLY TRANSFIXED, WITHOUT ANY VOLITION TO MOVE, TALK OR THINK; BUT I AM DEFINITELY PRESENT AND AWARE OF EVERYTHING GOING ON AROUND ME.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26 To be effortless is just to be spontaneous</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 26
To be effortless is just to be spontaneous
15 April 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I HAVE BEEN STUDYING AIKIDO FOR THE PAST TEN YEARS, BUT I DIDN’T GET THE BASIC TRUTH.
BUT WHEN I SAW THE MOVEMENT OF YOUR BODY IN DISCOURSE, I UNDERSTOOD THE POINT OF THE BASIC TRUTH:
I UNDERSTOOD THAT THE MOVEMENT WHICH IS ONE WITH EXISTENCE IS COMING FROM TOTAL RELAXATION AND DEEP AWARENESS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27 Love your camel and trust</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 27
Love your camel and trust
16 April 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
CAN YOU TALK ABOUT THE SUFI SAYING, “TRUST IN ALLAH, BUT TETHER YOUR CAMEL FIRST”?
SOMETIMES I FEEL I HIDE IN PASSIVITY, WAITING FOR THINGS TO HAPPEN. AND YET SOMETIMES I AM IN AWE AT THE WAY EXISTENCE SEEMS TO BE CONSTANTLY CARING FOR ME.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28 The art of listening is enough</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part28/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 28
The art of listening is enough
17 April 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
NIETZSCHE WROTE, IN ECCE HOMO,
HERE THERE SPEAKS NO PROPHET, NONE OF THOSE GRUESOME HYBRIDS OF SICKNESS AND WILL TO POWER CALLED FOUNDERS OF RELIGIONS. ONE HAS ABOVE ALL TO HEAR CORRECTLY THE TONE THAT PROCEEDS FROM THIS MOUTH, THIS HALCYON TONE, IF ONE IS NOT TO DO PITIABLE INJUSTICE TO THE MEANING OF ITS WISDOM.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>29 When your hands are empty\...</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part29/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 29
When your hands are empty...
18 April 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
HOW DO YOU EXPERIENCE YOUR ENLIGHTENMENT?
Milarepa, enlightenment is not an experience.
Experience always divides the experiencer from itself. But enlightenment knows no duality; hence it is not an experience but simply experiencing. It may not be right language; in fact, it cannot be right language because the linguist will not understand what you mean by ‘experiencing’.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Heart is the soil \-- trust is the climate</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
Heart is the soil – trust is the climate
21 March 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
IN WHAT SOIL AND IN WHICH CLIMATE MIGHT ONE FIND THE MYSTIC ROSE?
Maneesha, the symbol of mystic rose vibrates tremendously significant memories...
It was one day in the early morning, a gathering of seekers just like you are... but the time goes twenty-five centuries back.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>30 Laughter and tears \-- a cleansing of the heart</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part30/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 30
Laughter and tears – a cleansing of the heart
21 April 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I’M SURE THERE IS MORE TO “YAA-HOO!” THAN MEETS THE EYE. ARE WE READY TO UNDERSTAND THE REAL MEANING OF “YAA-HOO!”?
Maneesha, no word has a meaning of itself; meanings are given, they are arbitrary. Otherwise every word is just a sound, meaningless.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Laugh and drop the past</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
Laugh and drop the past
22 March 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
LAST NIGHT, I WAS AMAZED TO SEE THAT THE PEOPLE FROM ‘BUNTE’ MAGAZINE WERE UPSET BY YOUR REMARKS IN THE DISCOURSE. FOR MYSELF AND OTHER GERMAN SANNYASINS IT WAS BEAUTIFUL TO SEE YOU MAKE SUCH GENTLE AND HILARIOUS FUN OF THE WHOLE NAZI TRIP.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Blindness and following are synonymous</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
Blindness and following are synonymous
23 March 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
GEORGE GURDJIEFF IS REPORTED TO HAVE SAID, “REPORTERS AND SMART ALECKS WHO ATTEMPT TO ATTACK ME THINK THAT TO START SOME KIND OF MASS MOVEMENT AND ATTRACT LARGE NUMBERS OF FOOLISH FOLLOWERS IS A SIMPLE MATTER.”
BELOVED OSHO, HOW ABOUT THE FOLLOWERS OF PEOPLE LIKE BILLY GRAHAM?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Let-go \-- the fundamental principle</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
Let-go – the fundamental principle
24 March 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
RECENTLY, YOU CONCLUDED A DISCOURSE BY SAYING: “REMEMBER, ‘LET-GO’ IS THE MOST IMPORTANT WORD IN EXISTENCE.” IT PENETRATED ME LIKE AN ARROW. SINCE THEN YOUR WORDS HAVE BEEN HAUNTING ME.
BELOVED MASTER, COULD YOU PLEASE SPEAK A LITTLE MORE ON THE ART OF LETTING GO?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 No dialogue, no monologue \-- yaa-hoo!</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
No dialogue, no monologue – yaa-hoo!
25 March 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
ARE WE MOVING INTO THE SOCRATIC DIALOGUE FORM OF DISCOURSES NOW?
BUT I DETECT AN ESSENTIAL DIFFERENCE. SOCRATES SAID: “KNOW THYSELF.” YOU HAVE SAID: “LET GO THYSELF!”
PLEASE COMMENT.
Maneesha, the subject of Socratic dialogue is something special to be discussed. His use of the word ‘dialogue’ was very original; he means by it that truth can be discovered by discussing in a friendly way, respectful towards each other.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 Our longing is for the stars</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
Our longing is for the stars
26 March 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHAT DO YOU MEAN BY THE RAISED HAND AND “YAA-HOO”?
Neelam, you must have seen that today I have raised both my hands, because the German idiots have made a law in Germany that raising one hand is a criminal act. And what about all the dogs?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 Say goodbye to politics \-- not to science</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/yaahoo_the_mystic_rose/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
Say goodbye to politics – not to science
27 March 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
THE WORLD OF TOMORROW IS A WORLD THAT WILL SEE A SIGNIFICANT PLAY OF SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY. THIS IS BOUND TO AFFECT THE LIVES OF PEOPLE AS IS ALREADY HAPPENING DRAMATICALLY, SOMETIMES FOR THE BETTER, SOMETIMES ADVERSELY.
DO YOU THINK WE SHOULD SAY GOODBYE TO ALL SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY; IF NOT, HOW DO WE PREPARE FOR THE FUTURE CITIZENRY?</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
