<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Hidden Harmony on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_hidden_harmony/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Hidden Harmony on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/the_hidden_harmony/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 1 - The Hidden Harmony</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_hidden_harmony/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_hidden_harmony/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 1 - The Hidden Harmony‌ 1 The Hidden Harmony
21 December 1974 am in Buddha Hall THE HIDDEN HARMONY
IS BETTER THAN THE OBVIOUS. OPPOSITION BRINGS CONCORD. OUT OF DISCORD
COMES THE FAIREST HARMONY. IT IS IN CHANGING
THAT THINGS FIND REPOSE. PEOPLE DO NOT UNDERSTAND
HOW THAT WHICH IS AT VARIANCE WITH ITSELF, AGREES WITH ITSELF.
THERE IS A HARMONY IN THE BENDING BACK, AS IN THE CASE OF THE BOW AND LYRE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 1 - The Hidden Harmony</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_hidden_harmony/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_hidden_harmony/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 1 - The Hidden Harmony‌ Old pond frog jump in water sound Finished! He has said everything. Pictorial: you can see an ancient pond, a frog sitting on the bank, and... the jump of the frog. You can see the splash, and the sound of water. And, says Basho, everything has been said. This is all life is: An ancient pond... a jump of the frog, the sound of water -- and silence.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 1 - The Hidden Harmony</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_hidden_harmony/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_hidden_harmony/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 1 - The Hidden Harmony‌ that these are climates, changes in season, moods that just come and go -- and you will see the gestalt in them.
This German word gestalt is beautiful. It says there is a harmony between the figure and background. They are not opposites, they APPEAR opposites. For example: in a small school you see the blackboard, and the teacher writes with white chalk on the blackboard.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 1 - The Hidden Harmony</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_hidden_harmony/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_hidden_harmony/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 1 - The Hidden Harmony‌ your enemy,&#34; and he upsets the whole temple -- he is rebellious. A man who talks of love seems to be inconsistent.
Bertrand Russell has written a book, Why I am not a Christian. In that book he raises all these inconsistencies. He says, &#34;Jesus is inconsistent and looks neurotic. Somewhere he says love your enemy, and then he behaves in such an angry way -- not only with persons, even with trees -- he curses a fig tree.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 1 - The Hidden Harmony</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_hidden_harmony/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_hidden_harmony/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 1 - The Hidden Harmony‌ will arise. So Mohammed made a rule that every Mohammedan could marry four women...
they are still following the rule.
Now it has become an ugly thing, but they say they are consistent with the Koran. Now the whole situation is different, absolutely different: there are not four times more women now --
but they follow the rule.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 1 - The Hidden Harmony</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_hidden_harmony/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_hidden_harmony/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 1 - The Hidden Harmony‌ OPPOSITION BRINGS CONCORD. OUT OF DISCORD
COMES THE FAIREST HARMONY. IT IS IN CHANGING
THAT THINGS FIND REPOSE. PEOPLE DO NOT UNDERSTAND
HOW THAT WHICH IS AT VARIANCE WITH ITSELF, AGREES WITH ITSELF.
THERE IS A HARMONY IN THE BENDING BACK, AS IN THE CASE OF THE BOW AND LYRE.
THE NAME OF THE BOW IS LIFE, BUT ITS WORK IS DEATH.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 1 - The Hidden Harmony</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_hidden_harmony/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_hidden_harmony/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 1 - The Hidden Harmony‌ branches are different: on one branch the Devil, on another branch the divine -- but the root is the same: DEV. There must be a conspiracy, otherwise the game cannot continue. There must be a deep harmony -- that is the conspiracy. Here God says to Adam, &#34;You are not to eat from this tree of knowledge.&#34; Now the conspiracy starts, the game starts; now, the first rules are being set.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 1 - The Hidden Harmony</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_hidden_harmony/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_hidden_harmony/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 1 - The Hidden Harmony‌ Mulla Nasruddin had arranged for his wife to go to the mountains for her asthma. But his wife was not willing, she refused. She said, &#34;I am afraid that the mountain air is going to disagree with me.&#34;
Mulla Nasruddin said, &#34;My dear, don&#39;t you be worried. There is no mountain air so brave as to disagree with you!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 1 - The Hidden Harmony</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_hidden_harmony/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_hidden_harmony/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌Chapter 1 - The Hidden Harmony‌ HOW THAT WHICH IS AT VARIANCE WITH ITSELF, AGREES WITH ITSELF.
The Devil agrees with God, God agrees with the Devil -- that&#39;s why the Devil exists.
THERE IS A HARMONY IN THE BENDING BACK, AS IN THE CASE OF THE BOW AND LYRE.
A musician plays with a bow and a lyre; the opposition is just on the surface. On the surface it is a clash, a struggle, a fight, a discord, but there comes beautiful music out of it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 1 - The Hidden Harmony</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_hidden_harmony/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_hidden_harmony/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 1 - The Hidden Harmony‌ not understood at all. He became more and more separate from the main current of Western thinking and the Western mind.
Heraclitus was like Gautam Buddha or Lao Tzu or Basho. The Greek soil was absolutely not good for him. He would have been a great tree in the East: millions would have profited, millions would have found the way through him.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 1 - The Hidden Harmony</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_hidden_harmony/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_hidden_harmony/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 1 - The Hidden Harmony‌ Remember this: life moves in a cycle, everything moves in a cycle. The child is born, then comes the age of youth, then old age, then death. It moves just as seasons move: summer comes, then rains follow, then comes winter, and it goes on in a circle. The same happens in the dimension of consciousness: every twenty-five centuries the circle is complete and before the new circle starts there is a gap you can escape through; the door is open for a few years.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 1 - The Hidden Harmony</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_hidden_harmony/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_hidden_harmony/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 1 - The Hidden Harmony‌ life, and life is paradoxical. Buddha is paradoxical, Lao Tzu is paradoxical; all those who have known are bound to be paradoxical. What can they do? If life itself is paradoxical, they have to be true to life. And life is not logical. It is a logos, but it is not logic. It is a cosmos, it is not a chaos -- but it is not logic.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 1 - The Hidden Harmony</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_hidden_harmony/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_hidden_harmony/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 1 - The Hidden Harmony‌ Why is it a facade? -- because you are avoiding the other. You say, &#34;You are my friend and a friend cannot be an enemy. And you are my enemy, you cannot be my friend.&#34; But these are two aspects of the same coin -- the enemy is a hidden friend, and the friend is a hidden enemy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 1 - The Hidden Harmony</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_hidden_harmony/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_hidden_harmony/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 1 - The Hidden Harmony‌ If there is no change life is static. If you cannot move to the opposite everything will go stale and it will become boring. That&#39;s why people who are too cultivated become boring --
because they always go on smiling, they are never angry. You insult them and they smile; you praise them and they smile; you condemn them and they smile.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 1 - The Hidden Harmony</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_hidden_harmony/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_hidden_harmony/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 1 - The Hidden Harmony‌ I the same? Are you the same? Both rivers have changed. You may be here again tomorrow, but you will not find me; somebody else will be here.
Life is changing. &#34;Only change is eternal,&#34; says Heraclitus -- only change never changes.
Everything else changes. He believes in a permanent revolution. Everything is in revolution. It is how it is there.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 1 - The Hidden Harmony</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_hidden_harmony/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_hidden_harmony/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 1 - The Hidden Harmony‌ are you the same man? Much has passed; the Ganges has flowed too much -- you are no longer there.
I have heard: One night Mulla Nasruddin&#39;s wife said, &#34;You no longer love me, you no longer kiss, you no longer hug me. Remember when you were courting me? -- you used to bite me and I loved that very much!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 1 - The Hidden Harmony</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_hidden_harmony/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_hidden_harmony/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 1 - The Hidden Harmony‌ practice rest! This is what rich people do: they rest the whole day, then they have insomnia and they say, &#34;We cannot sleep.&#34; And they are practicing the whole day
-- lying on their beds, lying on their easy chairs, resting and resting and resting. And then in the night, suddenly they find that they cannot sleep. They have followed Aristotle, they are logical.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
