<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>This Is It on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/</link>
    <description>Recent content in This Is It on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
1 May 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine and gupta means secret – divine secret. And the divine secret is that there is no secret in it! The divine secret is the open secret. It is very obvious – it is not far away, it is not distant. It is close-by, it is within, it is you... it is your very core.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
10 May 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, garima means glory – divine glory. One thing is very important for you to understand, and it is that when a person is young a few things are easy, a few things are difficult. For example, religion is difficult. It is easier to be in desires, it is difficult to leave them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
11 May 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin, who is leaving says he’s feeling that, has always been separate from his body and that now he is getting more in touch. He goes up and down a lot – first feeling possessive and jealous and angry and then quite calm.]
Everything will change – just continue to meditate.
The first basic thing is coming back to the body.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
12 May 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love and gatya means a river-like, dynamic quality.…
The english word ‘go’ comes from the same root ‘gatya’, ‘gathya’ – the quality that continuously moves.
Love is a moving energy. The moment you make it stop somewhere, it dies – then it becomes stagnant, it stinks. While love is moving it has tremendous beauty.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
13 May 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, urja means energy – divine energy... and start thinking about yourself more in terms of energy than in terms of body. Matter is just an appearance: it appears solid because we cannot see deeply into it, otherwise it is also liquid. Matter itself is not material; it is tremendous energy revolving with tremendous speed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
14 May 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine and giresh means god of the mountains. The full name will mean: god of the divine mountains. And I am giving this name to you for a certain reason – that your path will be almost as if one is climbing a mountain. A few people move towards height and few people move towards depth.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
15 May 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says: when people make him feel important, he feels bad because it seems to be helping him to go off on yet another ego-trip. Osho says this too is an ego-trip – to feel bad. If the ego is there, whatsoever you do is an ego-trip. Demanding that people not give you importance is ego-tripping as much as demanding that they do]</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
16 May 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says she has been working as a prostitute in the West. Returning there now to earn money to return here, she wonders whether to return to prostitution or not. A voice inside her says no – on the other hand it is a quick way to make money]
Then do something else, mm?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
17 May 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine and laya means absorbed – utterly absorbed in the divine, and that has to be the very key you work upon.
Start feeling that you are one with existence, start dropping your boundaries – and you will be able to do it. You have a very fluid energy, it will be very easy to do.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
18 May 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho speaks about the name ‘jamendra’ – one who has conquered himself. Only when one has conquered oneself is bliss possible. Misery is not because of others but is because you are not centred; desires and ambitions have become the master. One needs not to repress them but to make one’s centre so strong that they lose their hold and power]</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
19 May 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin, leaving for the West, asks about meditation. Should she still keep trying or is it time to let go and drop effort, she wonders. Osho checks her energy.
My feeling is that for a few months more you should continue doing things. Right now, it will not be possible for you to do meditations spontaneously.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
2 May 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine and tapan means heat energy – divine heat energy. And that’s exactly what life is. We are not matter. Matter simply does not exist, matter is a myth. That which exists is energy. Energy means that things are not things, they are processes. The whole existence is a dynamic force – it is not static: it is moving, it is growing, it is evolving.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
20 May 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin said her father has cancer and her family keep asking her to go home, but she is undecided as she also wants to stay here. Osho says that as the father is old, it is better she go]
And this is a significant time. Go, and be as loving to him as possible.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
21 May 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
A sannyasin is going back to the West and would like to run a group on the lines of the tao group that happens here. She isn’t sure though whether she is ready or able to lead groups. Osho says that her energy is ready – it just needs to flow a little bit more.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
22 May 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, abhinanda means joy – divine joy. Ordinarily what we think is joy is not joy; at the most it is entertainment. It is just a way to avoid oneself. It is a way to intoxicate yourself, it is a way to be drowned in something so you can forget your misery, your worry, your anguish, your anxiety.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
23 May 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin asks about becoming a Primal therapist.]
It is always good to find something that you like – because it is your life; it should not be wasted in any way. And if you have the feeling that you don’t like any job and that you have to do it, it becomes destructive.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 24
24 May 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho speaks about the name Deva Abhinandan. It means welcome to god, and that’s all sannyas is – a welcome to god. We can’t go to go, we can’t search for him, because we don’t know where he is. All we can do is to be ready to receive him, to invite him. Prayer is an invitation, a letter to the unknown to say that one is available.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 25
25 May 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho is explaining the name ‘Deva patra’ means divine worthiness, divine potential. He says man is a potentiality, not yet actualised. Man is like a seed that may or may not fall on the right soil, and it is only a possibility that he will grow, will bloom into flowers and will bear fruits]</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 26
26 May 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, joy, and niyama means discipline.
Let joy be your discipline... and a discipline is a discipline only when it is out of joy. If it is forced and you are not joyously in it then it is a self-imposed slavery, it is not discipline. You are torturing yourself, you are a kind of masochist – you enjoy self-torture.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 27
27 May 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says she feels a certain restlessness about her which she experiences mainly as being in her arms. They feel like they need to do something energetic.]
Mm mm, it can be. Start doing one thing every night: sit in a chair and rest your head (Osho demonstrates, his head resting back on the chair like you do at the dentist).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part28/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 28
28 May 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, nishavda means unuttered, unspoken, wordless, soundless – unuttered love, unspoken love, love without any word interfering with it.
The tendency of the mind is to analyse, to interpret, to express, and in that very effort much is lost.
Love is something which cannot be uttered. You can be love but you cannot say what it is.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>29</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part29/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 29
29 May 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine and dhyana means the state of meditation – divine state of meditation. The word ‘meditation’ is not as adequate as dhyana, because nothing like dhyana has ever existed in the West so no western language has any appropriate word for it. Meditation comes closest but still misses the target. Meditation means contemplation, to think about, and dhyana means not thinking at all, just being.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
3 May 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A new sannyasin said that he only came to visit a friend and decided to stay.]
One never knows! And that’s the beauty of life – that there is always surprise and there is always the unexpected... and because the unexpected happens there is joy, excitement, ecstasy. Whenever only the expected starts happening, joy dies.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>30</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part30/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 30
30 May 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin who is leaving says she has been feeling very open towards Osho but says that just now, as she is leaving, she feels closed and is sad that she is leaving feeling like this. Osho reassures her that her heart is open.]
That happens many times, because the heart and the mind have become almost disconnected, so whatsoever happens in the heart, the mind does not take note of it, it neglects it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>31</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part31/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 31
31 May 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says he wants to be able to open up more to Osho and to other people. Osho tells him that any effort to be open makes you more closed. You can’t do openness.…
The sannyasin explains: I don’t say anything that I mean in conversation, I don’t seem to be direct. If I want to say one thing I end up saying something else – something not related to what I wanted to say.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
4 May 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva guhen.And the heart is just a divine cave. The heart does not consist of the lungs only.
The lungs are the centre of the body, life circulates through the lungs, but hidden somewhere behind the lungs is the cave where you live, where god livesBecause you and god are not two separate</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
5 May 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, suman means a flower – a blissful flower. And remember that man is also a tree and has roots. They are invisible but they are there. We are as much rooted as any tree. Certainly our earth is different – our earth is our past, the whole past of humanity is our earth; it is there we are rooted.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
6 May 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin, returned from the West, says she is not ready to live in the West. She has a strong desire to be loved, feels a desperation that she hasn’t been loved. Osho says that is one of the basic problems that touches everyone]
.… because we live in a society which is absolutely loveless, so everybody is hungry for love, desperately hungry, dying for it, starving.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
7 May 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says his parents have asked him to guarantee that if ever the need arises, he will return to Italy to be with them for a few months. He is an only child and sees his parents regularly each year, but his relationship with both of them is heavy.
Osho says if this is all they are asking, then he should give them the guarantee they want from him.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
8 May 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss and hara is a japanese name for the centre just below the navel, two inches below the navel... and becoming aware of this centre is going to help you tremendously, so the more you abide there, the better.
Whenever you have nothing to do, just sit silently and move inside and fall into the stomach – just two inches below the navel – and remain there.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/this_is_it/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
9 May 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin asks about his brother, a former drug-taker and now a religious fanatic, who spends the day lying on his bed.]
I understand the type. The only way to bring him out is not to argue with him – the first thing... not to give him any indication that you want to bring him out of his state, otherwise he will defend himself.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
