<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>God\&#39;s Got a Thing About you on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/</link>
    <description>Recent content in God\&#39;s Got a Thing About you on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
1 September 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, aikanta means aloneness. Self-knowledge is possible only in deep aloneness. Ordinarily whatever we know about ourselves is the opinion of others. They say “You are good” and we think we are good. They say “You are beautiful” and we think we are beautiful. They say you are bad or ugly... whatsoever people say about us we go on collecting.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
10 September 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin and her two children are leaving. She asks about being frightened of other people. Osho had previously told her to be alone, but she wants love from other people.]
That is where the problem is: you want love from other people, and that is the wrong beginning; that is getting out of the bed from the wrong side.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
11 September 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, devada means God-given. Bliss is never attained through human effort. It is a grace, not an achievement, so the achiever’s mind goes on missing it. And our society creates the ambitious, achieving mind; hence so much misery in the world. It is a natural consequence of our approach towards life. We are aggressive towards life, and bliss comes only to those who are receptive.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
12 September 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[To a new sannyasin Osho says:]
Just do a few groups, meditate and forget everything of the past. for the time that you are here, be totally here, as if the past has never existed; then the benefit will be immense. If we can put the past aside great transformation is possible, and immediately possible.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
13 September 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, Baul is one belonging to a secret society of mystics. Just as Zen is in Buddhism and Sufis are part of Islam and Hassids are part of Judaism, Bauls are the flowering of the Hindu tradition; they are the highest flowering. But to understand the highest becomes very difficult.
The higher a truth is, the greater is the possibility that it will be misunderstood.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
14 September 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, vishram means relaxation – a blissful relaxation. The simple word “relax” contains my whole philosophy of life. To be in a relaxed state is to be in God. To be utterly relaxed is to disappear from the circumference and appear at the center. That is the only transformation; there is none other.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
15 September 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand Phulo. Anand means bliss, phulo means flowering – flowering of bliss. Bliss is a seed – we bring it with us, but very few people are good gardeners. They live their whole lives and the seed remains there; it never comes to bloom. The potential remains potential, never becomes actual. That’s what misery is: not to be that which one is destined to be.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
16 September 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin asks what to do to help herself in the west. She likes the kundalini meditation most.]
Then continue Kundalini, but make it regular; never miss it even for a single day. If you are traveling and it is not possible, then too for one hour just sit silently and do it inside in fantasy, and the same will be the result.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
17 September 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, paraso means vision – divine vision. God is not a thing outside you – God is not an object, so all search for God as an object is futile. God is a totally new quality of vision. It is a new way of seeing the world in a new light. It is the same world but your eyes are different.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
18 September 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, anado means silence – soundless silence. Love is silence – it is the music of silence. That’s why love cannot be expressed. And the moment you express it, you falsify it. It is no more the same experience that was felt in the heart. The moment it comes into the words it is already far away from the heart, because no word can enter the heart and the heart cannot enter into any word at all they never meet.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
19 September 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, sindhu means ocean – divine ocean. Man appears to be just a dewdrop, but that is only the appearance – don’t be deceived by the appearance – man contains an ocean within him. The boundary of man exists not. The boundary is just our imagination, because we begin nowhere and we end nowhere.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
2 September 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, surupa means beauty – divine beauty. This is one of the most fundamental things to be remembered always – that the innermost core of everything is beautiful. Even when the circumference is not beautiful, then too the center is always beautiful. But because we cannot see the center and we become acquainted only with the circumference, sometimes we start thinking: this is ugly, that is bad, this is sin and that one is a sinner.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
20 September 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, nirmalo means innocence – divine innocence, the original state of consciousness, the empty state of consciousness, before knowledge enters in. That’s what Zen people call “the original face – the face that you had before you were born and the face that you will have again when you are dead. Between the two we have many false faces – all those false faces constitute our personality.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
21 September 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, artha means meaning – divine meaning. Meaning has disappeared from man’s life. These three hundred years have seen it disappearing slowly slowly. Now man stands utterly devoid of meaning. And he is very hollow, naturally. He feels there is no purpose in life; nothing seems to make sense any more. This is one of the greatest crises that man has ever faced.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
22 September 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, samai means ecstasy – divine ecstasy. The word “ecstasy” is very significant. In its root form it means “to stand out” – ex-statis. The moment you can stand out of your mind you are in ecstasy. Ordinarily we are too involved in the mind. We have become the mind, this is our agony, so we have completely forgotten who we are.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
23 September 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, sahaja means simplicity, naturalness, spontaneity. Simplicity is living a life without any idea about how to live it, without any ideology. Ideology brings complexity into life. Animals are simple, no animal is ever complex because no animal is burdened by any ideology. There is no “should”; the animal simply lives the way it feels.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 24
24 September 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, prartho means prayer. Love is not an act. It is a state. You cannot do it – you can only be it. And love is not a relationship either; it is a participation. In a relationship two persons become entangled with each other, intertwined. They create slavery for each other, a mutual kind of bondage.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 25
25 September 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Veet means beyond, chhitijo means horizon – beyond the horizon, beyond the horizontal. Life consists of two dimensions: one is horizontal, the other is vertical. Millions of people simply live in the horizontal – they crawl and creep, they remain asleep. That’s why in sleep you have to go to the horizontal position. It is easier to fall asleep in the horizontal position; if you are standing it is difficult to fall asleep.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 26
26 September 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, rasal means full of juice – full of divine juice. My teaching is of life-affirmation. The old religions were based on life-negation; they denied life, they were against it. Their God could only be reached if you denied life. That was a false God, because God cannot be against life. God is the source of life – in fact God is another name for life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 27
27 September 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Veet means beyond, prabhavo means impressions, influences, conditionings – beyond all impressions, beyond all influences, beyond all conditionings. That is where truth is. That’s why the mind cannot know it, because the mind consists only of conditionings. Whatsoever has been taught, whatsoever has been put inside you from the outside is your mind. It is a deep effort, a cunning effort of the society to control you from within.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part28/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 28
28 September 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, sanjaya means a special kind of victory... not just victory but a special kind of victory. In English there is no word to translate it. Victory is possible in two ways: one is through coercion, violence; the other is through love. And the ways of both are totally different... not only different but diametrically opposite.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>29</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part29/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 29
29 September 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin couple have problems with their relationship. The woman says: So much misunderstanding and... ugliness from myself and him.]
Love has to grow through misunderstanding. Understanding is not easy – it is very rare to arrive at understanding; because you are confused, he is confused, you don’t know who you are, he does not know who he is.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
3 September 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin brings her baby and says she has been screaming a lot which upsets her.] That is part of being a mother.…
It is not an easy job.…
But now it is too late! Every woman wants to become a mother without knowing the responsibilities. It is a long commitment. And remember: never think of what is right and what is wrong.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>30</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part30/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 30
30 September 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means god, samarpo means surrendered – surrendered to God. And that is the very secret of religion, the most fundamental secret, the secret of the secrets. All that is needed is a total surrender – relaxing oneself into the totality of existence, dissolving, merging, melting, not keeping oneself separate. The whole misery of man consists in keeping oneself separate.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
4 September 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, amiro means rich, richness – richness that love brings. And in fact, except for love nothing else ever brings richness. And all other riches are substitutes. People search for them because they have missed love. The person who is too obsessed with money is of necessity the person who is empty of love.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
5 September 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Veet means beyond, jay means the idea of victory – one who has gone beyond the idea of winning. The idea of winning is the basic problem. It creates the whole politics of life. It creates violence. And one suffers infinite misery because of it, because this game of life is not a game in which anybody can be a winner.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
6 September 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Sagar means ocean, sundar means beauty – oceanic beauty. And remember that beauty is something of the wild beauty is never civilized. The moment you civilize it, it becomes ugly. There is no way to civilize beauty. Beauty has to be intrinsically wild, because beauty is part of nature. It is not nurture; it is nature.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
7 September 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Shunya means silence, shabdo means sound – the sound of silence. There is a sound of silence, and once it is heard then one has heard all. That is the fundamental of existence. Existence is constituted of that sound of silence. The Bible calls it “the word,” “logos,” and the Zen people call it “the sound of one hand clapping.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
8 September 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, tosha means contentment – and that is what has to be taught to her. The only way to teach love to a child is to be loving, there is no other way. Shower as much love as possible, and let it be unconditional, with no expectations. Just give it for the sheer joy of giving.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/gods_got_a_thing_about_you/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
9 September 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho reminds someone who is leaving of the importance of meditating regularly so that it becomes one’s climate; then only does it go deep. Through whatever you do a subtle current of meditation has to continue; only then does meditation become a transformation. So by the time you come back the thread will be there; then higher planes can be made available to you, He reminds her.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
