<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Revolution in Education on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/revolution_in_education/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Revolution in Education on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/revolution_in_education/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 Teacher, Society amp; Revolution</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/revolution_in_education/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/revolution_in_education/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
Teacher, Society amp; Revolution
Date unknown
This discourse was first published in KRANTINADA MONTHLY 1968 to 1969.
I would like to tell you a few things which I see about teachers and the society. Perhaps there will be no agreement between the way you think and the way I think. Perhaps I may be opposing the positions taken in the current code of education.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Towards the Birth of a New Man</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/revolution_in_education/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/revolution_in_education/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
Towards the Birth of a New Man
Date unknown
This discourse was given to a congregation of teachers and students published in booklet of same name.
I am very pleased to be present among you. Certainly, on this occasion, I would like to share some of my heartfelt views with you.
It is painful to see the present condition of education. Birth of a free and healthy man is not possible in a condition where, in the name of education, all sorts of slaveries are nourished.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Education: Love-Oriented</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/revolution_in_education/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/revolution_in_education/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
Education: Love-Oriented
Date unknown
This discourse was given before students under the title: Youth and Rebellion.
I am pleased at the prospect of speaking to the youth and the students. The first thing about the youth that comes to my mind is what today I would like to say to you in detail.
For the old the past exists; that is already gone, and their whole world is behind them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Education and Religion</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/revolution_in_education/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/revolution_in_education/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
Education and Religion
3 March 1967 pm in Sadar Vallabhai Patel University
There was a fakir who was very alone. He saw God in his dream and found that he was even more alone. The fakir was puzzled and asked God, “Why are you also so alone? You have many devotees – where are they?”
On hearing this, God said, “I have always been alone, and hence only those who become absolutely alone are able to experience me.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Knowledge is That Which Liberates</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/revolution_in_education/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/revolution_in_education/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
Knowledge is That Which Liberates
23 September 1968 pm in Birla Krida Kendra, Bombay, India
Sa Vidya Ya Vimuktaye. Knowledge is that which liberates.
This morning I would like to say a few things to you on this subject. This is a marvellous saying. It is the most original definition of knowledge. This is the definition of knowledge as well as its criterion.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Fire of Rebellion</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/revolution_in_education/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/revolution_in_education/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
Fire of Rebellion
12 February 1969 pm in Alembic Colony, Baroda
This discourse was given before teachers under the title: The Birth of New India!
Zarathustra was coming down a hill. He was rushing downwards as if he had heard some very important news from down the hill. He reached the plains, running and panting for breath. He asked the people in the market, “Have you heard the news?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Total Education</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/revolution_in_education/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/revolution_in_education/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
Total Education
21 January 1968 am in Poddar College
This discourse was given to teachers at Poddar College.
Of the misfortunes that have befallen mankind, the greatest are the ones which we have been regarding as blessings. Because of regarding them as benedictions, as blessings, it has not been possible to avoid those misfortunes, or to change them, and nothing has been done to be free of them; rather, on the contrary, we have been watering them at their roots.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 The Light of Disbelief</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/revolution_in_education/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/revolution_in_education/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
The Light of Disbelief
14 August 1969 pm
This discourse was given to students.
Just as an individual becomes old, the society also becomes old. Just as an individual dies, the society dies and civilizations also die, but no individual can refuse to become old or refuse to die. But a society, a civilization, can refuse to become old and to die if it so desires, although the society which refuses to die will cease to have a new life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 Transformation Through Awareness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/revolution_in_education/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/revolution_in_education/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 9
Transformation Through Awareness
2 September 1969 pm
The original title was: Education: Means and Ends Question 1
DO YOU THINK IT IS NECESSARY TO GIVE A NEW TYPE OF EDUCATION SO THAT PEOPLE MAY UNDERSTAND DIFFERENTIATIONS? CAN OBJECTIVITY AND SUBJECTIVITY BE SEPARATED? DO YOU THINK IT IS POSSIBLE TO GIVE SUCH RIGHT EDUCATION?
Yes, it is necessary to have such a civilization which does not teach distinctions from the very childhood and which may lead to the understanding of oneness.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
