<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Heartbeat of the Absolute on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heartbeat_of_the_absolute/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Heartbeat of the Absolute on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/the_heartbeat_of_the_absolute/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 All Is A Miracle</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heartbeat_of_the_absolute/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heartbeat_of_the_absolute/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
All Is A Miracle
4 April 1971 am in Mt. Abu, Rajasthan, India
OM.
THAT IS WHOLE, AND THIS ALSO IS WHOLE.
FOR ONLY THE WHOLE IS BORN OUT OF THE WHOLE; AND WHEN THE WHOLE IS TAKEN FROM THE WHOLE, BEHOLD, THE REMAINDER IS WHOLE.
OM. PEACE, PEACE, PEACE.
The Ishavasya Upanishad begins and ends with this sutra, and in it is declared all that can ever be said.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Ignorance Will Show You The Way</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heartbeat_of_the_absolute/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heartbeat_of_the_absolute/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
Ignorance Will Show You The Way
8 April 1971 pm in Mt. Abu, Rajasthan, India
THOSE WHO FOLLOW THE PATH OF IGNORANCE ENTER DARKNESS;
AND THOSE WHO ARE ABSORBED IN KNOWLEDGE ENTER A GREATER DARKNESS.
This sutra makes a profound proclamation of the truth – a very bold proclamation. Such an announcement can be made only by a sage. It is declared that those who tread on the path of ignorance lose their way and wander here and there in this world; but those who walk on the path of knowledge – that is, the path of “I know” – lose themselves in greater darkness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 I Too Am Listening</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heartbeat_of_the_absolute/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heartbeat_of_the_absolute/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
I Too Am Listening
9 April 1971 am in Mt. Abu, Rajasthan, India
ONE RESULT, THEY SAY, IS OBTAINED BY VIDYA,
AND ANOTHER RESULT, THEY SAY, IS OBTAINED BY AVIDYA;
THUS WE HAVE HEARD FROM THE WISE ONES WHO EXPLAINED IT TO US.
The truly learned, the wise ones, tell us that the fruit of true knowledge, wisdom, understanding – what the Upanishads call vidya – is quite distinct from the fruit of material, informational, acquired knowledge; this the Upanishads call avidya.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 I Am Not The Body</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heartbeat_of_the_absolute/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heartbeat_of_the_absolute/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
I Am Not The Body
9 April 1971 pm in Mt. Abu, Rajasthan, India
ONE WHO KNOWS
BOTH VIDYA AND AVIDYA TOGETHER OVERCOMES DEATH THROUGH AVIDYA AND EXPERIENCES IMMORTALITY THROUGH VIDYA.
One who knows both avidya and vidya, having overcome death, will know the immortal. This is a very rare couplet. I told you that the Upanishads are not opposed to avidya.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 Animal, Vegetable Or God?</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heartbeat_of_the_absolute/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heartbeat_of_the_absolute/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
Animal, Vegetable Or God?
In Mt. Abu, Rajasthan, India
THOSE WHO ARE ABSORBED IN THE FULFILLMENT OF PRAKRITI – THE MANIFEST NATURE –
ENTER DARKNESS,
AND THOSE WHO ARE ABSORBED IN THE FULFILLMENT
OF HIDDEN PRAKRITI – UNMANIFESTED NATURE – ENTER GREATER DARKNESS.
The outward manifestation of existence is called prakriti – the material nature of the universe – visible to the eyes, touchable with the hands, knowable through the sense organs; all that with which our organs become conversant.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 The Seed and The Tree</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heartbeat_of_the_absolute/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heartbeat_of_the_absolute/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
The Seed and The Tree
In Mt. Abu, Rajasthan, India
IT HAS BEEN POINTED OUT
THAT THE FRUITS OBTAINED BY THE WORSHIP OF MANIFEST BRAHMAN
ARE DIFFERENT FROM THOSE OBTAINED
BY THE WORSHIP OF UNMANIFEST BRAHMAN.
WE HAVE HEARD THIS FROM THOSE WISE PEOPLE WHO KNEW AND EXPLAINED IT TO US.
The Upanishads talk about two forms of Brahman, the supreme element.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 Let Us Die</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heartbeat_of_the_absolute/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heartbeat_of_the_absolute/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
Let Us Die
In Mt. Abu, Rajasthan, India
ONE WHO KNOWS
THE UNMANIFEST BRAHMAN
AND AT THE SAME TIME THE MANIFEST BRAHMAN, HAVING OVERCOME DEATH
BY THE WORSHIP OF THE MANIFEST BRAHMAN, ATTAINS TO IMMORTALITY
BY THE WORSHIP OF THE UNMANIFEST BRAHMAN.
We cannot draw a circle without a center. The circumference is drawn all around the center. As the circumference moves away from the center it grows larger and larger.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 Only The Knowing Remain</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heartbeat_of_the_absolute/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heartbeat_of_the_absolute/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
Only The Knowing Remain
In Mt. Abu, Rajasthan, India
THE FACE OF THAT BRAHMAN,
SITTING IN THE MIDST OF ABUNDANCE OF LIGHT, IS COVERED WITH A GOLDEN CURTAIN.
O LORD, REMOVE THAT CURTAIN SO THAT I, A SEEKER OF TRUTH, MAY ATTAIN TO THE SUPREME.
This sutra is rather difficult to understand, but it is of extraordinary significance for many reasons. First of all, we generally believe that if truth is covered, it must be covered by darkness, but the sutra says it is covered by light; hence the prayer that God will remove the curtain of light.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 The Ultimate Jump</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heartbeat_of_the_absolute/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heartbeat_of_the_absolute/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
The Ultimate Jump
In Mt. Abu, Rajasthan, India
O SUN,
NOURISHER AND SUPPORTER OF THE WORLD, O LONELY TRAVELER IN THE SKY,
O YAMA, O SUN, O SUN OF BRAHMAN,
I BESEECH YOU TO WITHDRAW YOUR RAYS.
I SEE YOUR FORM, FULL OF GRACE AND GOODNESS. I AM THAT ONE WHO IS SITTING IN THE
CIRCLE OF THE SUNS.
We are familiar with the one sun we see in the sky, but there are countless suns like ours.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 At The Door Of Samadhi</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heartbeat_of_the_absolute/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heartbeat_of_the_absolute/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
At The Door Of Samadhi
In Mt. Abu, Rajasthan, India
NOW LET MY SPIRIT MEET THE ABSOLUTE PERVADING ALL THROUGHOUT THE VITAL AIR, AND LET MY BODY BE REDUCED TO ASHES.
O MY MIND FULL OF EGO AND DESIRES, NOW REMEMBER YOUR PAST ACTIONS, REMEMBER YOUR PAST DEEDS.
Let life merge into that from which it was born. Let the shape lose itself in that formlessness from which it was created.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19 Transformation Is The Test</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heartbeat_of_the_absolute/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heartbeat_of_the_absolute/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
Transformation Is The Test
In Mt. Abu, Rajasthan, India
OH FIRE,
LEAD US TO THE RIGHTEOUS PATH. OH GOD,
THE KNOWER OF ALL KNOWLEDGE AND ACTIONS, DESTROY OUR DECEITFUL SINS.
WE BOW TO YOU INNUMERABLE TIMES.
We have seen streams and brooks flowing down from the mountain. We know that rivers flow towards the ocean. Water runs always towards lower and lower levels in search of the lowest level, and its journey ends in ditches.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Neither Mine Nor Yours</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heartbeat_of_the_absolute/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heartbeat_of_the_absolute/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
Neither Mine Nor Yours
4 April 1971 pm in Mt. Abu, Rajasthan, India
ALL THE THINGS OF THIS WORLD, ORGANIC AND INORGANIC, ARE FILLED WITH GOD. ENJOY THEM THROUGH RENOUNCING THEM.
BE DETACHED;
DO NOT COVET OTHER PEOPLE’S RICHES.
The essential proclamation of the Ishavasya Upanishad, the very meaning of its title, Ishavasya, is: Everything is God’s. All things belong to God.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 Existence Is One</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heartbeat_of_the_absolute/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heartbeat_of_the_absolute/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 20
Existence Is One
In Mt. Abu, Rajasthan, India
OM.
THAT IS PERFECT, AND THIS ALSO IS PERFECT.
FOR ONLY THE PERFECT IS BORN OUT OF THE PERFECT; AND WHEN THE PERFECT
IS TAKEN FROM THE PERFECT, BEHOLD, THE REMAINDER IS PERFECT. OM. PEACE, PEACE, PEACE.
It is the eternal law of existence that the end is to be found in the beginning. The end is where the beginning is.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 The Shape Of Water</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heartbeat_of_the_absolute/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heartbeat_of_the_absolute/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
The Shape Of Water
5 April 1971 am in Mt. Abu, Rajasthan, India
FOR A PERSON LIKE YOU,
WHO DESIRES TO LIVE A HUNDRED YEARS INVOLVED IN HIS ACTIVITIES IN THE WORLD AND BELIEVING THAT “I AM THE DOER,” THERE IS NO OTHER PATH THAN THIS –
THE PATH OF LIVING WITHOUT BEING SMEARED BY YOUR DOING.
There is only one path that can keep you unaffected while doing the things you must do in this world.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 The True Desire</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heartbeat_of_the_absolute/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heartbeat_of_the_absolute/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
The True Desire
5 April 1971 pm in Mt. Abu, Rajasthan, India
THE ASURAS – THE DEMONS –
ARE THOSE WHO ARE ENVELOPED
IN THE DARKNESS OF SELF-IGNORANCE. THOSE WHO ARE KILLERS OF THE SELF GO TO THE WORLD OF THE ASURAS AFTER DEATH.
The Upanishads divide man into two categories. First, those who kill the atman – the self; they are suicidal because they kill their own selves.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 A Milestone Marked Zero</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heartbeat_of_the_absolute/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heartbeat_of_the_absolute/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
A Milestone Marked Zero
6 April 1971 am in Mt. Abu, Rajasthan, India
THAT HIGHEST SPIRITUAL ELEMENT,
THE ATMAN, IS UNALTERABLE BY NATURE, AND HAS A QUICKER MOTION THAN THE MIND. THE SENSE ORGANS CANNOT
REACH IT, FOR IT PRECEDES THEM ALL.
IN ITS STILLNESS IT SURPASSES ALL MOVING THINGS.
ONLY IN ITS PRESENCE DOES THE AIR GOVERN ALL THE ACTIVITIES OF ALL LIVING BEINGS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Truth Is Absurd</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heartbeat_of_the_absolute/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heartbeat_of_the_absolute/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
Truth Is Absurd
6 April 1971 pm in Mt. Abu, Rajasthan, India THE HIGHEST SPIRITUAL ELEMENT IS MOVING
AND IS ALSO NOT MOVING.
IT IS FAR AWAY AND YET IS NEAR. IT IS CONCEALED IN EVERYTHING
AND IS OUTSIDE OF EVERYTHING ALSO.
The highest spiritual element, the atman, is not moving and yet it is moving. It is the nearest thing to us and yet it is far off.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Become A Mirror</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heartbeat_of_the_absolute/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heartbeat_of_the_absolute/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
Become A Mirror
7 April 1971 am in Mt. Abu, Rajasthan, India HE WHO SEES THE ENTIRE WORLD OF ANIMATE AND INANIMATE OBJECTS IN HIMSELF
AND ALSO SEES HIMSELF
IN ALL ANIMATE AND INANIMATE OBJECTS, BECAUSE OF THIS,
DOES NOT HATE ANYONE.
Dislike or hatred of another is the basis of deep-seated complications for mankind. It can be said that the poison of hatred becomes manifest in all his poisonous displays.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 The Shadow Of The Ego</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heartbeat_of_the_absolute/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heartbeat_of_the_absolute/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
The Shadow Of The Ego
7 April 1971 pm in Mt. Abu, Rajasthan, India
WHAT GRIEF OR ATTACHMENT
CAN THERE BE FOR A REALIZED SOUL – A MAN OF WISDOM –
WHEN ALL THE ANIMATE AND INANIMATE OBJECTS OF THE WORLD HAVE BECOME HIS SELF,
WHEN HE SEES ONENESS EVERYWHERE?
What sorrow or what attachment can there be for that realized person – that wise man – who has known himself in all animate and inanimate objects, or known all animate and inanimate objects in himself?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 Beyond Science</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heartbeat_of_the_absolute/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heartbeat_of_the_absolute/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
Beyond Science
8 April 1971 am in Mt. Abu, Rajasthan, India
IT IS ALL-PERVADING, IT IS THE PUREST,
IT IS BODILESS, IT IS INDESTRUCTIBLE, IT IS WITHOUT SINEWS, IT IS SPOTLESS, IT IS SINLESS, IT IS ALL-SEEING,
IT IS ALL-KNOWING, IT IS THE BEST AMONG THE BEST, AND IT IS SELF-CREATED.
This sutra gives us some indications about the nature of the atman – above all, that it is created of itself.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
