<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Hallelujah! on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hallelujah! on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 Sannyas is The Apprenticeship in Bliss</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
Sannyas is The Apprenticeship in Bliss
1 August 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[to a sannyasin returning to her husband in the West]
Just be there and be totally there. It is not a question of where you are; the question is always of being total or partial. Whenever you are partial, something goes on missing. But my feeling is that you will be partial there too – because you could not be total here, so how can you be total there?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Love is a Jumping Board</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
Love is a Jumping Board
10 August 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, mouna means silence. So learn two things: be loving to everybody – to people, to trees, to animals, even to the rocks – and the second thing: learn to be silent. Whenever you have time just sit silently with closed eyes. If these two things are attained you become a sannyasin!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 When one\&#39;s whole Being is in Celebration\...</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
When one’s whole Being is in Celebration...
11 August 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, nityo means eternal. Love is the only phenomenon in life which has the quality of eternity in it. Hence even a single moment of love takes you beyond time, takes you into timelessness. A single moment of love is a moment of eternity; it is not an ordinary moment.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 The Taste of God is Love</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
The Taste of God is Love
12 August 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Kusum means flower, swarna means gold – a golden flower. It is still in the seed but it can come; it has to be provoked, it has to be ca]led forth. One should not dissect the seed. If you dissect the seed you will not find the flower.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 Only in Bliss are you Close to Me</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
Only in Bliss are you Close to Me
13 August 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Avoda means service out of ecstasy. The Christian idea of service is that service has to be first then ecstasy follows. The Eastern idea is just the reverse: ecstasy has to come first then service follows. If service comes first it will be just a duty – imposed, cultivated, practised; it is impossible for ecstasy to arise out of it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 Music is a short-cut to God</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
Music is a short-cut to God
14 August 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, abhavo means absence. The moment you are absent, god is present; and god is present only when you are not. There is no co-existence possible – man cannot encounter god. That is impossible, as impossible as darkness encountering light. Darkness is possible only when light is not.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 Love\&#39;s madness takes one beyond all insanity</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
Love’s madness takes one beyond all insanity
15 August 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, veetkam means beyond sex. Bliss is the same energy as sex. If the energy remains completely involved in sex it cannot become bliss. Even in sexual orgasm that little bit of bliss comes to you because in that moment you are free of sex.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 Bliss is a Shadow of God</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
Bliss is a Shadow of God
16 August 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, sandhan means enquiry into... enquiry into love. Life is an enquiry into love. All else is secondary; the primary thing is love. Those who miss love, miss all. So remember it always, that only a life of love is a fulfilled life. Love immensely.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 Sannyas is the Dimension of the Festive</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
Sannyas is the Dimension of the Festive
17 August 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, paribhasho means definition. There is no definition of love, but one can become it. Life can become the definition of it. There is no possibility of defining love in words, but one can live in such a way that one’s whole being becomes its definition.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 Love is the Soul of the dance, dance, the Body of Love</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
Love is the Soul of the dance, dance, the Body of Love
18 August 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[To Ma Anand Christa]
Anand means blissful; and Christa is not Christ’s name but a state of consciousness, what in the East we call Buddhahood – the ultimate state of consciousness where all darkness has disappeared, where all is light, when man is no more identified with the body but knows himself as the supreme self, where one can say ‘I am god!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19 Aloneness is Celebration of Being</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
Aloneness is Celebration of Being
19 August 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, gariba means poverty. Jesus says ‘Blessed are the poor in spirit for theirs is the kingdom of god.’ To be poor in spirit means to be egoless. It means to be humble. It means to be a nobody. To be poor in spirit does not mean to live in poverty – because one can practise poverty and can be very egoistic about it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 The Night is over</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
The Night is over
2 August 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, devayan means divine vehicle – love, the divine vehicle. Love takes you to the ultimate and love also brings the ultimate to you; it is a double-edged sword. It is like a ladder: you can go up and down by the same ladder. And the meeting happens somewhere in the middle.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 Prayer is a Love Affair with Existence</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
Prayer is a Love Affair with Existence
20 August 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, gitama means a song – a song of love. Life cannot be more enriched by anything, except love. Life remains poor without love and life remains a hell without love. Love is the only quality that transforms life from misery to bliss. Love brings the transformation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 Love is Madness with a Method</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
Love is Madness with a Method
21 August 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, parijato is a flower, the name of a flower. Prem Parijato will mean a flower of love.
Man never blooms without love. Love is like spring: once you are in love, hidden possibilities start manifesting themselves, that which was latent before starts arising, surfacing. All the colours and all the fragrance that one contains are released.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22 Meditation is the Path of Ecstasy</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
Meditation is the Path of Ecstasy
22 August 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, aikanto means aloneness – the bliss of being alone. There is a kind of bliss which arises in relationship, in love, with people. But there is also a blissfulness which arises when you are simply, utterly alone. The first bliss can only be momentary because it depends on the interaction of two persons.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23 Bliss is a by-product of losing Yourself</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
Bliss is a by-product of losing Yourself
23 August 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, saburo means waiting – waiting is love. And that’s really what meditation is: waiting for the unknown to happen. We cannot make it happen. Whatsoever we do will always be a repetition of the known, because we are the known. There is no way for us to make the unknown happen.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 Love has never failed</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 24
Love has never failed
24 August 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, prapata means a waterfall. The waterfall is symbolic of many things. The first: it seeks depth, it is always moving towards the depth. And that should be the search. God is not there high in heaven but deep in you. Your consciousness has to become a waterfall, to seek the deepest valley in your being – and you will find god there.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25 Bliss is Prayer</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 25
Bliss is Prayer
25 August 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
This will be your new name... and remember that the change of name is not only a change of name but the getting out of the old, dropping out of the old continuum. It is only symbolic but it carries much meaning in it. If it is just a change of name it is not significant – then all names are the same; whether you have one name or another will not make any difference.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26 Whenever you are Joyous you are in God</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 26
Whenever you are Joyous you are in God
26 August 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[To an elderly sannyasin]
Because the last days of the life should be totally devoted to prayer, to meditation, to god. One has to prepare for death. And death is more important than life, because life is just superficial. Death will take you to the ultimate core of existence.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27 Meditation has to be a Love Affair</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 27
Meditation has to be a Love Affair
27 August 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A mother with her child says she feels resistance and indecision.]
It is on the right track. It is how trust arises. Trust arises out of the dark night of doubt. One has to go deep into doubt to find trust. Trust is not something that you can find by dropping the doubt.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28 Bliss is being in Orgasm with Existence</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part28/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 28
Bliss is being in Orgasm with Existence
28 August 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, ashen means hope. Love and hope are the foundations of life and all its meaning. The moment love and hope disappear, all that is left is despair, darkness, an utter meaninglessness. And these two things are disappearing from the world. People are falling into a kind of hopelessness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>29 Love is the Seed, God is the Flower</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part29/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 29
Love is the Seed, God is the Flower
29 August 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine nratyo means dance. Life is not static – it is a dance; it is dynamic, it is movement. Not even for a single moment does anything remain the same; everything goes on changing. Change is absolute. The mind wants things not to change, and that’s how the mind and life are in conflict.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Love is The Introduction to The Book of Bliss</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
Love is The Introduction to The Book of Bliss
3 August 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, dharia means patience – divine patience. God is not available to those who are in a hurry. God is not instant, and the more you are in a hurry, the less is the possibility. Patience is a very basic requirement... infinite patience.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>30 Learn how to Weep in Blissfulness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part30/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 30
Learn how to Weep in Blissfulness
30 August 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says: I am scared and sad because I have to leave you.]
That’s natural, but no need to be sad. In fact this going away can be used as an opportunity to come closer spiritually rather than physically; and that is real closeness. Real closeness is what love is all about.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>31 The Boat to the other Shore is Love</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part31/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 31
The Boat to the other Shore is Love
31 August 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, shobhana means beauty – divine beauty. Existence is utterly beautiful. If we cannot see it that simply proves that we are blind. And to see beauty is to see god. The search for truth never goes so deep as the search for beauty, because the very word ‘truth’ is of the head.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Religion: Allowing God to Find Us</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
Religion: Allowing God to Find Us
4 August 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means god, svarupo means self-nature. God is our self nature. God is not separate – god is our very being. He has not to be attained, only discovered. He is hidden in us; there is no need to go anywhere else to find him. One has to be silent enough and relaxed enough to feel him.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Prayer is the Highest Form of Play</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
Prayer is the Highest Form of Play
5 August 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, vandano means prayer – bliss is prayer. Whether one believes in god or not does not matter. A blissful man is a religious man. A blissful man is in prayer, because out of bliss, gratitude naturally arises, and gratitude is prayer... and out of gratitude, the vision of god.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Joy is Intunement</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
Joy is Intunement
6 August 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[To a sannyasin with his wife and child who is afraid to ‘burn all his bridges’ in the West in order to be with Osho]
Because of that fearFear always holds one back, keeps the past safe so that one can fall upon
it if the moment arises. But then the whole journey remains half-hearted and lukewarm.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Whenever you are Total you are with Me</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
Whenever you are Total you are with Me
7 August 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, unmado means madness – a loving madness. And that is the greatest sanity in the world. One who is not capable of loving madness is not even capable of living. He only thinks, never feels. And life is not a thought; it has to be felt, lived.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 To become a Song is to become a Saint</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
To become a Song is to become a Saint
8 August 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, astika means one who trusts, one who believes, one who trusts in bliss; and that’s my definition of a religious man. I don’t say to trust in god, because that is very far-fetched. God is very abstract – it is only a word; you don’t have any experience of it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 Sannyas is Initiation into Light</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hallelujah/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
Sannyas is Initiation into Light
9 August 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Love is a breakthrough; a breakthrough from the ego, from all boundaries, from all limitations. Hence love becomes the sky, the inner sky. And the outer sky is nothing compared to the inner; the outer is just a pale reflection of the inner. Once one has looked into the inner then for the first time one feels that even this sky that we have known always is not so unlimited; it has its own limitations.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
