<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Way of Tao, Volume 1 on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_1/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Way of Tao, Volume 1 on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 The eternal, unchanging tao</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_1/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_1/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
The eternal, unchanging tao
19 June 1971 pm in Immortal Study Circle
THE ABSOLUTE TAO
THE TAO THAT CAN BE TRODDEN IS NOT THE ENDURING AND UNCHANGING TAO. THE NAME THAT CAN BE NAMED IS NOT THE ENDURING AND UNCHANGING NAME.
Those who have known, not by words, not by scriptures but by actually living life, from amongst those very few, Lao Tzu is one.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 The secret of a full stomach and an empty mind \-- Tao</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_1/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_1/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
The secret of a full stomach and an empty mind – Tao
20 July 1971 pm in Immortal Study Circle
CHAPTER 3: SUTRA 2
THEREFORE THE SAGE, IN EXERCISE OF HIS GOVERNMENT, EMPTIES THEIR MINDS, FILLS THEIR BELLIES, WEAKENS THEIR WILLS AND STRENGTHENS THEIR BONES.
Lao-Tze’s talks seem upside down – or so it appears to us. The reason is not that they are upside down, the reason is that we are upside down.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 Empty (theoretical) knowledge leads to desire</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_1/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_1/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
Empty (theoretical) knowledge leads to desire
21 July 1971 pm in Immortal Study Circle
CHAPTER 3: SUTRA 3
HE CONSTANTLY TRIES TO KEEP THEM WITHOUT KNOWLEDGE AND WITHOUT DESIRE; AND WHERE THERE ARE THOSE WHO HAVE KNOWLEDGE TO KEEP THEM FROM PRESUMING TO ACT (ON IT). WHEN THERE IS THIS ABSTINENCE FROM ACTION GOOD ORDER IS UNIVERSAL.
Those who know, always endeavour to rid people of empty knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 The supreme void, the supreme ancestor, the ideal support \-- Tao</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_1/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_1/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
The supreme void, the supreme ancestor, the ideal support – Tao
22 July 1971 pm in Immortal Study Circle CHAPTER 4: SUTRA 1 CHARACTER OF TAO
THE TAO IS LIKE THE EMPTINESS OF A VESSEL; AND IN OUR EMPLOYMENT OF IT WE MUST
BE ON OUR GUARD AGAINST ALL FULLNESS. HOW DEEP AND UNFATHOMABLE IT IS, AS IF IT WERE THE HONOURED ANCESTOR OF ALL THINGS; (OR LIKE THE FOUNTAINHEAD OF ALL THINGS).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 Death of the ego and the entrance into the mystery</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_1/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_1/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
Death of the ego and the entrance into the mystery
23 July 1971 pm in Immortal Study Circle
CHAPTER 4: SUTRA 2
WE SHOULD BLUNT ITS SHARP POINTS, AND UNRAVEL ITS COMPLICATIONS. WE SHOULD ATTEMPER ITS BRIGHTNESS AND SUBMERGE ITS TURMOIL. YET DARK LIKE DEEP WATER IT SEEMS TO REMAIN.
Religion is the state of an empty consciousness; like the state of an empty vessel.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 Reflection of that \-- which was before god</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_1/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_1/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
Reflection of that – which was before god
24 July 1971 pm in Immortal Study Circle
CHAPTER 4 : SUTRA 3
I DO NOT KNOW WHOSE SON IT IS, MAY BE AN IMAGE OF WHAT EXISTED BEFORE GOD.
On attaining the void, becoming empty like an empty vessel, when all the sharp points of the mind fall away and the complexes are strengthened, when man unveils himself fully and knows, even then, that which is ultimate, which is the basis of creation, the most intrinsic, remains unknown.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 Understanding, emptiness, surrender and effort</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_1/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_1/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
Understanding, emptiness, surrender and effort
25 July 1971 pm in Immortal Study Circle
Question 1
WHY IS IT THAT NO REVOLUTION TAKES PLACE EVEN AFTER UNDERSTANDING? IF WE PRACTISE NON-ACTION, WHAT WILL HAPPEN TO LABOUR? HOW IS PERFECTION IN EMPTINESS ATTAINED? IF THE VESSEL IS EMPTY, IT WILL ALSO DISINTEGRATE? WHAT IS THE WAY TO EMPTY THE MIND?
QUESTION:
LAO TZU SAYS THAT UNDERSTANDING IS ENOUGH AND THAT TRANSFORMATION TAKES PLACE TOGETHER WITH UNDERSTANDING.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 Unbiased are the three \-- heaven, earth and the saint</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_1/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_1/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
Unbiased are the three – heaven, earth and the saint
2 November 1971 pm in Immortal Study Circle
CHAPTER 5: SUTRA 1 NATURE
HEAVEN AND EARTH DO NOT ACT FROM (THE IMPULSE OF) ANY WISH TO BE BENEVOLENT; THEY DEAL WITH ALL THINGS AS THE DOGS OF GRASS ARE DEALT WITH. THE SAGE DOES NOT ACT FROM (ANY WISH TO BE) BENEVOLENT; THEY DEAL WITH THE PEOPLE AS THE DOGS OF GRASS ARE DEALT WITH.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 Oneness in the opposites and installation into the void</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_1/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_1/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
Oneness in the opposites and installation into the void
3 November 1971 pm in Immortal Study Circle
CHAPTER 5: SUTRA 2
MAY NOT THE SPACE BETWEEN HEAVEN AND EARTH BE COMPARED TO A BELLOWS?
IT IS EMPTIED, YET IT LOSES NOT ITS POWER;
IT IS MOVED AGAIN, AND SENDS FORTH AIR THE MORE. MUCH SPEECH TO SWIFT EXHAUSTION LEAD WE SEE; YOUR INNER BEING GUARD, AND KEEP IT FREE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 The supreme power \-- corresponding to the valley female and mysterious</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_1/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_1/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
The supreme power – corresponding to the valley female and
mysterious
4 November 1971 om in Immortal Study Circle
CHAPTER 6: SUTRA I &amp;amp; 2 THE SPIRIT OF THE VALLEY
1. THE VALLEY SPIRIT DIES NOT, EVER THE SAME. THE FEMALE MYSTERY THUS DO WE NAME.
IT’S GATE FROM WHICH AT FIRST THEY ISSUED FORTH.
IS CALLED THE ROOT FROM WHICH GREW HEAVEN AND EARTH,</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19 Other dimensions of a feminine consciousness: faith, acceptance and surrender</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_1/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_1/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
Other dimensions of a feminine consciousness: faith, acceptance
and surrender
4 November 1971 pm in Immortal Study Circle
Question 1
QUESTION: BHAGWAN SRI, YESTERDAY YOU TALKED ABOUT THE FEMININE-MYSTERY. WILL YOU KINDLY ENLIGHTEN US MORE ON THE SUBJECT?
Bhagwan Sri: All dimensions of Existence can be divided into male and female dimensions.
The division of man and woman is not on the basis of sex alone.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 The mysterious original current \-- Tao</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_1/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_1/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
The mysterious original current – Tao
20 June 1971 pm in Immortal Study Circle
(CONCEIVED OF AS) HAVING NO NAME, IT IS THE ORIGINATOR OF HEAVEN AND EARTH; THE NAMED IS THE MOTHER OF ALL THINGS.
Existence has no specific name. It is name-less. Objectification takes place as soon as a name is given.
Every object is a part of the boundless existence as long as it is unnamed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 Blessed are those who are ready to be last</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_1/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_1/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
Blessed are those who are ready to be last
5 November 1971 pm in Immortal Study Circle
CHAPTER 7: SUTRA 1 &amp;amp; 2 LIVING FOR OTHERS
1. HEAVEN IS LONG ENDURING AND EARTH CONTINUES LONG.
THE REASON WHY HEAVEN AND EARTH ARE ABLE TO ENDURE AND CONTINUE THUS LONG IS:
BECAUSE THEY DO NOT LIVE OF, OR FOR, THEMSELVES. THIS IS HOW THEY ARE ABLE TO CONTINUE AND ENDURE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 The nature of water is very much like Tao</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_1/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_1/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
The nature of water is very much like Tao
6 November 1971 pm in Immortal Study Circle
CHAPTER 3: SUTRA 1, 2 &amp;amp; 3 WATER
1. THE HIGHEST EXCELLENCE IS LIKE (THAT OF) WATER.
THE EXCELLENCE OF WATER APPEARS IN ITS BEFITTING ALL THINGS, AND ITS OCCUPYING, WITHOUT STRIVING (TO THE CONTRARY) THE LOW PLACE WHICH ALL MEN DISLIKE. HENCE (ITS WAY) IS NEAR TO (THAT OF) TAO.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22 Lao-tse is the most useful in the present state of the world</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_1/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_1/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 22
Lao-tse is the most useful in the present state of the world
8 November 1971 pm in Immortal Study Circle
Question 1
QUESTION: WHAT IS THE FORE-SIGHT AND WHAT ARE THE HOPES THAT HAVE INSTIGATED YOU TO RESURRECT THE 2,500 YEAR OLD RELIGIOUS TEACHINGS OF LAO TZU?
Bhagwan Sri: Whatever Lao Tzu has said is 2,500 years old. But in a way, it is as fresh as the morning dew.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Into the disinterested depths of Tao</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_1/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_1/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
Into the disinterested depths of Tao
21 June 1971 pm in Immortal Study Circle CHAPTER 1: SUTRA 3 THEREFORE:
ALWAYS STRIPPED OF PASSION WE MUST BE FOUND
IF LIFE’S SECRET WE WOULD SOUND; BUT IF PASSION ALWAYS WITHIN US BE,
ITS OUTER FRINGE IS ALL THAT WE SHALL SEE.
The path that can be trodden upon, is not the Path. The Truth that can be investigated, is not the Truth.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 The mysterious Tao \-- beyond ignorance and knowledge</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_1/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_1/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
The mysterious Tao – beyond ignorance and knowledge
22 June 1971 pm in Immortal Study Circle
CHAPTER 1: SUTRA 4
UNDER THESE TWO ASPECTS, IT IS REALLY THE SAME; BUT AS DEVELOPMENT TAKES PLACE, IT RECEIVES THE DIFFERENT NAMES. TOGETHER WE CALL THEM THE MYSTERY. WHERE THE MYSTERY IS THE DEEPEST, IS THE GATE OF ALL THAT IS SUBTLE AND WONDERFUL.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Free from the similar variances \-- the beautiful and the good</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_1/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_1/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
Free from the similar variances – the beautiful and the good
23 June 1971 pm in Immortal Study Circle
CHAPTER 2: SUTRA 1
THE RISE OF RELATIVE OPPOSITES.
WHEN THE PEOPLE OF THE EARTH ALL KNOW BEAUTY AS BEAUTY, THERE ARISES (THE RECOGNITION OF) UGLINESS. WHEN THE PEOPLE OF THE EARTH ALL KNOW THE GOOD AS GOOD, THERE ARISES (THE RECOGNITION OF) EVIL.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 The music of opposing notes</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_1/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_1/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
The music of opposing notes
24 June 1971 pm in Immortal Study Circle
CHAPTER 2: SUTRA 2
SO IT IS THAT EXISTENCE AND NON-EXISTENCE GIVE BIRTH THE ONE TO THE IDEA OF THE OTHER; THAT DIFFICULTY AND EASE PRODUCE THE ONE THE IDEA OF THE OTHER; THAT LENGTH AND SHORTNESS FASHION OUT THE ONE THE FIGURE OF THE OTHER; THAT THE IDEA OF HEIGHT AND LOWNESS ARISE FROM THE CONTRAST OF THE ONE WITH THE OTHER; THAT THE MUSICAL NOTES AND TONES BECOME HARMONIOUS THROUGH THE RELATIONSHIP OF ONE WITH ANOTHER; AND THAT BEING BEFORE AND BEHIND GIVE THE IDEA OF ONE FOLLOWING ANOTHER.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Actionless action and silent dialogue of the wise</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_1/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_1/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
Actionless action and silent dialogue of the wise
25 June 1971 pm in Immortal Study Circle
CHAPTER 2: SUTRA 3
THEREFORE THE SAGE MANAGES AFFAIRS WITHOUT ACTION; AND CONVEYS HIS DOCTRINE WITHOUT WORDS.
Existence is dual. Whatever we do, the opposite also begins to happen simultaneously.
Lao Tzu has talked about Existence in his first two sutras. Now in the third sutra, Lao Tzu says: “THEREFORE, THE SAGE MANAGES AFFAIRS WITHOUT ACTION.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 Action free from ownership and recognition</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_1/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_1/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
Action free from ownership and recognition
26 June 1971 pm in Immortal Study Circle
CHAPTER 2: SUTRA 4
ALL THINGS TAKE THEIR RISE BUT HE DOES NOT TURN AWAY FROM THEM; HE GIVES THEM LIFE, BUT DOES NOT TAKE POSSESSION OF THEM; HE GOES THROUGH THESE PROCESSES, BUT DOES NOT TAKE POSSESSION OF THEM; HE ACTS, BUT DOES NOT APPROPRIATE, IT IS BECAUSE HE LAYS CLAIM TO NO CREDIT THAT THE CREDIT CANNOT BE TAKEN AWAY FROM HIM.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 The poison of ambition and the order of life</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_1/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_1/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
The poison of ambition and the order of life
19 July 1971 pm in Immortal Study Circle
CHAPTER 3 : SUTRA 1 ACTION WITHOUT DEEDS
NOT TO RULE AND EMPLOY MEN OF SUPERIOR ABILITY, IS THE WAY TO KEEP THE PEOPLE FROM RIVALRY AMONG THEMSELVES; NOT TO PRIZE ARTICLES WHICH ARE DIFFICULT TO PROCURE IS THE WAY TO KEEP THEM FROM BECOMING THIEVES; NOT TO SHOW THEM WHAT IS LIKELY TO EXCITE THEIR DESIRES IS THE WAY TO KEEP THEIR MINDS FROM DISORDER.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
