<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Be Realistic. Plan for a Miracle on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/be_realistic_plan_for_a_miracle/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Be Realistic. Plan for a Miracle on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/be_realistic_plan_for_a_miracle/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/be_realistic_plan_for_a_miracle/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/be_realistic_plan_for_a_miracle/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
13 March 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin asks about his work in the West and his relationship:... it’s crazy that I should ask you these things... I’ve got my own mind.]
No, you ask... that is a way of making up your mind, mm? Now you are part of me and I am as much involved in you as you are – even more.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/be_realistic_plan_for_a_miracle/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/be_realistic_plan_for_a_miracle/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
25 March 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Veera means courageous, prem means love – courageous in love. And that is the only courage there is... all else is cowardice.
So be more loving, and love completely unconditionally, mm? That is going to be your flowering of being.
[A sannyasin says she is afraid of going back to the West: I’m afraid that all the things I’ve dropped will come back again, and that I will drown in them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/be_realistic_plan_for_a_miracle/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/be_realistic_plan_for_a_miracle/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
26 March 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says she is very scared to go back to the West; she is scared of just about everything.]
Everything will be okay... don’t be worried. The mind goes on imagining things, and ninety-nine percent never happen and that one percent that happens is always good.
Trust always that everything is going to happen – and that it is going to be good.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/be_realistic_plan_for_a_miracle/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/be_realistic_plan_for_a_miracle/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
27 March 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Geetanjali. It means an offering of the songs. You can offer God flowers, or you can offer your songs. So Geetanjali means offering God your songs.
It is the name of one of the most famous books in India. Have you heard the name of Rabindranath Tagore? He is the only nobel-prize-winning indian poet, and it was for this book ‘Geetanjali’ that he was given the nobel prize.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/be_realistic_plan_for_a_miracle/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/be_realistic_plan_for_a_miracle/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
28 March 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Marpa is one of the greatest tibetan mystics... one of the rare geniuses. You cannot count more than ten of his equal in the whole world. And anand means blissful – blissful Marpa. Rad his life, teachings, and everything about him.
... Milarepa. That is another tibetan mystic. Read him – all the books are translated into English – particularly his ‘A Thousand Songs of Milarepa’; they are tremendously beautiful.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/be_realistic_plan_for_a_miracle/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/be_realistic_plan_for_a_miracle/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
29 March 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Arihanto means one who has attained, and anand means bliss – one who has attained bliss. and I give you this name for a particular reason.
Start living from this moment as if you are blissful. don’t try to achieve it – rather feel that it is achieved, and now you have just to live it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/be_realistic_plan_for_a_miracle/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/be_realistic_plan_for_a_miracle/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
30 March 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho suggested to a sannyasin to start a small meditation centre.]
It will be good for you also. This is my observation, that there are many things that you learn only when you start teaching them. The best way to learn a thing is to teach it.
And you grow more when you are less concerned about your own growth and more concerned with others’ growth, their problems.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/be_realistic_plan_for_a_miracle/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/be_realistic_plan_for_a_miracle/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
31 March 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[To a sannyasin who had said he was studying history in the West, but didn’t like it.]
History is not good...(laughter) it is just useless. Read something else, study something else which can be of creative use for your future.
Ninety-nine percent of history concerns foolish politicians. It is better not to know it, because it gives you a wrong notion about human beings.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/be_realistic_plan_for_a_miracle/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/be_realistic_plan_for_a_miracle/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
1 April 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin said that she was feeling sad because she had separated from her man recently, and she found it difficult to stop thinking of him.]
Sadness can become a very very enriching experience. You have to work on it. It is easy to escape from your sadness – and all relationships ordinarily are escapes; one simply goes on avoiding it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/be_realistic_plan_for_a_miracle/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/be_realistic_plan_for_a_miracle/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
2 April 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says she is afraid of leaving for the West.] Don’t be afraid of such things.
It is always difficult to leave the ones you love, but it becomes difficult because when we are with them we don’t love them. If you really love them, feel for them, care for them – and you will be there for three, four months – you can leave them without any fear.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/be_realistic_plan_for_a_miracle/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/be_realistic_plan_for_a_miracle/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
3 April 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A couple returning to the West. The man had recently had hepatitis and was feeling apprehensive about trying to cope with the weakness it had left him with.]
For a few weeks, just go and rest... don’t do anything, mm? Sometimes weakness of the body can be used in very very creative ways.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/be_realistic_plan_for_a_miracle/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/be_realistic_plan_for_a_miracle/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
14 March 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[The brother of Vipassana, a sannyasin who died three days ago of an inoperable brain tumour came to darshan.]
You did well. It is difficult, but you did well. And if one can face a loved one’s death, one comes out of it completely integrated.
Death can be very disintegrating... it can shatter you, or it can be a very crystallizing force and can make you integrated.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/be_realistic_plan_for_a_miracle/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/be_realistic_plan_for_a_miracle/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
4 April 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho gave an individual meditation to a newly-arrived sannyasin.]
Start doing one meditation in the night before you go to sleep.
Put off the light and just stand in the darkness. Then start shaking from the head, just the head. Enjoy the shaking and feel how it feels from inside, mm? Then shake the upper part of the body – the head, the hands, the torso; don’t shake the lower part.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/be_realistic_plan_for_a_miracle/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/be_realistic_plan_for_a_miracle/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
5 April 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says: I have a lot of problems about girls... I really get frightened – sometimes just of everything, sometimes of nothing. It’s just a general sort of fear.]
A few groups will be very very helpful. The fear has to be dropped, but first you will have to go into it. You can drop a thing only when you have understood perfectly; otherwise you cannot drop it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/be_realistic_plan_for_a_miracle/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/be_realistic_plan_for_a_miracle/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 22
6 April 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin said that she had not been meditating for the past few months as she felt the presence of a force almost like a person’s presence when she started to meditate, and in fear she would have to open her eyes.
Osho checked her energy.]
It is nothing to be worried about. Rather you should be happy that it is happening.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/be_realistic_plan_for_a_miracle/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/be_realistic_plan_for_a_miracle/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
15 March 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A japanese man expressed some apprehension prior to taking sannyas, as he was already involved with a movement in Japan, called Tenrikyo, which he said started just one hundred and fifty years ago in Japan, and was something akin to Buddhism, yet not Buddhism.]
No need to leave it right now. Just go on making all efforts to search deep.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/be_realistic_plan_for_a_miracle/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/be_realistic_plan_for_a_miracle/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
16 March 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
... this will be your name: Ma Anand Soma.
Soma means the moon, and anand means bliss – blissful moon.
Meditate on the moon more and more. Whenever the moon is in the sky, just sit looking at it, but with very empty eyes. Looking, and yet not concentrating. Just looking, but with no strain.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/be_realistic_plan_for_a_miracle/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/be_realistic_plan_for_a_miracle/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
17 March 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says: I’m wondering about my relationship. There is a lot of good feeling, but we’re sort of keeping each other safe, and I feel restricted.
We’ll both be starting groups and I think we’ll be able to branch out.]
No relationship can truly grow if you go on holding back. If you remain clever and go on safeguarding and protecting yourself, only personalities meet, and the essential centres remain alone.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/be_realistic_plan_for_a_miracle/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/be_realistic_plan_for_a_miracle/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
18 March 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says: I don’t want to be here – and I don’t know why. Since Vipassana died I have felt afraid of death. And Amitabh (her boyfriend) seems different... I feel frightened. Sometimes I don’t even want to be human any more.
But I also don’t believe that if I went away I would feel any different.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/be_realistic_plan_for_a_miracle/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/be_realistic_plan_for_a_miracle/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
22 March 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[An indian visitor, who is a professional dancer, asked what meditation technique would be right for her, and then went on to ask about love and relationships.]
There is no need to find any other meditation. Dance itself becomes a meditation if the dancer is lost. The whole point is how to lose oneself.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/be_realistic_plan_for_a_miracle/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/be_realistic_plan_for_a_miracle/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
23 March 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin who is leaving says: I’ll try to be back in the winter, but I’ve no plans.]
There is no need to plan for the future. But if you have just a nucleus in the mind – that you have to do a certain thing – leave it there. Just put the thought there and it creates its own energy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/be_realistic_plan_for_a_miracle/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/be_realistic_plan_for_a_miracle/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
24 March 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A new sannyasin said she didn’t understand how or why she had come here; it was just that she felt she needed to.
Osho said it was good to move with one’s feelings rather than thinking too much, though it was of course safer to think, as society didn’t feel threatened by that... ]</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
