<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Until You Die on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/until_you_die/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Until You Die on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/until_you_die/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 Until You Die</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/until_you_die/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/until_you_die/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
Until You Die
11 April 1975 am in Buddha Hall
THERE WAS A RICH AND GENEROUS MAN OF BOKHARA. BECAUSE HE HAD A HIGH RANK IN THE INVISIBLE HIERARCHY, HE WAS KNOWN AS THE PRESIDENT OF THE WORLD.
EVERY DAY HE GAVE GOLD TO ONE CATEGORY OF PEOPLE – THE SICK, WIDOWS, AND SO ON. BUT NOTHING WAS GIVEN TO ANYONE WHO OPENED HIS MOUTH.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 A Rose Is A Rose Is A Rose\...</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/until_you_die/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/until_you_die/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 10
A Rose Is A Rose Is A Rose...
20 April 1975 am in Buddha Hall
A DISCIPLE CAME TO MARUF KARKHI AND SAID:
‘I HAVE BEEN TALKING TO PEOPLE ABOUT YOU. JEWS CLAIM THAT YOU ARE A JEW; CHRISTIANS REVERE YOU AS ONE OF THEIR OWN SAINTS; MUSLIMS INSIST THAT YOU ARE THE GREATEST OF ALL MUSLIMS.’
MARUF ANSWERED:
‘THIS IS WHAT HUMANITY SAYS IN BAGHDAD.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Judge Ye Not</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/until_you_die/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/until_you_die/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
Judge Ye Not
12 April 1975 am in Buddha Hall
A YOUNG MAN CAME TO DHUN-NUN AND SAID THAT THE SUFIS WERE WRONG, AND MANY ANOTHER THING BESIDES.
THE EGYPTIAN REMOVED A RING FROM HIS FINGER AND HANDED IT TO HIM. ‘TAKE THIS TO THE MARKET STALLHOLDERS OVER THERE AND SEE WHETHER YOU CAN GET A GOLD PIECE FOR IT,’ HE SAID.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Walking Without Crutches</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/until_you_die/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/until_you_die/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
Walking Without Crutches
13 April 1975 am in Buddha Hall
A MAN ONCE HURT HIS LEG. HE HAD TO WALK WITH A CRUTCH.
THIS CRUTCH WAS VERY USEFUL TO HIM, BOTH FOR WALKING, AND MANY OTHER THINGS.
HE TAUGHT ALL HIS FAMILY TO USE CRUTCHES, AND THEY BECAME PART OF NORMAL LIFE. IT WAS PART OF EVERYONE’S AMBITION TO HAVE A CRUTCH.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Straight To Freedom</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/until_you_die/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/until_you_die/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
Straight To Freedom
14 April 1975 am in Buddha Hall
A MAN CAME TO THE GREAT TEACHER BAHAUDIN AND ASKED FOR HELP IN HIS PROBLEMS, AND GUIDANCE ON THE PATH OF THE TEACHING.
BAHAUDIN TOLD HIM TO ABANDON SPIRITUAL STUDIES AND LEAVE HIS COURT AT ONCE. A KIND-HEARTED VISITOR BEGAN TO REMONSTRATE WITH BAHAUDIN.
‘YOU SHALL HAVE A DEMONSTRATION,’ SAID THE SAGE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Truth Is Not Veiled</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/until_you_die/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/until_you_die/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
Truth Is Not Veiled
15 April 1975 am in Buddha Hall
A MAN CAME TO BAYAZID AND SAID THAT HE HAD FASTED AND PRAYED FOR THIRTY YEARS AND YET HAD NOT COME NEAR TO AN UNDERSTANDING OF GOD.
BAYAZID TOLD HIM THAT EVEN A HUNDRED YEARS WOULD NOT BE ENOUGH. THE MAN ASKED WHY.
‘BECAUSE YOUR SELFISHNESS IS WORKING AS A BARRIER BETWEEN YOURSELF AND THE TRUTH,’ SAID BAYAZID.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Man Carries The Seed</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/until_you_die/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/until_you_die/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
Man Carries The Seed
16 April 1975 am in Buddha Hall
EL MAHDI ABBASSI ANNOUNCED THAT IT WAS VERIFIABLE THAT, WHETHER PEOPLE TRIED TO HELP A MAN OR NOT, SOMETHING IN THE MAN COULD FRUSTRATE THIS AIM.
CERTAIN PEOPLE HAVING OBJECTED TO THIS THEORY, EL MAHDI PROMISED A DEMONSTRATION.
WHEN EVERYONE HAD FORGOTTEN THE INCIDENT, EL MAHDI ORDERED ONE MAN TO LAY A SACK OF GOLD IN THE MIDDLE OF A BRIDGE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Knowledge Is Dangerous</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/until_you_die/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/until_you_die/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
Knowledge Is Dangerous
17 April 1975 am in Buddha Hall
A MAN WENT TO A DOCTOR AND TOLD HIM THAT HIS WIFE WAS NOT BEARING CHILDREN.
THE PHYSICIAN SAW THE WOMAN, TOOK HER PULSE AND SAID: ‘I CANNOT TREAT YOU FOR STERILITY BECAUSE I HAVE DISCOVERED THAT YOU WILL IN ANY CASE DIE WITHIN FORTY DAYS.’
WHEN SHE HEARD THIS THE WOMAN WAS SO WORRIED THAT SHE COULD EAT NOTHING DURING THE ENSUING FORTY DAYS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 This Too Will Pass</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/until_you_die/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/until_you_die/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
This Too Will Pass
18 April 1975 am in Buddha Hall
A POWERFUL KING, RULER OF MANY DOMAINS, WAS IN A POSITION OF SUCH MAGNIFICENCE THAT WISE MEN WERE HIS MERE EMPLOYEES. AND YET ONE DAY HE FELT HIMSELF CONFUSED AND CALLED HIS SAGES TO HIM.
HE SAID:
‘I DO NOT KNOW THE CAUSE, BUT SOMETHING IMPELS ME TO SEEK A CERTAIN RING, ONE THAT WILL ENABLE ME TO STABILIZE MY STATE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 Almost Dead With Thirst</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/until_you_die/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/until_you_die/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
Almost Dead With Thirst
19 April 1975 am in Buddha Hall
SHIBLI WAS ASKED: ‘WHO GUIDED YOU IN THE PATH?’
SHIBLI SAID: ’A DOG. ONE DAY I SAW HIM, ALMOST DEAD WITH THIRST, STANDING BY THE WATER’S EDGE. EVERY TIME HE LOOKED AT HIS REFLECTION IN THE WATER HE WAS FRIGHTENED AND WITHDREW, BECAUSE HE THOUGHT IT WAS ANOTHER DOG.
’FINALLY, SUCH WAS HIS NECESSITY, HE CAST AWAY FEAR AND LEAPT INTO THE WATER; AT WHICH THE REFLECTION DISAPPEARED.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
