<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Rebel on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Rebel on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 The rebel: the very essence of religion</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
The rebel: the very essence of religion
1 June 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
WHAT IS THE DIFFERENCE BETWEEN A REBEL AND A REVOLUTIONARY?
Maneesha, there is not only a quantitative difference between a rebel and a revolutionary, there is also a qualitative difference. The revolutionary is part of the political world. His approach is through politics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Jesus is not a christian</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
Jesus is not a christian
5 June 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
WHAT IS THE RELIGION OF A REBELLIOUS SPIRIT?
Maneesha, the rebellious spirit can be religious, but cannot have a religion. And the difference between the two is immense, unbridgeable.
To be religious is an experience, just like love. It is an encounter with the totality of existence.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 The failure of revolution</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
The failure of revolution
6 June 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
NINE YEARS AGO I FELL IN LOVE WITH CAMUS’ BOOK, “MAN IN REVOLT”, IN WHICH HE COMES TO THE CONCLUSION THAT ALL ATTEMPTS TO ABOLISH INJUSTICE THROUGH REVOLUTIONS ARE BOUND TO FAIL. RATHER, HE SAYS, THE ONLY WAY IS TO CREATE JUSTICE THROUGH LIVING IT.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 The magical door of eternity</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
The magical door of eternity
6 June 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
WHAT IS THE DIFFERENCE BETWEEN THE REBEL AND THE ENLIGHTENED ONE? IS IT POSSIBLE TO BE A REAL REBEL WITHOUT BEING ENLIGHTENED?
Anand Rupen, it is possible to be a rebel without being enlightened. It is also possible to be enlightened without being a rebel.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 Shadows of the dead</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
Shadows of the dead
7 June 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
ARE YOUR SANNYASINS ALL REBELS?
IS IT TRUE THAT A REBEL IS BORN AND NOT MADE?
OR ARE WE BORN REBELS BUT TAMED AND CONDITIONED BY OUR SOCIETIES?
Jivan Mary, one who is not a rebel will not come close to me. The very fact that he comes close to me, becomes an initiate, is proof enough that he is a rebel.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 As below, so above</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
As below, so above
7 June 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
I BOW MY HEAD TO YOUR LOTUS FEET. FOR YEARS I HAVE LOVED STORIES OF GURDJIEFF AND ZEN MASTERS WHO HIT THEIR DISCIPLES SO HARD THAT THEY GET IT.
THE OTHER NIGHT YOU STRUCK YOUR SCALPEL SHARP – NO ANESTHETIC – REMOVING A CANCER THAT’S BEEN THERE FOR LIVES.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 This is not a place of entertainment</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
This is not a place of entertainment
8 June 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
MY HUSBAND IS VERY MUCH ANNOYED WITH YOU AND YOUR SANNYASINS AND WITH ME, BECAUSE I CROSSED ALL THE LIMITS. HE COMES TO THE ASHRAM WITH ME, BUT HE DOESN’T LIKE THE IDEA OF LISTENING TO YOU. HE COMES TO THE GATES OF THE TEMPLE, BUT HE NEVER WANTS TO LOOK UPON THE LIVING IDOL.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 Live is on the razor\&#39;s edge</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
Live is on the razor’s edge
8 June 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
I FIND MYSELF BEING DEEPLY TOUCHED BY YOUR VISION OF THE REBEL. I ALWAYS PRIDED MYSELF IN BEING A NONCONFORMIST. LAST NIGHT IN A DREAM I SAW MYSELF BEING PERSECUTED FOR LIVING REBELLIOUSLY AND I BECAME AFRAID. WAKING UP, I REALIZED THAT WHAT I USED TO THINK OF AS REBELLION WAS ACTUALLY A SAFE GAME FOR ME, WELL WITHIN ACCEPTABLE LIMITS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 The solitary lion and his tremendously beautiful roar</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
The solitary lion and his tremendously beautiful roar
9 June 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
WHAT IS A BEAUTIFUL AND ENLIGHTENED CHAP LIKE YOU DOING WITH A MOTLEY CREW SUCH AS WE? ACTUALLY, I DON’T REALLY WANT TO KNOW WHAT YOU ARE DOING.
JUST, PLEASE, DON’T STOP DOING IT.
Maneesha, every crowd is a motley crowd, but no individual is motley.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 Every desire creates conflict</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
Every desire creates conflict
9 June 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
WHAT IS PEACE FOR THE REBELLIOUS MAN?
Raso, peace is, for the rebellious man, his very light. It is his very aroma, his fragrance, the harmony of his heart, his at-oneness with existence. All conflicts of the mind are just memories of the past. The mind is no longer divided, split or schizophrenic.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19 The promise of paradise</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
The promise of paradise
10 June 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
IN YOUR GOLDEN FUTURE, WILL THERE BE A TROUPE OF ENLIGHTENED ACTORS? IS IT POSSIBLE FOR A MAN WHO IS ENLIGHTENED TO BE AN ACTOR?
Vimal, the enlightened man is an actor. He cannot be otherwise. He knows he’s not the body, yet he behaves as if he’s the body; he knows he’s not the mind, yet he responds as if he’s the mind.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Beyond the capacity of the mind</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
Beyond the capacity of the mind
1 June 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
FOR THE PAST FEW WEEKS, I HAVE BEEN ABLE TO SIT AND ALLOW MY MIND TO BE QUIET – SOMETIMES FOR ONLY A SECOND, BUT SOMETIMES FOR LONGER. SINCE THIS HAS BEEN HAPPENING, I HAVE EXPERIENCED MANY BEAUTIFUL SPACES, AS IF THIS QUIETNESS SOMEHOW INVITES THE UNIVERSE IN.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 The rebel has no path</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
The rebel has no path
10 June 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
IS THE PATH OF THE REBEL THE MIDDLE PATH, OR THE PATH OF EXTREMES?
I HAVE HEARD YOU SPEAK FOR AND AGAINST BOTH, AND ALSO SAY THAT THERE IS NO PATH.
WHAT GUIDES THE REBEL?
Marga Madir, the rebel has no path to follow; those who follow any path are not rebels.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 Confess to the stars</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
Confess to the stars
11 June 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
I NOTICE THAT THE QUESTIONS I WRITE TO YOU USUALLY TURN OUT TO BE “CONFESSIONS.” I ASSUMED IT WAS BECAUSE OF SOME KIND OF CONDITIONING, ALTHOUGH MY UPBRINGING DID NOT INCLUDE THE PRACTICE OF CONFESSION TO A PRIEST.
IT SEEMS THAT I HAVE AN EXPECTATION THAT BY TELLING YOU, YOU CAN FREE ME.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22 Laughter is divine</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
Laughter is divine
11 June 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
I BROUGHT MYSELF TO YOUR DOORSTEP AND THEN TRIED TO RUN AWAY, BUT YOU WOULD NOT LET ME ESCAPE. NOW, SO MANY BELOVED FRIENDS AND FELLOW TRAVELERS HAVE HUGGED ME AND SPOKEN OF FEELING YOUR LOVE FOR ME WITHIN THEMSELVES, AND SO MANY FELT YOU DISSOLVE THEIR QUESTIONS IN MINE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23 Mind is a kind of insanity</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
Mind is a kind of insanity
12 June 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
CAN YOU PLEASE SAY SOMETHING ABOUT VIOLENCE AS THE EXPRESSION OF REBELLION?
Milarepa, violence can never be a part of the rebellious spirit for the simple reason that violence is the whole past of humanity – and the rebel wants to discontinue with the past.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 A questionless silence</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 24
A questionless silence
12 June 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
IS IT POSSIBLE TO MEDITATE WITHOUT ANY TECHNIQUE?
Deva Maturo, the question you have asked is certainly of great importance because meditation, as such, needs no technique at all. But techniques are needed to remove the obstacles in the way of meditation. So it has to be understood very clearly: meditation itself needs no techniques, it is a simple understanding, an alertness, an awareness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25 The field of awakening</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 25
The field of awakening
13 June 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
ALL THE PAIN AND SUFFERING OF THE PAST, PRESENT AND FUTURE WORLD THAT I HEAR YOU TALK ABOUT LEAVES ME WITH SUCH A SADNESS BECAUSE THIS WORLD IS SO BEAUTIFUL. AS LONG AS I AM NOT AWAKENED, I FEEL THAT SOMEHOW I AM PART OF THAT UNCONSCIOUS CRUELTY AND STUPIDITY, AND I REALLY WANT TO GET OUT OF IT.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26 Physician of the inner world</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 26
Physician of the inner world
13 June 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
OSCAR WILDE ONCE SAID: “WHEN THE GODS WANT TO PUNISH US, THEY ANSWER OUR PRAYERS.” WOULD YOU PLEASE COMMENT?
Devageet, Oscar Wilde is right. It often happens that what psychologists cannot explain about the human mind, the creative artist, the poet, can easily explore to the depths which are beyond logic, beyond reason, beyond scientific research.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27 A ray from the beyond</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 27
A ray from the beyond
14 June 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
WHEN YOU TOLD THE STORY ABOUT GAUTAM BUDDHA WAITING AT THE GATE OF PARADISE FOR THE LAST HUMAN BEING, I CRIED – AND I SAW YOU, WAITING FOR US.
MY QUESTION IS, IF YOU WILL WAIT ALSO FOR ME? RIGHT NOW, I’M PUTTING ALL MY ENERGY INTO WAKING UP, BUT EVERYTHING TAKES TIME.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28 The disappearance of sex</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part28/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 28
The disappearance of sex
14 June 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
MY SEX LIFE HAS BECOME VERY QUIET LATELY. NOT THAT I DON’T WANT SEX AND THAT I AM NOT COURAGEOUS ENOUGH TO APPROACH WOMEN, BUT IT JUST DOESN’T HAPPEN.
WHEN I APPROACH A WOMAN LOTS OF BEAUTIFUL ENERGY IS FLOWING, BUT WHEN IT COMES TO SEX, THE ENERGY CHANGES.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>29 Something of the wild</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part29/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 29
Something of the wild
15 June 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
I HAVE HEARD YOU SAY THAT NINETY-EIGHT PERCENT OF THE WOMEN OF THE EAST HAVE NOT KNOWN ORGASM. WHY IS IT THEY LOOK SO GRACEFUL AND NOT FRUSTRATED LIKE THE WOMEN IN THE WEST?
Prem Salila, it is a strange logic of life, but in a way very simple.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Enlightenment is not a device</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
Enlightenment is not a device
2 June 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
I SEE YOU HERE EVERY DAY, SO RADIANT, SO FULL OF LIGHT, SO FAR AWAY FROM THE EVERYDAY REALITY OF MY LIFE. YOU ARE A SHINING BEACON SHOWING THE WAY, AND THE POSSIBILITY OF SOMETHING MORE THAT CAN HAPPEN IN ME. YEARS AGO, HERE WITH YOU, I USED TO FEEL THAT ENLIGHTENMENT WAS JUST AROUND THE CORNER.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>30 The slavery of marriage</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part30/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 30
The slavery of marriage
15 June 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
CAN A MARRIED MAN ALSO BE A REBEL?
Anil Bharti, the question that you have asked is really complex. A married man certainly can be a rebel, in fact he has all the reasons to be a rebel. An unmarried man may not even think of rebellion, he may be thinking of getting married; but the married man cannot think of anything else except rebellion, although he only thinks of it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>31 Burning torches moving around the world</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part31/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 31
Burning torches moving around the world
16 June 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
YOU HAVE BEEN TALKING ON YOUR VISION OF THE REBEL LATELY, AND YET THE ATMOSPHERE I FEEL AROUND US AT THE MOMENT IS PARTICULARLY SOFT, LOVING, PLIABLE. TO ME, THIS FEELS LIKE PART OF YOUR MAGIC – THAT YOU ARE SHOWING US, EXISTENTIALLY, THAT THE REBEL WILL BE BORN NOT OUT OF THE FUMES OF VIOLENCE AND UNHAPPINESS, BUT FROM THE FRAGRANCE OF LOVE AND ECSTASY.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>32 The face behind the mask</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part32/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part32/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 32
The face behind the mask
16 June 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
FOR MY WHOLE LIFE, FRIENDLINESS HAS BEEN A SHIELD FOR ME TO PROTECT MYSELF FROM OTHERS. SITTING WITH YOU IN DISCOURSE AND FEELING YOUR OVERWHELMING LOVE, LAYERS OF THIS SHIELD ARE DROPPING AWAY, MORE AND MORE, AND I FEEL A SPACE IN WHICH I AM ENOUGH UNTO MYSELF.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>33 Tommorrow never comes</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part33/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part33/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 33
Tommorrow never comes
17 June 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
I FEEL INSIDE ME, WHEN I LISTEN TO YOU SPEAK, A DEEP LONGING FOR FREEDOM ARISE. I FEEL LIKE THE TIGER IN THE STORY AWAKENING TO ITS TRUE NATURE. I SENSE MY POTENTIAL FOR EXPANSION, FOR ECSTASY, FOR LOVE. YET, AT THE SAME TIME I FEEL AFRAID AND STILL HOLD BACK.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>34 A danger to the crowd</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part34/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part34/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 34
A danger to the crowd
17 June 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
WHY IS IT THAT SO MANY PEOPLE ABANDON THEIR INTELLIGENCE, THEIR SENSITIVITY, THEIR RESPONSIBILITY AND THEIR INDIVIDUALITY WHEN THEY BECOME PART OF A GROUP? MUST THE REBELLIOUS SPIRIT ALWAYS BE ALONE?
Dhyan Senshi, the rebellious spirit is basically the experience of one’s own individuality, absolutely free from any kind of psychological slavery.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>35 The purity of awareness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part35/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part35/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 35
The purity of awareness
18 June 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
SITTING WITH YOU EVERY DAY, I AM BECOMING AWARE OF A DARK, HEAVY SPACE INSIDE ME. IT FEELS AS IF IT IS NOT PART OF ME, BUT I KNOW I CARRY IT AROUND WITH ME. WILL IT DISAPPEAR IF I KEEP ON WATCHING, OR DO I NEED TO DO SOMETHING MORE?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 The rebel is utterly innocent</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
The rebel is utterly innocent
2 June 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
WHAT ARE THE QUALITIES OF A REBEL?
Maneesha, the qualities of a rebel are multidimensional. The first thing: the rebel does not believe in anything except his own experience. His truth is his only truth; no prophet, no messiah, no savior, no holy scripture, no ancient tradition can give him his truth.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Renounce the past, not the world</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
Renounce the past, not the world
3 June 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
IS RENOUNCING THE WORLD AND SOCIETY PART OF A REBELLIOUS SPIRIT?
Maneesha, the whole past of man is full of those people who have renounced the world and society. Renunciation has become part of almost all religions, a foundational principle.
The rebel is renouncing the past.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Herald a new dawn</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
Herald a new dawn
3 June 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
DOES THE REBEL BELONG TO ANY CATEGORY?
Maneesha, the rebel by his very nature cannot belong to any existent categories; he is a new category. He introduces a new man into the world. He is a herald of a new dawn, a new beginning. No category of the past can contain him; all the categories that have existed up to now have proved either failures, or insufficient to change the whole of humanity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 No more ready-made gods</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
No more ready-made gods
4 June 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
WHAT IS THE DIFFERENCE BETWEEN THE OLD SAGE AND THE NEW REBEL?
Maneesha, the old sage was respectable, honored by the society in which he was born. He followed the rules and regulations of the people, he went through all the disciplines required for being a sage.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 Zorba the buddha \-- man of the future</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
Zorba the buddha – man of the future
4 June 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
HOW IS YOUR REBEL CONCERNED WITH “ZORBA THE BUDDHA”?
Maneesha, my rebel, my new man, is Zorba the Buddha. Mankind has lived believing either in the reality of the soul and the illusoriness of matter, or in the reality of matter and the illusoriness of the soul.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 Society\&#39;s justice is revenge</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rebel/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
Society’s justice is revenge
5 June 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
WHAT IS JUSTICE FOR A REBELLIOUS MAN?
Raso, it is one of the most significant questions to be asked – for the simple reason that man has never tried to remove the causes of injustice. On the contrary, in the name of justice, he has been taking revenge on the individuals who were not obedient to the social order, to the establishment, to the vested interests.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
