<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Path of Yoga on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_yoga/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Path of Yoga on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_yoga/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About Osho</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_yoga/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_yoga/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌About Osho Osho defies categorization. His thousands of talks cover everything from the individual quest for meaning to the most urgent social and political issues facing society today. Osho’s books are not written but are transcribed from audio and video recordings of his extemporaneous talks to international audiences. As he puts it, “So remember: whatever I am saying is not just for you… I am talking also for the future generations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 1: Introduction to the Path of Yoga</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_yoga/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_yoga/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 1: Introduction to the Path of Yoga We live in a deep illusion – an illusion of hope, of future, of tomorrow. As man is, he cannot exist without self-deception.
Nietzsche says somewhere that man cannot live with the true: he needs dreams, he needs illusions, he needs lies to exist. And Nietzsche is right. As man is, he cannot exist with the truth.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 10: The End Is in the Beginning</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_yoga/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_yoga/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 10: The End Is in the Beginning The first question:
Osho,
How is it that you describe the life that is really ours, and which you have transcended, so correctly and in every detail, while we remain so ignorant of it? Is it not paradoxical?
It looks paradoxical; it is not. But you can understand only when you have transcended. While you are in a certain state of mind you cannot understand that state of mind; you are so involved in it, you are so identified with it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 2: Desireless, You Are Enlightened</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_yoga/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_yoga/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 2: Desireless, You Are Enlightened The first question:
Osho,
You said last night that total despair, frustration and hopelessness is the beginning ground for Yoga. This gives Yoga a pessimistic look. Is this pessimistic state really necessary to begin the path of Yoga? Can an optimist also begin with the path of Yoga?
It is neither pessimistic nor optimistic, because pessimism and optimism are two aspects of the same coin.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 3: Five Modifications of Mind</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_yoga/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_yoga/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 3: Five Modifications of Mind The modifications of the mind are five.
They can be either a source of misery or of non-misery.
They are right knowledge, wrong knowledge, imagination, sleep and memory.
Mind can be either the source of bondage or the source of freedom. Mind becomes the gate for this world, the entry; it can also become the exit. Mind leads you to hell, mind can also lead you to heaven.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4: Madness or Meditation</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_yoga/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_yoga/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 4: Madness or Meditation The first question:
Osho,
You said that there are only two alternatives for man, either madness or meditation. But millions of people on the earth have not reached to either of the two. Do you think they will?
They have reached. They have not reached to meditation, but they have reached to madness. And the difference between the mad who are inside the madhouses and the mad who are outside the madhouses is only of degrees.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 5: Why Can&#39;t you Dance?</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_yoga/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_yoga/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 5: Why Can’t you Dance? Right-knowledge has three sources: direct-cognition, inference and the words of the awakened ones,
Wrong-knowledge is a false conception not corresponding to the thing as it is.
An image conjured up by words without any substance behind it is vikalpa, imagination.
The modification of the mind which is based on the absence of any content in it, is sleep.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 6: The Purity of Yoga</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_yoga/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_yoga/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 6: The Purity of Yoga The first question:
Osho,
You said that Patanjali’s Yoga is an exact science, absolutely logical, in which the result is as certain as two plus two make four. If the attainment of the unknown and infinite can be reduced to mere logic, is it not true and at the same time absurd that the infinite phenomenon is within the orbit of the finite mind?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 7: An Ecstasy Is Born</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_yoga/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_yoga/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 7: An Ecstasy Is Born Their cessation is brought about by persistent inner effort and non-attachment
Of these two, abhyasa, the inner practice,
is the effort to be firmly established in oneself.
It becomes firmly grounded when continued for a long time, without interruption and with reverent devotion.
Man is not only his conscious mind. He has also nine times more than the conscious – the unconscious layer of the mind.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 8: Stop, and It Is Here!</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_yoga/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_yoga/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 8: Stop, and It Is Here! The first question:
Osho,
Patanjali has stressed the importance of non-attachment, that is, cessation of desire, for being rooted in oneself. But is non-attachment really at the beginning of the journey or at the very end?
The beginning and the end are not two things. The beginning is the end, so don’t divide them and don’t think in terms of duality.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 9: This Very Life, the Ultimate Joy</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_yoga/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_yoga/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 9: This Very Life, the Ultimate Joy The first state of vairagya, desirelessness: cessation from self-indulgence in the thirst for sensuous pleasures, with conscious effort.
The last state of vairagya, desirelessness: cessation of all desiring by knowing the innermost nature of purush, the supreme self.
Abhyasa andvairagya – constant inner practice and desirelessness: these are the two foundation stones of Patanjali’s Yoga. Constant inner effort is needed not because something has to be achieved but because of wrong habits.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Copyright page</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_yoga/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_yoga/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
Copyright © 1973, 2013 OSHO International Foundation{#bookmark1 style=” color: black; font-family:&#34;Times New Roman&#34;, serif; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; text-decoration: none; font-size: 10.5pt;” target=“_blank”} www.osho.com/copyrights
Images and cover design © OSHO International Foundation
All rights reserved. No part of this book may be reproduced or transmitted in any form or by any means, electronic or mechanical, including photocopying, recording, or by any information storage and retrieval system, without prior written permission from the publisher.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OSHO International Meditation Resort</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_yoga/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_yoga/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
OSHO International Meditation Resort
www.osho.com/meditationresort
Each year the OSHO International Meditation Resort welcomes thousands of people from more than 100 countries. The unique campus provides an opportunity for a direct personal experience of a new way of living – with more awareness, relaxation, celebration and creativity. A great variety of around-the- clock and around-the-year program options are available. Doing nothing and just relaxing is one of them!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preface</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_yoga/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_yoga/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Preface Mind is not a thing, but an event. A thing has substance in it; an event is just a process. A thing is like a rock; an event is like a wave: it exists, but is not substantial. It is just the event between the wind and the ocean – a process, a phenomenon.
This is the first thing to be understood: that mind is a process, like a wave or like a river, but it has no substance in it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Title page</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_yoga/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_yoga/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Yoga: The Science of the Soul, Vol.1 The Path of Yoga Discovering the Essence and Origin of Yoga The Yoga Sutras of Patanjali
OSHO &amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
