<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>From Personality to Individuality on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/</link>
    <description>Recent content in From Personality to Individuality on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 Man is born with a question mark in his heart</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
Man is born with a question mark in his heart
30 December 1984 pm in Lao Tzu Grove
Question 1 OSHO,
WHAT PLACE HAS MYSTICISM IN YOUR RELIGION?
My religion is pure mysticism. There is nothing else in it.
The other religions have no place for mysticism in them. They cannot have, for the simple reason that they have answers for every question – bogus answers, without any evidence, with no argument.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Christianity: just a nice Jewish boy\&#39;s hang-up</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
Christianity: just a nice Jewish boy’s hang-up
8 January 1985 pm in Lao Tzu Grove
Question 1 OSHO,
YOU SAY CHRIST WAS THE LAST CHRISTIAN. ARE YOU THE LAST RAJNEESHEE? PLEASE EXPLAIN.
IT was not me who said that Christ was the last Christian. I was simply quoting Friedrich Nietzsche; it was Nietzsche who made that statement. In a certain sense Nietzsche is absolutely right, because in this world no individual is ever repeated.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 God \-- the phantom fuehrer</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
God – the phantom fuehrer
9 January 1985 pm in Lao Tzu Grove
Question 1 OSHO,
ALAN WATTS ONCE DESCRIBED THE UNIVERSE BY SAYING, “IT IS AS IF GOD IS PLAYING A GAME.” IF THERE IS NO GOD, WHO IS PLAYING AND WHAT IS THE GAME?
ALAN Watts was a nice guy but that statement he made was stolen from Hindu mythology.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Death: The ultimate orgasm</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
Death: The ultimate orgasm
10 January 1985 pm in Lao Tzu Grove
Question 1 OSHO,
IN OTHER RELIGIONS DEATH IS ALMOST NEVER SPOKEN OF AND WHEN IT IS MENTIONED THE TONES ARE GRAVE AND FEARFUL. IN YOUR RELIGION, DEATH IS TALKED ABOUT FREELY AND HAPPILY IS THIS SIGNIFICANT?
IT is certainly one of the most significant things.
It determines whether a religion is authentic or pseudo.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 The new man: intellect in harmony with the heart</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
The new man: intellect in harmony with the heart
11 January 1985 pm in Lao Tzu Grove
Question 1 OSHO,
HOW CAN WE BELIEVE THAT THE SOUL EXISTS AFTER DEATH AND TRANSMIGRATES TO ANOTHER FORM OF LIFE, OR DISSOLVES INTO THE UNIVERSE?
I have never asked you to believe in anything.
It is my experience that the soul exists after death, that it transmigrates into other forms of life, and finally when there is no more to learn, no question to be answered, no search, no desire – when that ultimate point of absolute contentment, fulfillment, enlightenment arises – then the soul simply dissolves into existence.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 The only hope: the enlightenment of humanity</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
The only hope: the enlightenment of humanity
12 January 1985 pm in Lao Tzu Grove
Question 1 OSHO,
WOULDN’T IT HAVE BEEN MUCH EASIER FOR YOU TO WORK WITHOUT BEING ASSOCIATED WITH THE WORD RELIGION? WHAT IS THE SECRET BEHIND YOUR CHOOSING TO DO IT THIS WAY?
I would have loved not to be associated in any way with the word religion.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 Truth said, truth dead</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
Truth said, truth dead
13 January 1985 pm in Lao Tzu Grove
Question 1 OSHO,
WHAT ARE YOU PREPARING US, YOUR SANNYASINS, FOR?
I am preparing my sannyasins for everything and nothing. The second is more important. The first is only a preparation for the second.
“Everything” includes everything that is necessary for a person to get to his being, to be fulfilled, to be contented, to be in that ultimate state where there is no desire, no need; where one is sufficient unto oneself</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 Superman: the fantasy for the inferior</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
Superman: the fantasy for the inferior
14 January 1985 pm in Lao Tzu Grove
Question 1 OSHO,
ISN’T THE VISION OF THE NEW MAN SOMEHOW SIMILAR TO THE IDEA OF THE SUPERMAN?
THE idea of the new man is not only not similar to the idea of the superman, it is just the very opposite.
The superman is a continuity with the old man.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 Holy Scriptures: wholly Bullshit</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
Holy Scriptures: wholly Bullshit
15 January 1985 pm in Lao Tzu Grove
Question 1 OSHO,
WHAT IS THE DIFFERENCE BETWEEN MADNESS AND ENLIGHTENMENT?
THERE is a great difference and also a great similarity. The similarity has to be understood first, because without understanding it, it will be difficult to understand the difference.
Both are beyond the mind – madness and enlightenment. Madness is below the mind.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 The good shepherd \-- the butcher\&#39;s friend</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
The good shepherd – the butcher’s friend
16 January 1985 pm in Lao Tzu Grove
Question 1 OSHO,
ARE YOU ESPECIALLY AGAINST CHRISTIANITY?
I hate to favor Christianity with any special attention but unfortunately it deserves it. It is the ugliest manifestation of religion on the earth, for many reasons.
The first: Christianity is the only well-organized religion.
The more a religion is well-organized, the less is the possibility of its being a religion.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19 Hell hath no fury like a Christian scorned</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
Hell hath no fury like a Christian scorned
17 January 1985 pm in Lao Tzu Grove
Question 1 OSHO,
TODAY, I OVERHEARD TWO BIBLE-BASHING A CHRISTIANS IN HEATED DEBATE WITH TWO SANNYASINS. I HEARD AND FELT FROM THE CHRISTIANS ANGER, NARROW-MINDEDNESS, AN ACUTE INABILITY TO LISTEN, AND AN UTTER LACK OF HUMOR. WHAT DID JESUS DO TO DESERVE SUCH FOLLOWERS?
IT is an absolute necessity to be retarded if you want to be a Christian.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 To define is to confine \-- existence has no boundaries</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
To define is to confine – existence has no boundaries
31 December 1984 pm in Lao Tzu Grove
Question 1 OSHO,
WHY DO I FEEL THAT IF LIFE IS MEANINGLESS AND EMPTY? IT SEEMS THAT I AM DEATHLY AFRAID OF BEING ALONE. HOW CAN I GO TOTALLY INTO MY ALONENESS WITH JOY INSTEAD OF FEAR?
THE word “meaning” is irrelevant to life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 Fear of hell, greed for heaven, the saviors soft sell</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
Fear of hell, greed for heaven, the saviors soft sell
18 January 1985 pm in Lao Tzu Grove
Question 1 OSHO,
IS IT WRONG TO TRY TO SAVE SOMEBODY? IS IT NOT PART OF COMPASSION?
COMPASSION is a very delicate affair. It certainly has some place in making an effort to save others, but there are many conditions which have to be fulfilled first.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 Priest and politicians: from genesis to genocide</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
Priest and politicians: from genesis to genocide
19 January 1985 pm in Lao Tzu Grove
Question 1 OSHO,
ALL THE OTHER MASTERS SEEM LIKE PYGMIES. WHAT IS YOUR SECRET?
THEY ARE pygmies. It is not a question that they seem like pygmies, they are in fact so – for the simple reason that religion is now having its birth.
The so-called masters of the past are just like primitive scientists who discovered fire, who created the spinning wheel, who invented the bullock cart.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22 Countdown to catastrophe: global suicide, or sannyas</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
Countdown to catastrophe: global suicide, or sannyas
20 January 1985 pm in Lao Tzu Grove
Question 1 OSHO,
WHY DO YOU THINK THAT NOW IS THE RIGHT TIME FOR THE AUTHENTIC RELIGION TO BE BORN?
I do not think. Thinking has fallen away a long time ago. Chronologically the distance is not much, only three decades, but metaphysically the distance is as big as possible.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23 Bored to death? \-- you\&#39;re on the trail to transformation</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
Bored to death? – you’re on the trail to transformation
21 January 1985 pm in Lao Tzu Grove
Question 1 OSHO,
WHAT IS BOREDOM? ARE YOU NEVER BORED WITH LIFE?
IT is one of the most significant questions to be asked, because it is only man’s privilege to be bored. No other animal has the capacity. Why has man the capacity to be bored?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 Infallibility: just a popedream</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 24
Infallibility: just a popedream
22 January 1985 pm in Lao Tzu Grove
Question 1 OSHO,
WHY ARE YOU AGAINST THE CHRISTIAN POPE? ISN’T THE POPE INFALLIBLE? WHY DO YOU CALL HIM, AGAIN AND AGAIN, “POPE THE POLACK”?
I am not against anyone in the whole world, for the simple reason that I have no vested interest in anything at all, not even in my own life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25 My day: the juice, the whole juice, and nothing but the juice</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 25
My day: the juice, the whole juice, and nothing but the juice
23 January 1985 pm in Lao Tzu Grove
Question 1 OSHO,
YOU GOT AS FAR AS BREAKFAST. TO COMPLETE OUR RELIGIOUS HISTORICAL RECORDS, COULD YOU TELL US WHAT GOES BEYOND THE JUICE?
THERE is nothing that goes beyond the juice.
The seers of the UPANISHADS have described the ultimate reality as the “juice” – raso vai saha.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26 Only one sin \-- to forget your being. Only one virtue \-- to remember it</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 26
Only one sin – to forget your being. Only one virtue – to remember it
24 January 1985 pm in Lao Tzu Grove
Question 1 OSHO,
COULD YOU SAY SOMETHING TO US ABOUT BLISS?
I have been blissed out myself for almost thirty-three years. That is exactly the time Jesus lived on earth. Shankara also lived only thirty-three years, Vivekananda too. For the length of the whole life of Jesus I have been blissed out.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27 Seek and ye shall miss; relax and ye shall find</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 27
Seek and ye shall miss; relax and ye shall find
25 January 1985 pm in Lao Tzu Grove
Question 1 OSHO,
IT SEEMS THAT YOU WERE GOING TO TALK ABOUT THE AMERICAN CONSTITUTION’S IDEA OF THE PURSUIT OF HAPPINESS AS A BIRTHRIGHT, BUT YOU FORGOT ABOUT IT. PLEASE CAN YOU TAKE IT UP AGAIN?
IT reminds me of a story. Three old men were sitting in a park.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28 Knowledge is information; knowing is transformation</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part28/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 28
Knowledge is information; knowing is transformation
26 January 1985 pm in Lao Tzu Grove
Question 1 OSHO,
YOU SAID THAT YOU DON’T KNOW WHO YOU ARE. DON’T YOU REALLY? DO WE NEVER KNOW WHO WE ARE?
I know that I do not know who I am.
My knowing is not knowledge and my knowing is not ignorance. It is a little bit complex, but not difficult to understand.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>29 Belief \-- just a blind man\&#39;s bluff</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part29/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 29
Belief – just a blind man’s bluff
27 January 1985 pm in Lao Tzu Grove
Question 1 OSHO,
IS THE THEORY OF REINCARNATION NOT TRUE?
I do not deal in theories. I am a simple man, not a theoretician.
A theoretician is a great thinker. He knows nothing about reality, but he goes on creating theories about it. His whole life he goes around and around.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Beware! I am here to destroy your dreams</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
Beware! I am here to destroy your dreams
1 January 1985 pm in Lao Tzu Grove
Question 1 OSHO,
I HAVE HEARD YOU SAY THAT ONLY CHRISTIANS DREAM OF JESUS, AND FOLLOWERS OF KRISHNA DREAM ONLY OF KRISHNA SANNYASINS ARE DREAMING OF YOU, OSHO. WILL YOU COMMENT?
DREAMING is a substitute for the real. It is a mind device to console you.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>30 The only authentic democracy: the dictatorship of the enlightened ones</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part30/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 30
The only authentic democracy: the dictatorship of the enlightened
ones
28 January 1985 pm in Lao Tzu Grove
Question 1 OSHO,
WHY ARE YOU AGAINST COMMUNISM?
I am against communism, but for a very strange reason. The strange reason is that it is not communism at all. The word communism is derived from “commune”; but communism is not commune-ism. It has no base in the idea of the commune – on the contrary, it is simply anti- capitalism.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Jealousy: society\&#39;s device to divide and rule</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
Jealousy: society’s device to divide and rule
2 January 1985 pm in Lao Tzu Grove
Question 1 OSHO,
WHAT IS JEALOUSY? DOES OUR JEALOUSY SHOW THAT WE ARE VERY FAR FROM ALONENESS?
SOCIETY has exploited the individual in so many ways that it is almost impossible to believe.
It has created devices so clever and cunning that it is almost impossible even to detect that they are devices.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Sannyas: the odyssey of aloneness \-- a journey to the center of your being</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
Sannyas: the odyssey of aloneness – a journey to the center of your
being
3 January 1985 pm in Lao Tzu Grove
Question 1 OSHO,
OUR COMMUNE IS NOT LIKE ANY OF THE TRADITIONAL ASHRAMS OR MONASTERIES. WOULD YOU TALK TO US MORE ABOUT THE FUNCTION OF YOUR COMMUNE?
IT is necessary first to understand the traditional structure of an ashrama, and also of a monastery.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Anxiety: Who are you? Anguish: Who am I?</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
Anxiety: Who are you? Anguish: Who am I?
4 January 1985 pm in Lao Tzu Grove
Question 1 OSHO,
WHAT IS ANGUISH? IS IT JUST ANOTHER NAME FOR ANXIETY?
ANGUISH has something of anxiety in it, but it is not just anxiety. It is much more, much more profound.
Anxiety means you are concerned with a particular subject, in a state of indecisiveness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Conditioning: socially-sanctioned child abuse</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
Conditioning: socially-sanctioned child abuse
5 January 1985 pm in Lao Tzu Grove
Question 1 OSHO,
IS J. KRISHNAMURTI ENLIGHTENED?
YES, he is enlightened, but something is missing in his enlightenment. It is like when you arrive after a long journey at an airport. You have arrived but then suddenly you find your luggage is missing. With J. Krishnamurti something more serious has happened: the luggage has arrived but he is missing!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 Rajneeshism: womb for transformation</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
Rajneeshism: womb for transformation
6 January 1985 pm in Lao Tzu Grove
Question 1 OSHO,
PLEASE DESCRIBE AN ORTHODOX RAJNEESHEE.
IT is a contradiction in terms, but I will not dispose of the question so easily. I will try to squeeze as much juice out of it as possible.
Yes, there is some way to define the orthodox Rajneeshee. It is going to be a strange definition because two terms which are contradictory to each other are used together.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 The law of karma: A conspiracy of the priests to manipulate your mind</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_personality_to_individuality/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
The law of karma: A conspiracy of the priests to manipulate your
mind
7 January 1985 pm in Lao Tzu Grove
Question 1 OSHO,
WHAT DO YOU HAVE TO SAY ABOUT THE LAW OF KARMA?
I have very little to say about it – but it will still take two and a half hours!
The law of karma, in the first place, is not a law.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
