<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Zero Experience on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_zero_experience/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Zero Experience on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/the_zero_experience/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_zero_experience/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_zero_experience/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
1 March 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, rupesh means god of the form – the full name will mean god of the form of love, god of love. And once you recognise something in you, it starts happening; that is the miracle.
If you think of yourself as being depressed, you remain depressed. If you think of yourself as being unhappy, you remain unhappy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_zero_experience/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_zero_experience/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
10 March 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says: For these last two years I was a musician... I play the piano.]
Very good. So my meditations will fit you; they will go very deep in you. If somebody has been interested in music he has already been in meditation unknowingly. Now the effort will become deliberate and conscious.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_zero_experience/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_zero_experience/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
11 March 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, neeten means morality – divine morality. And there is a morality that man can create but that is worthless; it is only an imposition from the outside. There is another kind of morality which man cannot create, which is beyond man, which comes from the above. Man can only be the receiver of it, not the creator: that is divine morality.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_zero_experience/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_zero_experience/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
12 March 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, preeti means love. And one has to be constantly alert, only then does love flower. Much awareness is needed, otherwise int he name of love many other things go on. So if one is very alert then only can pure love flower, otherwise the name remains love but sometimes it is jealousy, sometimes it is domination, sometimes it is just pure animality, just sexuality; these things continue.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_zero_experience/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_zero_experience/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
13 March 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, pratibodha means awareness . . . And become more and more aware of whatsoever you are doing. Just keep one thing in mind continuously: that you have to be aware. Eating, be aware of it; talking, be aware of it; listening, be aware of it. Let awareness become a substratum of each and every activity so each activity becomes just a wave on the deeper substratum of awareness, and that very thing changes the quality of all actions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_zero_experience/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_zero_experience/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
14 March 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, blissful, and shailendra means god of the mountains. God of the mountains of bliss; this will be the whole meaning. And bliss is a mountain because it is a peak, it is a peak experience. Ordinarily we live in the valleys... the valleys are dark and dismal: we live on the lowest rung of our consciousness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_zero_experience/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_zero_experience/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
15 March 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem Maitri means love, friendship, and friendship has a higher quality than love. The next step of love is friendship. Not that it is lower, as it is understood ordinarily; it is not.
In love there is passion, lust; love is more rooted in the physical. Friendship is purer, not rooted in the sexual at all.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_zero_experience/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_zero_experience/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
17 March 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Shunya means the ultimate experience of nothingness, of non-being, of no-self, and jiten means conqueror – conqueror of the no-self. It is very paradoxical but life is paradoxical, truth is paradoxical. If truth is not paradoxical you can be certain that it cannot be truth.
Life exists only through death; that is the paradox.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_zero_experience/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_zero_experience/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
18 March 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Satya means truth and mitra means a friend – a friend of truth. And that’s the most difficult thing to be because our so – called society, civilisation, culture all exist on lies. That’s why we go on missing god, because we are trained for lies, we have been conditioned to be liars, to never be true, to never be authentic.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_zero_experience/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_zero_experience/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
19 March 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Pari means ultimate, nirvana means enlightenment – the ultimate enlightenment. It is a buddhist term of tremendous significance. The ultimate enlightenment means the ultimate dissolution of the ego, the ultimate disappearance of the individual.
When you become a non-being, when you are not, then god is, because when you are not the whole is.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_zero_experience/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_zero_experience/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
20 March 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, nirvana means enlightenment – enlightenment through love. And that is going to be your way: love, devotion, feeling, through the heart. So don’t bother about the mind; by-pass it. Let it be there, it’s okay. It’s need is there in the world, but it has nothing to contribute in the other world.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_zero_experience/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_zero_experience/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
2 March 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means god, anuneeta means disciplined by – disciplined by the divine.
There are two types of discipline in life: one discipline that you can manage – but that is very ordinary discipline, man-made, home-made, and naturally cannot lead you very far. It is also repressive because you have to continuously fight and you have to repress many things in your being.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_zero_experience/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_zero_experience/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌22 March 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss and tapesh means radiance. There is a radiance of the body and there is a radiance of the spirit. The radiance of the body shows the youthfulness, the health of the body, and the radiance of the spirit shows the youth and health of the spirit.
Bliss belongs to the second. The body can only promise but it cannot deliver: all its promises are impotent.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_zero_experience/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_zero_experience/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌23 March 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin asks: How it is possible to perceive the egoless state if you’re using this brain which is full of memories and full of ego, full of preconceived ideas?]
You don’t perceive it as a presence, you perceive it as an absence. For example, this chair is here: you look at the chair, mm? Then the chair is gone.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_zero_experience/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_zero_experience/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
24 March 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says: I’ve been avoiding you for a year now.] That’s a good indication!...
That means that something is going to happen so the mind is afraid. The mind is never afraid without any real cause, so the people who avoid me are the people who are going to be transformed by me.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_zero_experience/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_zero_experience/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
25 March 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Ma Anand Kosha. Anand means bliss, kosha means body – body of bliss.
In the East we have discovered that man consists of five bodies. Five layers of bodies are there; we don’t have one body, we have five bodies. And the first, the most superficial body, is the physical body, and the last, the most subtle body, is the body of bliss.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_zero_experience/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_zero_experience/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 24
26 March 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine and prayaga means the meeting of the three. Just as in christianity there is a concept of trinity – that god is three and yet one, three aspects of one reality – in the same way in Hinduism there is a concept of the meeting of the three; that concept is called prayaga.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_zero_experience/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_zero_experience/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 25
27 March 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho gives a name for a new centre in america]
This will be the name: Mahaprasthana – it means the great departure. Prasthana means departure and mahaprasthana means the great departure. It is a one hundred and eighty degree turn; you are never the same again. Even if you want to be the same, you cannot be, because once your vision has absorbed some meditative energy, your world changes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_zero_experience/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_zero_experience/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 26
28 March 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love and arudha is the last stage of sannyas, the perfect renunciation, where one transcends all disciplines, where one goes beyond all rules, where one follows no code, where one lives absolutely spontaneously, where one lives moment to moment not thinking of the consequences at all. That is the last stage of sannyas, renunciation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>29</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_zero_experience/part29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_zero_experience/part29/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 29
31 March 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine and aranya means wildness – divine wildness, divine chaos. Chaos is the source of all, and the moment we become capable of entering chaos we become capable of entering god. God is wild: he is more like a forest than like a garden. The very disorder of it is its order, the very chaos of it is its cosmos.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_zero_experience/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_zero_experience/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
3 March 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Krishna Venu. It means krishna’s flute.
Krishna is the only person in the whole history of human consciousness who is tremendously in love with life, with the poetry of life, with the music of life, with the dance of life. He is not at all life-negative, he is very affirmative. And he accepts life as it is; he does not put god and the world as opposites.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_zero_experience/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_zero_experience/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
4 March 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss and bhaven means feeling. Feel it and you will have it. You are missing it only because you have not looked at it through feeling. And feeling is real life. Thinking is phoney because thinking is always about; it is never the real thing.
It is not thinking about the wine that can make you intoxicated, it is the wine.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_zero_experience/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_zero_experience/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
5 March 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva Rahi: It means a traveller to the divine, a pilgrim of the divine – deva means divine, rahi means a traveller. You are a traveller and you have been a traveller for a long time, many lives.
This is not the first time that you have become interested in it; you are an old one.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_zero_experience/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_zero_experience/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
6 March 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means blissful, sudheer means wisdom. And I make it a condition that wisdom is significant only when it is blissful, and blissfulness is meaningful only when it has wisdom in it. Both can exist separately but then they are not meaningful.
A person can be very happy and foolish – maybe happy because he is foolish, maybe happy because he cannot understand the complexity of life, because he is below understanding so he is not aware that misery is implied in life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_zero_experience/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_zero_experience/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
7 March 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Annapurna: It means the goddess of nourishment. India has many symbols and thousands of god. Each symbol ultimately has to become the symbol of god. So about the goddess of nourishment they have a very beautiful concept; they call her ‘annapurna’.
‘Anna’ means food, ‘purna’ means perfect. And the mother is annapurna, the woman is annapurna; she is the goddess of nourishment.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_zero_experience/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_zero_experience/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
8 March 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine and raga means melody – a divine melody. And each heart is carrying a melody in it just as each bud is carrying fragrance. Man’s heart is a bud and carries a melody in it. And unless this bud opens and flowers man is never happy, cannot be happy before it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_zero_experience/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_zero_experience/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
9 March 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho tells a sannyasin couple that through sexual freedom within the community here, people would naturally find the sexual need dropping and a spontaneous celibacy arising. The swami says: I feel more and more that in me the suffering that’s happening is getting smaller and smaller.]
It is... it is! The more aware you become, the more childish and stupid it looks.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
