<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>The 99 Names of Nothingness on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_99_names_of_nothingness/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The 99 Names of Nothingness on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/the_99_names_of_nothingness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_99_names_of_nothingness/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_99_names_of_nothingness/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
1 May 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Khabira. It is a sufi name, a name of God. Literally it means: one who sees all, the cognizant one, the seer of all. And that is hidden in everybody – the witness. What we see may be true, may not be true, but the seer is always true. The seen may be, may not be.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_99_names_of_nothingness/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_99_names_of_nothingness/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
14 May 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Mujib. Prem means love, Mujib is a sufi name for God. It means ‘one who hears the prayer, the hearer of prayers.’ No prayer is ever lost, and if it is, that simply means it has not been done; it never means anything else. Your heart was not in it, it was only lip service.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_99_names_of_nothingness/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_99_names_of_nothingness/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
15 May 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Hafiz is a sufi name for God. It means the one who preserves all – the preserver, the sustainer, the nourisher.]
It is not only that God created existence in the beginning. He continuously creates it, the creativity is a continuum. It has never stopped. In fact there was no beginning and there will be no end.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_99_names_of_nothingness/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_99_names_of_nothingness/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
16 May 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Prem means love, Allaha is a sufi name for God.]
Allaha is far more significant than the word ‘God.’ In fact no other word in any language of the world exists which is more important than this word. All other words used for God are at the most qualities of God. They are not as comprehensive as ‘Allaha.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_99_names_of_nothingness/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_99_names_of_nothingness/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
17 May 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin has to return to the west because her mother is dying of a life-long illness.]
So it is a good release for her, mm? She should not be prevented, she should be helped to leave the body. Because life in each and every case is not a blessing. It is a blessing only if one can use the opportunity to grow; then it is a blessing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_99_names_of_nothingness/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_99_names_of_nothingness/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
18 May 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love and trilochana means the third eye – the third eye of love. These two eyes look at the outside, and because they are two, they create a duality, they divide everything into two. There is a third eye – it is a metaphor – which looks inward, and because it is one it does not create any duality, any conflict.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_99_names_of_nothingness/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_99_names_of_nothingness/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
19 May 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, Sami is a sufi name for God – it means: the all-hearing one. Your full name will mean: a loving capacity to hear all. And if one can really hear, nothing else is needed. If one can hear the wind passing through the trees, that is gospel. If one can hear the birds singing in the morning, one has heard prayer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_99_names_of_nothingness/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_99_names_of_nothingness/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
20 May 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem Hasibo. Prem means love and Hasibo is a sufi name for God. It means: one who satisfies all needs. The full name will mean: love, the god that satisfies all needs.
And love is the ultimate need. Everything else is secondary. Everything else is just a means to that great end. If love happens then all has happened; if love does not happen then nothing has happened, the whole of life has just been a wasteland.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_99_names_of_nothingness/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_99_names_of_nothingness/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
21 May 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine; Matina is a sufi name for God. It means ‘firmness, rootedness.’ The full name will mean: divine firmness, divine rootedness. And that is what is needed. Man has become uprooted, he is living without roots; that’s his problem. He has lost all roots. He does not know from where he comes, why he exists, where he is going.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_99_names_of_nothingness/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_99_names_of_nothingness/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
22 May 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Wasi – a sufi name of god]
It literally means: the all-comprehending one, the all-knowing one, one who understands all. Deva Wasi will mean: divine knowing, divine comprehension.
There is a human way to know; that is intellectual – it is like groping in darkness. There is a divine way to know; that is intuitive – it is not groping in the dark.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_99_names_of_nothingness/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_99_names_of_nothingness/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
23 May 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, and Hakima is a sufi name for God. It means: all-mighty, all-powerful, omnipotent. Deva Hakima will mean ‘divine power.’ Man in himself is powerless; all power is from God. Man is just a vehicle, a passage. The moment man starts thinking ‘This is my power’, he starts falling into sin. The ego is the original sin and it is the ego that separates you from reality.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_99_names_of_nothingness/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_99_names_of_nothingness/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
2 May 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Hasiba. It means: one who satisfies. Without God there is no satisfaction possible. One can go on searching and one will find many things in life but nothing is going to satisfy. Just a moment’s illusion that one feels satisfaction, one has not even felt it and it is gone. Just a dewdrop slipping on the grass leaf: you have not even seen it correctly and it has disappeared, fallen.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_99_names_of_nothingness/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_99_names_of_nothingness/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
24 May 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho gives sannyas to a six-year-old.]
Prem means love, Wahid is a sufi name for God – it means: the one – love for the one.
Right now it may not be possible for you to understand, but let it become a seed in your heart; one day you will understand. There are two kinds of love: love for the many – and that’s where everybody lives and suffers – and there is another kind of love: love for the one; that’s where bliss happens.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_99_names_of_nothingness/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_99_names_of_nothingness/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
25 May 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A visitor says she doesn’t want to take sannyas because to wear orange and mala will be difficult at home. Then asks about her boyfriend, who is more spiritual and ascetic than her, which causes difficulties.]
A relationship can never be without difficulties and if there is love, then there are more difficulties. This may look strange but it is one of the most fundamental facts of life to be understood: if there is no love, a relationship can move very smoothly Hence many societies in the past have decided for marriage without love.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_99_names_of_nothingness/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_99_names_of_nothingness/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
26 May 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Shunya Wahido. Shunya means nothingness and Wahido is a sufi name for God – it means: the one. The one is achieved through being nothing. Unless we disappear, God cannot appear: the death of the ego is the birth of God. One has to efface oneself completely. Even if a little bit of the ego is left, that is enough – enough to remain a barrier between you and God.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_99_names_of_nothingness/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_99_names_of_nothingness/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
27 May 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin and child are returning to the west. Osho asks if things have settled. The man says not totally.]
They never settle totally!
And one should not think of total settlement. that will mean stagnancy. A little bit of conflict keeps the flow moving on. Too much conflict destroys the relationship – too much adjustment also.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_99_names_of_nothingness/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_99_names_of_nothingness/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 24
28 May 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, Awwala is a sufi name for God. It means: the first, the alpha. Sufism has both names for God: one is ‘the first’ and the other is ‘the last’. God is the first and also the last, the source and the goal, the root and the flower. God is all – the beginning and the end.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_99_names_of_nothingness/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_99_names_of_nothingness/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 25
29 May 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin, leaving, says: It’s been very good being here. I’ll be back.]
Mm mm, you have to be back! Being here has done something, but much more has still to be done. Never be satisfied by the little that happens, because great is our destiny. And always remember that – less than God will not suffice.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_99_names_of_nothingness/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_99_names_of_nothingness/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 26
30 May 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, Khabiro is a sufi name for God. It means: one who sees, the cognizant one, the seeing one. The full name will mean: the divine vision, a divine way of seeing things. And it all depends on how you look at the world. It is your seeing that determines the world.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_99_names_of_nothingness/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_99_names_of_nothingness/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 27
31 May 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine; the word ‘divine’ comes from the same root as ‘deva.’ Basir is a sufi name for God – it means: all seeing. Your full name will mean: a divine way of seeing. Ordinarily what we see may not be there. It may be just our minds projecting something from the within. We see what we believe; our belief creates our vision.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_99_names_of_nothingness/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_99_names_of_nothingness/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
7 May 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Halima is a sufi name, a name of God. It means: one who forgives, forebears all. Even if you go against Him, He is not against you. Even if you deny Him, He will not deny you. Even if you go astray, He knows you will come back. His trust in you is absolute.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_99_names_of_nothingness/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_99_names_of_nothingness/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
8 May 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Basiro. It is a sufi name for God. It means ‘all-seeing.’ There is no way to hide from God but man goes on trying. Not that he succeeds, he cannot succeed in the very nature of things. But in the effort he wastes his life and becomes alienated from God, starts believing he has deceived God.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_99_names_of_nothingness/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_99_names_of_nothingness/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
9 May 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Shahido. It is a sufi name for God and means: one who witnesses all, the great witness]
Nothing is hidden from God because God is the inside of everything. And the inside knows all. You can hide something from others but you cannot hide it from yourself, and it is there that God is hiding.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_99_names_of_nothingness/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_99_names_of_nothingness/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
10 May 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Wajid. Wajid is a sufi name for God. It means: one who has no needs, one who is fulfilled, contented. Fulfilment is another name for God. Unless one becomes God one remains unfulfilled. Dissolving into God is disappearing from the world of needs. Then one simply is and all is good. Then whatsoever happens is blissful: life is blissful, death too.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_99_names_of_nothingness/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_99_names_of_nothingness/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
11 May 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Alima. It is a sufi name for God. It means: one who knows. Only God knows and unless we become one with God there is no knowing. All else that we think is knowledge is just trivia, rubbish – at the most information, but not knowledge. And the difference is great: to know means to know from the inside; information means to collect something from the outside.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_99_names_of_nothingness/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_99_names_of_nothingness/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
12 May 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Wahid – all is one.]
Multiplicity is false, it is only an appearance. Oneness is the truth of reality. We differ only superficially; deep down we are all one. On the circumference many, at the centre one.
So if you look at the circumference it is a chaos: everything seems to be accidental, unrelated to everything else.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_99_names_of_nothingness/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_99_names_of_nothingness/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
13 May 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A new sannyasin says since he read Osho’s book, he has found a new relationship to Christ... and it’s wonderful, full of life.]
That’s true. That’s good christians have destroyed all bridges towards Christ. Christ needs a new interpretation, a new approach, a new breakthrough. Christ needs people now who are not christians; only they can relate with him.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
