<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Perfect Way on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_perfect_way/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Perfect Way on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/the_perfect_way/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 The Welcome</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_perfect_way/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_perfect_way/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
The Welcome
3 June 1964 pm
I see man engulfed in deep darkness. He has become like a house whose lamp has been snuffed out on a dark night. Something in him has been extinguished. But a lamp that has been extinguished can be relit.
I see as well that man has lost all direction. He has become like a boat that has lost its way on the high seas.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 The Farewell</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_perfect_way/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_perfect_way/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 10
The Farewell
8 June 1964 am
One and only one moment of determination, of sankalpa, of complete determination is enough, whereas a whole life without it is nothing. Remember it is not time but determination that is the important thing. The achievements of the world are accomplished in the realm of time and those of truth in the realm of determination. Sankalpa, determination, must live in your sadhana.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 The First Morning</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_perfect_way/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_perfect_way/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
The First Morning
4 June 1964 am
It is a delight to see you. In this solitary place you have come together to realize God, to find the truth, to know your own selves. But may I ask you a question? Is what you are seeking separate from you¿ You can search for someone who is away but how can you seek that which is your own self¿ Your own self cannot be sought in the sense in which everything else is sought because in this case there is no difference between the one who is seeking and the one who is being sought.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 The First Evening</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_perfect_way/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_perfect_way/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
The First Evening
4 June 1964 pm
Question 1
THE FIRST QUESTION: IS THERE A CONFLICT BETWEEN RELIGION AND SCIENCE?
No. The knowledge of science is incomplete. It is as if there were light all over the world while in your own house there was darkness. With such imperfect knowledge, without the knowledge of one’s self, life simply turns into misery. For life to be crowned with peace, contentment and fulfillment, it is not enough to know material things alone.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 The Second Morning</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_perfect_way/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_perfect_way/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
The Second Morning
5 June 1964 am
My friends, we must not fight with ourselves, we must know ourselves. All of the inconsistencies and self-contradictions that have developed in us because of our ignorance about the self will evaporate in the light of self-knowledge – just like the dew that falls on the grass disappears with the rising of the sun.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 The Second Evening</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_perfect_way/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_perfect_way/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
The Second Evening
5 June 1964 pm
Question 1
THE FIRST QUESTION: DO YOU THINK IT IS A BAD THING TO BE MORAL?
No. I do not consider it bad to be moral but I do consider the illusion of being moral bad. It gets in the way of real morality.
False morality is an outer coating, a covering. It serves no purpose other than satisfying hypocrisy and in my view there is no greater immoral state of mind than that of hypocrisy and egoism.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 The Third Morning</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_perfect_way/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_perfect_way/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
The Third Morning
6 June 1964 am
I am unable to give you the truth. If anyone says he is capable of giving it to you, you can be certain he has begun by giving you an untruth. No one has the capacity to give the truth. This is no comment on the capacity of the giver, it only shows that truth is a living thing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 The third Evening</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_perfect_way/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_perfect_way/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
The third Evening
6 June 1964 pm
Question 1
THE FIRST QUESTION: ACCORDING TO YOU, NOBODY IS ABLE TO IMPART THE TRUTH. IS WHAT YOU SAY NOT TRUE THEN?
What I am telling you is only an indication and should not be regarded as true in itself. Truth is far removed from indication. It is not the indicator you have to see, but where it directs you.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 The Fourth Morning</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_perfect_way/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_perfect_way/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
The Fourth Morning
7 June 1964 am
I am indeed very happy to see all of you! I can feel the depth of your desire, of your thirst to know the truth. I see it in your eyes and feel it in every breath you take. And as your hearts throb for the attainment of truth my heart throbs as well! I am deeply touched by your thirst for knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 The Final Evening</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_perfect_way/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_perfect_way/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
The Final Evening
7 June 1964 pm
[THE FIRST QUESTION IS MISSING]
The truth cannot be known before you actually realize it. And knowing something about truth is quite different from knowing truth. Whatever you know about truth, it is bound to be untrue. It is untrue because in the absence of personal experience it simply cannot be understood. It is untrue, not from the point of view of the speaker, but from that of the listener.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
