<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>The White Lotus on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_white_lotus/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The White Lotus on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/the_white_lotus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 Lotus rain</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_white_lotus/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_white_lotus/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
Lotus rain
31 October 1979 am in Buddha Hall
BELOVED OSHO,
QUESTION: WHAT IS BUDDHA-MIND?
ANSWER: YOUR MIND IS IT. WHEN YOU SEE THE SELFSAME ESSENCE OF IT, YOU CAN CALL IT SUCHNESS. WHEN YOU SEE THE CHANGELESS NATURE OF IT, YOU CAN CALL IT DHARMAKAYA. IT DOES NOT BELONG TO ANYTHING; THEREFORE, IT IS CALLED EMANCIPATION. IT WORKS EASILY AND FREELY, NEVER BEING DISTURBED BY OTHERS; THEREFORE, IT IS CALLED THE TRUE PATH.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 A Love Affair With the Universe</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_white_lotus/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_white_lotus/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
A Love Affair With the Universe
9 November 1979 am in Buddha Hall
The first question:
Question 1
OSHO, THERE IS A GREAT DEAL OF HYPOCRISY IN INDIA ABOUT SEX. PEOPLE ARE NOT EVEN WILLING TO DISCUSS IT OPENLY, YET THERE IS A GROWING PROLIFERATION OF, AND OBSESSION WITH, NUDE PICTURES. WILL THIS FLOOD OF PORNOGRAPHY HELP? CAN IT FINALLY BRING SEX OUT INTO THE OPEN IN INDIA?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 Truly Right</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_white_lotus/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_white_lotus/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 11
Truly Right
10 November 1979 am in Buddha Hall
QUESTION: WHAT IS RIGHT AND WHAT IS WRONG?
ANSWER: DISCRIMINATION WITH NO-MIND IS RIGHT. DISCRIMINATION WITH MIND IS WRONG. WHEN ONE TRANSCENDS RIGHT AND WRONG, HE IS TRULY RIGHT. IN A SUTRA IT SAYS, ‘WHEN ONE DWELLS ON THE RIGHT ROAD, HE DOES NOT DISCRIMINATE “THIS IS RIGHT, THIS IS WRONG”.’
QUESTION: WHAT IS A SAGACIOUS STUDENT, AND WHAT IS A DULL STUDENT?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Because I Love You</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_white_lotus/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_white_lotus/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
Because I Love You
1 November 1979 am in Buddha Hall
The first question:
BELOVED OSHO,
Question 1
SOMETIMES I WANT TO SCREAM, “STOP, OSHO! NOT SO FAST! I’M NOT UP TO IT!”
I HAVEN’T BEEN HERE FOR TEN DAYS BEFORE I AM HAVING TO CONFRONT MY ATTACHMENTS, MY POSSESSIVENESS, MY JEALOUSY, MY FEAR OF DYING AND DISTRUST, IN ADDITION TO DIARRHEA.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Just Dreaming</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_white_lotus/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_white_lotus/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
Just Dreaming
2 November 1979 am in Buddha Hall
QUESTION: WHAT IS MEDITATION IN EMPTINESS?
ANSWER: ONE OBSERVES THINGS IN THE PHENOMENAL WORLD, YET ALWAYS DWELLS IN EMPTINESS. THAT IS MEDITATION IN EMPTINESS.
QUESTION: HOW CAN ONE DWELL IN DHARMA?
ANSWER: ONE SHOULD STAY NEITHER IN IN-DWELLING DHARMA NOR IN NON-DWELLING DHARMA. HE SHOULD LIVE NATURALLY IN DHARMA. THIS IS WHAT YOU CALL DWELLING IN DHARMA.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 The Highest Flight</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_white_lotus/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_white_lotus/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
The Highest Flight
3 November 1979 am in Buddha Hall
The first question:
BELOVED OSHO,
Question 1
WHAT IS A POET? WHAT IS POETRY?
Devaprem, there are three ways of looking at existence: seeing it, feeling it, being it. The first is science, the second is art, the third is religion.
Science looks at the universe in an objective way. It looks at the universe as if it is there, outside.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 The Eye of Zen</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_white_lotus/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_white_lotus/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
The Eye of Zen
4 November 1979 am in Buddha Hall
QUESTION: I HAVE HEARD THAT ALL BUDDHAS IN THE PAST, PRESENT AND FUTURE PREACHED THE SAME DHARMA AND COUNTLESS BEINGS WERE SAVED FROM SUFFERING. IS THIS NOT TRUE?
ANSWER: YOU HAVE HEARD SOMEONE SPEAK OF DREAMS, AND YOU YOURSELF ARE ACTUALLY DREAMING. WHATEVER YOU FIGURE WITH YOUR DUALISTIC MIND NEVER MAKES A TRUE ACCOUNT OF MIND ESSENCE, THEREFORE, I CALL YOU A DREAMER.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 No-Mind Innocence</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_white_lotus/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_white_lotus/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
No-Mind Innocence
5 November 1979 am in Buddha Hall
The first question:
BELOVED OSHO,
Question 1
WHAT IS INNOCENCE? DOES BEING INNOCENT REQUIRE ONE TO LIVE A SIMPLE LIFE?
Anand Manohara, innocence is a state of thoughtless awareness. It is another name for no-mind. It is the very essence of buddhahood. You become attuned to the ultimate law of things. You stop fighting, you start flowing with it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Lion Buddha</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_white_lotus/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_white_lotus/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
Lion Buddha
6 November 1979 am in Buddha Hall
QUESTION: WHAT DO YOU CALL THE MIND OF GREEDINESS? ANSWER: IT IS THE MIND OF IGNORANCE.
QUESTION: WHAT DO YOU CALL THE MIND OF EGOLESSNESS? ANSWER: IT IS THE MIND OF SHRAVAKA, BUDDHA’S ACTUAL DISCIPLE. QUESTION: WHAT DO YOU CALL THE MIND OF NO-ENTITY?
ANSWER: IT IS THE MIND OF THE SAGES WHO HAVE NO CONNECTION WITH THE TEACHING OF BUDDHA, BUT DISCOVER THE TRUTH OF NO-ENTITY BY THEMSELVES.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 Utterly Luminous</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_white_lotus/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_white_lotus/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
Utterly Luminous
7 November 1979 am in Buddha Hall
The first question:
BELOVED OSHO,
Question 1
I GIVE UP. I’M REACHING NOWHERE. I CAME HERE FULL OF HOPE AND JOY, BUT I NOW REALIZE THAT IT’S ALL MEANINGLESS. BEFORE, YOU TOUCHED ME TO TEARS, BUT THEY WERE TEARS OF ECSTASY, RELIEF, THE ONES THAT FLOW WHEN ONE LISTENS TO BEAUTIFUL MUSIC. NOW, EVEN MY LOVE FOR YOU HURTS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 Only In Silence</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_white_lotus/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_white_lotus/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
Only In Silence
8 November 1979 am in Buddha Hall
QUESTION: ARE THERE FAST AND SLOW WAYS OF ATTAINMENT?
ANSWER: IF ONE SEES THAT ENDLESS TIME IS THE MIND, HE WILL ATTAIN QUICKLY, BUT IF HE MAKES A POINT IN HIS MIND AND AIMS AT HIS DESTINATION, HE WILL ATTAIN SLOWLY. THE WISE ONE KNOWS HIS MIND IS THE PATH; THE STUPID ONE MAKES A PATH BEYOND HIS MIND.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
