<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>From Death to Deathlessness on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/</link>
    <description>Recent content in From Death to Deathlessness on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 The man of compassion has to lie</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
The man of compassion has to lie
2 August 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
YOU SAID THAT YOU LIE OUT OF COMPASSION, AND WE, YOUR SANNYASINS, CAN UNDERSTAND WHAT YOU ARE SAYING. BUT CAN THE OUTSIDE WORLD EVER UNDERSTAND? WON’T IT CREATE MORE MISUNDERSTANDING ABOUT YOU, ABOUT RAJNEESHISM, ABOUT YOUR SANNYASINS? PLEASE COMMENT.
Compassion knows no conditions. It can do anything, it knows no right and no wrong.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Become more and more sensuous</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
Become more and more sensuous
11 August 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHEN I LOOK AROUND YOUR COMMUNE AND SEE PEOPLE HUGGING THE WAY THEY DO, AND FEEL THE ENERGY I HAVE WHEN I HUG SOMEONE HERE, I WONDER WHY THIS DOESN’T HAPPEN IN THE OUTSIDE WORLD. PLEASE COMMENT.
It cannot happen in the outside world, because for centuries man has been conditioned against the body.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 I am not your father</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
I am not your father
12 August 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I’M A HYPOCRITE, AND A ROUGH MAN, AND I AM HAPPY TO HAVE A SOFT MASTER. IN MY UNCONSCIOUS I HAVE REPLACED MY FATHER BY YOU, AND I HAVE REPLACED MY FAMILY BY THE COMMUNE. I HAVE CREATED HATRED, RAGE, RESENTMENT TOWARDS YOU AND THE COMMUNE. YET I AM ENJOYING YOUR DISCOURSES VERY MUCH.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 The song of the tide</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
The song of the tide
13 August 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
YOUR CONTRADICTIONS, YOUR LIES, AND YOUR INSISTENCE THAT WE ARE NOT TO BELIEVE YOU, HAVE MADE MY MIND INOPERABLE. ALL IT CAN SAY WITH CERTAINTY IS, “I DON’T KNOW.” I USED TO BE QUITE PROUD OF MY MIND, BUT NOW IT SIMPLY FEELS STUPID. SO FAR, IT’S NOT NO-MIND, BUT PERHAPS SOMEDAY SOON, ITS DYING GASP MAY BE, “I DON’T KNOW.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 Put Mother Theresa in jail</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
Put Mother Theresa in jail
14 August 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
BUDDHA’S RELIGION SPREAD ALL OVER ASIA EXCEPT INDIA, AND STILL BUDDHA’S WAY OF LIFE HAS BEEN ACCEPTED BY INDIA – TO BECOME MORE AND MORE POOR. IS THERE ANY WAY THAT INDIA CAN ACCEPT YOUR LIFE-AFFIRMATIVE ATTITUDE AND BECOME RICH, EVEN WITHOUT ACCEPTING YOUR RELIGIOUSNESS WHICH IS SPREADING ALL OVER THE WORLD?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 Get out of this sheepskin</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
Get out of this sheepskin
15 August 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHY ARE THERE SO FEW AMERICAN SANNYASINS? I RECALL YOU SAYING THAT AMERICA WOULD BE A VERY SPIRITUAL COUNTRY BECAUSE THEY HAD ALREADY MASTERED MATERIAL ABUNDANCE AND FOUND IT DID NOT SATISFY. WHY ARE THEY SO SLEEPY? PLEASE COMMENT.
America has no roots. It is just a three-hundred-year-old country; it is passing through its childhood.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 We are the only alternative</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
We are the only alternative
16 August 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
DURING YOUR RECENT INTERVIEW WITH DER SPIEGEL, YOU MADE A STATEMENT ABOUT HITLER, SAYING YOU LOVE THE MAN BECAUSE HE’S CRAZY, AND ALSO THAT HE LIVED A LIFE OF A DISCIPLINE JUST AS A SAINT LIVES IN A MONASTERY. YOU ALSO COMPARED HIM WITH MAHATMA GANDHI AND CALLED HIM AS MORAL AS MAHATMA GANDHI.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 This moment: The golden key</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
This moment: The golden key
21 August 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
THE PRESIDENT OF INDIA SAID IN A SPEECH RECENTLY, “THERE IS SO MUCH EVIL AROUND HERE, AND RAJNEESH WENT TO AMERICA. WHY?” I FIND IT DISAPPOINTING THAT THE PRESIDENT OF INDIA SHOULD MISS YOUR PRESENCE IN THAT COUNTRY NOW, BUT WOULD NOT LISTEN TO YOUR ADVICE WHEN YOU WERE SHARING YOUR VISION FOR THIRTY YEARS BEFORE COMING TO AMERICA.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 Becoming is going away from being</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
Becoming is going away from being
22 August 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHEN I SEE YOU MY HEART EXPLODES, WHEN YOU DANCE I FEEL SO JOYOUS, WHEN YOU SPEAK I ENJOY IT IMMENSELY. SO OFTEN THESE DAYS, WITH ALL THE BLESSINGS YOU SHOWER UPON US, I FEEL SO OVERCOME. WHO NEEDS TO BE ENLIGHTENED, WITH SUCH AN EXQUISITE, OUTRAGEOUS MASTER LIKE YOU AROUND?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 Man\&#39;s monkey mind</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
Man’s monkey mind
23 August 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHY DON’T YOU ADDRESS YOUR AUDIENCE?
There is a certain basic foundation for it: there is no audience to be addressed. As far as I am concerned, we are not separate. To you, I am separate from you; hence the question. But to me, you are just part of a vast continent of consciousness – in the same way that I am part of it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19 Belief is a dirty word</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
Belief is a dirty word
24 August 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHAT EFFECT ON SCIENCE WOULD BE FELT IF PEOPLE STOPPED BELIEVING IN THE OLD RELIGIONS?
The fact of believing is the greatest barrier in the progress of science. In three hundred years science has done much in spite of all the religions, their superstitions, their beliefs. In these three hundred years, there would have been at least a hundred times more progress if religions had not come in the way at each step.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Abandon hope all those who enter here</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
Abandon hope all those who enter here
3 August 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
YOU HAVE OFTEN USED THE WORD “EXISTENTIALISM,” AND YOU HAVE REFERRED TO YOURSELF AS AN EXISTENTIALIST. PLEASE DEFINE THESE WORDS.
There has been a contemporary school of philosophy in Europe called existentialism. I have nothing to do with it. That is only a philosophy, a mind game.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 There is a bigger universe within you</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
There is a bigger universe within you
25 August 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
THE SCIENTIFIC VISION OF OBJECTIVE REALITY AND THE SUBJECTIVE EXPERIENCE OF EXISTENCE SEEM TO BE TWO COMPLETELY SEPARATE AND UNBRIDGEABLE DIMENSIONS. IS THIS BECAUSE OF THE NATURE OF THINGS, OR IS IT ONLY AN ILLUSION OF OUR MIND?
The scientific approach to existence and the religious approach have been in the past separate and unbridgeable.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 Science has to be religious</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
Science has to be religious
26 August 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
CAN SCIENCE ITSELF BE RELIGIOUS?
It has been one of the greatest misfortunes that science is not religious. It can be religious and it should be religious.
Science is only a method. It has no direction, no values; it is just a method. It can be used for destruction, it can be used for creativity, because in itself it is only a neutral methodology.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22 Tomorrow is in the womb of today</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
Tomorrow is in the womb of today
27 August 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WILLIAM JAMES SAYS, “THE MOST IMPORTANT THING IN LIFE IS TO LIVE YOUR LIFE FOR SOMETHING MORE IMPORTANT THAN YOUR LIFE.” CAN YOU COMMENT?
What William James is saying has been said for thousands of years, by almost all the politicians, all the priests – and you can see the result of such a teaching.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23 You are born as freedom</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
You are born as freedom
28 August 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
PLEASE EXPLAIN WHAT YOU MEAN BY FREEDOM. WHEN I TALK ABOUT FREEDOM, I MEAN FREEDOM FROM SOMETHING OR FREEDOM TO DO SOMETHING; IT IMPLIES MORE FREEDOM OF CHOICE. BUT MY IMPRESSION IS THAT CHOICELESS AWARENESS PRECEDES THE FREEDOM You TALK ABOUT. WHAT KIND OF FREEDOM DOES NOT INVOLVE CHOICE?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 Blessed are those who doubt</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 24
Blessed are those who doubt
29 August 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
CAN YOU SAY SOMETHING ABOUT DOUBT AND NEGATIVITY? WHAT IS THE DIFFERENCE?
The difference between doubt and negativity is great.
They look alike; on the surface they have the same color, but deep down the difference is unbridgeable.
First, doubt is not negativity; neither is it positivity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25 Cut the roots of guilt</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 25
Cut the roots of guilt
30 August 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I’VE OFTEN HEARD YOU SPEAK WITH LOVE AND ADMIRATION OF ZORBA. YET NIKOS KAZANTZAKIS, THE MAN WHO CREATED HIM, LED A TORTURED LIFE – GUILT-RIDDEN, OBSESSED WITH RELIGION, FEARFUL OF WOMEN, PREOCCUPIED WITH DEATH. ARE ZORBA AND KAZANTZAKIS THE TWO SIDES OF ALL OF US WHO ARE UNENLIGHTENED?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26 Your aloneness cannot be destroyed</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 26
Your aloneness cannot be destroyed
31 August 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
AIDS CONFRONTS US WITH THE IMMEDIACY OF OUR DEATH. OUR SERIOUSNESS SEEMS TO CREATE MORE DISEASE AND PARANOIA. INSTEAD OF FEELING LIKE VICTIMS, HOW CAN WE RESPOND THROUGH CELEBRATION?
Death is always there. You may be unaware of it, but it is always confronting you with immediacy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27 Anonymous graves</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 27
Anonymous graves
1 September 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I WANT TO CONCENTRATE MY EFFORTS. BE SINCERE WITH ME. IS TO BE A WITNESS OF MYSELF THE ONLY THING, OR IS THERE SOMETHING ELSE?
I am not interested in intellectual questions. First, be a witness to yourself, then ask.
You want me to be sincere with you; please just be sincere with yourself.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28 Education is amoral</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part28/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 28
Education is amoral
2 September 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
RECENTLY, IN A RADIO ADDRESS, PRESIDENT REAGAN URGED PARENTS TO GET INVOLVED IN THEIR CHILDREN’S EDUCATION BY INSISTING SCHOOLS TEACH ETHICS, MORALITY AND VALUES ALONG WITH THE THREE R’S. HE SAID, “TO ME, A VALUE- FREE EDUCATION IS A CONTRADICTION IN TERMS.” ADDRESSING STUDENTS, REAGAN SAID, “YOU ARE NOT ONLY STUDYING FOR YOURSELF, BUT FOR YOUR FAMILY, YOUR COMMUNITY, YOUR COUNTRY, AND YOUR GOD.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>29 Judgement Day - a very stupid idea</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part29/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 29
Judgement Day - a very stupid idea
3 September 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
THE SCIENTISTS WENT INTO SPACE AND REACHED DIFFERENT PLANETS, BUT THEY ARE NOT YET ABLE TO LOCATE HEAVEN AND HELL. COULD YOU TELL ME, WHERE IS HEAVEN AND WHERE IS HELL?
They will never locate heaven and hell anywhere. They are fictions, lies told to humanity to keep it enslaved, to console it in its suffering and torture, to prevent it from any revolution that could change the whole scene on the earth.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Belief is a barrier, trust is a bridge</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
Belief is a barrier, trust is a bridge
4 August 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I TRUST YOU UNCONDITIONALLY. AT THE SAME TIME, I DON’T BELIEVE YOU. CAN YOU SPEAK ABOUT TRUST AND BELIEF?
Baby, that is really great! Just groovy. I don’t believe in my own statements either! We are in perfect agreement. I trust myself, I trust you, because I trust love.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>30 A sunrise that never sets</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part30/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 30
A sunrise that never sets
4 September 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I ASK YOU A QUESTION BECAUSE I WANT YOUR ATTENTION. AND THE ONLY QUESTION THAT OCCURS TO ME IN THE TWO YEARS I HAVE BEEN HERE IS ABOUT THE DARK NIGHT OF THE SOUL. YOU SAID SOMETIMES THAT WE HAVE TO DANCE AND CELEBRATE SO THAT WE CAN GO THROUGH IT EASILY.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>31 The art of being human</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part31/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 31
The art of being human
5 September 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
ALL OVER THE WORLD PEOPLE ARE BEING TORTURED. AT THE PRESENT TIME – ESPECIALLY IN THIRD WORLD COUNTRIES – REPORTS ARE SURFACING EVERY DAY OF UNBELIEVABLE ATROCITIES COMMITTED BY MAN AGAINST MAN. FROM WHERE DOES THIS DESIRE TO TORTURE OTHERS ARISE? DO SUCH PERVERTED ACTS STEM FROM A DEEP SENSE OF FRUSTRATION AND THE NEED TO TAKE REVENGE AGAINST SOCIETY?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>32 Silence is the highest music</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part32/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part32/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 32
Silence is the highest music
6 September 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
YOU SAY THAT THERE IS ONLY ONE SIN, AND THAT IS UNAWARENESS. I TRIED FOR YEARS TO LOOK FOR THE GOOD IN EVERY SITUATION, HOWEVER PAINFUL IT SEEMED, BUT I STILL HAVE NOT COME TO UNDERSTAND HOW THERE IS NO WRONG. TO ME, THINGS LIKE THE ABUSE OF A CHILD – EITHER PHYSICALLY OR PSYCHOLOGICALLY – AND THE RAPE OF A WOMAN ARE WRONG.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>33 This nonsense of nations</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part33/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part33/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 33
This nonsense of nations
7 September 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
YOU HAVE ALWAYS BEEN AN INSPIRATION TO ME. YOU GIVE ME THE COURAGE TO CONTINUE TO DO MY THING AND NOT COMPROMISE IN MY WORK, EVEN THOUGH I FEEL LIKE AN OUTCAST ALMOST EVERYWHERE I GO. I NEED YOU TO SAY IT IS OKAY FOR ME TO KEEP ON BEING A MISFIT.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>34 The power of nothingness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part34/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part34/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 34
The power of nothingness
8 September 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
AT THE GATES OF UNIVERSITIES IN INDIA, IT IS WRITTEN, “EDUCATION IS THAT WHICH LIBERATES.” TODAY IN INDIA EVERYONE AGREES THAT THE EDUCATION SYSTEM IS A MESS, BUT NO ONE TRIES TO CHANGE IT. WHAT ARE THE DEFECTS OF THE EDUCATION SYSTEM IN INDIA? WHAT KIND OF EDUCATION CAN BE HELPFUL FOR THE INNER AND OUTER GROWTH OF THE INDIVIDUAL SO THAT THE NEW MAN AND THE NEW SOCIETY CAN BE BORN?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>35 Too much doing</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part35/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part35/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 35
Too much doing
9 September 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHAT ARE THE DEFECTS OF THE PRESENT POLITICAL SYSTEM IN INDIA, AND WHAT IS THE REMEDY?
WHAT TYPE OF POLITICAL SYSTEM WOULD BE SUITABLE?
India is in a political mess. The reason lies in its past history.
Before the British government, India was never one country. It was divided into hundreds of small kingdoms.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>36 Rise in Love</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part36/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part36/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 36
Rise in Love
10 September 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
TO FALL IN LOVE IS SO EASY. WHY IS IT SO DIFFICULT TO FALL OUT OF LOVE? SO MANY DISCUSSIONS, TEARS, FIGHTS, FEARSI DON’T WANT TO HURT THE PERSON I’VE BEEN
WITH, BECAUSE IT’S NOT THAT THERE IS NO FEELING. I’M SO CONFUSED. AND THE LOVE FOR YOU IS A DIFFERENT FEELING ALTOGETHER.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>37 The eternal light at your center</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part37/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part37/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 37
The eternal light at your center
11 September 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I AM A RESEARCH SCIENTIST. FOR ELEVEN YEARS I HAVE BEEN INVOLVED IN A MEDICAL RESEARCH PROGRAM TO DEVELOP ARTIFICIAL ORGANS, INCLUDING HEARTS, SKIN, AND BLOOD. I ENJOY MY WORK, BUT I DO NOT HAVE A RIGHT SENSE ABOUT WHAT I AM DOING, AS NATURAL ORGANS ARE ALWAYS BETTER.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>38 Enjoy this orgasmic moment</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part38/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part38/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 38
Enjoy this orgasmic moment
12 September 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
IS THERE ANY BIOLOGICAL CHANCE OF AN UNCONDITIONED, FREE AND LOVING RELATIONSHIP BETWEEN CHILD AND PARENT?
Absolutely no. Biology is blind; hence there is no biological chance. But you can get over biology. You are conscious, intelligent human beings, so there is a possibility; but the possibility will be through meditation, not through biology.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>39 The journey from despair</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part39/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part39/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 39
The journey from despair
13 September 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHEN I TOOK SANNYAS TWO YEARS AGO, I FELT AN ECSTASY AND JOY THAT I HAD NEVER IMAGINED POSSIBLE FOR ME. BUT LATELY I FEEL MUCH NEGATIVITY, FEAR, RESISTANCE AND “NO” TO EVERYTHING, AND MY LIFE IS A CONSTANT CHAOS. I CANNOT GO BACK AND I CANNOT GO FORWARDS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 The taste of peace</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
The taste of peace
5 August 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I SEEM TO HAVE HEARD YOU SAY THAT PEOPLE ARE ATTRACTED TO WAR BECAUSE IT IS EXCITING, WHEREAS PEACE IS BORING. IN MY OWN EXPERIENCE I SEEM TO ENJOY INDULGING MY PERSONAL DRAMAS AND TRAUMAS, AND WHEN I’M NOT INDULGING THEM LIFE IS A BIT FLAT. IS IT POSSIBLE TO BE ATTRACTED TO PEACE?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>40 Your music is your madness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part40/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part40/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 40
Your music is your madness
14 September 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
EVERY TIME I AM ON MY OWN, I FEEL SEPARATE, LONELY, AND MISERABLE. I LOVE MYSELF ONLY WHEN I AM WITH OTHERS. IF I AM ALONE, I FEEL ASHAMED AND DISLIKE MYSELF. IT SEEMS AS IF I JUDGE MYSELF THROUGH THE EYES OF OTHERS.
CAN YOU SAY SOMETHING?
It is one of the basic problems.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 If you really love me, then wake up</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
If you really love me, then wake up
6 August 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
SINCE YOU HAVE BECOME AVAILABLE TO US IN THIS EARTHLY, EVERYDAY WAY, I HAVE BEEN AMAZED AT THE AMOUNT OF FEAR I FEEL WITH YOU SO CLOSE. IT MAKES ME WANT TO HIDE FROM YOU. I LOVE YOU SO MUCH, AND I DON’T UNDERSTAND THIS FEAR.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Wait and you shall find</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
Wait and you shall find
7 August 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
FOR YEARS YOU HAVE TALKED TO US OF SIMPLICITY: SIMPLICITY IN LOVE, THE SIMPLICITY OF ENLIGHTENMENT, AND NOW THE SIMPLE SOLUTION TO THE POWER GAME BETWEEN THE UNITED STATES AND RUSSIA. WHY HAS MAN DEVELOPED SUCH COMPLEXITY, AND WHY DOES HE SHOW SUCH MISTRUST AND DISBELIEF IN THE SIMPLE?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Doing is going to be your undoing</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
Doing is going to be your undoing
8 August 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
EVERY DAY YOU MAKE A STEP DESCENDING FROM THE PEDESTAL OF BEING A MASTER TO BECOMING A FRIEND TO US, THE ULTIMATE FRIEND. AND YET MY REVERENCE FOR YOU IS INCREASING EVERY DAY. HOW CAN THIS HAPPEN? PLEASE EXPLAIN.
The relationship between the master and the disciple is in a subtle way a kind of slavery.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 No society rewards lovers</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
No society rewards lovers
9 August 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
IS IT POSSIBLE TO BE RESPONSIBLE FOR ONESELF WITHOUT FIRST LEARNING TO LOVE ONESELF?
It is absolutely impossible to be responsible for yourself unless you learn to love yourself. Every child is born with tremendous love for himself. It is the society that destroys that love, it is the religion that destroys that love – because if a child goes on growing in loving himself, who is going to love Jesus Christ?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 My empire consists only of Emperors</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_death_to_deathlessness/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
My empire consists only of Emperors
10 August 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I TRUST YOU UNCONDITIONALLY, AND NOW I’M NO LONGER A SANNYASIN SIMPLY TO RID MYSELF OF MY FEARS. I AM NOW HERE WITHOUT ANY NEED, HOPE, DESIRE OR EXPECTATION. I AM NO LONGER FEELING DEPENDENT ON YOU. I AM WITH YOU WITHOUT ANY REASON, JUST FOR FUN, AND I TRUST YOU WITHOUT BELIEF.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
