<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Goose is Out on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Goose is Out on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 2 - Just see it</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 2 - Just see it‌ 2 Just see it
2 March 1981 am in Buddha Hall The first question
Question 1
OSHO, I FEEL THAT WE NEED TO HURRY, THAT THERE IS NOT MUCH TIME
LEFT. THE COCOON OF SLUMBER I AM EXISTING IN SEEMS TO SUFFOCATE ME, AND I AM AFRAID I WILL NEVER MAKE IT. YOU SAY THE GOOSE IS OUT</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 2 - Just see it</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 2 - Just see it‌ escaping from one&#39;s own problems -- subtle strategies, dangerous, because one feels that one is doing something great, while one is simply being a coward.
Werner, first face your own problems, encounter them. First try to transform YOUR being.
Only a transformed person can trigger processes of transformation in others. You ask me:
OSHO, HAVE YOU SOMETHING TO SAY TO ME?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 2 - Just see it</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 2 - Just see it‌ come the revolution, and everything will be all right.&#34; You have to sacrifice your today for tomorrow, and the tomorrow never comes.
Sixty years have passed since the Russian Revolution, and the tomorrow is still as far away as before. Thirty years have passed since the Indian Revolution, the Gandhian Revolution, and the tomorrow remains as far away, in fact, farther away than before.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 2 - Just see it</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 2 - Just see it‌ I HAVE HEARD YOU SAY THAT KNOWLEDGE IS USELESS.
No, I have not said that. Knowledge is very useful -- wisdom is useless! Knowledge is needed in the marketplace, in business, in politics. Everywhere knowledge is needed -- in technology, in science -- everywhere knowledge is needed. Knowledge is very useful, utilitarian; wisdom is absolutely useless, but that&#39;s its beauty.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 2 - Just see it</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 2 - Just see it‌ Life can be lived either with utility as your very style or it can be lived as a playfulness.
Music, love, flowers, stars, poetry, painting, dancing, all belong to the inner world. I am not against knowledge; when you are doing something in the world use your knowledge. There, to use wisdom is foolish; there, sitting in a car and meditating is dangerous.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 2 - Just see it</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 2 - Just see it‌ childlike. The sage again becomes a child. He starts collecting colored stones, pebbles, seashells on the sea beach. He starts collecting wildflowers, for no reason at all, just for the sheer joy of it.
The Sunday-schoolteacher asked her class of youngsters if they could name any of the Ten Commandments, and the kindergarten-aged boy stood up and announced proudly, &#34;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 2 - Just see it</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 2 - Just see it‌ &#34;Legs,&#34; the boy replied.
&#34;What is a four-letter word meaning intercourse?&#34; she continued. &#34;Talk,&#34; he answered.
The teacher turned to the principal. &#34;Well, what should I do?&#34;
He drew her aside and whispered, &#34;Better promote him to the fourth grade. I missed all three questions!&#34;
The last question Question 4
OSHO, WILL YOU SAY SOMETHING SERIOUS SO THAT I CAN ALSO UNDERSTAND?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 2 - Just see it</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 2 - Just see it‌ I missed again! I am not a good archer because I don&#39;t believe in targets and goals, so my arrows go everywhere except the target.
The last attempt:
It is the annual hunting season in heaven. Only the Holy Ghost is reluctant to participate --
every year up to now he has ended up with a shot in his bum.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 2 - Just see it</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 2 - Just see it‌ goose is out!&#34; It cannot be said by Nansen. Nansen is not referring to there and here, he is not even referring to then and now, he is simply saying, &#34;See, the goose is out! It has never been in, it cannot be in.&#34;
Your consciousness is always free, it is freedom itself. But the problem is arising, Bhagawati, because you want to grasp it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 2 - Just see it</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 2 - Just see it‌ &#34;The landlady of the tavern, thinking Grimaldi would like to see his patient, told the man that if he would call next morning he should see the actor who had made him laugh so much.
Grimaldi, being apprised of the circumstances, repaired to the house at the appointed time, and saw him, accompanied by several of his companions, all of whom still continued to manifest the liveliest interest in the sudden change that had happened to their friend, and kept on cheering, and drinking and treating everybody in the house, in proof of their gratification.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 2 - Just see it</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 2 - Just see it‌ this patient&#39;s symptoms. We might imagine that it occurred to the doctor, just as it might to one of his latter-day colleagues, that his patient&#39;s physical complaints were in all probability serving as a mask for deep-seated emotional stress and depression.
Suddenly, an inspired idea came to him. He said to the old man that Joseph Grimaldi, perhaps the greatest clown of all times, was in town for a performance that very evening, and he told the whole story which I have just told you.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 2 - Just see it</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 2 - Just see it‌ Enlightenment is ungraspable, so the more you try to grasp it, Bhagawati, the less it is possible. You cannot hold enlightenment in your fist -- the tighter the fist, the less is the possibility. But you can hold enlightenment in your open hands; that is the only way to hold it.
In your open hands you can hold the whole sky, all the stars, the whole existence, but in your closed fist there is nothing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 2 - Just see it</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 2 - Just see it‌ Jesus said -- a very simple statement but very pregnant -- he said, &#34;There shall be time no longer.&#34; Strange, unexpected. One should have expected something else from Jesus: God the Father will be there, the Holy Ghost will be there, all the saints will be there, and the angels will be playing on their harps &#34;Alleluia&#34; -- something like that.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 2 - Just see it</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 2 - Just see it‌ A long report, a full-page story... I told Sheela, &#34;You keep it, because this is an old thing, it has always been happening. This is what the RISHIS, the MUNIS, the bishops, the saints have always been doing. This man is unfortunate.&#34;
One of my teachers, a very beautiful old man, used to say before every examination in the school.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 2 - Just see it</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 2 - Just see it‌ time no longer. This is not right; it is putting the horse behind the cart. How will you enter the kingdom of God? From where will you enter the kingdom of God? In fact, with the very idea that there will no longer be any time in the kingdom of God, you will be in a deep hurry:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 2 - Just see it</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 2 - Just see it‌ and about, going in circles, it is not a question of great intellectuality, of philosophical acumen, of logical efficiency. It is not a question of a trained mind; it is a question of an innocent heart.
Just see it! Wipe your eyes of all the tears, wipe your eyes of all the dust that has accumulated on them, and just look at existence.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4 - Transcendence brings buddhahood</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 4 - Transcendence brings buddhahood‌ 4 Transcendence brings buddhahood 4 March 1981 am in Buddha Hall The first question
Question 1 OSHO,
WHY DO INDIANS THINK OF SEX IN TERMS OF NEED INSTEAD OF FUN? THEY
ALSO THINK AT THE SAME TIME THAT THEY HAVE TRANSCENDED SEX, BUT IN
REALITY IT HAS ONLY BEEN SUPPRESSED. OSHO, IS THERE ANY SIMILARITY
BETWEEN SUPPRESSION AND TRANSCENDENCE WHICH CAN MISLEAD PEOPLE, AS YOU SOMETIMES SAY THAT THERE IS SOME SIMILARITY BETWEEN A BUDDHA AND A MADMAN?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4 - Transcendence brings buddhahood</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 4 - Transcendence brings buddhahood‌ invent new mistakes. That&#39;s the way one expands, grows; that&#39;s the way consciousness becomes integrated.
Life is a trial-and-error process. The old man drops all mistakes, errors. He becomes so accustomed to doing the right thing that exploration, adventure, disappears from his life. And because of his own fears he won&#39;t allow the new generations to go in new directions, into new dimensions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4 - Transcendence brings buddhahood</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 4 - Transcendence brings buddhahood‌ A man who is hungry cannot think of poetry. A man who is hungry cannot conceive of meditation. It is impossible! But a long, long traditional ego tries to hide its poverty. The so-called Indian spiritualism, the so-called desire of Indian culture to guide the whole world towards spirituality is just stupid. It is sheer nonsense, it is rubbish.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4 - Transcendence brings buddhahood</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 4 - Transcendence brings buddhahood‌ to humanity are basically cutting the very roots of humanity. If they were to be followed literally there would be no humanity left.
There would have been no Mahavira, no Buddha, no Krishna, there would have been no Mohammed, no Kabir, no Nanak, if their parents had followed the idea of celibacy. It is good, it is fortunate that Buddha&#39;s father did not follow the stupid idea of celibacy, otherwise the world would have missed one of the greatest flowerings.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4 - Transcendence brings buddhahood</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 4 - Transcendence brings buddhahood‌ Love should be deep caring. One should not think in terms of food, things, of eating, biting
-- these are ugly expressions.
But India lives in all kinds of needs. Hence, sex also becomes only a need, at the most, a release, a tranquilizer -- the same kind of release that you feel when you have a good sneeze: some burden, some tension is gone.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4 - Transcendence brings buddhahood</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 4 - Transcendence brings buddhahood‌ You can talk about God, you can talk about the soul, you can talk about MOKSHA, NIRVANA, you can talk about the vedas, and there will be no misunderstanding, because they are like parrots -- for thousands of years they have been reading those words. Not that they will understand you, but at least they will understand the words.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4 - Transcendence brings buddhahood</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 4 - Transcendence brings buddhahood‌ WHY DO INDIANS THINK OF SEX IN TERMS OF NEED INSTEAD OF FUN?
They don&#39;t know anything about fun, about playfulness. They are serious people
-- very holy, very spiritual. They are walking corpses. You cannot expect playfulness from them, you can expect only long faces.
You cannot live with saints for long. Even to be with a saint for twenty-four hours is a punishment; it is not a reward because within twenty-four hours he will make you so bitter towards life, he will make you so sad, he will make you so sour, he will make you feel so guilty, condemned.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4 - Transcendence brings buddhahood</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 4 - Transcendence brings buddhahood‌ far behind. Once you leave the window, a miracle happens. Because your ego was framed by the window. Once you leave the window behind, your ego is also left behind. The ego needs the other: when the other is no more there, the ego is no more there.
Psychologists say the ego comes later on. First, you start feeling the presence of the other.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4 - Transcendence brings buddhahood</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 4 - Transcendence brings buddhahood‌ They have something to do with it. Saints need it, religious people need it. These are their fantasies, these are what they are seeing inside themselves. They want them to be projected.
And in Indian scriptures you will be surprised to note that the Indian gods are the most rapist gods in the world. They are not contented with heavenly beauties, they go on descending on the earth and seducing, raping earthly women.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4 - Transcendence brings buddhahood</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 4 - Transcendence brings buddhahood‌ And the same similarity exists between transcendence of sex and suppression of sex.
Transcendence is going beyond sex -- and to go beyond one has to go through; sex has to be used as a ladder -- and suppression is falling below sex.
Suppression creates neurosis. Transcendence brings flowering -- flowering of all that is best in you, flowering of all that is your real being.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4 - Transcendence brings buddhahood</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 4 - Transcendence brings buddhahood‌ was not a meditator he could not transform his sexual energy into a playfulness, a prayerfulness, and ultimately into an orgasmic existence.
That&#39;s why he went mad. It is dangerous to play with fire. If you don&#39;t understand its nature it is better to leave it alone. Sex is fire because it is life: to play with it without understanding the whole process of its transformation is certainly dangerous.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4 - Transcendence brings buddhahood</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part28/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 4 - Transcendence brings buddhahood‌ His whole life he was talking about living in the now, but it was only talk, mere talk; he never lived in the now. He was thinking of himself in the old foolish pattern, as being a prophet.
This stupid Judaic idea of being a prophet has tortured many people in the West.
Christians, Mohammedans, Jews -- all the three religions which were born outside India, have revolved around the idea of the prophet.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4 - Transcendence brings buddhahood</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part29/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 4 - Transcendence brings buddhahood‌ But he thinks -- the Christian theologian who came from Germany just to study what is happening here -- that of course it looks beautiful now, but when Osho dies it will disappear.
It should disappear. I will make every arrangement for it to disappear. It should not remain even for a single moment, because that will be a dead thing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4 - Transcendence brings buddhahood</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part30/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 4 - Transcendence brings buddhahood‌ So everything that I am saying is purposeless -- as purposeless as the roses, as a bird on the wing, as the stars, as the dewdrops in the early morning sun. What purpose? I am not in any way purposive. It is sheer joy.
Three Polacks, Madia, are standing outside a brothel discussing what prices they are willing to pay for the services inside.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 5 - Perfectly imperfect</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part31/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 5 - Perfectly imperfect‌ 5 Perfectly imperfect
5 March 1981 am in Buddha Hall The first question
Question 1
OSHO, ARE YOU INFALLIBLE?
Thomas V. Kempis, I am infallibly fallible! First, I am not a perfectionist because to me perfectionism is the root cause of all neurosis. Unless humanity gets rid of the idea of perfection it is never going to be sane.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 5 - Perfectly imperfect</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part32/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part32/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 5 - Perfectly imperfect‌ Jesus comes followed by his followers -- that bunch of fools they call apostles. He is hungry, that whole bunch is hungry. They come to a fig tree, and the fig tree is not in season.
It is not its fault, but Jesus gets so angry that he condemns the fig tree, he curses the fig tree.
Now, how is this possible?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 5 - Perfectly imperfect</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part33/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part33/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 5 - Perfectly imperfect‌ FORTY years! This is the longest period that any man has been able to control his bowels.
This is real yoga! The greatest case of constipation in the whole history of man... and I don&#39;t think anybody is going to defeat him.
These stupid ideas have been perpetuated just to make humanity suffer. If you have these ideas in your mind then you will feel guilty about everything.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 5 - Perfectly imperfect</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part34/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part34/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 5 - Perfectly imperfect‌ St Peter challenged the Archangel Gabriel to a game of golf. St. Peter&#39;s first drive resulted in a hole-in-one. Gabriel&#39;s first drive produced the same result The same thing happened at the next shot.
St. Peter looked at Gabriel thoughtfully and then said, &#34;What do you say we cut out the miracles and play some golf?&#34;
I am not infallible, and I would never like to be infallible either, because that is suicidal.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 5 - Perfectly imperfect</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part35/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part35/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 5 - Perfectly imperfect‌ But he said, &#34;Okay, you be happy. This is your last desire, and I have never followed any advice of yours. At least this much I can do before I depart.&#34;
But the woman did not stay there to see him depart. She said, &#34;You just lie down there. I am going. And die on the bed in a proper way.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 5 - Perfectly imperfect</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part36/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part36/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 5 - Perfectly imperfect‌ That is a very unconscious longing in every man -- to prove something. And the moment a person falls in love with a woman, immediately the question becomes of predominant importance. He starts proving himself by earning more money, by becoming a president or prime minister, by conquering the world. But whatsoever he does still remains incomplete --</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 5 - Perfectly imperfect</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part37/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part37/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 5 - Perfectly imperfect‌ Birbal went around Delhi, and wherever he went he had to present a hen. Only in one place was he in a little difficulty. A very muscular man -- he had never seen such a strong, muscular body -- was sitting in the sun, massaging his muscles.
Birbal asked him, &#34;Are you a henpecked husband?&#34;
He simply showed his muscles to Birbal and said, &#34;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 5 - Perfectly imperfect</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part38/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part38/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 5 - Perfectly imperfect‌ He had heard all the stories about Socrates and his wife, Xanthippe. She must have been a really dangerous woman, an Amazon! She used to beat Socrates. Once she poured hot water, boiling hot water on him; she was boiling it for tea but became angry and poured it on Socrates&#39; face.
Socrates was an ugly man, very ugly -- snub-nosed, nothing worth looking at, disgusting.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 5 - Perfectly imperfect</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part39/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part39/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 5 - Perfectly imperfect‌ prospect, but four rings later he pretended that he had to go out to get some cigarettes and staggered off to the watchman&#39;s tower.
&#34;Listen, old man,&#34; he wheezed to the man, &#34;do me a favor, will you? For the rest of the night ring that bell of yours at two-hour intervals instead of hourly!&#34;
&#34;Ah,&#34; replied the ancient watchman, fingering his moustache, &#34;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 5 - Perfectly imperfect</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part40/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part40/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 5 - Perfectly imperfect‌ A month later the man returned, obviously satisfied with the results. &#34;The pills are terrific!&#34; he said. &#34;I&#39;ve been doing it three times a night.&#34;
&#34;Wonderful,&#34; the doctor replied. &#34;What does your wife say about your love- making now?&#34;
&#34;How should I know?&#34; the fellow shrugged. &#34;I haven&#39;t been home yet!&#34; You ask me, Prasad:
WHAT IS YOUR SECRET?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 5 - Perfectly imperfect</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part41/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part41/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 5 - Perfectly imperfect‌ If the woman takes charge of the whole world, the world will drop many stupid things. For example, wars will disappear. Of course there will be more beautiful clothes, fashion shows, modelling, but weapons, atomic bombs, hydrogen bombs, etcetera, will disappear -- no woman is interested in all these things. Hiroshima and Nagasaki will not happen again; it is only the man who can do these things.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 5 - Perfectly imperfect</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part42/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part42/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 5 - Perfectly imperfect‌ flowers come of their own accord. Flowers will come, but they cannot come without roots.
Roots and flowers are like two wings: if you have both wings then the whole sky is yours. But the most important thing, the first, the basic, the fundamental, is the root.
The woman is the root of all life; man can at the most be a branch, a flowering branch, a beautiful branch -- a longing, an aspiration to touch the stars.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 5 - Perfectly imperfect</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part43/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part43/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 5 - Perfectly imperfect‌ Very pragmatic!
Sam told his wife, Becky, that because of inflation they had to cut expenses -- no more dining out, theater, concerts, etcetera. Becky chided him in reply, &#34;But, Sam, if you would just learn how to fuck, we could get rid of the chauffeur!&#34;
But man lives in a totally different world!
A man returned from a convention and proudly showed his wife a gallon of bourbon he had won for having the largest sex organ of all present.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 5 - Perfectly imperfect</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part44/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_goose_is_out/part44/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌Chapter 5 - Perfectly imperfect‌ There is no need to listen to my words, Anneliese, just being with me is enough, just being in tune, that&#39;s enough. Words are only strategies to keep you attuned to me so that you don&#39;t fall asleep, so that you remain awake.
You say:
EVERY TIME I FINISHED A LETTER, I FELT THAT EVERYTHING I WROTE WAS
NONSENSE...
It is! But there is no need to throw it away, otherwise what am I going to do here?</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
