<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>You Ain\&#39;t Seen Nothin\&#39; Yet on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/</link>
    <description>Recent content in You Ain\&#39;t Seen Nothin\&#39; Yet on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
1 March 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Bliss is not a result of prayer, it is not a reward: it is prayer itself. It is not that prayerful people become blissful; just the contrary: blissful people are prayerful. There is no question of becoming; bliss and prayer are synonymous. And once this is understood then the whole of life can be a prayer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
10 March 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Atmo means the self, and volker means the master – master not of the people but master of one’s self.
That is true mastery; to be master of others is really a poor substitute. People try to be masters of others because they are not masters of themselves. Once the self-mastery has happened, all desire to dominate, all desire to possess, all desire to be superior, simply disappears.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
11 March 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Samagra means total, catherine comes from a Greek root, catheros; from the same root comes catharsis. It means the process of purification. Your full name will mean total process of purification. And this is what sannyas is all about: a process of cleansing.
The old religions used to repress. My approach is: instead of repressing, cathart, throw it out.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
12 March 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin explains her son’s name, Jolon: valley of the dead oak trees.]
Prem means love. Love and death are very deeply related. Love is a kind of death: it is the death of the ego. Those who are not capable of dying cannot be capable of love either, because it is the same phenomenon looked at from different angles.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
13 March 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, yuuichi means strength – divine strength. Man in himself is impotent. All that is alive in him comes from god, all that is power in him is divine: man is only a vehicle. If one functions simply as a vehicle of god then one’s life is religious. And if one starts interfering in the flow of the energy and is no more just a vehicle but becomes a controller, then one’s life is irreligious.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
14 March 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means blissful, helga has three meanings. The first is holy, the second is pious, and the third is religious. They look alike, they are not; they look synonymous, they are not. There is a great difference between them, and the difference is of immense import.
The religious is always a formal person, a pretender – a Christian, a Hindu, a Mohammedan.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
15 March 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Etyan: strong and stable.]
Veet Etyan. Veet means going beyond, transcending – transcending the desire to be strong and stable. Man has always desired to be strong because he feels weak; the desire simply proves that man feels weak. Man is weak, because the part can never be strong; only the whole is strong.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
16 March 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, robbie means bright, shining one. God is the shining one. He shines through everything – through the flowers and through the stars and through the eyes of people. That which shines is divine, and the person is blind who cannot see it. Not to see god is the greatest calamity that can happen to a person, and that has happened to millions of people: people have become utterly incapable of seeing god.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
17 March 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, julian means youthful – divine youthfulness. To remain young forever is of immense importance. It is the past that makes one old. If one can go on dying to the past every day, one remains young. If one lives moment to moment then one never becomes old. The body will become old, certainly, but the body is not the question; the spirit is the question.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
18 March 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, karin means rejoice – rejoice in the divine. The world is full of god, each particle is overflowing with his existence, but we cannot see him unless we rejoice, because when we rejoice we function at the optimum. When we rejoice we become total, when we rejoice then we are not holding anything back.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
19 March 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Veet means going beyond, transcending, andre means manly strength. There are two possibilities open to man: either he can move in search of manly strength or he can move in search of womanly strength. The manly strength is gross, aggressive, violent; the feminine strength is subtle, non- aggressive, non-violent. Politics remains in the first, religion moves into the second.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
2 March 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, francesco means free, freedom. Your full name will mean a loving freedom. One can be free in anger, but then freedom loses something tremendously beautiful, then freedom is more a reaction against something; and when you are against something you are never really free of it. It will haunt you, it will follow you like a dark shadow.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
20 March 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, kerry is a name of a place. Bliss is a place within you, it is a space within you. It is not something that happens to you: it is already there. It has just to be allowed to overflow, to overwhelm you.
We have created many hindrances for it, we have blocked all its ways.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
22 March 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[March 21st was the Enlightenment Day celebration with singing and dancing in Osho’s presence.]
Yogadeva. Yoga means union, deva means god. To be in a union with existence is to know god. That union, that very union, is god. God is not a person; it is a principle – the principle of unity, the principle that makes the universe a universe and not a multi-verse.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
24 March 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means god, ray means a wise protector – god, the wise protector. We are protected each and every moment of our lives. We may not be aware of it, but the protection is always there. We are not strangers to existence, we are part of it; and we are not unnecessary, not accidental, we are intrinsically necessary.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
26 March 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, anneke means grace. Love is the only experience in life which makes you aware of the presence of god. And to be aware of the presence of god is to be full of grace; suddenly one is overflowing with grace. The benediction is such, the blessing is such, that one becomes a blessing to existence through it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 24
27 March 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, heinz means home – home of bliss; and that’s what you have to create in your being. Bliss is always ready to come in; it is just that we are not prepared to receive it, to welcome it, even to recognise it. We have forgotten all language that can recognise it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 25
28 March 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, david means god’s, the lord’s – one who belongs to god, bliss that is god’s. There is a bliss which is not ours, which cannot be ours; we cannot claim it as a possession. It comes on its own and goes on its own; it is a visitor.
The moment we try to possess it, we destroy it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 26
29 March 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, larry is from laurel, a symbol of victory – bliss is the symbol of victory. Unless bliss is achieved a man has lived in vain, his life has been nothillg but a failure. He may have all the riches of the world – that will not make any difference: if his heart is not overflowing with bliss nothing is going to make any difference.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 27
30 March 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, brita means strength. Love is strength, the strongest phenomenon in existence, yet it is the most delicate one too. It is very fragile, vulnerable, soft, gentle, yet it is the strongest force in the world. It conquers everything, it is undefeatable. It is a paradox, and all that is true is always a paradox; truth exists in paradox.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/part28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/part28/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 28
31 March 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, jen means a white wave – a white wave of bliss. White is not a single colour: white is all colours together, all colours in a symphony. That’s what creates white – all colours in such deep harmony that they lose their individuality in something total and higher. White is multi- dimensional. And it is the colour of bliss.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
3 March 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, darshano means insight. They say that love is blind; I say that only love is not blind. The person who lives without love lives in blindness and in darkness. His ears hear not but only translate. His eyes don’t see but impose. His mind does not understand but only interprets. His whole life is phoney.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
4 March 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, jurgen means a farmer.
Life is an opportunity, just a seed. One can miss it, one can remain a seed; that will be the missing of the opportunity. One has to seek the right soil. One has to be a farmer; One has to learn how to grow.
All that is needed in farming is needed in inner growth too: the right soil, the right season, protection for the new sprouts, the right quantity of water and sun and air, and not too much protection; that is the most important thing, because too much protection will not be helpful, it will be harmful.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
5 March 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, ariel means a lion of god... and each sannyasin has to become a lion. There are two many sheep in the world, and the world needs individuals. It needs really free people, because only out of freedom do flowers of love, bliss, arise.
Prem means love, janaina means god’s gift. Love is the gift of god, the greatest gift.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
6 March 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Rick Atmo. Rick means a powerful ruler, atmo means your own self. One can rule others or one can rule oneself. To rule others is a poor substitute, because the real ruler is one who rules himself. Because it is arduous to rule oneself, people have chosen the cheaper thing; the cheaper thing is to rule others.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
7 March 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Veet means beyond, andy means manly. The past has been very male chauvinistic, so anything manly was praised very much. The woman was thought to be not really human. In China, one could kill one’s wife and it was not a crime. No court would take any note of it; it was a private affair.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
8 March 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho gives sannyas to two small children]
Prem means love, dylan means sea, ocean. Prem Dylan will mean ocean of love. Create such huge love... as the ocean, boundless, without any shore.
Prem means love, emmet means work. Let your work be your love; do everything very lovingly. Work is worship.
[The father of the children says he is a bit upset because his wife was unable to enter the darshan due to a fragrance.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/you_aint_seen_nothin_yet/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
9 March 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, Laila is from a symbolic Sufi story. Sufis believe that god is the beloved, that god is the woman, and that the seeker is the lover.
The story of Laila and Majnu represents the seeker and the sought. Majnu is the seeker, Laila is the beloved; Laila represents god. It is one of the most beautiful stories, but it has lost its message.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
