<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>The True Name, Vol 1 on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_true_name_vol_1/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The True Name, Vol 1 on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/the_true_name_vol_1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 The Singer</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_true_name_vol_1/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_true_name_vol_1/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
The Singer
21 November 1974 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
HE IS ONE, HE IS OMKAR, THE SUPREME TRUTH.
HE IS THE CREATOR, BEYOND FEAR, BEYOND RANCOR. HIS IS THE TIMELESS FORM.
NEVER BORN, SELF-CREATING.
HE IS ATTAINED BY THE GURU’S GRACE.
HE WAS TRUTH BEFORE THE AGES AND AS TIME RAN ITS COURSE. NANAK SAYS, NOW IS HE TRUTH ETERNAL, AND FOREVER WILL HE BE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 The Lure of the Infinite</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_true_name_vol_1/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_true_name_vol_1/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 10
The Lure of the Infinite
30 November 1974 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium THERE ARE MILLIONS OF UNDERWORLDS AND INFINITE SKIES ABOVE.
THE VEDAS SAY MILLIONS HAVE SEARCHED AND SEARCHED,
ONLY TO END IN EXHAUSTION.
THE HOLY BOOKS CLAIM EIGHTEEN THOUSAND WORLDS BUT ONLY ONE POWER BEHIND ALL CREATION.
IF ANYTHING COULD BE WRITTEN WE WOULD KEEP THE ACCOUNT, BUT ALL ESTIMATES ARE DESTRUCTIBLE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 The Weight of a Flower</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_true_name_vol_1/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_true_name_vol_1/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
The Weight of a Flower
22 November 1974 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
BY DIVINE ORDER ALL FORM WAS CREATED, BUT HIS ORDER CANNOT BE DESCRIBED. DIVINE ORDER HAS CREATED ALL LIFE,
AND BY IT ALL GREATNESS BESTOWED;
BY DIVINE ORDER ARE SOME HIGH AND SOME LOW, AND PAIN AND PLEASURE GRANTED;
BY HIS ORDER DO SOME ATTAIN SALVATION,
OR ENDLESSLY WANDER THROUGH CYCLES OF DEATH AND BIRTH.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Solving the Riddle</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_true_name_vol_1/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_true_name_vol_1/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
Solving the Riddle
23 November 1974 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium THE LORD IS TRUTH. TRUTH IS HIS NAME. HIS PRAISES ARE SUNG IN ENDLESS WAYS.
EVEN WHILE PRAISING THEY ASK FOR MORE AND MORE,
AND THE LORD KEEPS ON GIVING.
THEN WHAT OFFERING CAN WE MAKE TO GAIN A GLIMPSE OF HIS COURT? AND WHAT LANGUAGE SHALL WE SPEAK TO ENDEAR US TO HIM?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Some Other Ganges</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_true_name_vol_1/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_true_name_vol_1/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
Some Other Ganges
24 November 1974 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
IF I HAVE SUCCEEDED IN ATTAINING HIS PLEASURE, I HAVE BATHED IN ALL THE HOLY RIVERS.
AND IF I FAIL TO PLEASE HIM, WHY SHOULD I BATHE AND ADORN MYSELF?
IN THIS WHOLE CREATED UNIVERSE, NOTHING IS ATTAINED WITHOUT ACTIONS; BUT HE WHO LISTENS TO BUT ONE TEACHING OF THE GURU,</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 The Art Of Listening</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_true_name_vol_1/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_true_name_vol_1/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
The Art Of Listening
25 November 1974 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
THROUGH LISTENING OCCULT POWERS AND SAINTLINESS ARE GAINED, HEAVEN AND EARTH ARE MADE STABLE,
AND THE WORLD AND LOWER WORLDS REVOLVE. THROUGH LISTENING DEATH DOES NOT TOUCH.
NANAK SAYS, THROUGH LISTENING DEVOTEES ATTAIN BLISS, AND SIN AND SORROW ARE DESTROYED.
THROUGH LISTENING VISHNU, BRAHMA AND INDRA CAME INTO BEING, THE MOST SINFUL WILL SING HIS PRAISES,</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Only Contemplating Can Know</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_true_name_vol_1/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_true_name_vol_1/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
Only Contemplating Can Know
26 November 1974 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
THE STATE OF CONTEMPLATION CANNOT BE EXPRESSED; WHOEVER ATTEMPTS IT WILL AFTERWARDS REPENT. THERE IS NO PAPER, NO PEN, NO WRITER,
THAT CAN PENETRATE SUCH A STATE.
THE NAME OF THE FLAWLESS ONE IS SUCH THAT ONLY CONTEMPLATING CAN KNOW.IT.
THROUGH CONTEMPLATION IS REMEMBRANCE BORN IN MIND AND INTELLECT, AND AWARENESS OF THE UNIVERSE ACQUIRED.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 The Journey Ends</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_true_name_vol_1/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_true_name_vol_1/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
The Journey Ends
27 November 1974 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
FIVE ARE THE TESTS AND THE MINISTERS;
THEY GAIN SHELTER AND RESPECT AT HIS DOOR; THEY DECORATE THE KING’S COURT.
ATTENTION IS THE GURU OF THE FIVE. WHATEVER YOU WILL SAY, CONSIDER WELL FIRST,
FOR THE DOINGS OF THE DOER ARE IMPOSSIBLE TO ASSESS. RELIGION UPHOLDS THE EARTH AND IS BORN OF COMPASSION.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 Countless Ways</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_true_name_vol_1/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_true_name_vol_1/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
Countless Ways
28 November 1974 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
THERE ARE COUNTLESS WAYS TO REPEAT HIS NAME AND EXPRESS DEVOTION, COUNTLESS WAYS OF WORSHIP AND PURIFICATION.
THERE ARE COUNTLESS SCRIPTURES AND COUNTLESS MOUTHS TO RECITE THEM, COUNTLESS WAYS OF YOGA TO MAKE THE MIND DISPASSIONATE.
THERE ARE COUNTLESS DEVOTEES WHO CONTEMPLATE HIS VIRTUES AND KNOWLEDGE, COUNTLESS WHO ARE VIRTUOUS AND GENEROUS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 Dyed In His Hue</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_true_name_vol_1/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_true_name_vol_1/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
Dyed In His Hue
29 November 1974 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium IF THE BODY IS COVERED WITH DIRT, WATER CAN WASH IT AWAY.
IF THE CLOTHES ARE SOILED AND POLLUTED,
SOAP AND WATER CAN WASH THEM CLEAN. EVEN IF MIND IS FILLED WITH EVIL,
LOVE FOR HIS NAME CAN DYE YOU IN HIS HUE. SAINT OR SINNER ARE NO EMPTY WORDS; ALL OUR ACTIONS HAVE BEEN RECORDED.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
