<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Chakra Book on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_chakra_book/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Chakra Book on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/the_chakra_book/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 1: The Changing Seasons of Life</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_chakra_book/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_chakra_book/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 1: The Changing Seasons of Life Life has an inner pattern; it is good to understand it. Every seven years, physiologists say, the body and mind go through a crisis and a change. Every seven years all the cells of the body change, are completely renewed. In fact, if you live seventy years, the average limit, your body dies ten times. Each seventh year everything changes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 10: Tantra and the World of the Chakras</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_chakra_book/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_chakra_book/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 10: Tantra and the World of the Chakras Tantra is freedom – freedom from all mind constructs, from all mind games; freedom from all structures, freedom from the other. Tantra is a space to be. Tantra is liberation.
Tantra is not a religion in the ordinary sense. Religion is again a mind game, religion gives you a certain pattern. A Christian has a certain pattern, so has a Hindu, so has a Muslim.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 11: OSHO Chakra Breathing Meditation</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_chakra_book/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_chakra_book/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 11: OSHO Chakra Breathing Meditation This active meditation uses deep, rapid breathing and body movement to open and bring awareness, vitality and silence to each of the seven chakras* and thus into your life.
The accompanying music and bells energetically support the process and indicate the beginning of each stage. The meditation is best done on an empty stomach.
* All chakras lie deep within, rather than on the surface of the body.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 12: OSHO Chakra Sounds Meditation</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_chakra_book/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_chakra_book/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 12: OSHO Chakra Sounds Meditation This meditation can be done at any time. It uses vocal sounds to open and harmonize the chakras* or energy centers while bringing awareness to them. It can bring you into a deep, peaceful, inner silence either through making your own vocal sounds or by just listening to the music and feeling the sounds within you.
* All chakras lie deep within, rather than on the surface of the body.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 2: Man Is a Rainbow</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_chakra_book/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_chakra_book/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 2: Man Is a Rainbow Man is a rainbow, all the seven colors together. That is his beauty and that is his problem too. Man is multifaceted, multidimensional. His being is not simple, it is a great complexity. And out of that complexity is born the harmony we call God: the divine melody.
So the first thing to be understood about man is that man is not yet.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 3: Understanding the Chakras and Kundalini</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_chakra_book/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_chakra_book/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 3: Understanding the Chakras and Kundalini No theoretical knowledge ever helps and no anatomical visualization of kundalini is really meaningful for meditation. When I say this, I do not mean that there is nothing like kundalini or chakras. Kundalini is there, the chakras are there, but no knowledge helps in any way. Rather, it can hinder. It can become a barrier for so many reasons.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4: Seven Subtle Bodies and the Energy of Breath</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_chakra_book/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_chakra_book/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 4: Seven Subtle Bodies and the Energy of Breath Prana is energy – the living energy in us, the life in us. This life manifests itself, as far as the physical body is concerned, as the incoming and the outgoing breath. These are two opposite things; we take them as one. We say “breathing” – but breathing has two polarities: the incoming breath and the outgoing breath.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 5: Sleep and Wakefulness in the Chakras</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_chakra_book/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_chakra_book/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 5: Sleep and Wakefulness in the Chakras Each chakra has a sleep part, except the last – the sahasrar. At the seventh chakra, awareness is total: it is pure awareness. That’s why Krishna says in the Gita: “The yogi never sleeps.” “The yogi” means one who has come to the last center of his being, to the ultimate flowering; one who has become a lotus.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 6: The Experience of Death and Life in the Subtle Bodies</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_chakra_book/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_chakra_book/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 6: The Experience of Death and Life in the Subtle Bodies The soul resides within two bodies – the subtle body and the gross body. At the time of death, the gross body dies. The body which is made of earth and water, the body which consists of flesh, bones and marrow, drops, dies. Subsequently, the body comprised of subtle thoughts, subtle feelings, subtle vibrations, subtle filaments, remains.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 7: The Heart Sutra and the Path of Buddha</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_chakra_book/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_chakra_book/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 7: The Heart Sutra and the Path of Buddha Homage to the perfection of wisdom, the lovely, the holy!
Avalokita, the holy lord and bodhisattva, was moving in the deep course of the wisdom which has gone beyond. He looked down from on high, he beheld but five heaps, and he saw that in their own being they were empty.
I salute the buddha within you.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 8: Patanjali and the Path of Yoga</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_chakra_book/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_chakra_book/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 8: Patanjali and the Path of Yoga Patanjali’s skill in expressing the inexpressible is superb. Nobody has ever been able to surpass him. He has mapped the inner world of consciousness as accurately as it is possible; he has almost done an impossible job.
I have heard a story about Ramakrishna…
One day he said to his disciples, “I will tell you everything today and will not keep anything secret.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 9: The Subtle Bodies According to Patanjali</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_chakra_book/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_chakra_book/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 9: The Subtle Bodies According to Patanjali The yoga system of Patanjali is not a philosophical system. It is empirical; it is a tool to work with – but still it has a philosophy. That too, is just to give an intellectual understanding of where you are moving, what you are seeking. But philosophy is arbitrary, utilitarian, just to give a comprehensive picture of the territory you are going to discover; but the philosophy has to be understood.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Copyright page</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_chakra_book/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_chakra_book/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
Copyright © 1999, 2015 OSHO International Foundation{#bookmark1 style=” color: black; font-family:&#34;Times New Roman&#34;, serif; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; text-decoration: none; font-size: 10.5pt;” target=“_blank”} www.osho.com/copyrights
Images and cover design © OSHO International Foundation
All rights reserved. No part of this book may be reproduced or transmitted in any form or by any means, electronic or mechanical, including photocopying, recording, or by any information storage and retrieval system, without prior written permission from the publisher.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_chakra_book/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_chakra_book/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Introduction Osho,
Is knowledge about esoteric subjects such as chakras, collective unconsciousness, energy fields, really helpful along the way, or not? Or will whatever is needed come to me through experience, in its own time?
Anything that is needed will come of its own accord, in its own time. All this so-called esoteric knowledge about chakras, energy fields, kundalini, astral bodies, is dangerous as knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OSHO International Meditation Resort</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_chakra_book/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_chakra_book/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
OSHO International Meditation Resort
www.osho.com/meditationresort
Each year the OSHO International Meditation Resort welcomes thousands of people from more than 100 countries. The unique campus provides an opportunity for a direct personal experience of a new way of living – with more awareness, relaxation, celebration and creativity. A great variety of around-the- clock and around-the-year program options are available. Doing nothing and just relaxing is one of them!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PART I: THE SEVEN CENTERS OF BEING</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_chakra_book/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_chakra_book/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌PART I: THE SEVEN CENTERS OF BEING &amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PART II: DIFFERENT MAPS FOR DIFFERENT PATHS</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_chakra_book/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_chakra_book/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌PART II: DIFFERENT MAPS FOR DIFFERENT PATHS &amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PART III: CHAKRA MEDITATIONS</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_chakra_book/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_chakra_book/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌PART III: CHAKRA MEDITATIONS &amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Title page</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_chakra_book/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_chakra_book/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌The Chakra Book Energy and Healing Power of the Subtle Body
OSHO &amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
