<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Hidden Mysteries on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hidden_mysteries/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hidden Mysteries on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/hidden_mysteries/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 The Secret of Shapes, Sounds and Fragrances</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hidden_mysteries/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hidden_mysteries/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
The Secret of Shapes, Sounds and Fragrances
26 April 1971 pm in Woodlands, Bombay, India
Suppose we have a key in our hands. We cannot directly understand the purpose of it from the key itself, nor is it possible to imagine from the key itself that a great treasure is likely to be revealed with its help. There is no hidden indication in the key regarding the treasure; the key itself is closed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Alchemical Secrets of Places of Holy Pilgrimage</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hidden_mysteries/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hidden_mysteries/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
Alchemical Secrets of Places of Holy Pilgrimage
6 June 1971 pm in Woodlands, Bombay, India
In the Pacific Ocean there is a small island, Easter Island, on which there are one thousand huge stone idols, all about seventy feet tall. The population of the island is just two hundred. It was found, when that island was first discovered, that it was so small, it couldn’t produce food for more than two hundred people.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 The Occult Science of the Third Eye</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hidden_mysteries/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hidden_mysteries/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
The Occult Science of the Third Eye
12 June 1971 pm in Woodlands, Bombay, India
Before I tell you about the vermillion or sandal paste mark, I would like to tell you about two events. It will make things easier for you to understand. Both of them are historical facts.
In the 1888 a person named Ramanujan was born in a poor Brahmin family in South India.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 The Transformative Power of Idol Worship, Mantras, Music and Dance</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hidden_mysteries/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hidden_mysteries/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
The Transformative Power of Idol Worship, Mantras, Music and
Dance
16 June 1971 pm in Woodlands, Bombay, India
Dr. Frank Rudolf spent his whole life with some primitive tribes of the Amazon doing research on a very strange phenomenon. I would like to tell you about it so that you can understand more easily what idol worship was meant for. Most primitive communities have known for a long time of a particular process.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Astrology: The Science of Cosmic Oneness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hidden_mysteries/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hidden_mysteries/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
Astrology: The Science of Cosmic Oneness
9 July 1971 pm in Woodlands, Bombay, India
Astrology is perhaps the most ancient subject and also in a way the most tabooed. It is the most ancient because as far back as we have been able to investigate the history of mankind, astrology has been in existence. Astrological inscriptions have been found on bone remnants from the Sumerian civilization which existed twenty-five thousand years before Jesus.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Astrology: A Door to Religiousness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hidden_mysteries/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hidden_mysteries/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 6
Astrology: A Door to Religiousness
10 July 1971 pm in Woodlands, Bombay, India
It is necessary that some matters be understood. First, it is necessary to know that from a scientific point of view the whole solar family is born out of the sun. The moon, Mars, Jupiter, and the rest of the planets, including this earth, are all organic parts of the sun. Slowly, life on earth came into being – from plants to man.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
