<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Sacred Yes on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Sacred Yes on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌1 November 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Veet means beyond, nastiko means no – beyond no-saying. The religions in the past have been teaching people a kind of negative attitude. The old religions depend on the don’t: don’t do this, don’t do that. Their whole approach is: How to negate life? They think that by negating life they will be a coming closer to god, and that is just absurd.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
10 November 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Jesus says again and again: Unless you are like a child you will not enter into my kingdom of god. The child has something which the grown-up loses; that something has to be regained. The child has some qualities of paradise. Once you start growing up you start losing paradise; that paradise has to be regained.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
11 November 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Veet means beyond, marga, in Sanskrit, means the way... beyond the way.
The outward journey needs a way, the inward needs no way at all. If you want to go to the moon, there is distance, and the distance has to be covered by a way. But if you want to go into your own being there is no distance at all; you are already there.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
12 November 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Veet means beyond, nishedh means negation – beyond the negation, beyond the negative, beyond the no.
The mind exists as a no, the heart exists as a yes. That’s the difference between the mind and the heart. The whole climate of the mind consists of nos and nos. It cannot say yes, it is impotent in saying yes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
13 November 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, sandip means a lamp – a divine lamp. The light is already there – it has not to be created; it is inborn, innate. But it has to be discovered. All that is needed is a deep penetration into one’s own being. One has to make an arrow of one’s consciousness so that the arrow can go to the very target of one’s heart, and there is the light of all lights.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
14 November 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Veet means beyond, santap means anguish – beyond anguish. Anguish is one of the most fundamental problems of the human mind. Man exists in anguish, man is anguish, a constant anxiety, a constant feeling of falling apart, a constant fear of being torn. No other animal in existence lives in such anguish. All other animals are at peace with themselves, except for man.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
15 November 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, nijo means individuality. Individuality is your essential core. Individuality is not your personality. Personality is given to you by the family, the society, culture; individuality is that which you bring into the world – that is your original face. The individuality gets lost in many layers of personality, and a man has many personalities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
16 November 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, lolit means moved by – moved by the divine, moved by god. God always comes as a great stirring in the heart. God always comes as a tremendous movement in the being, because god is energy and because god is creativity. God comes as a dance, god comes and possesses you.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
17 November 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Baba has three meanings. One is: the small child, the innocent child, the child who cannot yet speak, because the moment a child starts speaking he is no more a child; he has become part of civilisation. Language is the world of civilisation; it is language that makes man different from animals. If language disappears then man will be just as one of the animals; there will be no distinction.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
18 November 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin had sent Osho some photos of his stone sculptures; stone arrangements.]
I looked at your stone sculpture – beautiful! In the new commune you will have to do a few things. When the new commune is ready you have to plan a small place for your statues. Just make as many Buddhas as possible!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
19 November 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Sarva means all, sambhavo means possible – all is possible. Man is a seed of infinity. Nothing is impossible, and one should not be satisfied with oneself too early, in fact one should never be satisfied with oneself; the fire of discontentment should be kept burning. One should be satisfied with things but one should not be satisfied with oneself.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌2 November 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, samvega means feeling, emotion. God is available through feeling and only through feeling. It is not a question of thinking; and the people who start thinking about god are bound to conclude that there is no god. Their very method prohibits it. It is as if one is trying to listen to music through the eyes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
20 November 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Madhu means sweet, mati means intelligence – sweet intelligence. There is a great difference between intellect and intelligence. Intellect is bitter, intellect is argumentative, intellect is sceptical. Intelligence is a totally different affair. It is basically love. It is not negative; it is yea-saying, it is affirmative, it is positive.
Intellect is negative; it is nay-saying.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
21 November 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Veet means beyond, Osho explains, and amo means darkness: beyond the darkness is the dawn.]
The darkness is not something outside, it is something inside; hence the light is also not going to happen from the outside, it has to arise within. No outer light can dispel inner darkness. Only the inner can function on the inner.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
22 November 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, vidheya means positivity, acceptability, affirmation, the quality of saying yes to existence – and that is the greatest religious quality. In fact only that quality makes a person religious. Renouncing the no is renouncing the mind. The mind exists by saying no, the mind is basically negativity. Its whole existence is that of denial.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
23 November 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Madhu means sweet, veda means wisdom – sweet wisdom. Knowledge is never sweet because it is something foreign. It burdens you; it is a pollution, a poisoning of your system. It does not grow out of you, hence It can’t be sweet. And because it is imposed, you are a victim of it. It is a violence perpetuated by the society on the individual.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 24
24 November 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Veet means beyond, ahmo means ego. The truth is very close by; just a thin layer of the ego is preventing it. It is really a very thin layer, because the ego is not substantial. It is not an entity, It is not a thing; it is just an activity. In fact the ego should used as a verb rather than as a noun.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 25
25 November 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, and pritam means beloved – a blissful beloved. and the beloved is hiding in our own heart. The whole search outside is utterly meaningless. God is within but we seek him in the churches, in the temples, in the mosques, and we go on missing him. God is not in the scriptures either.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 26
26 November 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin has followed his wife, of thirty years marriage, to the ashram after they separated. He wishes to live with her again and asks advice. He says the ashram has been a good influence on her.]
Mm mm. No, she is happy and things can start flowing again.
Mm. In fact, there are just a few misunderstandings, nothing else.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 27
27 November 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, kranto means revolution – divine revolution. The political revolution, the social revolution, the economic revolution, are not really revolutions. They are only reforms, modifications, rearrangements, but nothing new ever happens through them. They remain continuous with the past. To call them revolution is not right.
The first requirement for a revolution is that it should be discontinuous with the past.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part28/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 28
28 November 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, shakti means power – love’s power. And that is the real power in the world. It is very paradoxical, because love is very humble; it is not powerful. And that’s its power. Love is surrender, but that’s its victory. It is a very passive way of conquering, it is the feminine way of conquering.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>29</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part29/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 29
29 November 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Sumitro means a good friend. Friendship is something immensely valuable. Love tends to be possessive; friendship is non-possessive love. Friendship is all that is good in love minus that which is not good. Friendship is the very essential core of love. To rise to friendship is really a great spiritual growth. People fall in love, and people rise in friendship.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
3 November 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, sambhava means possibility, potentiality – the possibility of the divine. God is not something that is available ready-made; it is your potential. You can actualise it, but you can miss it also.
Man is like a seed: the seed has the potential to become the tree, but only the potential. It is not yet the tree; it can miss also.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>30</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part30/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 30
30 November 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, sahaj means spontaneous. Love can only be spontaneous. If it is otherwise, it is something else, not love. Love cannot be calculated phenomenon. It happens of its own accord. You cannot do it, you cannot UNdo it. It comes from the beyond, hence it has the flavour of the divine. It comes from nothingness, hence its magical quality.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
4 November 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Do you know what Joshua means?...
It is the same as Jesus; the real name of Jesus was Joshua.
It means for which the people have been waiting, the awaited one. Deva Joshua means the divine one for which the world has been waiting.
Prem means love; lalit means beautiful. Love is beautiful, and anything else, that which is not love, is bound to be ugly.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
5 November 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, anadi means beginningless – the beginningless god. God has no beginning, no end. It is eternal.
Prem means love, adi means beginning – beginning of love, and that is the beginning of sannyas. If you can help them to become more and more loving, that’s all, they will become perfect sannyasins.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
6 November 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
And there is not only the sound outside, there is also a garden within. There is a music inside too, and it is far more beautiful, because the outer is confined by time and space. The inner is completely free of all limitations. The inner is eternal music; once one has heard it, one goes on hearing it forever.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
7 November 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, agya means order or commandment – a divine order. Man cannot choose god; it is always god who chooses man. Man cannot enquire on his own, it is impossible. The desire to enquire into truth comes from the beyond; it is an order from above, it is a commandment.
And to be initiated is not an ordinary matter.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
8 November 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, sugito means a song, a divine song. Life can become a divine song, it has the potential but the potential is not yet actual; it has to be actualised. That is the work of sannyas: to help the potential to come to a realisation.
This is the most subtle art, because man is the most mysterious being on the earth.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sacred_yes/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
9 November 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, nikash means criterion. Love is the criterion, the touchstone. One has to test everything in life from the criterion of love. If love says it’s okay, then it is okay; if love says no, then you are going astray. If one simply follows the subtle indications of love one arrives at god naturally, without any effort.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
