<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Shadow Of The Whip on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_whip/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Shadow Of The Whip on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_whip/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chapter title: Be a Pure Hedonist</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_whip/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_whip/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter title: Be a Pure Hedonist‌ 18 November 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium Archive code: 7611185 ShortTitle: WHIP10 Audio:
No Video:
No
[To a sannyasin, newly arrived:]
Do a few groups here, mm? Join the music group and become part of the family here. Music melts people very easily. Otherwise something remains frozen and one is not even aware of it. So the first necessity of all growth is to be relaxed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter title: Childbirth can be orgasmic</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_whip/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_whip/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter title: Childbirth can be orgasmic‌ 13 November 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium Archive code: 7611135 ShortTitle: WHIP06 Audio:
No Video:
No 1/08/07
Copyright Osho International Foundation 1994
Osho&#39;s books on CD-ROM, published and unpublished Query:-
[A sannyasin, eight months pregnant, asks: There is one thing I wanted to ask -- if there is any possibility, is there something that the mother can do to reduce the break of memory that the child has through the birth and to make it as easy as possible for the child?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter title: God is also Darkness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_whip/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_whip/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter title: God is also Darkness‌ 29 November 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium Archive code: 7611295 ShortTitle: WHIP20 Audio:
No Video:
No 1/08/07
Copyright Osho International Foundation 1994
Osho&#39;s books on CD-ROM, published and unpublished Query:-
[A visitor asks which groups he needed to do.]
You book for [three groups] and then I will tell you what else to do. The camp will reveal many things about you -- how your energy is moving and where, and what is needed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter title: Laughter is Prayer</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_whip/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_whip/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter title: Laughter is Prayer‌ 17 November 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium Archive code: 7611175 ShortTitle: WHIP09 Audio:
No Video:
No
[Osho gives sannyas to a five-year-old girl and she skips back to her seat. Osho speaks to her parents:]
Anand means bliss, joy, and hasya means laughter. Teach her to laugh more and more. And when you play with her, keep the atmosphere of laughter around her.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter title: Live at the Maximum</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_whip/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_whip/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter title: Live at the Maximum‌ 1/08/07
Copyright Osho International Foundation 1994
Osho&#39;s books on CD-ROM, published and unpublished Query:-
25 November 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium Archive code: 7611255 ShortTitle: WHIP16 Audio:
No Video:
No
Anand means bliss and amara means eternal, deathless, immortal. And in the East we define bliss as that which is eternal. Happiness is that which is momentary.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter title: Nothing Fails Like Success</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_whip/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_whip/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter title: Nothing Fails Like Success‌ 21 November 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium Archive code: 7611215 ShortTitle: WHIP13 Audio:
No Video:
No
It is raining today so I remember Indra; Indra is the indian mythological god of rains. In India we have changed everything into a god. The river is a god, a tree is a god; the thundering clouds, the rain --</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter title: Search for the Undefined</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_whip/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_whip/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter title: Search for the Undefined‌ 12 November 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium Archive code: 7611125 ShortTitle: WHIP05 Audio:
No Video:
No
Shanti means silence, peace, a state of no mind, and prabhu means lord; lord of silence. And that&#39;s how I see your energy moving -- it is moving towards the great silence. You are holding it. If you stop holding it you will simply plunge into a totally different dimension.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter title: The Essential is One</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_whip/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_whip/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter title: The Essential is One‌ 9 November 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium Archive code: 7611095 ShortTitle: WHIP02 Audio:
No Video:
No
Sannyas is a disidentification with the past... a new beginning, a new being, a fresh breeze, a rebirth. All that is implied in giving you a new name. One name was given to you by your mother and father. Now I am giving you another name.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter title: The Magic is Here</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_whip/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_whip/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌Chapter title: The Magic is Here‌ 3 December 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium Archive code: 7612035 ShortTitle: WHIP24 Audio:
No Video:
No
[Osho asks a visitor how long he has been here. The visitor replies that he has lost track of time.]
That&#39;s very good, mm? When one can really lose track of time, one has really arrived! Very good. Being here one loses track of time and space both.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter title: You are Freedom</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_whip/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_whip/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter title: You are Freedom‌ 11 November 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium Archive code: 7611115 ShortTitle: WHIP04 Audio:
No Video:
No
[A sannyasin who is leaving for the States: For the last three or four days I feel very lost. I don&#39;t know what my position is. I don&#39;t know what my role is or anything.]
There is no need to know it and nobody knows exactly.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
