<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Turn On, Tune In and Drop the Lot on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Turn On, Tune In and Drop the Lot on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
1 December 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Samvad means communion. Man is living as an island, and that’s from where all misery arises. Down the centuries man has been trying to live independently from existence. That is not possible in the very nature of things. Man can neither be independent nor dependent. Existence is a state of interdependence: everything depends on everything else.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
10 December 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Premendra. It means god of love. Love has to become the very centre of your whole life. Whatsoever you do, it has to be kept in mind that you are doing it out of love, that you are doing it for love. It has to be part of your growing heart, then only does one enter into the world of god.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
12 December 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[December 11th was Osho’s birthday celebration darshan in Buddha Hall.]
Sourabh means fragrance. The seed and the flower and the fragrance – these are also the states of human consciousness. Man is born as a seed. There is no necessity that the seed will become the flower; the seed can die as a seed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
13 December 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Niro means the element water. And water is very symbolic, symbolic of flow, symbolic of non- resistance, symbolic of let-go. And these have to become the qualities of a sannyasin.
One should never become stagnant, because life is a process, a constant process; the moment you stop the process you are dead. Life is a river, on-going, from infinity to infinity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
14 December 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Sitaro. It is the root of the word ‘star’, the Sanskrit root. It means the star...
Remember that the real star is within. And the real star is not even a whispering star: it is utterly silent, not even a whisper. And we reach it only when we are totally silent.
Even if a little whispering remains, that is enough of a barrier, that is enough of a wall.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
15 December 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, iman means faith. Man can either live in belief or in faith. Belief is man-made: faith is a grace that comes from beyond. Belief is a thing of the mind: faith, a stirring in the heart. Belief is superficial, it never transforms anybody. Rather than transforming it only consoles. It is convenient to be a Hindu, to be a Christian, to be a Mohammedan, because the crowd is there, surrounding you in every way.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
16 December 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Darpano means the mirror. The moment one starts functioning as a pure mirror, god is revealed immediately. God is already here: we are just not a mirror to him. One need not search for god, because he is not far away: he is very close, he is closer to you than you are to yourself.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
17 December 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Sangit, means music; and music is something that is the most spiritual, religious, and the most expressive of the existence of god. Where words fail, music succeeds. Words can only describe god: they go round and round. Music can represent; it is very symbolic.
So become more and more musical in your being. Life has to be treated as a musical instrument.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
18 December 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love. And only love brings victory; everything else brings defeat. Money brings defeat, power brings defeat, success brings defeat. Only love brings victory; that is one of the most fundamental laws of life.
We try everything but we never try love. That’s why there is so much depression, despair in the world.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
19 December 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Veet means beyond, charitro means character. I don’t teach character: I teach consciousness. Character is a false phenomenon, imposed from the outside. It is fulfilling others’ expectations about you. It is not growth, because it has not arisen out of your own spontaneity. It is a conditioning, and all conditionings are slaveries, subtle strategies of the society to manipulate the individual, to destroy the individual.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
20 December 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, wilayat means a sage. The birth of a sage is through love, not through knowing. It is not a head phenomenon, it is a heart phenomenon. The saint remains in the head; he cultivates it thoughtfully. The sage disappears into the heart. The saint is very clever, calculating, logical, methodological. The sage is almost mad, but his madness has beauty, his madness has a transcendence; it is something not of this world.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
2 December 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Atit means beyond, manaso means mind. The whole pilgrimage consists only of one step: from mind to no-mind. The mind is the world: no-mind is nirvana. The mind is a state of sleep: no-mind is an awakening. Everyone is a born Buddha, but fast asleep, dreaming a thousand and one dreams lost in the world of thoughts and desires and aspirations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
21 December 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Arhata means one who has arrived. Man is in a constant wandering. He is always departing from one point for another, but he is never arriving anywhere. It is much ado about nothing. The mind goes in circles, and when you move in a circle you cannot arrive. You can go on moving forever, for eternity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
22 December 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Srajan means creativity. The highest value in existence is creativity, and it is creativity that brings you close to the creator, nothing else; there is no other bridge. Only a creative person comes to know something of god. And it is always only something, because god is infinite: the more we know the more there is to know.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
23 December 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, darpano means mirror – mirror for the divine. And this is the whole art of meditation. God is; we just have to mirror him. Our mirror is covered with layers of dust. We are not to go anywhere to search and seek because god is everywhere, as much here as there.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
24 December 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, anando means bliss. Love and bliss are two aspects of the same energy. They always happen together: if one happens, the other follows, has to follow. They cannot be divided, they are indivisible. And just like that, hate and misery are two aspects of the same phenomenon: the person who is full of hate can never be blissful; and the person who is full of love can never be anything else other than blissful.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 24
25 December 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Veet means beyond, apeksha means expectation. The root cause of misery is to expect, and the mind is full of expectations. The more you expect, the more you will feel frustrated; frustration is a shadow of expectation. Nobody wants to be frustrated but everybody goes on expecting ‘Things should be like this’ and they never are.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 25
26 December 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, bhadrena means grace. There are things which man can achieve by his own efforts and there are things which he can never achieve by his own efforts. The things that man cannot achieve by his own efforts are the really valuable things. The things that man can achieve will be lost sooner or later, death will take them away; they are momentary.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 26
27 December 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Manava means a real human being. There are millions of human beings on the earth but it is very difficult to find a real human being. The humanity of the millions is just an appearance; in truth it doesn’t exist, it is only a facade, a mask. Deep down they have not yet grown to be human.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 27
28 December 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means god, prarthi means in prayer. Prayer is not something that you do or that you can do: it is something in which you can be. It is a state of being, not a state of doing. Prayer simply means in deep communion with existence. It is not a dialogue, it is not a verbal communiCation; it is non-verbal.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part28/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 28
29 December 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, dipa means an earthen lamp – a small lamp of love. Love’s small lamp is far more significant. far more powerful, than the whole darkness of hate, anger, greed. The darkness of the centuries is not so powerful, so potent, as just a small flame of love. Darkness has no power, it is impotent; in fact it does not exist, it only appears to exist.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>29</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part29/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 29
30 December 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, sahaja means spontaneous. Love is true only when it is spontaneous, unplanned, unpracticed, uncultivated, unthought. Whenever you plan for love, whenever deliberateness enters into it it becomes phony and false. And that’s why people go on loving yet it never satisfies, because no phony food can be nourishing.
True love has to be spontaneous, it has to happen without any preparation preceding it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
3 December 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Svadesh means homeland. Man’s search is for his real homeland. In this world man is a stranger, a foreigner; he lives a kind of uprooted life. Something essential is missing: he is missing the soil where he can grow his roots. His life remains an empty gesture. a constant occupation just so he remains occupied, so that he can forget, forget the longing for the homeland.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>30</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part30/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 30
31 December 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Darpana means a mirror. Thinking is a barrier: mirroring is the way. To think is to miss: to reflect is to get. Truth has not to be invented but only discovered. And the veil is not on truth; it is on our mirror. Truth is utterly naked, it is not covered. So when I say ‘It has to be discovered’ I mean that we have to open up to it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
4 December 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin mother with her exuberant child, says: Sometimes his energy is too much and I don’t know what to do with him.]
It’s perfectly good; this is the time he should have more energy. Don’t repress his energy. Each child brings great energy into the world but we repress it; that is a kind of crippling.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
5 December 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, pravasi means a stranger – a divine stranger.
Man is a stranger on the earth; this is not his true home, hence the search. All search is basically the search for the source, the true home. And whatsoever we make here on the earth disappears: all these palaces that we make are made of playing cards.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
6 December 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Madhuma means absolutely sweet – that’s the taste of god. Buddha is reported to have said: Truth is sweet in the beginning, in the middle, in the end; truth is sweet all over. If it feels bitter to us, and sometimes it does, that simply shows that we have become too accustomed to the lies.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
7 December 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, subhadro means grace. There are things which man can do and there are things which man can never do. There are things which only god can do; and all that is great comes into that category. Man can do only mundane things which have no ultimate value. Utility they have but value they don’t have.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
8 December 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, sambhavo means potential. Love is not an actuality, it is only a seed, and the seed can die without ever becoming the actual. That’s the risk of life: every man is born with a possibility but it is only a possibility – it may be actualised, it may be missed. If it is missed then life remains futile, meaningless, a tale told by an idiot, full of fury and noise signifying nothing – because love is the significance, love is the meaning.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/turn_on_tune_in_and_drop_the_lot/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
9 December 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Veeto means transcendence; and that’s the secret of all meditation. It is the very foundation of all religion. That which we know as the world is only the periphery; the centre is hidden. The centre is transcendental. It cannot be seen by the eyes, it cannot be heard by the ears, it cannot be touched by the hands, yet it is, yet it can be experienced.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
