<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>The No Book (No Buddha, No Teaching, No Discipline) on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The No Book (No Buddha, No Teaching, No Discipline) on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
1 August 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, blissfulness, and buddha means the awakened state of consciousness – the utterly awakened state when there is no more any unconscious desire, when there is no dark corner left, when all is consciousness within... when the conscious goes on spreading, spreading, and takes over the whole territory of the unconscious.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
10 August 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A new sannyasin agrees to do the groups Osho suggests, but says she would like to travel around india first.]
I think the better course will be that first you be here and then travel...
First groups. Then you will have a better vision to see the country; you will have a better attitude.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
11 August 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem Rahim. Prem means love, rahim means compassion. Love for those whom you can love.… And I don’t demand the impossible: I don’t say to love all because theat will not be possible. Love is something you cannot manage. Sometimes it clicks and you feel love arising for a person; sometimes it doesn’t click.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
12 August 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin couple are leaving for the West. The man explains they have to travel on separate days because the wife had come to poona after him.]
Mm mm, separately?...
That’s very good... that’s very good! We come separately and we go separately, and all our meetings are just on the way, mm? One should remember it – that we are strangers – and one should never take the other for granted; that destroys all love.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
13 August 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Deva Marifa – the divine way of knowing. It’s a sufi term. Osho explains that God can be known in two ways, either through intelligence or through feeling... the way through intelligence is marifa... ]
You have to become more and more alert, more and more mindful: watch life, watch yourself. Try to come out of the sleep everybody is in; that slumber has to be broken.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
14 August 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss and sujan means awareness. This has to be remembered – that awareness is good only when it is suffused with blissfulness. If it is dry it will enhance the ego; if it is dry, with no joy in it, it will not lead you towards the divine; it will make you more and more self-centred.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
15 August 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A visitor says she wants to leave the work she is doing in an embassy in rome and to separate from her husband, who is a writer but earns no money.
Osho advises her to leave him unless she wants to be a babysitter for the rest of her life! He says that a relationship should only be out of love and for no other reason.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
16 August 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho talks about monastic life... ]
So help the monks to get free... they need to!
They are good people, they are in search; they are honest sincere people. They are good people but they are trapped and it happens that good people are easily trapped because they are not cunning. It is very difficult to trap cunning persons.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
17 August 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Jivan means life, harito means green – green life, fresh life, young life. and always remember that life is green, theories are grey. Avoid the theories and plunge into life. Theories are suicidal, poisonous; they destroy. Life is divine, life is eternity.
To get in tune with life is to enter into god, and to remain confined to the theories is to remain in the prison of the mind.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
18 August 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Prem Deval... let love be the god and you become the temple... Feel love for anybody and for everybody... for all, with no conditions.…
... Shift from the intellectual to the world of feeling. Intellectuality is just rubbish. Words cannot fulfil, logic cannot satisfy. One can have beautiful philosophies but one remains ugly; those philosophies don’t help.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
19 August 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love and chandralekha is a mythological tree, a tree that is found in paradise. The whole name will mean, a love tree of paradise. Get more and more in tune with trees and you will find great moments of silence through it. Just sitting by the side of the tree get lost in it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
2 August 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho gives someone sannyas.]
Just drop the control over the body, and if the body starts leaning backwards, forwards, or sideways, allow it. If it falls, allow it to fall like a lump. Just relax into death... because death is exactly like meditation.
[The new sannyasin closes his eyes and then opens them.]</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
20 August 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho gives sannyas to someone who had great difficulty to decide to take sannyas, because of her commitments in the West.]
The decision was difficult – decisions are always difficult but it is good to be decisive. Sometimes one may even take a wrong decision; then too it is better to be decisive rather than remaining indecisive, because in indecisiveness one disintegrates, one becomes fragments; one has a centre no more.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
21 August 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho and warns a new sannyasin that much is going to happen so not to be afraid!]
It is very natural that when something really starts happening one becomes frightened, because we have become so accustomed to a life where nothing happens, so when something starts happening one gets frightened. We want it to happen, but when it really starts happening we become afraid because we have become very much accustomed to a dull and dead routine life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
22 August 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says: I have had a dream for years... It is only a feeling – I have no pictures, nothing, but it’s a feeling. There’s a feeling of death.
Osho checks his energy.]
The dream is significant and has much to convey to you. It is not just a rubbish dream; it is a good indication of something that is going to happen.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
23 August 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin, who is a journalist, says he would like to change his job towards more growth oriented work, but is afraid of the insecurity. Osho assures him that any security he fancies he has now is illusory, and that real life is in insecurity – so that shouldn’t be a factor. Uncertainty is a blessing, because it opens new doors]</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 24
24 August 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says that during a group she began to speak in a language she knew nothing about. She has a fever afterwards. Since the group it has been happening many times to her. Osho tells her to go into it while he checks her energy.]
You have stumbled upon a beautiful method of meditation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 25
25 August 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Deva Nasti – divine nothing. The past is something, Osho says – solid, concrete, there. And the future is absolutely uncertain but you can create a kind of certainty that is projection, desires, dreams. Between these two the present remains out of our reach. The past is, the future is – the present is not.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 26
26 August 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho gives a three-year-old girl sannyas. The mother says her daughter wants to ask Osho about dying. She wants Osho to tell her where everything goes when it dies.]
That’s very good.All children are interested in death; it is one of the natural curiosities. But rather
than answering them – because all answers will be false.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 27
27 August 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin who is leaving asks if it is okay for her not to be in a relationship. She also says she can feel Osho inside and is confused because he is outside.]
I understand... I understand. It will be happening to many many sannyasins soon. It is something very significant and you are fortunate to be feeling that.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part28/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 28
28 August 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss and haramita is a japanese form of a sanskrit word, ‘paramita’. ‘Paramita’ means going to the other shore. The unknown is the other shore, god is the other shore. The visible is this shore; the invisible is the other shore. So the whole search is for the other shore. This shore is not satisfying – it only creates more and more desires and more and more frustrations; it is utterly futile.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>29</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part29/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 29
29 August 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[To a sannyasin couple who are leaving Osho says:]
Manage to come forever; become a part. I will be calling all of my people to stay with me now, so prepare...
Because now it will be needed. The work has to take on a totally new dimension and I will be working now on deeper planes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
3 August 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin, leaving for the west, says: The whole thing about leaving does not come from within; it comes from without – conditions and situations... But to stay comes from within.]
I know... That too is true. And as far as the within is concerned, you are staying; only the without is going. No need to worry about it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>30</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part30/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 30
30 August 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, pargal means mad – divinely mad. And just by remaining ordinarily sane god cannot be attained. For the ordinary sanity nothing of the eternal is possible because the eternal needs total commitment, utter involvement. Of that only a madman is capable.
By madness I mean when you put aside your mind and you don’t listen to the mind at all; you listen to the heart.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>31</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part31/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 31
31 August 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho gives sannyas to an Indian prince.]
Mayoor is so good and so meaningful. Mayoor is the symbol of dance and celebration and joy... and if life becomes joyful, then nothing else is needed. It is through joy that god comes; it is through joy that the first contact happens. So create this dancing energy around you.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
4 August 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho explains the meaning of deva maneeshi, divine wisdom, explaining the difference between the western and eastern ideas of a wise man.]
Wisdom has nothing to do with thinking or knowledge. In fact just the contrary is the case: when thinking disappears there is wisdom. It is not the ultimate in thinking but the absencewhen the</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
5 August 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva Viyog. It means separation from god. That’s where we are... that’s why there is so much anguish; and once we consciously understand it union becomes possible. Right now we are separate, we are like islands – have lost contact with the continent. We have forgotten that we are rooted in god: god seems to be just a fantasy, not a reality.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
6 August 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho gives someone sannyas.]
Raise your hands and close your eyes, and just feel as if you are being born from the mother’s womb, right now this moment, and whatsoever body posture comes, allow it. If you start crying, weeping, it’s okay. Just think of birth. If your body falls and starts rolling or anything, just allow it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
7 August 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho gives sannyas.]
Close your eyes, and just feel as if you are dying; just relax the body. If the body falls, don’t be worried: allow it, cooperate. Go on feeling as if you are dying, dying, dying. At the very moment when you are almost dying it is very simple for me to make a contact with you.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
8 August 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, upeeksha literally means ‘indifference’, but in english there is no exact word for it. Indifference feels like something negative; upeeksha is something very positive.
It means a centering of consciousness so that you are not wavered by anything. Success comes, it is okay; failure comes, it is okay. That is called upeeksha.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_no_book_no_buddha_no_teaching_no_discipline/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
9 August 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyas brings her young son to take sannyas and says that she is afraid he may get sick here, so she is reluctant to do groups.]
No, no, he will not get sick; no need to be afraid. He will not get sick, mm? And if you are too much afraid your fear can create something.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
