<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Socrates Poisoned Again After 25 Centuries on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Socrates Poisoned Again After 25 Centuries on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 I belong to the whole world</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
I belong to the whole world
19 February 1986 pm in
QUESTIONS FROM The Rajneesh Times, GERMANY. Question 1
YOU ARE TRAVELING LIKE THE POPE. DO YOU WANT EVERYBODY TO BECOME A SANNYASIN?
The first thing to be remembered: you cannot compare me to the pope. He represents Jesus Christ, and through Jesus Christ he represents God.
I represent no one.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Pope the polack is the antichrist</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
Pope the polack is the antichrist
24 February 1986 am in
Question 1
FOR THE LAST MONTH, THE VATICAN HAS BEEN SUGGESTING TO THE ITALIAN CATHOLIC MEDIA TO KEEP SILENT ABOUT YOUR EXISTENCE. SUCH A THING HAS NOT EVEN HAPPENED REGARDING THE TERRORISTS. THIS SEEMS TO SHOW THAT THE POPE IS AFRAID OF YOU.
PLEASE COMMENT.
The pope and other religious leaders of the world are not afraid of terrorists, but they are afraid of me.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 Utopia is just around the corner</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
Utopia is just around the corner
24 February 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHAT DO YOU SAY TO THE PEOPLE WHO CALL YOU A UTOPIAN?
They are right – just their idea of utopia is not right. They think that utopia is something which cannot be achieved; that’s exactly the meaning of the word utopia. Sir Thomas More wrote a book called UTOPIA, in which he hopes for everything that man has always aspired to but has never been able to achieve.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 You are accepted by the whole universe</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
You are accepted by the whole universe
25 February 1986 am in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
GOETHE ONCE WROTE IN HIS ‘GOETZ VON BERLICHINGEN’, “POVERTY, CHASTITY AND OBEDIENCE – UNBEARABLE ARE THEY ALL.”
WHAT DO YOU THINK ABOUT HIS STATEMENT?
It is absolutely correct. These are the three calamities that have ruined the very being of humanity.
Obedience means, in other words, slavery.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 Growing your own consciousness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
Growing your own consciousness
25 February 1986 pm in
Question 1
SOCIAL RULES SEEM TO BE A BASIC NEED FOR HUMAN BEINGS. YET NO SOCIETY HAS EVER HELPED MAN TO REALIZE HIMSELF. CAN YOU PLEASE EXPLAIN WHAT KIND OF RELATIONSHIP EXISTS BETWEEN INDIVIDUALS AND SOCIETY, AND HOW THEY CAN HELP EACH OTHER TO EVOLVE?
It is a very complex question, but very fundamental too.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 It is your mind again</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
It is your mind again
26 February 1986 am in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
SOME YOUNG PEOPLE IN GERMANY OFTEN USE THIS MOTTO: “GOD DOES NOT EXIST, BUT STILL I HATE HIM.”
PLEASE COMMENT.
The experience of hate is not very far away from love. It is love standing on its head.
The people who say, “God is dead but still I hate him,” do not understand what they are saying, and where they are going.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 The logic of the ostrich</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
The logic of the ostrich
26 February 1986 pm in
Question 1
HAVE THE HARDSHIPS WHICH YOU HAVE JUST LIVED THROUGH CAUSED YOU TO MODIFY YOUR PHILOSOPHY? DO YOU FEEL RESENTMENT?
I do not have a philosophy; hence nothing can make any difference to it. I have a way of life, and there is no possibility which can modify it because it is not a mind projection, it is my innermost being and its experience.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 Only idiots are consistent</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
Only idiots are consistent
27 February 1986 am in
Question 1
YOU ARE SURPRISING AND SHOCKING PEOPLE BY ALWAYS GIVING CONTRADICTORY ANSWERS TO GERMANS. WHY DO YOU WANT TO STUDY THE QUESTIONS NOW BEFOREHAND?
Just so that I can surprise you. Question 2
YOU ONCE SAID THAT TO THE SAME QUESTION YOU CAN GIVE A THOUSAND DIFFERENT ANSWERS. SO WHY DO YOU WANT TO PREPARE FOR AN INTERVIEW?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 This too will pass</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
This too will pass
27 February 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHEN I LEAVE YOUR DISCOURSES, I FEEL TREMENDOUSLY GOOD AND BRIGHT, BUT STILL I’M AFRAID TO GET INFLUENCED AGAIN BY PEOPLE OUTSIDE SO THAT I FALL BACK AGAIN INTO MY OLD MIND. CAN YOU SAY SOMETHING ABOUT ENERGIES AND EXPERIENCES, AND HOW WE CAN MOVE IN THE MARKETPLACE WITHOUT GETTING INFLUENCED BY OTHER PEOPLE WHO HAVE NOT SUCH GOOD ENERGY.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 Logic is a prostitute</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
Logic is a prostitute
28 February 1986 am in
Question 1
THERE IS A DUTCH PROVERB WHICH SAYS: CHILDREN AND FOOLS SAY THE TRUTH. WHERE DO YOU FIT IN?
The proverb has great wisdom in it. The moment one comes to know the truth, he becomes both – a child on his part, a fool in the eyes of others. They are not two things.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19 Rabbis and rubbish!</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
Rabbis and rubbish!
28 February 1986 pm in
Question 1
YOU ALWAYS SAY THAT YOU ARE NOT THE DOER OF WHAT IS HAPPENING AROUND YOU. STILL, THE GENERAL TENDENCY IS TO SEE YOU AS THE STAR IN IT ALL.
CAN YOU PLEASE DESCRIBE YOURSELF AND THE MOVEMENT THAT IS EXISTING AROUND YOU AND ITS EVOLUTION THROUGHOUT ALL THESE YEARS?
It is difficult for people to understand something that they have never experienced in their lives.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Time knows only the present tense</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
Time knows only the present tense
20 February 1986 am in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHAT IS THE DIFFERENCE BETWEEN LOVE AND HATRED, BETWEEN GOOD AND BAD?
They are the two sides of the same coin; there is not much difference. Love can change into hate, hate can change into love. And this change is possible only if they both have the same quality.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 Health: overflowing energy of life</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
Health: overflowing energy of life
1 March 1986 am in
Question 1
WESTERN SOCIETIES HAVE DEVELOPED THE COSTLIEST HEALTH SYSTEM THAT EVER EXISTED. PEOPLE SPEND BILLIONS OF DOLLARS A YEAR FOR IT AND IT IS REALLY SUCCESSFUL IN SOME FIELDS OF SURGERY OR IN TRANSPLANTATION AND PREVENTING INFECTIONS. BUT IT SEEMS THAT PEOPLE ARE MORE SICK THAN THEY EVER WERE BEFORE. WHAT IS HEALTH?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 The fear of tomorrow destroys your today</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
The fear of tomorrow destroys your today
1 March 1986 pm in
Question 1
YOU ARE SUCH AN OUTRAGEOUSLY BEAUTIFUL MAN. IS THAT THE REASON WHY MORE WOMEN BECOME SANNYASINS THAN MEN? IS THERE ANYTHING YOU’D LIKE TO SAY ESPECIALLY TO GERMAN WOMEN?
Perhaps you are right. Only one thing I would like to say to German women: they should be attracted to the outrageous and the most beautiful men a little more.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22 The whole existence is with you</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
The whole existence is with you
2 March 1986 am in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I HAVE TO ASK YOU THIS ESOTERIC QUESTION. HOW CAN YOU SAY WITH SUCH CERTAINTY THAT THIS EARTH IS THE ONLY PLACE IN THE UNIVERSE WHERE LIFE HAS BLOSSOMED, AND CONSCIOUSNESS HAS ARISEN?
HOW DO YOU KNOW?
It is not an esoteric question; it belongs to the inner science of man.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23 A new world a new man</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
A new world a new man
2 March 1986 pm in
Question 1
MANY PEOPLE ARE READY TO SIMPLY CHANGE THEIR STATE OF BEING, BUT THEY ARE TERRIFIED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF THE END OF THE WORLD. I, TOO, TOYED AROUND LIKE A PUPPET UNTIL I SEARCHED IN THE SCRIPTURES. I FOUND OUT THAT THE ANCIENT PHRASE IS NOT “THE END OF THE WORLD” BUT “THE END OF TIME” OR “THE END OF DAYS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 Spirituality is not for sale</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 24
Spirituality is not for sale
3 March 1986 am in
Question 1
DO YOU PLAN TO STAY IN GREECE? IF SO, DO YOU WANT TO ESTABLISH A PERMANENT COMMUNE HERE? IF NOT, IS THERE ANY PLACE THAT YOU WOULD CONSIDER GOING?
Greece is beautiful. I would love to stay here, and I would like to establish a big commune too. But it all depends on how much courage the people of Greece have, whether they can digest me or not.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25 Consciousness is contagious</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 25
Consciousness is contagious
3 March 1986 pm in
Question 1
CAN YOU TELL US ABOUT YOUR CONNECTION WITH J. KRISHNAMURTI?
It is a real mystery. I have loved him since I have known him, and he has been very loving towards me. But we have never met; hence the relationship, the connection is something beyond words. We have not seen each other ever, but yet.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26 Sympathy is a false coin</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 26
Sympathy is a false coin
4 March 1986 am in
Question 1
SWITZERLAND IS A RICH AND BEAUTIFUL COUNTRY, BUT THERE ARE SO MANY PEOPLE SUFFERING FOR MANY REASONS, AND THEY EVEN ENJOY THIS. WHY CAN’T THEY USE THEIR FREEDOM AND PROSPERITY TO BE HAPPY?
Humanity can be divided into two parts: the first is sadist, the second is masochist. The sadist enjoys torturing others; the masochist enjoys torturing himself.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27 Existence is never wrong</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 27
Existence is never wrong
4 March 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I FEEL VERY GRATEFUL TOWARDS YOU. SINCE I TOOK SANNYAS, MY LIFE HAS CHANGED AND I HAVE STARTED TO ENJOY MYSELF. BUT THERE IS STILL THE DOER IN ME. I WOULD LIKE TO PRODUCE MORE BEAUTIFUL BOOKS, ESPECIALLY ON YOU. IT IS STILL DIFFICULT FOR ME TO COMBINE BUSINESS AND MEDITATION.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28 Peace or mind</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/part28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/part28/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 28
Peace or mind
5 March 1986 am in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I USED TO THINK THAT RELIGIOUS FEELINGS WERE SOMETHING GREAT, SOMETHING EXCITING AND EXTRAORDINARY WHICH HAPPENED TO ONLY VERY SENSITIVE PEOPLE. BEING WITH YOU, I FEEL VERY FINE AND TENDER LOVE THAT MAKES ME FEEL HAPPY AND WHOLE AND FREE. IT’S SUCH A SIMPLE AND ORDINARY FEELING THAT MY MIND TELLS ME THERE MUST BE SOMETHING GREATER AND MORE INTENSE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 The well is going to the thirsty</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
The well is going to the thirsty
20 February 1986 pm in
QUESTIONS FROM TROS TV, HOLLAND.
Question 1
THIS IS A KIND OF A PARADISE YOU HAVE FOUND AGAIN.
HOW DO YOU MANAGE TO FIND THESE BEAUTIFUL PLACES OVER AND OVER AGAIN? IS IT A DIFFICULT QUESTION? YOU HAVE BEEN THINKING SUCH A LONG TIME..
It is a difficult question, because I never try to find any place.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 The art of not planning life</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
The art of not planning life
21 February 1986 am in
QUESTIONS FROM QUICK MAGAZINE, GERMANY
Question 1
DO YOU THINK THE GERMAN CHANCELLOR IS AFRAID OF YOU?
Absolutely – otherwise there is no reason to make a law that I cannot enter Germany. I have never been in Germany; I have never committed any crime against German law. I have not even applied for any tourist visa, so from my side there has been no question of entering Germany.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Existence does not like carbon copies</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
Existence does not like carbon copies
21 February 1986 pm in
QUESTIONS FROM “TA NEA”, GREECE.
Question 1
HOW WOULD YOU LIKE TO INTRODUCE YOURSELF TO THE GREEK PEOPLE?
My God! Can’t you recognize me? I am the same person you have poisoned twenty-five centuries ago. You have forgotten me, but I have not forgotten you. And just being here for two days, I was thinking that in twenty-five centuries Greece would have evolved towards some better qualities, towards more humanity, towards more truth.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 If you can get it, get it</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
If you can get it, get it
22 February 1986 am in
QUESTIONS FROM NBC TELEVISION, AMERICA.
Question 1
COULD YOU PORTRAY BRIEFLY: WHO ARE YOU? PEOPLE SAY YOU ARE A CROOK. ARE YOU A CROOK?
I am just a mirror. When a crook looks at me, he sees a crook in me. It all depends on you.
As far as I am concerned, it is impossible to portray me.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Zorba is my past: buddha is my present</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
Zorba is my past: buddha is my present
22 February 1986 pm in
QUESTIONS FROM AP, VPI AND REUTERS NEWS AGENCIES.
Question 1
CAN YOU TELL US WHY, AS AN ADMIRER OF SOCRATES, YOU DON’T PRACTICE THE SOCRATIC METHOD OF DIALOGUE?
Dialogue is possible between two blind men; they can discuss ad infinitum about light without coming to any conclusion. Dialogue is impossible between two persons who can see light: the dialogue is unnecessary; light is the experience of both.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 The center of the cyclone</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
The center of the cyclone
23 February 1986 am in
QUESTIONS FROM NEWSWEEK, USA. SONNTAGS BLICK, SWITZERLAND TEMPO, GERMANY
Question 1
DO YOU SOMETIMES FANTASIZE, AND IF SO, COULD YOU GIVE US SOME EXAMPLES?
It is impossible for me to fantasize. I have lost my mind and its stupid activities thirty-five years back. Right now I am just utterly empty of words, dreams, fantasies.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 Truth is a search, not a faith</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/socrates_poisoned_again_after_25_centuries/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
Truth is a search, not a faith
23 February 1986 pm in
Question 1
WHY ARE YOU GOING TO ITALY?
I do not believe in nations. The whole of humanity is one. I am going to Italy because Italy is there. Question 2
WHAT DO YOU KNOW ABOUT ITALY AND THE ITALIAN PEOPLE?
I know everything about the Italian people. My first Western sannyasins were Italians; they introduced me to the West.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
