<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Far Beyond the Stars on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Far Beyond the Stars on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 The moment you become part of the community, you dissapear</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌The moment you become part of the community, you dissapear
2 July 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Rama prem. It means love for god, and create that love more]
It is there, it is just like a small drop; it can become an ocean, it can become bigger than you. And when it is bigger than you and when you are drowned in it, you have arrived.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Meditate on the early morning\....</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
Meditate on the early morning.…
13 July 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, and aruna means early morning, dawn... the sun is just going to rise, just before sunrise. Mm? the East becomes red but the sun is not yet on the horizon – it is coming; it is very imminent, just within a second it will be there but it is not there yet.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 The key is in your hands</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
The key is in your hands
14 July 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, manoj means out of the mind, born out of the mind, so the whole name will mean, born out of the divine mind.
And that’s where we come from, that’s the stuff we are made of. We can forget about it but we cannot be other than it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 With me, nobody is going to be a loser</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
With me, nobody is going to be a loser
15 July 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin, returning to the West, says: I’d just like to ask you about sannyas for my children. I have two children, six and eight, and they’re probably going to come back with me in January for about six months.
I have some doubts about sannyas, that it seems to be another form of baptism to put on them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 No answer is needed\....</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
No answer is needed.…
16 July 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, nirvakar means purity, innocence, virginity.…
It is a very very important term in the East – nirvakar. It means your originalness, the way you essentially are, uncorrupted by anything foreign from the outside... Like the mirror when nothing is reflected in it: a mirror not reflecting anything, not even a reflection corrupting it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 While you are here let your head disappear</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
While you are here let your head disappear
17 July 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho gives someone sannyas.]
Sit here! Raise your hands and close your eyes and just think of yourself as a tree. Forget that you are in the human body but are in the body of a tree and these hands are like branches in the sky.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 Now begin the enquiry into god</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
Now begin the enquiry into god
18 July 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
The new name is of tremendous significance: it is closing accounts with the old, getting out of the old continuity.
The name is the only continuity: everything else goes on changing, only the name remains continuous, and because of the name, the fallacy exists that we are not changing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 I am not a guru \-- at the most a friend</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
I am not a guru – at the most a friend
19 July 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A new sannyasin reminds Osho that he had darshan with him a year ago but did not take sannyas because he had just left the Israeli army and wanted to see a bit of life.]
Mm mm, good, but that was not the right time – one has to wait for the right time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 We can all become gods\....</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
We can all become gods.…
20 July 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho explains to a new sannyasin, You are ready for me, and for many more things! Having a new name is significant, because it is my reading of you and it has a message. It is like a seed that I have put in your hearat. Soon you will find many things arising out of this small seed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 You have known me, heard me \-- you cannot go back</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
You have known me, heard me – you cannot go back
21 July 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva avigan – divine harmony... and that’s what has to be attained.…
That’s what is missing everywhere in every human being: people are in discord, in conflict, in division. Man is not one, man is a crowd, and that is the problem. So one part of you is going north, another part going south, and there is constant friction.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19 Happiness is a gift that only you can give to yourself</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
Happiness is a gift that only you can give to yourself
22 July 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin married couple bring their one-year-old daughter for sannyas.]
Deva tara... It means divine star. Tar means star, mm? – the english word ‘star’ comes from the sanskrit root ‘tara’. In sanskrit it is ‘sitara’; from sitara it has become tara in Hindi and star in English.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 One needs the courage to be oneself</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌One needs the courage to be oneself
3 July 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho explains the meaning of prem veeresh. Prem means love and veeresh means courage, and you have to imbibe the spirit of love and courage. Love is the basic quality of the religious man, and out of love, courage grows.]
When I was a small child at school there was a wrestling competition for the whole district; I have never been able to forget that incident.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 Being lost is the beginning of finding oneself</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
Being lost is the beginning of finding oneself
23 July 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin, who is returning to the West, says he is feeling emotionally exhausted since he completed the primal group two months ago: I feel there’s just big wounds inside me, and I’m just a bit afraid that they won’t heal when I go back to the west.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 A space created for people who want to be spontaneous\...</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
A space created for people who want to be spontaneous...
24 July 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho checks the energy of a sannyasin who has come to darshan for the first time.]
The energy is perfect... just on the verge, mm? Something is going to happen, it can be predicted. Very few people are on the verge, so much has to be done before they can come to that, to the verge, because only from the verge is the jump possible.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22 My work is with individuals</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
My work is with individuals
25 July 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho explains the meaning deva aukash. It means divine space]
Create more and more space within yourself. Remove all furniture, remove everything from the inside; let there be just pure emptiness. When nothing exists, god exists: nothing is synonymous with god.
When you cannot find anything within yourself, not even yourself, then god isthat very space is</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23 The unfamiliar has to be invited, the unknown has to be loved\...</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
The unfamiliar has to be invited, the unknown has to be loved...
26 July 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin who is leaving says: I’m a horrible kid, she says, embarrassed – I’m always wasting everything!]
Stop doing that, because it is wasting a great opportunity; you are not wasting anything else but your own opportunity. Life is very precious and these moments may not be repeated.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 Spirituality is a vision of living this life with totality</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 24
Spirituality is a vision of living this life with totality
27 July 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho gives a seeker sannyas.]
And just start visualising a bluish light at the third eye... just a bluish flame. Forget everything and let that flame be there, the only focus... the whole consciousness focused on it.…
Prem means love, chinmaya means consciousness – love consciousness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25 The significance is not in the goal but in the journey</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 25
The significance is not in the goal but in the journey
28 July 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A new sannyasin says he’s been doing zen meditation for two years... he was frustrated; it was only discipline.]
It is... but we will change it. Once you have passed through a few cathartic groups, you will start enjoying the same zen meditation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26 Become a part of the family</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 26
Become a part of the family
29 July 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin who is a teacher says she gets angry with her students. No, we will take it away, promises Osho. The problem is not with the students – it is with you. The expectations create trouble, and teachers down the ages have enforced things; now they can’t do that.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27 Everybody is carrying a sun within him</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 27
Everybody is carrying a sun within him
30 July 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Anand suriya. Anand means bliss, suriya, the source of light: the sun, blissful source of light... ]
And everybody is carrying a sun within him. If we are living in darkness it is not because we don’t have light; it is because we never look at the light.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28 Life is eternal dance, a non-ending hallelujah!</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/part28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/part28/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 28
Life is eternal dance, a non-ending hallelujah!
31 July 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho suggests groups to a newly arrived sannyasin, who replies that he has been running groups himself in London. Osho stresses the importance of his putting aside all his knowledge, for it is a barrier. When people become knowledgeable they lose the childlike quality of innocence and the ability to wonder, to be surprised.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Love is the natural meditation</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
Love is the natural meditation
4 July 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says: If I run a group and the group goes well I feel good, and if not, I feel bad. I wanted to ask you how to avoid this... how can I avoid this dependence?]
Rather than avoiding it... Because it can be avoided but then you will miss something; then the quality of the work will suffer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Will divides, awareness unites</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
Will divides, awareness unites
6 July 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin asks about the pattern her relationships seem to fall into: I feel very attracted to a kind of power, aura, and then in the end it’s very destructive for meI find myself loving that person a
lot and then they tell me that they don’t really think that they’re interested in me.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Sannyas is pure adventure</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
Sannyas is pure adventure
7 July 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
First, a few things about sannyasIt is an initiation into the formless. It is not an initiation into some
rigid form, it is not giving you a certain discipline – on the contrary it is an initiation into freedom, into a formless creative chaos.
The old concept of sannyas all over the world was to give you a rigid discipline, to give you a character, to give you a certain form, a pattern, a life style.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Sipping tea can be prayer</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
Sipping tea can be prayer
8 July 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
A few things about sannyasThe oldest concept of sannyas was very life-negative, it was utterly
against life, but my idea of concept is absolutely life-affirmative. Nothing has to be dropped, everything has to be transformed. All that is available is immensely valuable: anything denied will never allow you to be whole, and if you are not whole you can never be holy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 When the abyss is your home</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
When the abyss is your home
9 July 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine and himani means coolness – mm? divine coolness. And that is the whole secret of bliss: if one wants to be blissful in existence, one has to be cool. The moment we become hot we lose our centre; the moment we become hot we start moving towards the periphery.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 The victory that comes through surrender</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
The victory that comes through surrender
11 July 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Jayananda. It means victory and bliss... but this victory is something very paradoxical: it comes only when you stop desiring it; it comes only when you accept your utter defeat.
So there are two kinds of victories in the world: one is that which comes through desire, aggression, fight, mm?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 Every pain can become a satori</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/far_beyond_the_stars/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
Every pain can become a satori
12 July 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin who came to Osho because he has cancer of the foot, has just discovered that it has now spread to the rest of his body. He says he feels strangely at peace. He is returning to the West.]
Mm mm, no, nothing to be worried about; just go.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
