<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Meditation. The Art of Ecstasy on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation_the_art_of_ecstasy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Meditation. The Art of Ecstasy on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/meditation_the_art_of_ecstasy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 Meditation: The Art of Celebration</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation_the_art_of_ecstasy/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation_the_art_of_ecstasy/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
Meditation: The Art of Celebration
Concentration is a choice. It excludes all except its object of concentration; it is a narrowing. If you are walking on the street, you will have to narrow your consciousness in order to walk. You cannot ordinarily be aware of all that is happening because if you are aware of everything that is happening you will become unfocused.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Sannyas: Dying to the Past</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation_the_art_of_ecstasy/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation_the_art_of_ecstasy/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
Sannyas: Dying to the Past
That is why I can initiate anyone into sannyas. To me, initiation itself is a play. And I will not ask for any qualifications – whether you are qualified or not – because qualifications are asked when something serious is done. Just by existing everyone is qualified enough to play, and even if he is unqualified to be a sannyasin it makes no difference, because the whole thing is just a play.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 Total Desire: The Path to Desirelessness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation_the_art_of_ecstasy/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation_the_art_of_ecstasy/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
Total Desire: The Path to Desirelessness
Whatever we say and mean by life is just a journey toward death. If you can understand that your whole life is just a journey and nothing else, then you are less interested in life and more interested in death. And once someone becomes more interested in death, he can go deep into the very depths of life; otherwise, he is just going to remain on the surface.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 What is the Soul?</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation_the_art_of_ecstasy/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation_the_art_of_ecstasy/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
What is the Soul?
QUESTION: WHAT IS IT THAT YOU CALL ATMAN, SOUL? IS THIS SOUL CONSCIOUSNESS ITSELF OR IS IT SOMETHING INDIVIDUAL?
Really, no matter what we call it, we will miss it. Any conceptualization is going to miss the real – any conceptualization – so whatever has been known as the self, the soul, the atman, is not the real thing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 LSD and Meditation</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation_the_art_of_ecstasy/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation_the_art_of_ecstasy/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
LSD and Meditation
QUESTION: CAN LSD BE USED AS A HELP IN MEDITATION?
LSD can be used as a help, but the help is very dangerous; it is not so easy. If you use a mantra, even that can become difficult to throw, but if you use acid, LSD it will be even more difficult to throw.
The moment you are on an LSD trip you are not in control.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 Intuition: A Non-Explanation</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation_the_art_of_ecstasy/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation_the_art_of_ecstasy/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
Intuition: A Non-Explanation
QUESTION: CAN INTUITION BE EXPLAINED SCIENTIFICALLY? IS IT A PHENOMENON OF THE MIND?
Intuition cannot be explained scientifically because the very phenomenon is unscientific and irrational. The very phenomenon of intuition is irrational. In language it looks okay to ask, “Can intuition be explained?” It means: can intuition be reduced to intellect? But intuition means something beyond the intellect, something not of the intellect, something coming from someplace where intellect is totally unaware.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 Consciousness, Witnessing amp; Awareness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation_the_art_of_ecstasy/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation_the_art_of_ecstasy/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
Consciousness, Witnessing amp; Awareness
QUESTION: WHAT IS THE DIFFERENCE BETWEEN AWARENESS AND WITNESSING?
There is much difference between awareness and witnessing. Witnessing is still an act; you are doing it, the ego is there. So the phenomenon of witnessing is divided between the subject and the object.
Witnessing is a relationship between subject and object. Awareness is absolutely devoid of any subjectivity or objectivity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 The Difference between Satori amp; Samadhi</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation_the_art_of_ecstasy/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation_the_art_of_ecstasy/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
The Difference between Satori amp; Samadhi
QUESTION: WHAT IS THE DIFFERENCE IN EXPERIENCE BETWEEN SATORI – IN ZEN, A GLIMPSE OF ENLIGHTENMENT – AND SAMADHI, COSMIC CONSCIOUSNESS?
Samadhi begins as a gap, but it never ends. A gap always begins and ends – it has boundaries: a beginning and an end – but samadhi begins as a gap and then is everlasting.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 Sexual Energy amp; the Awakening of the Kundalini</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation_the_art_of_ecstasy/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation_the_art_of_ecstasy/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
Sexual Energy amp; the Awakening of the Kundalini
QUESTION: HOW DOES ONE OVERCOME THE PULL TOWARD SEX SO THAT THE KUNDALINI CAN GO UPWARD?
Energy has been going downward through the sex center continuously for many births, so when any energy is created it will first try to move downward. That is why meditation sometimes will create more sexuality in you than you have ever felt before.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 The Manifestations of Prana in the Seven Bodies</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation_the_art_of_ecstasy/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation_the_art_of_ecstasy/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
The Manifestations of Prana in the Seven Bodies
QUESTION: WHAT IS PRANA AND HOW IS IT MANIFESTED IN EACH OF THE SEVEN BODIES?
Prana is energy – the living energy in us, the life in us. This life manifests itself, as far as the physical body is concerned, as the incoming and the outgoing breath. These are two opposite things. We take them as one.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19 Traditional Techniques</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation_the_art_of_ecstasy/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation_the_art_of_ecstasy/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 19
Traditional Techniques
A flower that has never known the sun and a flower that has encountered the sun are not the same. They cannot be. A flower that has never known the sunrise has never known the sun to rise within itself. It is dead; it is just a potentiality. It has never known its own spirit. But a flower that has seen the sun rise has also seen something arise within itself.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Yoga: the Growth of Consciousness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation_the_art_of_ecstasy/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation_the_art_of_ecstasy/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
Yoga: the Growth of Consciousness
The evolution of life is to become more and more conscious, but the consciousness is always other oriented: you are conscious of some thing, some object. Yoga means to be evolving in the dimension where there is no object and only consciousness remains. Yoga is the method of evolving toward pure consciousness; not being conscious of something, but being consciousness itself.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Non-Doing Through Doing</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation_the_art_of_ecstasy/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation_the_art_of_ecstasy/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
Non-Doing Through Doing
Non-doing is meditation, but when I say non-doing is meditation I do not mean that you need not do anything. Even to achieve this non-doing, one has to do much. But this doing is not meditation. It is only a stepping stone, only a jumping board. All “doing” is just a jumping board, not meditation.
You are just on the door, on the stepsThe door is non-doing, but to reach the non-doing state of</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 \&#34;Chaotic\&#34; Meditation</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation_the_art_of_ecstasy/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation_the_art_of_ecstasy/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
“Chaotic” Meditation
QUESTION: IT IS AN INTERESTING COINCIDENCE THAT YOUR MEDITATION TECHNIQUE OF RELEASE THROUGH INTENSE CHAOTIC BREATHING EVOLVED AT THE SAME TIME THAT CERTAIN CHAOTIC THERAPY TECHNIQUES WERE HAPPENING IN THE WEST, SUCH AS R.D.LAING’S THEORY THAT SCHIZOPHRENIA IS NOT SOMETHING TO BE FOUGHT, BUT SOMETHING TO BE EXPERIENCED VOLUNTARILY. LAING HAS SAID THAT YOU CANNOT BE SANE UNTIL YOU HAVE BEEN NON-SANE OR INSANE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Dynamic Meditation or, Silent Meditation</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation_the_art_of_ecstasy/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation_the_art_of_ecstasy/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
Dynamic Meditation or, Silent Meditation
QUESTION: DYNAMIC MEDITATION IS VERY ACTIVE, VERY STRENUOUS.CAN ONE NOT GO INTO MEDITATION JUST BY SITTING SILENTLY?
You can go into meditation just by sitting, but then be just sitting; do not do anything else. If you can be just sitting, it becomes meditation. Be completely in the sitting; nonmovement should be your only movement. In fact, the word zen comes from the word zazen, which means, just sitting, doing nothing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Moving Deeply into the Known</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation_the_art_of_ecstasy/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation_the_art_of_ecstasy/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
Moving Deeply into the Known
You cannot seek the divine, it cannot be sought after, because you can seek only that which you know already. Seeking means desiring and you cannot seek something that is unknown. How can you seek something that you have not known at all? The very urge to seek comes only after you have tasted something, known something – even a glimpse.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Kundalini: The Awakening of the Life Force</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation_the_art_of_ecstasy/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation_the_art_of_ecstasy/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
Kundalini: The Awakening of the Life Force
One reason is that any knowledge about kundalini or about esoteric paths of bioenergy – the inner paths of elan vital – is generalized. It differs from individual to individual; the root is not going to be the same. With A it will be different, with B it will be different, with C it will be different.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 Enlightenment: An Endless Beginning</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation_the_art_of_ecstasy/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation_the_art_of_ecstasy/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
Enlightenment: An Endless Beginning
There are no degrees of enlightenment. Once it is, it is there. It is just like jumping into an ocean of feeling. You jump, you become one with it, like a drop dropping into the ocean becomes one with it. But that doesn’t mean that you have known the whole ocean.
The moment is total: the moment of dropping the ego - the moment of ego elimination, the moment of egolessness - is total; it is complete.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 Initiation to a Master: The Ultimate Technique</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation_the_art_of_ecstasy/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation_the_art_of_ecstasy/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
Initiation to a Master: The Ultimate Technique
When I say that man is asleep, this has to be understood. We are dreaming continually, twenty-four hours a day. In the night we are closed to the outward world, dreaming inside. In the day our senses are opened toward the outside world, but the dream continues inside. Close your eyes for a moment, and you can again be in a dream; it is a continuity inside.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
