<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Perennial Path. The Art of Living on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_perennial_path_the_art_of_living/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Perennial Path. The Art of Living on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/the_perennial_path_the_art_of_living/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 Nonviolence</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_perennial_path_the_art_of_living/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_perennial_path_the_art_of_living/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
Nonviolence
9 November 1970 am in
Violence is a disease of human beings, but it is not so for beasts. For beasts, it is their nature. There is no possibility of nonviolence at the level of beasts. That is why they haven’t got any idea of violence. Violence is the disease which man bas inherited from beasts, and it is a disease obstructing his evolving consciousness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Source of violence in man</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_perennial_path_the_art_of_living/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_perennial_path_the_art_of_living/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
Source of violence in man
10 November 1970 am in
There would not be any difference if a person sitting in his cave on a dark night of the last day of the dark half of the months keeps his eyes closed or open. There will be darkness even if the eyes are closed or open. But there would be difference if that person keeps on sitting with his eyes closed when morning comes, the sun is rising, the rays the of the sun are falling on the door of the cave and birds begin to sing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Material prosperity and nonpossessiveness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_perennial_path_the_art_of_living/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_perennial_path_the_art_of_living/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
Material prosperity and nonpossessiveness
11 November 1970 am in
Material prosperity is the basis of spiritual life, without which no building is constructed Foundations can be there without buildings. Some one may leave the foundation as it is after filling it to the top; then the building will not be there in spite of the foundation. Prosperity is the basis of the condition which is above passions and passionlessness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Nonstealing</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_perennial_path_the_art_of_living/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_perennial_path_the_art_of_living/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
Nonstealing
12 November 1970 am in
Life is a network of interconnected relationships. An individual is required to be interrelated. Even an interrelationship is a relationship between two individuals. But two individuals are necessary for a relationship to establish. So life when seen from outside is interrelated; but along with it life is also interrelated from within. If that individual is not there, all the interrelationships become false.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Process of progress</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_perennial_path_the_art_of_living/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_perennial_path_the_art_of_living/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
Process of progress
13 November 1970 am in
Nonviolence, nonpossessiveness, nonstealing, desirelessness and awareness are the fundamental vows of the art of sannyas. Sannyas like life is an art. Only those who are experts in the art of life can achieve sannyas. The art of sannyas goes beyond life. Only those who can experience life in its totality are able to enter sannyas.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Self energy from sex energy</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_perennial_path_the_art_of_living/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_perennial_path_the_art_of_living/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
Self energy from sex energy
14 November 1970 am in
Life can be viewed in two ways in all its layers. Life has two aspects – one is material, and the other is spiritual. It is necessary to examine sex also from these two directions. One aspect of sex is biological which is linked with the body and its particles. The other is of energy, of soul which is linked with the mind by consciousness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Tantric path to super energy</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_perennial_path_the_art_of_living/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_perennial_path_the_art_of_living/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
Tantric path to super energy
15 November 1970 am in
Tantra is a philosophy of nonduality. It accepts life in its totality – even the wicked, the inauspicious, the darkness. Tantra accepts them not with a view to treat darkness as darkness or to treat bad as bad or to treat inauspicious as inauspicious, but because there is a possibility of transforming inauspicious into auspicious.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 Perfect knowledge</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_perennial_path_the_art_of_living/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_perennial_path_the_art_of_living/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 8
Perfect knowledge
16 November 1970 am in
A person wishes to go into the depths of an ocean after tying himself with chains to the shore. He wants to go deep into the depths of the ocean and also wants to know what difficulties, hurdles, he will have to face. We shall have to tell him that his first problem is that he is clinging to the chains on the shore.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
