<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Secret of Secrets, Vol 1 on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_1/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Secret of Secrets, Vol 1 on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 Animus and Anima</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_1/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_1/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
Animus and Anima
11 August 1978 am in Buddha Hall
MASTER LU-TSU SAID: THAT WHICH EXISTS THROUGH ITSELF IS CALLED THE WAY (TAO) TAO HAS NEITHER NAME NOR SHAPE. IT IS THE ONE ESSENCE THE ONE PRIMAL SPIRIT. ESSENCE AND LIFE CANNOT BE SEEN. THEY ARE CONTAINED IN THE LIGHT OF HEAVEN. THE LIGHT OF HEAVEN CANNOT BE SEEN. IT IS CONTAINED IN THE TWO EYES.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 The Zorba-Buddha Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_1/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_1/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
The Zorba-Buddha Synthesis
20 August 1978 am in Buddha Hall
The first question:
Question 1
OSHO, ALL MY LIFE I HAVE SAID YES AND NOW THAT I AM HERE WITH YOU AND THE YES SEEMS REALLY RIGHT, THERE COMES ONLY NO. WHAT IS THIS NO?
Bhadra, it is very natural. If all your life you have been saying yes, it must have been false, it must have been pseudo.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 The Whole and Holy Circle</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_1/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_1/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
The Whole and Holy Circle
21 August 1978 am in Buddha Hall
MASTER LU-TSU SAID: NOTHING IS POSSIBLE WITHOUT CONTEMPLATION. PERCEIVING BRINGS ONE TO THE GOAL.
WHAT HAS TO BE REVERSED BY REFLECTION IS THE SELF-CONSCIOUS HEART, WHICH HAS TO DIRECT ITSELF TOWARDS THAT POINT WHERE THE FORMATIVE SPIRIT IS NOT YET MANIFEST. WITHIN OUR SIX-FOOT BODY WE MUST STRIVE FOR THE FORM WHICH EXISTED BEFORE THE LAYING DOWN OF HEAVEN AND EARTH.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 To Create a Balance</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_1/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_1/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
To Create a Balance
22 August 1978 am in Buddha Hall
The first question:
Question 1
IS IT FAIR TO PUT POLITICIANS WITH DOGS?
I am sorry. I apologize – because dogs are so innocent. It is not fair at all. The second question:
Question 2
WHAT IS NEUROSIS AND WHAT IS THE CURE FOR IT?
Neurosis has never been so epidemic in the past as it is now.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 A Listening Heart</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_1/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_1/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
A Listening Heart
23 August 1978 am in Buddha Hall
MASTER LU-TSU SAID: THE DECISION MUST BE CARRIED OUT WITH A COLLECTED HEART AND NOT SEEKING SUCCESS; SUCCESS WILL THEN COME OF ITSELF. IN THE FIRST PERIOD OF RELEASE THERE ARE CHIEFLY TWO MISTAKES: INDOLENCE AND DISTRACTION. BUT THAT CAN BE REMEDIED; THE HEART MUST NOT ENTER INTO THE BREATHING TOO COMPLETELY.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 The New Man</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_1/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_1/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
The New Man
24 August 1978 am in Buddha Hall
The first question:
Question 1
OSHO, WHAT ACCORDING TO YOU IS THE MOST SIGNIFICANT THING THAT IS HAPPENING TODAY IN THE WORLD?
A new man is emerging. The image of the new man is not yet clear, but the horizon is becoming red and the sun will soon be there. The morning mist is there and the image of the new man is vague, but still a few things are very crystal clear about the new man.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 Beyond Indolence and Distraction</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_1/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_1/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
Beyond Indolence and Distraction
25 August 1978 am in Buddha Hall
MASTER LU-TSU SAID: THE TWO MISTAKES OF INDOLENCE AND DISTRACTION MUST BE COMBATED BY QUIET WORK THAT IS CARRIED ON DAILY WITHOUT INTERRUPTION; THEN SUCCESS WILL CERTAINLY BE ACHIEVED. IF ONE IS NOT SEATED IN MEDITATION, ONE WILL OFTEN BE DISTRACTED WITHOUT NOTICING IT. TO BECOME CONSCIOUS OF THE DISTRACTION IS THE MECHANISM BY WHICH TO DO AWAY WITH DISTRACTION.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 In the Lake of the Void</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_1/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_1/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 16
In the Lake of the Void
26 August 1978 am in Buddha Hall
The first question:
Question 1
WOULD YOU PLEASE COMMENT FURTHER ON THE DIFFERENCES BETWEEN C. G. JUNG’S ‘PROCESS OF INDIVIDUATION’ AND THE ESSENCE OF THE SECRET OF THE GOLDEN FLOWER?
Habib, Carl Gustav Jung was groping in the right direction but he had not yet arrived. It was not his own experience, it was a philosophy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Empty Eyes</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_1/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_1/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
Empty Eyes
12 August 1978 am in Buddha Hall
The first question:
Question 1
LATELY SEVERAL FRIENDS HAVE ASKED ME IF I WAS SCEPTICAL TOWARDS SANNYAS, THE ASHRAM AND YOU. I HAD TO ADMIT TO THE TRUTH AND SAID, ‘YES, AT TIMES I AM.’ THIS LEFT ME WITH A FEELING OF GUILT. HAVE I COMMITTED SOME UNFORGIVABLE, SACRILEGIOUS CRIME OR IS IT NATURAL TO BE SCEPTICAL OUT OF BEING SURE?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 The Atomic Moment</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_1/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_1/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
The Atomic Moment
13 August 1978 am in Buddha Hall
MASTER LU-TSU SAID: ONLY THE PRIMAL SPIRIT AND THE TRUE NATURE OVERCOME TIME AND SPACE.
THE PRIMAL SPIRIT IS BEYOND THE POLAR DIFFERENCES. HERE IS THE PLACE WHENCE HEAVEN AND EARTH DERIVE THEIR BEING. WHEN STUDENTS UNDERSTAND HOW TO GRASP THE PRIMAL SPIRIT THEY OVERCOME THE POLAR OPPOSITES OF LIGHT AND DARKNESS AND TARRY NO LONGER IN THE THREE WORLDS BUT ONLY HE WHO HAS ENVISIONED HUMAN NATURE’S ORIGINAL FACE IS ABLE TO DO THIS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 I Mean Business Here!</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_1/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_1/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
I Mean Business Here!
14 August 1978 am in Buddha Hall
The first question:
Question 1
THE RIVER ULTIMATELY REACHES THE SEA. THE BODY GOES AND THERE REMAINS ONLY EXISTENCE, THE INFINITE. WHAT THEN IS THIS URGE AND THE PURPOSE OF GETTING THERE NOW? ISN’T IT PUSHING THE RIVER?
Hamid, the problem is that man is NOT a river, man is very much frozen.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 To be One Again</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_1/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_1/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
To be One Again
15 August 1978 am in Buddha Hall
IN THE BODY IS THE ANIMA. THE ANIMA IS FEMININE (YIN), IT IS THE SUBSTANCE OF CONSCIOUSNESS.
BUT, BESIDES THIS, THERE IS THE ANIMUS IN WHICH THE SPIRIT SHELTERS. THE ANIMUS LIVES IN THE EYES: IT SEES, IT DREAMS. BUT WHOEVER IS IN A DARK AND WITHDRAWN MOOD, AND CHAINED TO HIS BODILY FORM, IS FETTERED BY THE ANIMA.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Born with Joy</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_1/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_1/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
Born with Joy
16 August 1978 am in Buddha Hall
The first question:
Question 1
WHY IS IT SO DIFFICULT TO ENJOY?
Rani, it is difficult to enjoy because you will have to disappear. Joy is possible if you are not. You and joy cannot coexist: when joy is there you are absent, when you are there joy is absent. They are like light and darkness – they can’t exist together in the same place.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Turning the Key</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_1/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_1/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
Turning the Key
17 August 1978 am in Buddha Hall
MASTER LU-TSU SAID: WHEN THE LIGHT IS MADE TO MOVE IN A CIRCLE, ALL THE ENERGIES OF HEAVEN AND EARTH, OF THE LIGHT AND THE DARK, ARE CRYSTALLIZED. WHEN ONE BEGINS TO APPLY THIS MAGIC IT IS AS IF, IN THE MIDDLE OF BEING, THERE WERE NON-BEING. WHEN IN THE COURSE OF TIME THE WORK IS COMPLETED, AND BEYOND THE BODY THERE IS A BODY, IT IS AS IF, IN THE MIDDLE OF NON-BEING, THERE WERE BEING.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 Real is for Always</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_1/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_1/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
Real is for Always
18 August 1978 am in Buddha Hall
The first question:
Question 1
WOULD YOU TALK ABOUT THE RELATIONSHIP BETWEEN DISILLUSIONMENT AND CELEBRATION. I’M FEELING A STRANGE MIXTURE OF THE TWO – A DYING AND A COMING TO LIFE AT THE SAME TIME.
Venu Gopal, mind lives in illusions. And to live in illusions is to be miserable, because they cannot be fulfilled.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 Riding on a Miracle</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_1/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_1/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
Riding on a Miracle
19 August 1978 am in Buddha Hall
MASTER LU-TSU SAID: ‘RELEASE IS IN THE EYE... THE SEED-BLOSSOMS OF THE HUMAN BODY MUST BE CONCENTRATED UPWARD IN THE EMPTY SPACE.’ IMMORTALITY IS CONTAINED IN THIS AND ALSO THE OVERCOMING OF THE WORLD.
THE LIGHT IS NOT IN THE BODY ALONE, NOR IS IT ONLY OUTSIDE THE BODY. MOUNTAINS AND RIVERS AND THE GREAT EARTH ARE LIT BY SUN AND MOON; ALL THAT IS THIS LIGHT.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
