<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Om Mani Padme Hum on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Om Mani Padme Hum on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 The music of OM</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
The music of OM
7 December 1987 am in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
WOULD YOU LIKE TO SAY SOMETHING ABOUT THE FAMOUS TIBETAN MANTRA, “OM MANI PADME HUM”?
Maneesha, the only country in the world which has devoted all its genius to the inner exploration is Tibet. Its findings are of tremendous value. Om mani padme hum is one of the most beautiful expressions for the ultimate experience.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 We disown our past</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
We disown our past
26 December 1987 am in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
ARE IDIOTS BORN OR TRAINED?
Nirupa, it is a complicated question. Almost ninety percent of idiots are trained. Ten percent are born. And the ten percent are born because of those ninety percent who have been trained.
Man from his very beginning has lived a very weird life – weird in the sense that it needs idiots.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 The very nature of things</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
The very nature of things
26 December 1987 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
IS ENLIGHTENMENT BEYOND THE NATURE OF THINGS?
Milarepa, enlightenment is the very nature of things. But it has never been said that way; on the contrary, people’s minds have been corrupted by creating a goal against nature, giving it beautiful names, “supernature.” And man was caught in this because of a very simple reason:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Existence has its own ways</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
Existence has its own ways
27 December 1987 am in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
I CAN RELATE TO THE TASTE OF GOOD GERMAN CHOCOLATE, BUT WHAT ABOUT THE TASTE OF ENLIGHTENMENT?
Devageet, mind has an incurable disease: the name of the disease is duality. It does not matter what the mind is focused on, it immediately creates a division – in the knower and in the known, in the observer and in the observed, in the subject and in the object; in short, between I and thou.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 Reality is indivisible</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
Reality is indivisible
27 December 1987 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
IN THE WEST, CELEBRATION IS ASSOCIATED WITH THE AMERICAN IDEA OF HAVING A GOOD TIME WHICH IS SYNONYMOUS WITH NOISE, LOUD MUSIC, WATCHING MOVIES, SMOKING, SEX, AND RELEASE OF ENERGY AS SUCH, WHILE SILENCE AND SERENITY ARE AUTOMATICALLY ASSOCIATED WITH BOREDOM AND EXCESSIVE ACCUMULATION OF ENERGY WHICH RESULTS IN TENSION AND ANXIETY.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 A rock among the waves</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
A rock among the waves
28 December 1987 am in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
AS YOU GREET US, AND AGAIN AS YOU LEAVE, YOU ARE POURING YOUR ENERGY ON US. HOW COME MY BODY DOESN’T GRACEFULLY BOW DOWN TO YOU? I KNOW MY HEART DOES! AM I A ROCK AMONG THE WAVES?
Deva Ashu, I myself have been watching.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 For no reason at all</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
For no reason at all
28 December 1987 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
THE MORE I TRUST IN MEDITATION THE MORE I FEEL MY HEART OPENING AND VASTLY PRESENT. AT THE SAME TIME I LOSE KNOWLEDGE ABOUT WHO I AM, WHY I AM HERE AND FOR WHAT. I CAN’T DO ANYTHING ABOUT IT EXCEPT WATCH, CRY, LAUGH, SING, GIGGLE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 The psychology of the buddhas</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
The psychology of the buddhas
29 December 1987 am in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
WHAT IS THE PSYCHOLOGY OF THE BUDDHAS? IT SOUNDS LIKE A SCIENCE ONLY FOR ENLIGHTENED BEINGS WHO NEED TO PULL, PUSH, SEDUCE, HIT OR KISS THEIR DISCIPLES AT THE RIGHT MOMENT, SO THAT THEY DON’T WOBBLE, GET STUCK OR FALL INTO TRAPS. CAN YOU PLEASE REVEAL SOME OF YOUR FINDINGS OF THE PAST THIRTY YEARS?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 Immediate and ultimate ordinariness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
Immediate and ultimate ordinariness
29 December 1987 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
I HEARD YOU SAYING THAT WE ARE ALL ENLIGHTENED. IF SO, WHY AM I WAITING FOR SOMETHING TO HAPPEN? IS IT AN OLD HABIT?
Veet Vigyanam, it is one thing to hear; it is another thing to understand. You certainly heard me saying that we are all enlightened, but you did not trust it – at least you excluded yourself.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 Personality: the false disease</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
Personality: the false disease
30 December 1987 am in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
AS YOU GLIDE INTO BUDDHA HALL, SLOWLY TURNING TOWARDS WHERE I SIT WAITING FOR YOUR GAZE TO TOUCH ME, A STRANGE OVERWHELMING FEAR GRIPS ME. I SAY TO MYSELF, “DARSHAN, AFTER ALL THESE YEARS OF BEING WITH HIM, WHY THIS FEAR?” THEN AS YOUR EYES CARESS ME, THE FEAR MELTS IMMEDIATELY, I MELT AND SOMETHING LOVELY STARTS DANCING WITHIN ME.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19 Simply singing my own song</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
Simply singing my own song
30 December 1987 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
THERE IS NOTHING I NEED TO KNOW – I JUST LOVE THE SOUND OF YOUR VOICE. PLEASE COMMENT.
Deva Pagalo, it is not a coincidence that I have given you a name which means “the madman.” It is a very rare and unique situation to be meditative and to be mad.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 A very simple and humble affair</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
A very simple and humble affair
7 December 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
IS BLISSFULNESS AN EXPRESSION OF GRATITUDE TOWARDS EXISTENCE?
Sanjiva, it is just the reverse. Blissfulness is not an expression of gratitude; on the contrary, gratitude is an expression of blissfulness. First comes the experience of bliss. First you attain to the state of consciousness where ecstasy is natural, where your potential blossoms to its ultimate expression.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 Life has no boundaries</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
Life has no boundaries
31 December 1987 am in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
CAN YOU PLEASE TALK ABOUT THE ART OF NOURISHING ONESELF WITH LOVE? I FEEL SO MUCH LOVE FOR YOU! IS THIS ENOUGH?
Deva Bhasha, love is never enough. There are mysteries in existence which don’t have any limitation. Love is the closest experience to understanding all those mysteries – because as far as the mind is concerned, it imposes limits; it cannot accept anything that is unlimited.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 The twain are already meeting</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
The twain are already meeting
31 December 1987 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER
IT IS SO GOOD TO BE BACK AGAIN. SITTING IN YOUR DISCOURSE I FIND MYSELF CONNECTING WITH MY INSIDE TO AN EXTENT THAT DOESN’T HAPPEN IN THE WEST. WHAT IS THIS ALCHEMY?
Sat Vijaya, your question can be answered only if you can understand the phenomenon of energy fields.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22 This is my secret: this silence</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
This is my secret: this silence
1 January 1988 am in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
THE OTHER NIGHT YOU WERE LIKE A MASTER MUSICIAN PLAYING A BEAUTIFUL MELODY ON THE STRINGS OF MY HEART. BELOVED MASTER, IS THIS YOUR SECRET IN LETTING ME SING MY SONG MORE AND MORE?
Anand Premartha, music is the only language that comes very close to silence, the only sound which is able to create the soundless.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23 I stand for the whole man</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
I stand for the whole man
13 January 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
WOULD YOU LIKE TO COMMENT ON THE DIFFERENCES BETWEEN BEING WITHDRAWN, BEING INTROVERTED AND TURNING IN?
Prem Ageha, Western psychology has created a very schizophrenic situation by dividing man into extroverts and introverts. Man is one. This division has been destructive of all humanity and its whole past.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 Nirvana means nothingness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 24
Nirvana means nothingness
14 January 1988 am in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
ALL MY LIFE I HAVE BEEN INTRIGUED BY POWER AND THE RECOGNITION I CAN TAKE FROM IT. NOW, THAT SEEMS VERY CONFINED AND PETTY. YET, I SENSE ALSO THAT THERE IS A MORE AUTHENTIC TYPE OF POWER, NOT DEPENDENT ON OTHER PEOPLE OR THEIR REACTIONS – MORE WITHIN MYSELF.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25 Nowhere to fall to</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 25
Nowhere to fall to
14 January 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
FOR YEARS NOW, I HAVE BEEN SITTING BY YOUR SIDE. KNOWINGLY AND UNKNOWINGLY, AN INNER MOUNTAIN HAS BEEN CLIMBED, EFFORTLESSLY FOR THE MOST PART. JUST TODAY I LOOKED DOWN AND IT FRIGHTENED ME HOW FAR OFF THE GROUND I AM. A FEAR THAT I COULD FALL GRIPS ME.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26 Not a \`work\&#39; but a celebration</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 26
Not a ‘work’ but a celebration
15 January 1988 am in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
OFTEN, WHEN I LOOK AT THE SUNSET, SADNESS ARISES FROM DEEP WITHIN. IT FEELS AS IF THE SUN IS MY HOME – THE PLACE I WILL RETURN TO WHEN “THE WORK” IS DONE. BUT NOW I HAVE FALLEN IN LOVE WITH “THE WORK,” THIS EARTH, THIS EXISTENCE, THESE PEOPLE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27 Unhinge yourself</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 27
Unhinge yourself
15 January 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
WHEN I FIRST SAT IN FRONT OF YOU AT WOODLANDS, FOURTEEN YEARS AGO, THERE WAS AN EXPLOSION INSIDE. I DON’T KNOW WHAT IT MEANS, BUT I’VE OFTEN HAD THE FEELING THAT ALL I’VE BEEN TRYING TO DO EVER SINCE IS CATCH UP TO SOMETHING THAT HAS ALREADY HAPPENED.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28 Start with meditation</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part28/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 28
Start with meditation
16 January 1988 am in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
YOUR SILENCE GOES SO DEEP INTO MY HEART THAT IT MAKES MY LOVE UNCONDITIONAL. BELOVED MASTER, IS THIS WHAT “SATSANG” IS?
Satyam Svarup, there are two ways to look at life. One is the way of the schizophrenic. That has been followed by the crowds around the world down the centuries.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>29 Just be a little saner</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part29/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 29
Just be a little saner
16 January 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
I AM A TWENTY-FOUR-YEAR-OLD GERMAN GUY AND AFTER DOING A PRIMAL GROUP I KNOW PRETTY WELL THAT I DON’T WANT TO ACCEPT ANY OTHER FATHER OR MOTHER THAN ME.
NOW I LIKE YOUR TEACHING, YOUR DESTROYING OF MY OLD CONDITIONING VERY MUCH BUT WHY SHOULD I CHANGE MY NAME, BE A SANNYASIN AND ACCEPT A MASTER WHO SAYS THAT THERE IS NO NEED FOR ANY AUTHORITY?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 This place is for innocence</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
This place is for innocence
22 December 1987 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
WHY IS CHILDLIKENESS COMPARED TO MEDITATION?
Garimo, when a man is reborn, only then he understands the beauty and the grandeur of childhood. The child is ignorant; hence he is unable to understand the tremendous innocence that surrounds him. Once a child becomes aware of his own innocence, there is no difference between the child and the sage.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>30 The greatest synthesis ever</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part30/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 30
The greatest synthesis ever
17 January 1988 am in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
WHAT IS YOUR VISION OF A WORLD ACADEMY OF SCIENCES FOR CREATIVITY?
Amrito, the world has come so close to a point of crisis that the so-called thinkers of the world simply avoid talking about the coming suicide. It is not far away; by the end of the century, if we do not do anything.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Never meditate over something</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
Never meditate over something
23 December 1987 am in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
WHAT DOES IT MEAN TO “MEDITATE OVER” SOMETHING? I KNOW WHAT IT MEANS TO “THINK OVER” SOMETHING; THAT’S WHAT THE MIND IS CONTINUOUSLY DOING: REMEMBERING, ANALYZING, PLANNING, IMAGINING, ETCETERA.
I ALSO CAME TO KNOW A STATE OF MEDITATION WHERE THE “I” IS NO MORE, WHERE ALL THE BOUNDARIES ARE LOST, JUST A MELTING INTO THE WHOLE, A DISAPPEARING, WEIGHTLESSNESS, LIGHT, AND BLISS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Just to relax on the river</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
Just to relax on the river
23 December 1987 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
WHEN I HEARD YOU SAY THAT YOU ARE HERE FOR US AND WE ARE HERE FOR YOU, I WAS SO TOUCHED BY THE SIMPLICITY AND THE TRUTH OF IT. IT WENT TO MY HEART LIKE AN ARROW. OH BELOVED MASTER, IT’S ALL SO DEEP.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Don\&#39;t just accept: rejoice!</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
Don’t just accept: rejoice!
24 December 1987 am in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
WHAT IS TOTAL ACCEPTANCE?
Milarepa, the very word total acceptance has somewhere in it the shadow of non-acceptance. Total acceptance has been preached because people are living in total rejection; whatever happens to them, they are bound to find something wrong in it.
It is something very important to understand that all our so-called religious qualities are reactions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Time to be completely disillusioned</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
Time to be completely disillusioned
24 December 1987 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
IT SEEMS THAT AN AUTOMATIC PROCESS, MORE LIKE A PREGNANCY, HAS TAKEN OVER THE STEERING WHEEL. I DON’T HAVE TO DO A THING, THOUGH I CAN’T STOP LISTENING. INSIGHTS PRESENT THEMSELVES EVEN IF NOT ASKED FOR. IS THIS THE MEANING OF THE EXPRESSION “A GOOD SADHANA IS EFFORTLESS”?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 Aha!</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
Aha!
25 December 1987 am in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
A FEW WEEKS AGO, I WAS AWAKE, AND SUDDENLY THERE WAS ONLY TALKING. THERE WAS NO TALKER. FOR YEARS I HAD LISTENED TO THE STATEMENT THAT THE OBSERVER AND THE OBSERVED WERE ONE. I SAW THERE WAS NO ROOM, NO NECESSITY FOR A THINKER; ONLY CONSCIOUSNESS AND THE ARISING OF PHENOMENA.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 These games keep you retarded</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/om_mani_padme_hum/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
These games keep you retarded
25 December 1987 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
YOU HAVE NOW BEEN ENLIGHTENED FOR ALMOST THIRTY-SIX YEARS. HOW DOES IT FEEL TO BE BEYOND THE BEYOND THE BEYOND?
P.S. CAN I MEET YOU IN THE PUB AFTERWARDS?
Vimal, it seems you have taken too much drink, because we are in the pub!</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
