<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>The New Dawn on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The New Dawn on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 Life is such a puzzling affair</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
Life is such a puzzling affair
18 June 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I HAVE TRIED, AND CANNOT FIND THE WORDS THAT ADEQUATELY CONVEY THE BEAUTY OF THOSE MOMENTS WHEN YOU ENTER THE AUDITORIUM. I SEE THE HEADS OF MY BELOVED FRIENDS BEND DOWN: THEIR LOVE AND REVERENCE FOR YOU IS SO POIGNANT, AND TOUCHES ME SO DEEPLY.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Deja vu \-- a small fragment from the past</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
Deja vu – a small fragment from the past
23 June 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHO ARE YOU? SOMEWHERE I FEEL THE ANSWER WILL BE THERE WHEN I REALIZE WHO AM I, YET, WHAT I GET IS ALREADY SO MUCH. TO SIT AT YOUR FEET IS THE GREATEST BLESSING OF ALL MY LIVES. SUDDENLY, I KNOW I AM LOVED BY EXISTENCE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 Only a meditator can be a lover</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
Only a meditator can be a lover
23 June 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I HAVE HEARD YOU SAY THAT THE FRIEND WILL NOT CHANGE A PERSON,BUT THAT THE ENEMY WILL. ANOTHER TIME, I HEARD YOU SAY THAT LOVE WILL CHANGE BOTH.
WOULD YOU PLEASE COMMENT ON LOVE AND ENMITY? HOW DO THEY RELATE TO ONE ANOTHER?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 If you want consolation, go somewhere else</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
If you want consolation, go somewhere else
24 June 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
FROM YOUR ANSWER TO THE WOMAN WHO FALLS IN LOVE WITH BANK BALANCES, NOT THE MAN, I REALIZED THAT I CAN’T EVEN SEE THE MAN, LET ALONE LOVE HIM. I HAVE ACCEPTED MY MOTHER’S ANGRY CONDITIONING TOWARDS MEN. WHEN A MAN COMES TO ME WITH HIS LOVE, I RUN AWAY, WHICH ENCOURAGES HIM TO CHASE ME.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 You go on drinking poison</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
You go on drinking poison
24 June 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
IN YOUR PRESENCE, I FEEL SHOWERED WITH YOUR UNCONDITIONAL LOVE AND COMPASSION. MY HUNGRY HEART IS OPENING, AND I HAVE EXPERIENCED A LOT OF JOY AND STILLNESS HERE IN YOUR BUDDHAFIELD. BUT MY FEELINGS OF UNWORTHINESS STILL DOMINATE MY LIFE, AND I’M CLINGING TO THEM SO TIGHTLY THAT I DESPAIR OF EVER LETTING GO.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 Words from the silences of your heart</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
Words from the silences of your heart
25 June 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I HAVE WRITTEN MANY BEAUTIFUL WORDS ABOUT YOU AND ABOUT YOUR BOOKS – WORDS THAT SEEM TO COME FROM SOME PLACE EITHER BEYOND OR DEEP INSIDE WHEN THEY HAPPEN. AND AFTERWARDS I FEEL ALMOST ASHAMED, AS THOUGH I HAVE SAID SOMETHING WHICH I HAVE NO RIGHT TO SAY.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 You fool around \-- then learn the lesson</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
You fool around – then learn the lesson
25 June 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WOULD YOU SAY SOMETHING TO US ABOUT WISDOM?
Raso, wisdom is one of the most misunderstood words in any of the languages of the world. Mostly, the misunderstanding has arisen because of the word ‘knowledge’. People think both are identical, synonymous. In reality, they are just the opposite of each other.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 The only gift to me: your enlightenment</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
The only gift to me: your enlightenment
26 June 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHAT IS THE RELATIONSHIP BETWEEN ENLIGHTENMENT AND THE SPRING OF LIFE? IS ENLIGHTENMENT THE SPRING OF LIFE?
Chandaram, one basic thing has always to be remembered: not to get involved in questions of intellect. They are pseudo questions, they don’t belong to your experience.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 Letting me in is finding yourself</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
Letting me in is finding yourself
26 June 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHAT IS THE LANGUAGE OF ENLIGHTENMENT?
Milarepa, there is no language of enlightenment. There cannot be by the very nature of the phenomenon. Enlightenment happens beyond mind and language is part of the mind. Enlightenment is experienced in utter silence.
If you want to call silence a language, then of course enlightenment has a language which consists of silence, which consists of blissfulness, which consists of ecstasy, which consists of innocence.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 Beware of the mind: it is blind</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
Beware of the mind: it is blind
27 June 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
DO I HAVE TO KNOW AND UNDERSTAND THE ROOTS OF MY OLD PATTERNS IN ORDER TO BE ABLE TO DROP THEM, OR IS AWARENESS ENOUGH? PLEASE COMMENT.
Deva Suparni, this is the dividing line between Western psychology and Eastern mysticism. Western psychology is an effort to understand the roots of your old patterns, but it does not help anybody to get rid of them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19 Journalism: Making saints out of criminals</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
Journalism: Making saints out of criminals
27 June 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
YOU ARE THE GREATEST MARKETING PERSON OF A PRODUCT THAT GRATIFIES THE SOUL. WE ARE IN THE BUSINESS OF SELLING A PRODUCT THAT GRATIFIES THE MIND; THERE ARE OTHERS WHO SELL PRODUCTS THAT GRATIFY THE BODY. WHAT LESSONS CAN WE LEARN FROM YOU TO EFFECTIVELY MARKET MIND AND BODY PRODUCTS?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Sanity is just boring</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
Sanity is just boring
19 June 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
FOR THE PAST THREE MONTHS, I HAVE BEEN WORKING PHYSICALLY QUITE HARD IN THE GARDEN. I LOVED THE WORK VERY MUCH, AND I FELT DEEPLY CONNECTED TO YOU. IT WAS AS IF YOUR CREATIVITY AND GRACE WERE BLISSFULLY FLOWING THROUGH ME. BUT SOMEHOW IN THE LAST FEW WEEKS, I HAVE FALLEN OUT OF THIS BEAUTIFUL SPACE AND I HAVE SEEN A LOT OF OLD GHOSTS TURNING UP AGAIN: IMPATIENCE, COMPETITIVENESS, PERFECTIONISM, LOTS OF ANGER AND SERIOUSNESS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 Friendliness is enough</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
Friendliness is enough
28 June 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
IS THE CONCEPT OF SOULMATES MORE USEFUL THAN MARRIAGE?
Prem Pragyan, one of the most significant things in man’s life has been the love affair. Birth is not in your hands, death is not in your hands; and these are the only three great things in life: birth, love, and death.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 Genetic science: for those who love creation</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
Genetic science: for those who love creation
28 June 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I HEARD YOU SPEAK OF SCIENTISTS CHOOSING FUTURE PEOPLE FROM THEIR GENETIC ANALYSIS OF SPERMS. I HAVE NO TRUST IN SCIENTISTS, OR DOCTORS OR ANYBODY WHOSE KNOWLEDGE EXTENDS NO FURTHER THAN THEIR HEAD. I INTUITIVELY FEEL THAT GENETICS PLAYS ONLY A SMALL ROLE IN DETERMINING WHAT A PERSON BECOMES.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22 Compassion - love come of age</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
Compassion - love come of age
29 June 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
BUDDHA WAS SAYING AGAIN AND AGAIN TO HIS DISCIPLES THAT MEDITATION AND COMPASSION SHOULD GROW SIDE BY SIDE. THESE DAYS I HAVE BEEN FEELING YOUR COMPASSION AS NEVER BEFORE, AND I HAVE ALSO BEEN FEELING THE URGE TO START LEARNING FROM IT, AT LEAST THE ABC.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23 Existence is very shy</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
Existence is very shy
29 June 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
DURING DISCOURSE THE OTHER NIGHT, I EXPERIENCED MYSELF FILLING WITH AIR LIKE A BALLOON AND BECOMING MIND-BOGGLINGLY ENORMOUS. IT WAS AS THOUGH MY BODY WAS JUST A SKIN OF THE FINEST ELASTIC AND HAD THE CAPACITY TO STRETCH TO ETERNITY. IT SEEMED AS IF MY BELLY WAS TAKING IN THE AIR AND FILLING OUT EVERY LITTLE CREVICE AND CREASE OF ME.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 The mirror reflecting nothing</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 24
The mirror reflecting nothing
30 June 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I HAVE KNOWN FRUSTRATION ATTEMPTING TO DESCRIBE MY MYSTICAL EXPERIENCES TO PEOPLE. IT IS LIKE TRYING TO EXPLAIN WHAT AN ORGASM IS TO SOMEONE THAT HAS NEVER KNOWN ONE. ONE CAN SAY IT IS LIKE A WAVE OF PLEASURE OR LIKE A SNEEZE, BUT THE REALITY OF THE EXPERIENCE IS MUCH MORE SATISFYING THAN THE WORDS CONVEY.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25 The puzzle remains but you are solved</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 25
The puzzle remains but you are solved
30 June 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
THE OTHER DAY, SARITO ASKED ABOUT WRITING BEAUTIFUL WORDS ABOUT YOU THAT SHE FELT SHE HAD NO RIGHT TO SAY, AND YOU ENCOURAGED US TO EXPRESS OURSELVES IN THE WORLD. BELOVED MASTER, I AM NOT A SPEAKER OR WRITER OF BEAUTIFUL WORDS, STILL, MANY TIMES I HAVE EXPERIENCED SHARING MYSELF WITH PEOPLE IN THE WORLD, SHARING YOU, SHARING YOUR VISION.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26 Memory is not understanding</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 26
Memory is not understanding
1 July 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
IS IT ENOUGH TO GO TO YOUR DISCOURSES WITHOUT UNDERSTANDING THE WORDS? MY JAPANESE GIRLFRIEND DOES NOT SPEAK ANY ENGLISH BUT ENJOYED YOUR LECTURES VERY MUCH.
SHE WROTE TO ME THAT SHE WILL NOT LEARN ENGLISH BECAUSE IT IS TOO DANGEROUS FOR HER TO UNDERSTAND WHAT YOU SAY.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27 You are sufficient unto yourself</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 27
You are sufficient unto yourself
1 July 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
IN THE LAST TWO YEARS, WHILE IN DEEP MEDITATION I HAVE BEEN HEARING A SOUND. IT’S A SORT OF OCEAN SOUND, LIKE DISTANT OCEAN WAVES. I CALL THIS NOISE MY TONE AND ENJOY IT AS A SIGN OF THE BEGINNING OF SILENCE. BUT THE OTHER NIGHT I HEARD YOU SAY THAT WE CAN HEAR OUR BLOOD CIRCULATING.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28 A thirst, a prayer without words</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part28/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 28
A thirst, a prayer without words
2 July 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
AS MEDITATION IS DEEPENING, I FEEL TENSION AND FRUSTRATION AT NOT BEING OKAY WITH MYSELF, MELTING MORE AND MORE. NOW AS YOU PUSH US ON, ANOTHER KIND OF TENSION WILL NOT ALLOW ME TO BE SATISFIED, EXCEPT MOMENTARILY. I HAVE HEARD YOU CALL THIS DIVINE DISCONTENT.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>29 A real encounter with existence</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part29/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 29
A real encounter with existence
2 July 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I FIND MYSELF IN CONFLICT BETWEEN A PART OF MYSELF THAT TRIES TO BE CLEAR AND INTELLIGENT WITH OTHERS AND A PART THAT IS EMOTIONAL, UNPREDICTABLE, VERY UNCLEAR AND SOMEHOW UNCONSCIOUS, BUT PERHAPS MORE REAL. I TELL MYSELF JUST TO BE AUTHENTIC AND THEN I GET REALLY CONFUSED.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 A feeling of coming home</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
A feeling of coming home
19 June 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
AN EARTHQUAKE IS HAPPENING: MY ANCIENT CRUST IS CRACKING AND MARVELOUS SQUIRTS OF BLISS ARE POURING OUT. MORE AND MORE, YOUR WORDS ARE INCREDIBLY ACCURATE DESCRIPTIONS OF MY INNER WORLD, NOT JUST BEAUTIFUL IMAGES OF SOMEWHERE ELSE. YOUR FINGER USED TO POINT TO THE MOON, BUT NOW I HAVE SEEN MY OWN MOON; YOUR FINGER IS POINTING TO MY VERY CENTER.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>30 The path goes round and round</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part30/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 30
The path goes round and round
3 July 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
LATELY, SITTING IN YOUR PRESENCE I AM AWARE THAT I DON’T FEEL THE LOVE I USED TO FEEL IN THE PAST. RATHER, I AM AWARE MORE OF YOUR SILENCE AND MY FALLING INTO THIS SILENCE, THIS STILLNESS, BEAUTY, QUIET AND GRACE. OSHO, CAN YOU PLEASE EXPLAIN THE DIFFERENCE BETWEEN LOVE AND SILENCE, AND WHY I FEEL SADDENED BY THIS HAPPENING?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>31 Unholy gossip \-- not holy gospels</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part31/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 31
Unholy gossip – not holy gospels
3 July 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
IS IT BECAUSE OF WOMEN BEING REPRESSED SO LONG THAT THERE ARE NOT MANY WOMEN COMEDIENNES OR JOKES THAT DON’T HAVE A MALE CHAUVINISTIC RING TO THEM? DO WOMEN NOT HAVE SUCH A GREAT SENSE OF HUMOR AS MEN? I AM ASKING THIS QUESTION VERY SERIOUSLY, BUT WOULD SETTLE FOR A JOKE AS AN ANSWER.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>32 A little bit off the track</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part32/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part32/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 32
A little bit off the track
4 July 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I SEEM TO HAVE BECOME VERY MUDDLEHEADED AND SCATTER-BRAINED LATELY. BUT UNFORTUNATELY THERE HAS BEEN NO CORRESPONDING UPSURGE OF INTELLIGENCE. IS THIS JUST A TEMPORARY LAPSE OR DO I HAVE A LEAK SOMEWHERE?
Anando, you are a rare intelligence but it often happens that the people who are intelligent don’t have a good memory.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>33 The new dawn is very close</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part33/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part33/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 33
The new dawn is very close
4 July 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
TWELVE YEARS AGO I LEFT JAPAN TO FIND MY OWN WAY, WITHOUT LOOKING BACK. AT THAT TIME I HATED TO FACE ANY REMINDER THAT PULLED ME BACK TO THE JAPANESE CONDITIONING. NOW, WHAT I FEEL IS TOTALLY DIFFERENT. IT SEEMS AS IF THE OLD JAPAN HAS DIED IN ME, AND A NEW JAPAN APPEARED.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 A different wavelength</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
A different wavelength
20 June 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
ON ONE HAND THE WORLD IS PREPARING FOR A GLOBAL SUICIDE; IT LOOKS LIKE THERE IS NOT MUCH TIME LEFT FOR OUR GROWTH. ON THE OTHER HAND, WHAT I HEARD FROM YOU IS THAT GROWTH IS ONLY POSSIBLE WHEN WE RELAX, SIT SILENTLY, AND WAIT. THIS IS A PARADOX.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 How to avoid the ditches</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
How to avoid the ditches
20 June 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
GOING INSIDE TO FEEL THE QUESTION, I WAS REMINDED OF THE TIME I FIRST SAT AT YOUR FEET, TWELVE PRECIOUS YEARS AGO. I SAID, “I HAVE NO QUESTION.” YOU THEN LOVINGLY DIFFUSED ME. OSHO, I NEVER WANT TO RECOVER FROM THIS LOVE. DO I NEED TO KNOW THE QUESTION?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 What has god been doing for eternity?</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
What has god been doing for eternity?
21 June 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
LATELY, I HAVE BEEN FEELING VERY INSECURE, AND I SEE HOW MUCH I DISLIKE THAT SPACE OF NOT KNOWING. AND THEN I TRY ALL KINDS OF STUPID THINGS TO CONTROL THE SITUATION. I FEEL AS IF IT IS SUCH AN IMPRISONMENT, AND AT THE SAME TIME, I HAVE A DEEP FEELING IN ME THAT KNOWS THAT THIS IS HOW LIFE IS, AND I SHOULD ACCEPT IT.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Your ego is the distance between you and me</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
Your ego is the distance between you and me
21 June 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I LOOK AT OTHER PEOPLE’S QUESTIONS TO SEE HOW THEY CAN EXPRESS THESE FEELINGS. I JUST CAN’T FIND WORDS TO EXPRESS MY TEARS OR MY LOVE, ALTHOUGH THE LONGING IS THERE. DO I NEED TO USE WORDS TO EXPOSE MYSELF?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 Clean the path, remove the rocks</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
Clean the path, remove the rocks
22 June 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHEN I CAME TO POONA I FELT MORE STRONGLY THAN EVER BEFORE THAT I HAVE COME HOME. RECENTLY I BEGAN TO SEE THAT ALTHOUGH I HEAR YOUR WORDS, I DON’T LISTEN. THE FEW TIMES THAT I HAVE ALLOWED MYSELF TO LISTEN, I HAVE FELT SUCH A TRANSFORMATION, AN OPENING.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 The more you know it, the less you know it</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_new_dawn/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
The more you know it, the less you know it
22 June 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
ROBERT BLY SPEAKS OF THE THREE BRAINS OF MAN – THE REPTILIAN, THE MAMMALIAN AND THE NEW BRAIN. THE REPTILE BRAIN IS UTTERLY COLD AND RUTHLESS. IT DEALS WITH, AND GROWS ON, SURVIVAL ISSUES. THE MAMMALIAN DEALS WITH COMFORTS, WHICH INCLUDE: FAMILY, FRIENDS, RELATIONSHIP, HOME, SOCIETY, RELIGION, ETC.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
