<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Snap Your Fingers, Slap Your Face and Wake Up! on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/snap_your_fingers_slap_your_face_and_wake_up/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Snap Your Fingers, Slap Your Face and Wake Up! on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/snap_your_fingers_slap_your_face_and_wake_up/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/snap_your_fingers_slap_your_face_and_wake_up/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/snap_your_fingers_slap_your_face_and_wake_up/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌1 June 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Satyo Dorothee. Satyo means truth; Dorothee means a gift of God.
Truth is never an achievement; one cannot seek and search it. Seeking is a sure way of not finding it. Search and you will miss, because the very idea of searching, seeking, is rooted in desire, and desire is the barrier.
Truth happens when there is no desire in the mind.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/snap_your_fingers_slap_your_face_and_wake_up/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/snap_your_fingers_slap_your_face_and_wake_up/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
10 June 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand Rosalba. Anand means bliss; Rosalba means a white rose. Bliss is a white rose. It is white because white is the combination of all the colors. White represents totality. White is the most positive phenomenon, just as the black is the most negative. The black represents the absence of all colors, and white, the presence of all colors.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/snap_your_fingers_slap_your_face_and_wake_up/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/snap_your_fingers_slap_your_face_and_wake_up/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
14 June 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Veet Lynne. Veet means going beyond; Lynne means idols – going beyond all idols: idols of religion, idols of race, idols of nation. They all make us idolators, and a religious person really cannot be a worshipper of an idol. He wants the real.
The idol is only a symbol. To be trapped by the symbol is the misery of man, and all men are trapped by symbols.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/snap_your_fingers_slap_your_face_and_wake_up/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/snap_your_fingers_slap_your_face_and_wake_up/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
15 June 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand Angelika. Anand means bliss; Angelika means a messenger of God. Bliss is the true messenger of God. No man can be a messenger of God; man can only be a vehicle of bliss.
Bliss is the message. And if one can be blissful, one suddenly becomes religious, because it is impossible to be blissful and not to be religious.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/snap_your_fingers_slap_your_face_and_wake_up/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/snap_your_fingers_slap_your_face_and_wake_up/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
16 June 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Maria Surya. Maria is Hebrew. It is a tremendously significant word; it means rebellion. And it is not just coincidence that Jesus’ mother’s name is Maria. A man like Jesus can come only out of the womb of revolution. Jesus is a rebel, and only a rebellious mother can give birth to such a child.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/snap_your_fingers_slap_your_face_and_wake_up/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/snap_your_fingers_slap_your_face_and_wake_up/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
17 June 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand Trees. Anand means bliss; Trees means a reaper, a harvester – a reaper of bliss. We are seeds, we are only potentialities; we have to become actual. And that is the moment of great bliss, when we become actual, when the seed is no more a seed but becomes a flower.
Ordinarily millions of people are born as seeds and die as seeds.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/snap_your_fingers_slap_your_face_and_wake_up/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/snap_your_fingers_slap_your_face_and_wake_up/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
18 June 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Satyam Janis. Satyam means deep truth – the ultimate truth: and Janis means grace. Truth brings grace; untruth is disgrace.
And people live in untruth, people live in lies. The society supports lies; the state strengthens lies, the church. Nobody is for truth, because truth is dangerous, because truth is rebellious, because truth cannot be enslaved, because truth cannot be exploited, because truth makes a person so utterly unique that the crowd is afraid of it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/snap_your_fingers_slap_your_face_and_wake_up/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/snap_your_fingers_slap_your_face_and_wake_up/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
19 June 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho initiates a two-week old baby with the name Anand Ruho – the spirit of bliss, and addresses the parents.]
And that’s my message, the whole message.
The man without bliss is without any soul. He is just a mechanism; the soul is not yet born. He is functioning just as any other machine can function, and he may be functioning very efficiently, but efficiency does not prove the existence of the soul.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/snap_your_fingers_slap_your_face_and_wake_up/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/snap_your_fingers_slap_your_face_and_wake_up/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
20 June 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva Pritama. Deva means God; Pritama means beloved – God’s beloved. Yes, to be a sannyasin is to become a beloved of God.
Sannyas is not anything less than a love affair – more, certainly it is, but not less. It is mad, mad, mad love... and a madness that is absolutely incomprehensible, a madness that is not a pathology but the ultimate in health, in sanity, in being whole.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/snap_your_fingers_slap_your_face_and_wake_up/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/snap_your_fingers_slap_your_face_and_wake_up/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
21 June 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Love is not something which we can create; it is something given. It is inbuilt in our very being. It is not something that we produce later on; it comes with our birth, it is a natural energy. We may deny it expression; then it becomes a repressed force. It can turn sour, bitter, poisonous, if it is repressed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/snap_your_fingers_slap_your_face_and_wake_up/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/snap_your_fingers_slap_your_face_and_wake_up/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
22 June 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand Franz. Anand means bliss; Franz means freedom. Bliss is a state of freedom; misery is a state of bondage. The more limited we feel, the more miserable we are. The more unlimited we feel, the more blissful. Freedom means a state of no limit, a state which has no boundaries, no China walls surrounding it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/snap_your_fingers_slap_your_face_and_wake_up/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/snap_your_fingers_slap_your_face_and_wake_up/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌2 June 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem Ellen. Prem means love; Ellen means light. Love is the only light there is in life. Love is the inner light. It needs no fuel; it is eternal. It is not caused by anything, hence it cannot be turned off. Anything that can be put on can be turned off. It is simply there; you cannot put it on, you cannot put it off.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/snap_your_fingers_slap_your_face_and_wake_up/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/snap_your_fingers_slap_your_face_and_wake_up/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
23 June 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand Ron. Anand means bliss; Ron means power. Bliss has a power of its own, very different from any other power, qualitatively different from any other power. All other powers are destructive, violent. Bliss has a non-violent power, the power of love. Bliss has the power to bless others. It is not destructive, it is creative energy; it only creates.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/snap_your_fingers_slap_your_face_and_wake_up/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/snap_your_fingers_slap_your_face_and_wake_up/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
24 June 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva Louis. Deva means God; Louis means victory. God is our only victory. Nothing else can make us victorious. Everything else ends in failure, unexceptionally. Without failure, everything falls into failure.
There are many illusions in life, very attractive, but they are attractive only from the distance. As you come closer you become disillusioned.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/snap_your_fingers_slap_your_face_and_wake_up/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/snap_your_fingers_slap_your_face_and_wake_up/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
25 June 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Dhamma Klaus. Dhamma means the ultimate law, the law that keeps the whole universe together, the very core of existence, the center, the soul. And Klaus means victory. The only way to be victorious is to be with the law and not against it. One can choose to be against it – that freedom is ours – but if we choose to be against the law, we are committing suicide.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/snap_your_fingers_slap_your_face_and_wake_up/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/snap_your_fingers_slap_your_face_and_wake_up/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
26 June 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem Marion. Prem means love; Marion means rebellion. Love is the greatest rebellion in the world. It is the greatest rebellion because love is not part of this world; love belongs to the beyond. Love is God’s nature.
To be in love is not to be of this world. To be in love is to transcend the world.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/snap_your_fingers_slap_your_face_and_wake_up/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/snap_your_fingers_slap_your_face_and_wake_up/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 24
27 June 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem Carolina. Prem means love; Carolina means freedom. And hitherto man has not been able to synthesize these two ultimate elements of life: love and freedom. Those who have chosen love have lost their freedom, and those who wanted to be free had to sacrifice their love.
That has been the history up to now and because of this, life has suffered very much, because life can grow only when both are available.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/snap_your_fingers_slap_your_face_and_wake_up/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/snap_your_fingers_slap_your_face_and_wake_up/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 25
28 June 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva Faina. Deva means divine; Faina means freedom. Freedom is the most divine thing in existence. Everything can be sacrificed for it, but it cannot be sacrificed for anything else. Even love, if it goes against freedom, becomes worthless. Love has value only if it protects freedom, nourishes freedom, if it helps freedom. Otherwise it goes ugly, nauseating.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/snap_your_fingers_slap_your_face_and_wake_up/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/snap_your_fingers_slap_your_face_and_wake_up/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 26
29 June 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Come here. Close your eyes. Listen to the sounds... I am sorry that you had to wait so long to get in, but I am also happy that you waited with love, prayer, hope. Those are the basic qualities of a sannyasin: to wait patiently, to wait with trust. Even if it takes infinite time, love knows how to wait.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/snap_your_fingers_slap_your_face_and_wake_up/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/snap_your_fingers_slap_your_face_and_wake_up/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 27
30 June 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand Nimus. Anand means bliss. Bliss does not mean happiness; it is something totally different. It is not only quantitatively different, it is qualitatively different. Happiness always has unhappiness as the other side of it, as a shadow to it. It is never alone. Even when you are happy you know that unhappiness is just close by.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/snap_your_fingers_slap_your_face_and_wake_up/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/snap_your_fingers_slap_your_face_and_wake_up/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌3 June 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva Ageho. Deva means divine; Ageho means homelessness.
Life has no security; it thrives in danger. It has no safety; it is possible only in danger. Death is safe and secure; life is a risk. Hence those who really want to live have to take many risks. They have to go on moving into the unknown.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/snap_your_fingers_slap_your_face_and_wake_up/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/snap_your_fingers_slap_your_face_and_wake_up/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌4 June 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Gian Carlo. Gian means God’s gracious gift; Carlo means a man. To be a man is God’s gracious gift. It is no ordinary happening. It is very rare, unique, because in this whole universe where millions of solar systems exist, it is only on this small planet earth that life has arisen. And life has millions of forms, from the lowest amoeba to man.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/snap_your_fingers_slap_your_face_and_wake_up/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/snap_your_fingers_slap_your_face_and_wake_up/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
5 June 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva Thomas. Deva means divine: Thomas is the name of one of the apostles of Jesus who has come synonymous with doubt, because he doubted. He was one of the most beloved disciples of Jesus. But doubt is very natural. It goes only by and by, very slowly. We are born with it. Jesus loved him tremendously; he loved Jesus, but still the doubt persisted.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/snap_your_fingers_slap_your_face_and_wake_up/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/snap_your_fingers_slap_your_face_and_wake_up/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
6 June 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand Gopi. Anand means bliss. Gopi is a very significant word; it comes from the tradition of the devotee.
There are two paths: one is of knowledge, wisdom, meditation, and the other is that of love, devotion, surrender. The word “gopi” belongs to the other tradition, the tradition of surrender. Literally Gopi means the beloved of God.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/snap_your_fingers_slap_your_face_and_wake_up/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/snap_your_fingers_slap_your_face_and_wake_up/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
7 June 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Dharma Farrell. Dharma means religion; Farrell means a man of courage.
Religion is possible only through courage, but usually the cowardly become religious. The temples, the churches, the mosques, are full of cowards. Their God is nothing but a projection of their fear; their prayer is nothing but a demand for protection. It is a kind of bribe.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/snap_your_fingers_slap_your_face_and_wake_up/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/snap_your_fingers_slap_your_face_and_wake_up/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
8 June 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand Ryoko. Anand means bliss; Ryoko means good. Bliss is good; everything else is bad. Bliss is virtue; everything else is sin. But this has not been said to humanity.
People have been taught many things but not the truth, because the truth goes against the vested interests. It goes against the status quo.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/snap_your_fingers_slap_your_face_and_wake_up/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/snap_your_fingers_slap_your_face_and_wake_up/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
9 June 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Veet Atito – beyond the past.…
The only problem that a seeker of truth has to encounter is the past. It is the past that stands between you and the reality; it is the past that functions as a barrier. It does not allow you to see that which is. It goes on interfering, distorting, interpreting.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
