<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Great Challenge on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_challenge/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Great Challenge on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_challenge/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 Flight of the alone to the alone</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_challenge/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_challenge/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
Flight of the alone to the alone
16 August 1970 pm
Question 1
PLEASE EXPLAIN WHAT YOU MEAN BY YOGA, THE YOGI, AND MEDITATION.
The first thing to be remembered about meditation is that it is not something that can be done. Throughout the world people have the notion that meditation means doing something. It is not a doing, it is not an act, it is something that happens.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Out of nothing</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_challenge/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_challenge/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
Out of nothing
WERE ALL SOULS CREATED TOGETHER, AS PAUL BRUNTON THEORIZES, OR WERE THEY CREATED AT SEPARATE STAGES? IS THIS DIFFERENCE – THE DIFFERENCE IN THEIR STAGES – DUE TO THEIR OWN CHOICE OR IS IT THEIR DESTINY? WHAT DEGREE OF CHOICE DO WE HAVE AS FAR AS REINCARNATION IS CONCERNED?
Before I can answer this question, two or three things must be understood.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 Remaining closed to the lower: A technique for transformation</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_challenge/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_challenge/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
Remaining closed to the lower: A technique for transformation
IN THIS DESPERATE SPIRITUAL SITUATION, HOW CAN WE GET HELP FROM ADVANCED SOULS IN THE ASTRAL WORLD? HOW CAN WE BECOME OPEN TO THE HIGHER?
There is an old saying: “When the disciple is ready, the teacher appears.” The disciple cannot find the teacher; it is impossible. Only the teacher can find the disciple.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 A personal seeking, an individual quest</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_challenge/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_challenge/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
A personal seeking, an individual quest
DOES GOD EXIST?
Something about right inquiryBefore you ask something, it will be good to know what is meant
by right questioning. Every question is not a right inquiry, because as far as the inner dimension is concerned you can ask many, many, questions that appear to be meaningful but are not; they are nonsense.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 Between Death and Rebirth</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_challenge/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_challenge/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 13
Between Death and Rebirth
YOU HAVE SAID THAT YOU REMEMBER YOUR FORMER LIFE SEVEN HUNDRED YEARS AGO. CAN YOU REMEMBER YOUR NAME AT THAT TIME AND THE OCCASION OF YOUR DEATH? WHAT I AM INTERESTED IN IS WHAT HAPPENED BETWEEN YOUR LAST LIFE AND YOUR PRESENT LIFE.
The question seems meaningful, but it is not. Life means that something is happening, and between two lives, there is nothing happening.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Dynamic Meditation</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_challenge/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_challenge/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
Dynamic Meditation
29 July 1970 pm
Question 1
WHAT IS DYNAMIC MEDITATION?
The first thing to be understood about Dynamic Meditation is that it is a method of creating a situation through tension in which meditation can happen. If your total being is completely tense, the only possibility that remains is relaxation. Ordinarily one cannot go directly into relaxation, but if your whole being is at a peak of total tension then the second step comes automatically, spontaneously: silence is created.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Yoga: A spontaneous happening</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_challenge/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_challenge/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
Yoga: A spontaneous happening
27 October 1970 pm
Question 1
IS THE PRACTICING OF TRADITIONAL ASANAS HELPFUL FOR MEDITATION?
Man’s personality is neither solely physical nor solely mental but both simultaneously. Rather, it would be correct to say that it is psychosomatic. There is no gap between the two, so anything that happens on the physical plane vibrates on the mental plane and vice versa.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 LSD: A shortcut to false samadhi</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_challenge/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_challenge/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
LSD: A shortcut to false samadhi
25 October 1970 pm
Question 1
IN EXPERIMENTING WITH LSD I HAVE EXPERIENCED STATES WHICH SEEM TO BE SIMILAR TO DESCRIPTIONS I HAVE READ OF SAMADHI. I COULD FEEL MY KUNDALINI RISING AND MY CHAKRAS OPENING UP. I FELT A ONENESS WITH THE WHOLE COSMOS. WERE THESE GENUINE EXPERIENCES OF SAMADHI? IS PERMANENT SELF-REALIZATION POSSIBLE THROUGH THE USE OF LSD?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 The vital balance</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_challenge/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_challenge/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
The vital balance
6 January 1971 pm
Question 1
IN OUR CIVILIZATION, PROFESSIONAL PEOPLE LIKE ME HAVE A PARTICULAR PROBLEM: WE MAKE TOO MUCH USE OF OUR INTELLIGENCE, SO MUCH SO THAT WE TEND TO VIEW LIFE THROUGH THE INTELLECT ONLY, THUS NEGATING ALL OTHER MEANS OF DOING SO. THIS TENDS TO MAKE LIFE BORING AND DULL, AND ROBS IT OF ITS LUSTER.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Religion: The last luxury</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_challenge/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_challenge/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
Religion: The last luxury
WHY IS IT THAT WESTERN SOCIETIES ARE BECOMING SO INTERESTED IN INDIAN RELIGION NOW?
I consider religion to be the last luxury. Only when a society becomes affluent does religion become meaningful. And now, for the first time, a greater part of the world is not poor. America in particular is the first society in human history to reach such affluence.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 The secrets of discipleship</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_challenge/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_challenge/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
The secrets of discipleship
26 February 1971 pm
Question 1
WHAT IS THE GURU/DISCIPLE RELATIONSHIP?
First of all, a guru is not a teacher; a guru is a person who has attained to a religious mode of living. Religion is not information, it cannot be taught because religion is a way of living. The very presence of the guru is a communion.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 God is existence itself</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_challenge/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_challenge/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
God is existence itself
DOES GOD EXIST? HOW CAN THERE BE SO MUCH EVIL AND CORRUPTION IN THE WORLD IF GOD EXISTS?
God is a mythical word, a mumbo-jumbo word that is the invention of the priesthood. Actually, to ask whether God exists is absurd. For those who know, God is existence, or existence is God.
Things exist, not God. A chair exists because a chair can go into nonexistence.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 The unknown life of Jesus</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_challenge/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_challenge/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
The unknown life of Jesus
WAS JESUS FULLY ENLIGHTENED?
Yes, he was fully enlightened. But because he lived amidst a people who were absolutely ignorant about enlightenment, he had to speak in a language which may indicate he was not. He had to use such language because, at that particular time and place, there was no other possibility – only this could be understood.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
