<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Psychology of the Esoteric on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_psychology_of_the_esoteric/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Psychology of the Esoteric on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/the_psychology_of_the_esoteric/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 Inward revolution</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_psychology_of_the_esoteric/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_psychology_of_the_esoteric/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
Inward revolution
24 July 1970 pm in
Question 1
ON MAN’S PATH OF EVOLUTION IS IT POSSIBLE THAT AT SOME TIME IN THE FUTURE HUMANITY AS A WHOLE CAN ATTAIN ENLIGHTENMENT? AT WHAT POINT OF EVOLUTION IS MAN TODAY?
With man, the natural, automatic process of evolution ends. Man is the last product of unconscious evolution. With man, conscious evolution begins. Many things are to be taken into account.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Windows to the divine</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_psychology_of_the_esoteric/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_psychology_of_the_esoteric/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
Windows to the divine
21 October 1971 pm in
Question 1
IN INDIAN PHILOSOPHY, THE NATURE OF ULTIMATE TRUTH HAS BEEN DESCRIBED AS TRUTH, SATYAM, BEAUTY, SUNDRAM AND GOODNESS, SHIVAM. ARE THESE THE CHARACTERISTICS OF GOD?
These are not the qualities of God. Rather, they are our experiences of God. They do not belong to the divine as such; they are our perceptions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 Right questioning</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_psychology_of_the_esoteric/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_psychology_of_the_esoteric/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
Right questioning
12 March 1972 pm in
Question 1
NO QUESTION.!
Do not ask theoretical questions. Theories solve less and confuse more. If there were no theories, there would be less problems. It is not that theories solve questions or problems. On the contrary, questions arise out of theories.
And do not ask philosophical questions. Philosophical questions only seem to be questions, but they are not.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Balancing the rational and the irrational</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_psychology_of_the_esoteric/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_psychology_of_the_esoteric/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 12
Balancing the rational and the irrational
21 October 1971 pm in
Question 4
WHAT FACTORS DO YOU ATTRIBUTE THE WESTERN YOUTH REVOLT TO, AND WHY ARE SO MANY YOUNG PEOPLE FROM THE WEST NOW BECOMING INTERESTED IN EASTERN RELIGION AND PHILOSOPHY?
Mind is a very contradictory thing. It works in polar opposites. But our logical way of thinking always chooses one part and denies the other.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 The mystery of meditation</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_psychology_of_the_esoteric/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_psychology_of_the_esoteric/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
The mystery of meditation
4 February 1971 pm in
Question 1
WHAT IS MEDITATION?
Meditation is not an Indian method; it is not simply a technique. You cannot learn it. It is a growth: a growth of your total living, out of your total living. Meditation is not something that can be added to you as you are. It can come to you only through a basic transformation, a mutation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Sex, love and prayer: three steps to the divine</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_psychology_of_the_esoteric/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_psychology_of_the_esoteric/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
Sex, love and prayer: three steps to the divine
14 February 1971 pm in
Question 1
PLEASE DESCRIBE TO US THE SPIRITUAL SIGNIFICANCE OF SEX ENERGY. HOW CAN WE SUBLIMATE AND SPIRITUALIZE SEX? IS IT POSSIBLE TO HAVE SEX, TO MAKE LOVE, AS A MEDITATION, AS A JUMPING BOARD TOWARD HIGHER LEVELS OF CONSCIOUSNESS?
There is no such thing as sex energy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Kundalini Yoga: returning to the roots</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_psychology_of_the_esoteric/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_psychology_of_the_esoteric/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
Kundalini Yoga: returning to the roots
25 July 1970 pm in
Question 1
WHAT IS KUNDALINI YOGA AND HOW CAN IT HELP THE WEST? WHY IS YOUR METHOD FOR AWAKENING KUNDALINI CHAOTIC RATHER THAN LIKE THE TRADITIONAL, CONTROLLED METHODS?
Existence is energy, the movement of energy in so many ways and so many forms. As far as human existence is concerned, this energy is kundalini energy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Esoteric games: a hindrance to growth</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_psychology_of_the_esoteric/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_psychology_of_the_esoteric/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
Esoteric games: a hindrance to growth
26 July 1970 pm in
Question 1
IS THERE A DIVISION BETWEEN BODY AND MIND, MATTER AND CONSCIOUSNESS, THE PHYSICAL AND THE SPIRITUAL? HOW CAN ONE TRANSCEND BODY AND MIND TO ATTAIN SPIRITUAL CONSCIOUSNESS?
The first thing to be understood is that the division between body and mind is abso-lutely false. If you begin with that division you will reach nowhere; a false beginning leads nowhere.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 The psychology of dreams</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_psychology_of_the_esoteric/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_psychology_of_the_esoteric/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
The psychology of dreams
16 September 1970 pm in
Question 1
CAN YOU EXPLAIN WHAT YOU MEAN BY DREAMS?
We have seven bodies: the physical, the etheric, the astral, the mental, the spiritual, the cosmic, and the nirvanic. Each body has its own type of dream. The physical body is known in Western psychology as the conscious, the etheric body as the unconscious, and the astral body as the collective unconscious.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Transcending the seven bodies</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_psychology_of_the_esoteric/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_psychology_of_the_esoteric/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
Transcending the seven bodies
25 March 1971 pm in
Question 1
YOU SAID WE HAVE SEVEN BODIES: AN ETHERIC BODY, A MENTAL BODY AND SO ON. SOMETIMES IT IS DIFFICULT TO ADJUST THE INDIAN LANGUAGE TO THE TERMS OF WESTERN PSYCHOLOGY. WE HAVE NO THEORY FOR THIS IN THE WEST, SO HOW CAN WE TRANSLATE THESE DIFFERENT BODIES INTO OUR LANGUAGE? THE SPIRITUAL IS NO PROBLEM, BUT THE ETHERIC?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 Becoming and being</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_psychology_of_the_esoteric/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_psychology_of_the_esoteric/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
Becoming and being
9 January 1971 pm in
Question 1
PLEASE TELL US SOMETHING ABOUT THE TENSIONS AND RELAXATION OF THE SEVEN BODIES.
The original source of all tension is becoming. One is always trying to be something; no one is at ease with himself as he is. The being is not accepted, the being is denied, and something else is taken as an ideal to become.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 The fallacy of knowledge</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_psychology_of_the_esoteric/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_psychology_of_the_esoteric/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
The fallacy of knowledge
1 December 1971 pm in
Question 1
WHAT DO YOU TEACH AND WHAT IS YOUR DOCTRINE ?
I am not teaching a doctrine. Teaching a doctrine is rather meaningless. I am not a philosopher; my mind is antiphilosophical. Philosophy has led nowhere and cannot lead anywhere. The mind that thinks, that questions, cannot know.
There are so many doctrines.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
