<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>When the Shoe Fits on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/when_the_shoe_fits/</link>
    <description>Recent content in When the Shoe Fits on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/when_the_shoe_fits/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 When The Shoe Fits</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/when_the_shoe_fits/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/when_the_shoe_fits/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
When The Shoe Fits
11 October 1974 am in Buddha Hall
CHU’I THE DRAFTSMAN COULD DRAW MORE PERFECT CIRCLES FREEHAND THAN WITH A COMPASS.
HIS FINGERS BROUGHT FORTH SPONTANEOUS FORMS FROM NOWHERE. HIS MIND WAS MEANWHILE FREE AND WITHOUT CONCERN WITH WHAT HE WAS DOING.
NO APPLICATION WAS NEEDED, HIS MIND WAS PERFECTLY SIMPLE AND KNEW NO OBSTACLE.
SO, WHEN THE SHOE FITS, THE FOOT IS FORGOTTEN, WHEN THE BELT FITS, THE BELLY IS FORGOTTEN, WHEN THE HEART IS RIGHT, ‘FOR’ AND ‘AGAINST’ ARE FORGOTTEN.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Man Is A Born In Tao</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/when_the_shoe_fits/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/when_the_shoe_fits/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 10
Man Is A Born In Tao
20 October 1974 am in Buddha Hall
FISHES ARE BORN IN WATER, MAN IS BORN IN TAO. IF FISHES, BORN IN WATER, SEEK THE DEEP SHADOW OF POND AND POOL, ALL THEIR NEEDS ARE SATISFIED.
IF MAN, BORN IN TAO, SINKS INTO THE DEEP SHADOW OF NON-ACTION TO FORGET AGGRESSION AND CONCERN, HE LACKS NOTHING, HIS LIFE IS SECURE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 The Tower Of The Spirit</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/when_the_shoe_fits/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/when_the_shoe_fits/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
The Tower Of The Spirit
12 October 1974 am in Buddha Hall
THE SPIRIT HAS AN IMPREGNABLE TOWER WHICH NO DANGER CAN DISTURB AS LONG AS THE TOWER IS GUARDED BY THE INVISIBLE PROTECTOR WHO ACTS UNCONSCIOUSLY, AND WHOSE ACTIONS GO ASTRAY WHEN THEY BECOME DELIBERATE, REFLEXIVE AND INTENTIONAL.
THE UNCONSCIOUSNESS AND ENTIRE SINCERITY OF TAO ARE DISTURBED BY ANY EFFORT AT SELF-CONSCIOUS DEMONSTRATION.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Flight From The Shadow</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/when_the_shoe_fits/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/when_the_shoe_fits/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
Flight From The Shadow
13 October 1974 am in Buddha Hall
THERE WAS A MAN WHO WAS SO DISTURBED BY THE SIGHT OF HIS OWN SHADOW AND SO DISPLEASED WITH HIS OWN FOOTSTEPS, THAT HE DETERMINED TO GET RID OF BOTH.
THE METHOD HE HIT UPON WAS TO RUN AWAY FROM THEM. SO HE GOT UP AND RAN.
BUT EVERY TIME HE PUT HIS FOOT DOWN THERE WAS ANOTHER STEP, WHILE HIS SHADOW KEPT UP WITH HIM WITHOUT THE SLIGHTEST DIFFICULTY.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Fighting Cock</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/when_the_shoe_fits/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/when_the_shoe_fits/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
Fighting Cock
14 October 1974 am in Buddha Hall
CHI HSING TZU WAS A TRAINER OF FIGHTING COCKS FOR KING HSUAN. HE WAS TRAINING A FINE BIRD. THE KING KEPT ASKING IF THE BIRD WERE READY FOR COMBAT.
‘NOT YET’, SAID THE TRAINER. ‘HE IS FULL OF FIRE. HE IS READY TO PICK A FIGHT WITH EVERY OTHER BIRD. HE IS VAIN AND CONFIDENT OF HIS OWN STRENGTH’.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Monkey Mountain</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/when_the_shoe_fits/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/when_the_shoe_fits/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
Monkey Mountain
15 October 1974 am in Buddha Hall
THE PRINCE OF WU TOOK A BOAT TO MONKEY MOUNTAIN. AS SOON AS THE MONKEYS SAW HIM THEY ALL FLED IN PANIC AND HID IN THE TREETOPS.
ONE MONKEY, HOWEVER, REMAINED, COMPLETELY UNCONCERNED, SWINGING FROM BRANCH TO BRANCH – AN EXTRAORDINARY DISPLAY.
THE PRINCE SHOT AN ARROW AT THE MONKEY, BUT THE MONKEY DEXTEROUSLY CAUGHT THE ARROW IN MID-FLIGHT.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Symphony For A Seabird</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/when_the_shoe_fits/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/when_the_shoe_fits/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
Symphony For A Seabird
16 October 1974 am in Buddha Hall
YOU CANNOT PUT A BIG LOAD IN A SMALL BAG, NOR CAN YOU, WITH A SHORT ROPE, DRAW WATER FROM A DEEP WELL.
HAVE YOU NOT HEARD HOW A BIRD FROM THE SEA WAS BLOWN INSHORE AND LANDED OUTSIDE THE CAPITAL OF LU?
THE PRINCE ORDERED A SOLEMN RECEPTION, OFFERED THE SEA BIRD WINE IN THE SACRED PRECINCT, CALLED FOR MUSICIANS TO PLAY THE COMPOSITIONS OF SHUN, SLAUGHTERED CATTLE TO NOURISH IT.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Autumn Floods</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/when_the_shoe_fits/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/when_the_shoe_fits/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
Autumn Floods
17 October 1974 am in Buddha Hall
THE AUTUMN FLOODS HAD COME. THOUSANDS OF WILD TORRENTS POURED FURIOUSLY INTO THE YELLOW RIVER. IT SURGED AND FLOODED ITS BANKS UNTIL, LOOKING ACROSS, YOU COULD NOT TELL AN OX FROM A HORSE ON THE OTHER SIDE.
THEN THE RIVER GOD LAUGHED, DELIGHTED TO THINK THAT ALL THE BEAUTY IN THE WORLD HAD FALLEN INTO HIS KEEPING.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 The Turtle</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/when_the_shoe_fits/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/when_the_shoe_fits/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
The Turtle
18 October 1974 am in Buddha Hall
CHUANG TZU WITH HIS BAMBOO POLE WAS FISHING IN THE PU RIVER.
THE PRINCE OF CHU SENT TWO VICE CHANCELLORS WITH A FORMAL DOCUMENT: WE HEREBY APPOINT YOU PRIME MINISTER.
CHUANG TZU HELD HIS BAMBOO POLE. STILL WATCHING PU RIVER, HE SAID: ‘I AM TOLD THERE IS A SACRED TORTOISE OFFERED AND CANONISED THREE THOUSAND YEARS AGO, VENERATED BY THE PRINCE, WRAPPED IN SILK, IN A PRECIOUS SHRINE ON AN ALTAR IN THE TEMPLE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 Duke Hwan And The Wheelright</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/when_the_shoe_fits/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/when_the_shoe_fits/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
Duke Hwan And The Wheelright
19 October 1974 am in Buddha Hall
DUKE HWAN OF KHI, FIRST IN HIS DYNASTY, SAT UNDER HIS CANOPY READING HIS PHILOSOPHY. AND PHIEN THE WHEELWRIGHT WAS OUT IN THE YARD MAKING A WHEEL.
PHIEN LAID ASIDE HAMMER AND CHISEL, CLIMBED THE STEPS, AND SAID TO DUKE HWAN: ‘MAY I ASK YOU, LORD, WHAT IS THIS YOU ARE READING?</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
