<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Hari Om Tat Sat on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hari Om Tat Sat on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 The master thief sound</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
The master thief sound
17 January 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
I HAVE HEARD YOU SAY, HARI OM TAT SAT: THE DIVINE SOUND – THAT IS THE TRUTH.
WHEN YOU SPEAK I HEAR THE SOUND OF TRUTH RESONATING IN ME, YET I AM NOT ENLIGHTENED. HOW IS IT THAT I CAN RECOGNIZE THAT WHICH I HAVEN’T REALIZED?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 The greatest art of being silent</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
The greatest art of being silent
22 January 1988 am in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
I HAVE BEEN IN POONA FOR TWO WEEKS, AND EVERY DAY I FEEL MORE AND MORE STUPID AND HELPLESS. YOU SAY THAT ONLY INTELLIGENT PEOPLE WHO UNDERSTAND CAN BE WITH YOU. LISTENING TO YOU, ENJOYING EVERY WORD YOU SAY, I WONDER: DO I REALLY UNDERSTAND, OR AM I JUST HAPPY TO BE IN YOUR PRESENCE?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 Go dancing in</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
Go dancing in
22 January 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
WHY DON’T YOU ANSWER MY QUESTIONS? IS THERE A CERTAIN SELECTION BEFORE THEY REACH YOU? IF SO, THEN THESE ARE THE WRONG PERSONS AT THE RIGHT PLACE, BECAUSE THEY CHOOSE THE STUPID ONES INSTEAD OF MINE, WHICH HAVE SOME QUALITY. IT’S NOT ONLY AN EGO-SATISFACTION-COMPARISON STATE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Every joke has a great reason</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
Every joke has a great reason
23 January 1988 am in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
ARE ALL JOKES IRRATIONAL?
Devageet, it is not that all jokes are irrational. You cannot even find one joke that is irrational. But the joke has its own psychology and rationality. The psychology of the joke has to be understood and then the rationality of it will be clear.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 Ride on the wave of joy</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
Ride on the wave of joy
23 January 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
WHY IS IT THAT, APART FROM SITTING WITH YOU TWICE A DAY, I ONLY FIND MYSELF MEDITATING WHEN I AM DOWN OR CONFUSED?
WHY IS THAT I RARELY MEDITATE OUT OF MY JOYOUSNESS?
Deva Anupo, your question touches very deeply the human heart and its workings.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 Was god thinking of a circus</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
Was god thinking of a circus
1 February 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
WHEN YOU LOOK AT ME IN DISCOURSE – WHETHER OR NOT YOU ACTUALLY SEE ME – I FEEL YOUR LOVE POURING OUT OF YOU AND PENETRATING TO MY HEART. AT FIRST IT FEELS A LITTLE SCARY BECAUSE I FEEL VERY EXPOSED, AND THEN I LOVE THE FEELING INSIDE MY HEART.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 Everybody is unique, not equal</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
Everybody is unique, not equal
2 February 1988 am in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
I FEEL A NEW KIND OF AUTHORITY AND LOVE GROWING IN ME, A CLARITY ABOUT MYSELF AND LOVE FOR MYSELF AND OTHERS. IT FEELS LIKE EVERYBODY IS EQUAL FOR ME AND I DON’T HAVE A SPECIAL AFFECTION TOWARDS ANYBODY. I FEEL FREE AND BEAUTIFUL.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 No master can betray love</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
No master can betray love
2 February 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
TO THE WESTERN WORLD THE TERMS “FREEDOM” AND “THE MASTER” ARE VIRTUALLY MUTUALLY EXCLUSIVE; FOR THOSE WHO HAVE MET YOU THIS IS WILDLY INACCURATE. HOW DO YOU REDEFINE “FREEDOM” AND “THE MASTER” FOR THE WESTERN UNDERSTANDING?
Vadan and Iti, the Western world has not come in contact with the tremendous reality that happens in the meeting of a master and a disciple.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 Buddhas are trying to be buddhas</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
Buddhas are trying to be buddhas
3 February 1988 am in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
THE OTHER DAY, WHEN YOU SAID WE LOOK LIKE GAUTAM BUDDHAS WHEN WE LAUGH, A BIG LET-GO HAPPENED DEEP INSIDE ME AND I CRIED FOR A LONG TIME. TODAY I FEEL VERY FRAGILE AND THE CRYING OFTEN COMES BACK. I CANNOT EVEN MEDITATE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 A gathering of friends</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
A gathering of friends
3 February 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
IN THE OLD DAYS IN BOMBAY, EVEN THOUGH I FELT PHYSICALLY SO CLOSE TO YOU, YOU WERE SO FAR AWAY. NOW SITTING HERE WITH YOU IN BUDDHA HALL, WHERE THOUSANDS OF US MOVE AROUND YOU – COMPARED TO THE ROOM IN BOMBAY – I FEEL YOU SO INTIMATELY AND PERSONALLY, LIKE I NEVER DID BEFORE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19 Truth is nobody\&#39;s monopoly</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
Truth is nobody’s monopoly
4 February 1988 am in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
THE OTHER DAY YOU SAID IT WAS EASIER FOR ONE TO MEDITATE WHEN ONE WAS ELEVATED FROM THE EARTH, SUCH AS ON A TREE. IN AIKIDO, ONE OF THE FUNDAMENTAL PRINCIPLES IS TO FEEL THE BODY CONNECTED WITH THE GRAVITY OF THE EARTH. IS THERE ANY CONTRADICTION IN IT?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Nobody is at home</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
Nobody is at home
18 January 1988 am in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
MY GIRLFRIEND TOLD ME I AM A LITTLE BORING, NOT VERY JUICY, VERY DEPENDENT AND A VICTIM. THEN I FELT VERY GUILTY AND DEPRESSED AND UTTERLY UNWORTHY. I BEGAN TO FEEL INSIDE ME A BIG NO: TOWARDS EXISTENCE, LIFE, LOVE, YOU. MEANWHILE I OBSERVED IN ME THIS DESTRUCTIVE ENERGY AND I FELT THAT I SOMEHOW ENJOYED IT!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 Religion can only be aesthetic</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
Religion can only be aesthetic
4 February 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
A FRIEND TOLD US THAT SHE ONCE HEARD YOU SAY THAT YOU WANT US TO BECOME ENLIGHTENED IN THE MOST AESTHETIC WAY POSSIBLE. WILL YOU SPEAK ON THE AESTHETICS OF CONSCIOUSNESS? HAVE YOU EVER SPOKEN OF ANYTHING ELSE?
Vadan and Iti, you have raised a very significant question.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 Logic is not the way to life</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
Logic is not the way to life
5 February 1988 am in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
THE OTHER NIGHT I HEARD YOU SAY THAT YOU ARE AS IRRELEVANT AS EXISTENCE. HOWEVER, AS FAR AS I AM CONCERNED, YOU ARE TOTALLY RELEVANT AND ESSENTIAL. ARE WE IN CONTRADICTION WITH EACH OTHER?
Milarepa, I am in absolute agreement with you.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22 Here everyone is the best</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
Here everyone is the best
5 February 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
A LOT CAME UP FOR ME IN DISCOURSE WHEN YOU SAID ANUBUDDHA WAS SO LOVING, SO CARING, SO SUCCESSFUL. THE LINE THAT GOT ME THE MOST WAS, “OUR BEST BODYWORKER.” MY NEED FOR PRAISE AND FEAR OF REJECTION WAS HIT BY A STRONG PUNCH IN THE STOMACH.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23 A woman is more poetic</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
A woman is more poetic
6 February 1988 am in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
THEORETICALLY SPEAKING, ENLIGHTENMENT AND WOMEN ARE JUST GREAT. BUT WHAT ABOUT PRACTICALLY SPEAKING?
Milarepa, without women there would not have been any enlightenment. That’s the reason why women themselves don’t become enlightened; they are continuously engaged in making men enlightened. They don’t have time enough for themselves.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 A complete holiday for your whole life</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 24
A complete holiday for your whole life
6 February 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
SOME SCIENTISTS ARE CONCERNED THAT MAN WILL SOME DAY RELINQUISH HIS INTELLECTUAL SUPREMACY TO COMPUTERS – MONSTER ARTIFICIAL SUPER-BRAINS WITH AN INTELLECTUAL POWER FAR BEYOND ANYTHING WE CAN NOW COMPREHEND. ANOTHER FEAR IS THAT THROUGH GENETIC ENGINEERING, MAN WILL BE CAPABLE OF GROWING ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE TO ORDER.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25 Zen: a contagious blissfulness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 25
Zen: a contagious blissfulness
22 February 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
YEARS AGO VIMALKIRTI AND I MET COUNT DURKHEIM, WHO AT THAT TIME WAS EIGHTY AND ONE OF THE MOST INFLUENTIAL SO-CALLED SPIRITUAL LEADERS OF EUROPE. HE CALLED US FOR A VISIT TO WARN US AGAINST YOU. HE SAID THAT YOUR PICTURE ON THE MALA REMINDED HIM OF MR.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26 The first religious people in this world</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 26
The first religious people in this world
23 February 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
WHAT IS THE “DARK NIGHT OF THE SOUL”? AND IS IT OUT OF DATE? LOOKING INSIDE ME AND ALL AROUND ME, I ONLY SEE MORE JOY, CONTENTMENT, LOVINGNESS, APPRECIATION OF LIFE AND OF WHAT IS. LOOKING BACK, I SEE A LOT OF MISERY, HEAVINESS, PAIN – BUT THEY SEEM TO BE RELATED TO WRONG UPBRINGING AND UNNECESSARY SELF-TORTURE, NOT TO ANY DARK NIGHT OF THE SOUL.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27 The vertical line opens a door to eternity</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 27
The vertical line opens a door to eternity
24 February 1988 am in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
YOU ONCE SAID, “THE MOMENT IS RARE WHEN ETERNITY PENETRATES TIME.” CAN YOU SPEAK MORE ON THIS?
Vadan, the question seems to be simple but the answer is very complex. And the complexity becomes multidimensional, because the answer can come only from your own experience, not from outside.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28 Vipassana comes in the end</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part28/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 28
Vipassana comes in the end
24 February 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
OVER THE PAST FIVE YEARS I’VE SPENT MANY WEEKS IN ISOLATION AT DHARMAGIRI, PRACTICING VIPASSANA MEDITATION AS TAUGHT BY S.N. GOENKA. I’VE NEVER EXPERIENCED SUCH PAIN, SUFFERING AND DOUBT EVER BEFORE. PRESENTLY I FEEL VERY EXHAUSTED, TIRED, YEARNING DEEPLY TO CONNECT WITH MY HEART.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>29 Nobody is missing anything</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part29/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 29
Nobody is missing anything
25 February 1988 am in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
A FEW MONTHS AGO I HAD WHAT SEEMED TO BE A GREAT REALIZATION – THAT ALL YOU HAVE EVER BEEN TEACHING IS WITNESSING. AT THE TIME I WAS VERY EXCITED ABOUT IT BUT THIS HAS FADED, LEAVING ME AFTER TWELVE YEARS OF SANNYAS STILL WITH THE QUESTION: WHAT AM I DOING WITH MY TIME HERE?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 In the search is the ego</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
In the search is the ego
18 January 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
WHEN YOU SAID LAST NIGHT THAT I AM ENLIGHTENED, IT REALLY FREAKED ME OUT. IT LOOKS LIKE I’M MUCH MORE AT EASE WITH BEING UNENLIGHTENED AND SEARCHING FOR IT, RATHER THAN JUST BEING ENLIGHTENED. I DON’T KNOW WHAT THE QUESTION IS BUT I FEEL I NEED A SLAP TO WAKE ME UP!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>30 Truth: beyond mind, beyond language</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part30/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 30
Truth: beyond mind, beyond language
25 February 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
WHAT IS YOUR CONCEPT ABOUT GOD?
Rahul, before I answer your question, I would like to say something about you. Unless something is said about you, the question will not have a proper context. You belong to the Krishnamurti Foundation of India.
In the first place, his whole life Krishnamurti tried to say that nobody should be his follower, that there should be no doctrine in his name, that there should be no organization around him, that he is not teaching you some belief system, but only sharing his experience.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Fear is to be understood, not conquered</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
Fear is to be understood, not conquered
19 January 1988 am in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
I ALWAYS THOUGHT THAT ONE HAD TO CONQUER FEAR, AND THEN DEATH WOULD NOT BE SCARY ANYMORE. THE OTHER DAY I WAS SITTING IN A PLACE IN THE HILLS WHERE PEOPLE WERE KILLED AND I SAW THAT DEATH IS SWEET.
NOW I THINK IT MUST BE MORE LIKE THIS – THAT DEATH HELPS ONE TO UNDERSTAND FEAR; THAT FIRST YOU EXPERIENCE DEATH AND SHE HELPS YOU SEE WHAT FEAR IS ALL ABOUT.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 This earth is more than a paradise</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
This earth is more than a paradise
19 January 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
AT VARIOUS TIMES I HAVE HEARD YOU DESCRIBE YOUR WORK AS “AN EXPERIMENT TO PROVOKE GOD” AND “A MODEL CITY FOR THE FUTURE.” THEN THERE WAS THE WORLD TOUR.
IN THE PRESENT CONTEXT OF ACCELERATING GLOBAL CRISIS, HOW WOULD YOU DESCRIBE YOUR WORK NOW, AND WHAT IS HAPPENING TO THOSE WHO HAVE GATHERED AROUND YOU HERE?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Guilt is inverted revenge</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
Guilt is inverted revenge
20 January 1988 am in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
EVERY TIME YOU CALL HOMOSEXUALITY A PERVERSION, EVEN THOUGH YOU DO NOT CONDEMN HOMOSEXUALS, I FEEL HURT AS I AM A GAY. I HAVE TRIED TO LOOK, TO WATCH, TO MEDITATE ON IT BUT STILL MY FEELINGS, MY LOVE GO NATURALLY AFTER MEN. SINCE BEING WITH A MAN I LIKE AND TRUST, I HAVE FELT SILENCE AND HAPPINESS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Your master is your whole universe</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
Your master is your whole universe
20 January 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
I WAS WITH A VERY STRICT ENLIGHTENED TEACHER, LEE LOZOWICK, IN AMERICA FOR SIX YEARS. WHILE IN BOULDER, COLORADO, I FELL IN LOVE WITH YOUR SANNYASINS, AND THEN YOU. NOW, AFTER ONE WEEK IN POONA, A NAGGING FEELING HAS ARISEN IN ME: HAVE I TRULY TAKEN SANNYAS, AND ARE YOU TRULY MY MASTER?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 No one is insignificant</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
No one is insignificant
21 January 1988 am in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
THE OTHER MORNING, DISCOURSE LEFT ME FEELING TERRIFIED AND DESPERATE: DESPERATE TO SAVE THIS INCREDIBLE, BEAUTIFUL PLANET, AND TERRIFIED BECAUSE THE ODDS AGAINST US SEEM SO HIGH AND I FEEL SO INSIGNIFICANT, AND HELPLESS TO DO ANYTHING! THE ONLY THING I CAN SEE TO DO IS TO BE HERE WITH YOU AS MUCH AS POSSIBLE, NOURISHING MY CONSCIOUSNESS AND SUPPORTING YOUR VISION.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 A god is a despot</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hari_om_tat_sat/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
A god is a despot
21 January 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
WHAT IS EXISTENCE? IS IT SOMETHING LIKE WHAT PEOPLE CALL GOD?
Sampurna, existence is that which is, and God is that which is not. Existence is a reality, God is a fiction. Existence is available only to meditators, people of silence; God is a consolation for sick minds, sick psychologies.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
