<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Further Shore on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Further Shore on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 Blessings on your journey to the further shore beyond darkness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
Blessings on your journey to the further shore beyond darkness
1 June 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says: Just that I hope to make more progress with myself. I’ve been working on myself, and I hope I get somewhere with it.It’s so joyous being here.]
You will grow every day. Just relax and meditate and sing and dance and forget the whole world!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 When the time is right, the fruit falls down</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
When the time is right, the fruit falls down
11 June 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says that although everything is fine he feels he is still missing something, maybe laughter.]
That feeling of missing something continues to the very end; it goes only at the last moment. You are not missing anything really, mm? – you are growing rightly, you ate moving in the right direction.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 Nature is the temple of god</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
Nature is the temple of god
12 June 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, giten means consciousness – bliss consciousness. And these two things have to be remembered: on one hand, remember to be more conscious; on the other hand, remember to be more blissful. These are the two wings, and if you can attain to these two wings god is not very far away; the whole sky is available.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Each individual is a gift of god</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
Each individual is a gift of god
13 June 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho gives a sannyasin a name for a centre in the West.]
This will be the name: neerava. It means such a silence that sound is not a disturbance to it.
There are two kinds of silences: one silence which can be disturbed by sound.That’s not very</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 Unless you meet god how can you be satisfied</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
Unless you meet god how can you be satisfied
15 June 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says he has a lot of tension in his back and neck – tension that is so painful at times that it totally occupies his attention.It comes in the silent parts of the meditations.
Osho asks him for details, and then checks his energy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 Become a child, full of wonder</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
Become a child, full of wonder
16 June 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin, returning to the West, says she is confused.]
Confusion remains, and one has to learn to live with it because life cannot be sorted out; it is so big. The confusion arises because of our impossible effort to sort everything out; it is too big for that!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 To have to risk all</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
To have to risk all
17 June 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho explains the meaning deva savya – all is divine. Without any exception, all is divine; the moment you exclude something you have not understood this. Everything that god has given you, Osho continues, has to be used and transformed because nothing is without meaning or significance]
[The new sannyasin says: I changed my mind several times!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 There are not golden rules</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
There are not golden rules
18 June 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho tells a sannyasin there are some things about his energy that it will be helpful for him to know. You haven’t allowed yourself to ever be wild, you’ve always had a subtle control inside you – and that can be a hindrance to spiritual growth... ]
There is a subtle difference between repression and control.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 Allow nothing to happen</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
Allow nothing to happen
19 June 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho explains the meaning of deva vanya: a wild forest! Drop civilisation, drop culture, he says to her, and become more and more natural. That’s your religion... that has to be your religion.]
Start learning the language of nature again: talk to the trees and talk to the rivers and talk to the rocks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 In the darkest night, search for and find a star</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
In the darkest night, search for and find a star
20 June 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, mahamani means the cosmic mind – bliss mind. And all depends on the mind. Ultimately all is our attitude. If we suffer, we suffer because of our wrong attitude, because of our wrong mind. Because we have created a mind which suffers, because we have cultivated a suffering mind, we suffer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19 The courage of a madman is needed</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
The courage of a madman is needed
21 June 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
... Let the past be dropped as if it were part of a dream, as if it belonged to somebody else, as if you had seen it in a movie that you were just a witness to and not a participant in – just a watcher, a spectator, standing aloof.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 To be with a master is just a device</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
To be with a master is just a device
2 June 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says he is continually changing his mind about staying or going to the West: So there’s never an acceptance of the way the thing is. It’s always wanting the other, and then as soon as that possibility happens, I don’t want that either.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 Become an instrument to me</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
Become an instrument to me
22 June 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin who is leaving for the west says he has a hard time accepting everything about himself and finds it particularly tricky relating to people – especially to strangers and to groups of people: I don’t know whether to just accept it, or to try and do something about it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 People who are full of wonder are people of god</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
People who are full of wonder are people of god
23 June 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin is returning to the west. Osho gives him a box, saying that whenever he needs him, he should hold the box in his hands, close his eyes and feel Osho. Don’t remember me, Osho reiterates, feel me]
Remembrance is just memory. Live it rather than remember it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22 Walk, enter \-- the way is here</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
Walk, enter – the way is here
24 June 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A new sannyasin says he is a musician. Osho says, perfectly good – that will fit with me!... ]
People who are in any way concerned with art are my people, because to me art is closer to religion than anything else. A mathematician is far away; a musician is very close.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23 Doing is okay \-- non-doing is okay</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
Doing is okay – non-doing is okay
25 June 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A fifteen-year-old sannyasin tells Osho he left school, in the West, because he had some problems there. Very good! says Osho, the earlier the problems start, the better, so one can start solving them. He suggests some groups and then asks him if he has anything to say.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 The beginning is half the journey</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 24
The beginning is half the journey
26 June 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A visitor says: For a long time I’ve been trying to understand ‘tat twam asi’. I’ve been meditating on it and intellectually I can’t get any understanding about this phrase.]
Intellectually there is no way to understand it; it has nothing to do with intellect and it is not a philosophical statement.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25 We are coming closer to a better world</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 25
We are coming closer to a better world
27 June 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Ram is one of the names of god. In india we have one thousand names for god. The basic idea is that all names are of god – obviously, because there is nobody else other than god so all names are his, all forms are his.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26 To me, this and that world are not separate</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 26
To me, this and that world are not separate
28 June 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A visitor said he had been, for a short time, in a seminary in rome monastery in Thailand.]
... This is also good, mm? – nothing is bad, everything helps. Do a few groups here – that will help you to come out of the monastery.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27 Love is the bridge between the human and the divine</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 27
Love is the bridge between the human and the divine
29 June 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Keshava.… It is Krishna’s name and literally it means ‘the long-haired one’. He has many names, each name to indicate just one of his qualities.
He is called ‘the long-haired one’ because he was one of the greatest incarnations of the feminine spirit, of yin.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28 The more you flow into existence, the more it flows into you</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/part28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/part28/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 28
The more you flow into existence, the more it flows into you
30 June 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva shakta. It means divine energy. And you have to play with your energy as much as possible. Create more and more loving intimacy with your energy, allow it all kinds of play. Sitting silently, let kriya happen and don’t inhibit it, don’t repress it; that is the way to commune with god.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 In this community everything is allowed</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
In this community everything is allowed
3 June 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin who has just completed the primal group says: I feel very young and unable to be grown-up. And it frightens me... My body feels very unloose – as if it’s not me. I feel very separate from it and with what’s going on in me.]</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Religion is a courting, not a conquering</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
Religion is a courting, not a conquering
4 June 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Jivan kavya: life poetry.
And poetry is the right approach towards life: prose is not the right approach. They are worlds apart – poetry and prose – and they are the two approaches to know.
By prose I mean the logical approach, the argumentative, the rational, and by poetry I mean the feeling approach, the aesthetic approach, the intuitive approach.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 I accept you as you are. I love you.</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
I accept you as you are. I love you.
5 June 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says: I’m going back to pursue my study of astrology and to try to use it as a medium to communicate with people – not for its predictative qualities but just as a psychological tool.in
pointing out blocks and indicating how best we can use our energy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Love utterly, totally\... Love madly.</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
Love utterly, totally... Love madly.
6 June 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A newly arrived sannyasin says she did encounter group in Germany and felt she was on the point of exploding but kept control, she held back from the point of total let-go. Osho checks her energy and says that she is controlling a lot, but reassures her that something can be done; it is not a problem.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Even in your deepest sleep I am there</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
Even in your deepest sleep I am there
7 June 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin who is leaving says she is afraid she will forget Osho.]
You will not slip back... and you will not forget me; don’t be worried. But the fear comes to everybody. It is natural. Here you live in a different climate: for twenty-four hours you are thinking of me, remembering me.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 You are entering a chaos</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
You are entering a chaos
9 June 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Savya means all, sachi means true... and that’s your path too: become as authentic as possible. Let authenticity be your god; don’t allow any falsity to abide in you. The moment you feel something is false drop it immediately, instantly, whatsoever the cost. The moment you feel that you are wearing a mask, throw it away.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 Meditation is a way of living</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_further_shore/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
Meditation is a way of living
10 June 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A visitor, a poet and teacher of creative writing, said he felt very moved by Osho’s books, but now he feels confused. He will stay for the camp.]
Very good! So do the camp, mm? and get into meditations, because the thing that has brought you towards me is a deep desire somewhere for meditation.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
