<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Get Out of Your Own Way on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/get_out_of_your_own_way/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Get Out of Your Own Way on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/get_out_of_your_own_way/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/get_out_of_your_own_way/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/get_out_of_your_own_way/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
7 April 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[To a sannyasin, a film-producer who is returning to the States, Osho said that meditation could be introduced to many people through the medium of film and television.]
Books are very old media. The days for books are gone. People don’t have that much time to read, because reading is active; you have to do something.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/get_out_of_your_own_way/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/get_out_of_your_own_way/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
17 April 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin said he was feeling a little apprehensive about going, saying that he hoped he would not lose that which he had gained while he was here.]
You can never lose that. Whatsoever is attained is attained forever. There is no way to fall back. If you fall back that simply shows that you were imagining that you had attained something.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/get_out_of_your_own_way/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/get_out_of_your_own_way/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
18 April 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[ A sannyasin says: When I am by myself I feel I can let go in some ways and love people but as soon as I come into their presence, the shutters go up.]
Mm... mm. It is difficult to love real people because a real person is not going to fulfil your expectations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/get_out_of_your_own_way/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/get_out_of_your_own_way/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
19 April 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin commented that he was very surprised to read in the Rajneesh newsletter that Osho had said that about half of the Westerners who come here are homosexual.
He seemed unclear as to whether he should try to change his own homosexual relationships or remain as he was.
Osho said that these kinds of issues are not serious problems.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/get_out_of_your_own_way/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/get_out_of_your_own_way/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
20 April 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Natyam means a drama, and anand means bliss – the drama of bliss. That is what life is meant to be – a game and play, a game and play of bliss.
From this very moment, start being blissful. Don’t wait for any reason – there is no need; just start being blissful.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/get_out_of_your_own_way/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/get_out_of_your_own_way/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
21 April 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin said that he had decided some time ago to dedicate his life to music. He went on to say that he played drums and had been part of a group in Australia.]
Really devote yourself to it... religiously devote yourself. Sacrifice your whole being.
Music is a very subtle meditation. The seven notes of music are concerned with the seven chakras of the body and each chakra has its own note.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/get_out_of_your_own_way/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/get_out_of_your_own_way/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
22 April 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love and sadhu means two or three things. One is, being unattached to the world, a deep non-attachment, a renunciation. It also means goodness ... a very good man whose goodness is not just a discipline of morality but which has arisen through his being; whose goodness is simply his nature, spontaneity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/get_out_of_your_own_way/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/get_out_of_your_own_way/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
23 April 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[The divine healing group is present and gives a demonstration. Osho has spoken on healing recently, saying:]
The healer is not really a healer because he is not a doer. Healing happens through him; he has just to annihilate himself. To be a healer really means not to be. The less you are, the better healing will happen.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/get_out_of_your_own_way/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/get_out_of_your_own_way/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
24 April 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says she hasn’t the courage to take risks.]
But that may be your thing – not taking risks. There is no need to take risks. If that is your thing, it’s okay. If that is not your thing, there is no need. Always remember that when I say ‘Do your thing’, I mean do it – whatsoever it is.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/get_out_of_your_own_way/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/get_out_of_your_own_way/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
25 April 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin leaving for Scotland said he was feeling apprehensive about going home.
Osho said it was good to pass through different situations, changes, otherwise one began to stagnate and to have a false sense of security. Life takes care of one, and though there may be change and upheaval, things always settle again, and slowly one begins to have a trust in life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/get_out_of_your_own_way/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/get_out_of_your_own_way/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
26 April 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[An assistant groupleader says: I’m not feeling unhappy or happy.] If you want to be happy then who is blocking the way?
... That can be an even bigger problem. If you feel unhappy, it is easier to feel happy, but if you are not feeling unhappy, it will be more difficult. This will create a sort of numbness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/get_out_of_your_own_way/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/get_out_of_your_own_way/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
8 April 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin studying acupuncture, said that he was a little dubious about the value of what he was doing... ]
Just these weeks you spend here will create much. It will give you more confidence and centring.
And everybody hesitates in the beginning. It is good... only fools don’t hesitate. You are moving in a very delicate world.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/get_out_of_your_own_way/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/get_out_of_your_own_way/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
27 April 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A small boy sannyasin asks what it means to be enlightened.]
(chuckling) Very good! I will make you enlightened and then you will know!
The word means when the inner light bums and you are full of light. It is just like a small lamp inside which is not burning yet, mm? It has to be kindled and then you will be full of light.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/get_out_of_your_own_way/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/get_out_of_your_own_way/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
28 April 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A newcomer, asked Osho what he should do in the time he was here.]
Start the meditations and do one group, Aum marathon. It will stir your energy, your bio-energy.
We have been taught to live at the minimum and the society is absolutely afraid to allow the maximum possibility, so we have been taught, somehow, to lower our energy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/get_out_of_your_own_way/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/get_out_of_your_own_way/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
29 April 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A couple ask Osho about their relationship. He wants more space amd freedom. She says her whole life revolves around him. At first she wanted to blame him or herself for the problem, but then she realised there was nothing wrong with them.]
There is nothing wrong. In fact there is never anything wrong with anybody.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/get_out_of_your_own_way/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/get_out_of_your_own_way/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
30 April 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin said he had learnt a form of massage based on the acupuncture points which worked on the blood circulation and the nervous system. He said he would like to share this.]
Share whatsoever you know and want to share. It is always good to share, because the more you share, the more you know.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/get_out_of_your_own_way/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/get_out_of_your_own_way/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 24
1 May 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Dharma Deepam. It means light of religion, light of the law, light of the ultimate. Dharma means many things, but basically it means exactly what Tao means – the fundamental law of existence. It is used for religion because religion is also a fundamental law, life.
The english word ‘religion’ has very wrong connotations with it – sectarian, moral, theological; less concerned with the spontaneity of existence.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/get_out_of_your_own_way/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/get_out_of_your_own_way/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 25
2 May 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Santan means silence and anand means bliss. These two things have to be remembered. Be as peaceful and silent as possible. Let it become a climate around you. Walking, feel as if you are surrounded by a deep silence.
In the beginning it will just be ‘as if’, but every idea becomes a reality, and every reality was just an idea in the beginning.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/get_out_of_your_own_way/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/get_out_of_your_own_way/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
9 April 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin about his responsibilities as a father as he would be separating from his wife. His wife and he had arranged that the three boys would live with him, while the girl would live with her mother.]
Much will have to be done, because when the mother is not there, your responsibilities become greater, bigger.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/get_out_of_your_own_way/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/get_out_of_your_own_way/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
10 April 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says: I want to feel more of an intensity with you, but things seem cloudy. Nothing is wrong, and nothing is especially right.]
That’s how it should be. Because anything special is not going to last. Anything special is a sort of excitement. No excitement can become a permanent thing. It is a honeymoon.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/get_out_of_your_own_way/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/get_out_of_your_own_way/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
11 April 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin said that she had been practising Yoga for about ten years. Osho said that it would be helpful for her if she did a few growth groups while she was here, as though there are many benefits in Yoga, it is slightly repressive... ]
The more you train your body, the more you are able to control it, the more repressive you become, unknowingly, because all sorts of control brings repression.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/get_out_of_your_own_way/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/get_out_of_your_own_way/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
12 April 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin said she had been having very frightening dreams, since childhood, in which she was being cut into.]
This will go... this will go. You have to do one thing – do it consciously. It will be difficult, but you have to do it consciously. Whatever one avoids in the day, comes in the night.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/get_out_of_your_own_way/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/get_out_of_your_own_way/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
13 April 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin said she was uncertain whether she should be in a relationship or not and whether the man she was with was the right one for her.]
Ordinarily a relationship always disturbs. Unless you are capable of remaining alone, a relationship always disturbs.
It is almost like a banker. If you have money, the banker will give it to you.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/get_out_of_your_own_way/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/get_out_of_your_own_way/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
14 April 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A couple were at darshan together. He said that he felt some frustration in their relationship – over just little things.]
Relationships bring up many things which are hidden in you. A relationship never creates anything. It can only bring out something which is already there.
So never throw the responsibility on the other.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/get_out_of_your_own_way/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/get_out_of_your_own_way/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
15 April 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[To a sannyasin who said he was studying Yoga but had never done any groups, Osho recommended he do some groups, saying that otherwise Yoga could make one very repressed.]
Yoga is good, but something more is needed. Alone, it has crippled the whole country. This country has suffered too much.
It creates a very stiff, structured being.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
