<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Eternal Quest on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_eternal_quest/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Eternal Quest on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/the_eternal_quest/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 Religion: The Door of Feeling</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_eternal_quest/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_eternal_quest/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
Religion: The Door of Feeling
Date Unknown
Question
WHAT IS THE BASIC INDIAN PHILOSOPHY?
As far as I am concerned, I do not see philosophy as Indian or non-Indian. It is not possible. Philosophy is only universal. There can be no geographical division in the human mind. These divisions, these distinctions, are political. Indian, Japanese and German, or eastern and western – all these divisions are political.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 If You Take the Whole out of the Whole</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_eternal_quest/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_eternal_quest/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
If You Take the Whole out of the Whole
Date Unknown
Question
HOW CAN WE BECOME ONE WITH THE REALITY AND WHY ARE WE SEPARATE FROM IS?
The division is something that we ourselves have created. Reality has always been one; it has never known any division. All division is a mental division, a creation of our own conditioning. Reality has always been undivided, indivisible.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 A Meeting with the Hare Krishna People</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_eternal_quest/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_eternal_quest/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
A Meeting with the Hare Krishna People
Date Unknown
Question
WHAT IS YOUR CONCEPTION OF ABSOLUTE TRUTH?
No conception about absolute truth is possible because every conception is bound to be relative. The absolute transcends every conceptualization; you cannot conceive it. You can live it, you can be in it, but no intellectual conception is possible about the absolute. All conceptions are bound to be erroneous because conception, as such, is relative.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Right Questioning</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_eternal_quest/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_eternal_quest/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
Right Questioning
Date Unknown
Before you ask something, I must tell you that there are two types of questioning. One type of questioning comes not because you do not know, but because you know something. It comes out of your so-called knowledge. You have the answer already and then you raise the question. It is so stupid!
Whatever you know, you have not really known it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 Moving Between Polarities</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_eternal_quest/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_eternal_quest/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
Moving Between Polarities
Date Unknown
Question
MAN IS WEAK AND HELPLESS WHAT CAN HE DO TO FIND STRENGTH?
It is not that you feel helpless and weak because you do not have strength You feel weak because there is a craving for more strength. It is relative.
It is not that you are weak. You are what you are: neither weak nor strong.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 The Alchemy of Religion</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_eternal_quest/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_eternal_quest/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
The Alchemy of Religion
Date Unknown
Question
PEOPLE IN BOTH THE EAST AND THE WEST ARE SUFFERING IN EVERY DIMENSION OF LIFE. WILL YOU DIAGNOSE THIS SUFFERING FOR US: ITS CAUSES, ITS PREVENTIONS AND ITS CURES?
Suffering is symbolic. It does not have causes, but only one cause. Howsoever different the suffering, the cause is always the same. The cause is that the hidden harmony between the human mind and the cosmic existence is lost.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 The Last Flowering</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_eternal_quest/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_eternal_quest/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 15
The Last Flowering
Date Unknown
Question
ON EVERY OTHER STREET CORNER IN INDIA, IT SEEMS ONE SEES BEGGARS WHO CLAIM TO BE SADHUS, RENUNCIATES. ARE THEY JUST PARASITES ANT EXPLOITERS, OR ARE THEY REALLY AUTHENTIC HOLY MEN?
Everything that can be helpful can be harmful also. For every authentic coin there is, a false coin can be interpreted as authentic. But it cannot be avoided.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Discovering Your Own Path</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_eternal_quest/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_eternal_quest/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
Discovering Your Own Path
Date Unknown
Question
PEOPLE IN THE WEST TODAY ARE CRYING OUT OF THEORETICAL SOLUTIONS TO THEIR PROBLEMS. YOU HAVE OFTEN SPOKEN ABOUT 112 MAJOR TECHNIQUES THAT HAVE BEEN USED TO REACH THE DIVINE. WILL YOU PLEASE TELL US ABOUT SOME OF THOSE METHODS?
No theoretical solutions are ever possible. It appears as though the human problem is a theoretical problem, but the problem is always existential.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 A Psychological Approach</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_eternal_quest/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_eternal_quest/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
A Psychological Approach
Date Unknown
Question
WHAT IS THE BASIC DIFFERENCE BETWEEN THE MORE FAMILIAR SYSTEMS OF YOGA AND THE SYSTEM THAT YOU HAVE DEVELOPED?
There are as many paths as there are minds. Each mind requires a particular path and each method is true for a particular person. No method is true as such or false as such. It depends on the person to whom it is to be applied.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Hatha Yoga: A Valid Approach?</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_eternal_quest/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_eternal_quest/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
Hatha Yoga: A Valid Approach?
Date Unknown
Question
IN TRADITIONAL YOGA, ONE STARTS WITH THE BODY – THROUGH HATHA YOGA METHODS. WHY IS IT THAT YOU DO NOT TEACH HATHA YOGA .
It is good to start with the body, it is necessary. But it is not sufficient. There are many problems with Hatha Yoga particularly for those in the West, because the system of Hatha Yoga and its related techniques were all developed in a very different milieu – really, for very differently constituted bodies as well as for different minds.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Freedom From Suppression</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_eternal_quest/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_eternal_quest/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
Freedom From Suppression
Date Unknown
Question
ONE DAY – IT WAS A FRIDAY WHEN ORTHODOX JEWS ARE BUSY PREPARING FOR THE SABBATH – A MAN WHO DIDN’T LIKE JEWS MET AN ORTHODOX RABBI ON THE STREET. IN AN ATTEMPT TO TORMENT HIM HE ASKED HIM TO EXPRESS THE ENTIRE PHILOSOPHY OF JUDAISM WHILE HE STOOD ON ONE FOOT. THE RABBI STOOD ON ONE FOOT AND SAID, “DO UNTO OTHERS AS YOU WOULD HAVE OTHERS DO UNTO YOU.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Religious Scriptures: History or Myth?</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_eternal_quest/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_eternal_quest/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
Religious Scriptures: History or Myth?
Date Unknown
Question
MANY WESTERN HISTORIANS FEEL THAT HUMANITY IS CONSTANTLY MAKING PROGRESS. IF THIS IS THE CASE, THEN HOW IS IT THAT HUMAN CONSCIOUSNESS IS SO UNEVOLVED?
The progress of humanity and the progress of human consciousness are two quite different dimensions. The progress of history is in time and the progress of consciousness is not in time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 The Disease Called Seriousness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_eternal_quest/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_eternal_quest/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
The Disease Called Seriousness
Date Unknown
Question
LIFE IS TREMENDOUSLY SERIOUS...
Life is not serious. You are serious. Life is not anything serious; nothing can be more nonserious than life. Life is absolutely nonserious!
Question
BUT CERTAIN THINGS HAVE BEEN ACHIEVED ONLY BECAUSE SOME PEOPLE HAVE BEEN – MAYBE THE WORD ‘SERIOUS’ IT IS NOT GOOD, BUT, RATHER, ‘INTENSE’.
Intensity is a very different thing from seriousness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 A Quest, Not a Questioning</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_eternal_quest/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_eternal_quest/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
A Quest, Not a Questioning
Date Unknown
Question
WE KNOW FROM MANY SOURCES, SUCH AS THE BIBLE, THAT GOD CREATED MAN IN HIS OWN IMAGE. IF HE HAS CREATED EVERYTHING, EVERYTHING MUST BE GOOD. THEN WHERE DOES THE IDEA OF WICKEDNESS COME FROM.
So many things will have to be taken into account. Firstly, to think of God as the creator is to divide reality into two: the creator and the created.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 The Need for Authenticity</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_eternal_quest/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_eternal_quest/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
The Need for Authenticity
Date Unknown
Question
IS REINCARNATION A PART OF YOUR TEACHINGS?
I don’t talk much about doctrines. I am not very interested in intellectual gymnastics. Reincarnation is a fact, but I don’t talk much about it. I may help you to remember your past lives, but I don’t make a doctrine out of it. If you can remember them than it is okay.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
