<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Being in Love on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/being_in_love/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Being in Love on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/being_in_love/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ABOUT THE AUTHOR</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/being_in_love/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/being_in_love/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌ABOUT THE AUTHOR‌ Osho’s teachings defy categorization, covering everything from the individual quest for meaning to the most urgent social and political issues facing society today. His books are not written but are transcribed from audio and video recordings of extemporaneous talks given to international audiences over a period of thirty-five years. Osho has been described by the London Sunday Times as one of the “1000 Makers of the 20th Century” and by American author Tom Robbins as “the most dangerous man since Jesus Christ.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ALSO BY OSHO</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/being_in_love/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/being_in_love/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌More OSHO Books‌
INSIGHTS FOR A NEW WAY OF LIVING SERIES
Awareness Compassion Courage Creativity Freedom Intelligence Intimacy Intuition Joy Maturity
OTHER BOOKS
Emotional Wellness
The Book of Understanding
Autobiography of a Spiritually Incorrect Mystic The Book of Secrets
Pharmacy for the Soul Love, Freedom, Aloneness
Meditation: The First and Last Freedom
Sex Matters
Your Answers Questioned Osho Transformation Tarot Osho Zen Tarot</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CHAPTER 1: BEYOND DEPENDENCY AND DOMINATION</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/being_in_love/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/being_in_love/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌BEYOND DEPENDENCY AND DOMINATION‌
Breaking Out of the Shell of the Ego I have been always surprised by the number of people who come to me and say they are afraid of love. What is the fear of love? It is because when you really love somebody your ego starts slipping away and melting. You cannot love with the ego; the ego becomes a barrier, and when you want to drop the barrier between yourself and the other, the ego says, “This is going to be a death.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CHAPTER 10: &#34;LOVE&#34; IS A VERB</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/being_in_love/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/being_in_love/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌“LOVE” IS A VERB‌ {#love-is-a-verb style=”padding-left: 69pt;text-indent: 0pt;text-align: left;“} Love is existential; fear is only the absence of love. And the problem with any absence is that you cannot do anything directly about it. Fear is like darkness. What can you do about darkness directly? You cannot drop it, you cannot throw it out, you cannot bring it in. There is no way to relate with darkness without bringing light in.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CHAPTER 11: COUPLES COUNSELING</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/being_in_love/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/being_in_love/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌COUPLES COUNSELING‌
Insights for Living and Growing in Love Editor’s note: The following selections are taken from the evening meetings where Osho spoke directly with one or both partners in a couple, or with individuals who had come to ask him for insight into their problems in relationships. When Telepathy Doesn’t Work It almost always happens that couples don’t make things clear to each other.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CHAPTER 12: ONLY LOVE REMAINS</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/being_in_love/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/being_in_love/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌ONLY LOVE REMAINS‌
Only after you have moved in deep love and the ego has really been dropped—and there is something very valuable which can be gained only if you drop the ego, and that price has to be paid—when you have really loved deeply, then a new kind of integration will arise in you. Love does two things: first it takes the ego away, then it gives you the center.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CHAPTER 2: THE NATURAL STAGES OF LIFE AND LOVING</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/being_in_love/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/being_in_love/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌THE NATURAL STAGES OF LIFE AND LOVING‌
People have asked me, what is the right way to provide a loving atmosphere that can help a child grow without interfering in his natural potentiality. Every way to help a child is wrong. The very idea of helping is not right. The child needs your love, not your help. The child needs nourishment, support, but not your help.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CHAPTER 3: THE CANDLE OF AWARENESS</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/being_in_love/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/being_in_love/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌THE CANDLE OF AWARENESS‌
A questioner has asked, “How to start the journey towards love?” Once you ask the question the journey has already started; you are in the journey. This has to be recognized—unconsciously, you are in the journey: that’s why it feels as if you have to start it. Recognize it, become conscious about it, and the very recognition becomes the beginning.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CHAPTER 4: NONSENSE IDEAS IN YOUR HEAD</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/being_in_love/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/being_in_love/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌NONSENSE IDEAS IN YOUR HEAD‌
Love is the only religion, the only god, the only mystery that has to be lived, understood. When love is understood, you have understood all the sages and all the mystics of the world. It is not anything difficult. It is as simple as your heartbeats or your breathing. It comes with you, it is not given to you by the society.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CHAPTER 5: &#34;LOVE HURTS&#34; AND OTHER MISUNDERSTANDINGS</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/being_in_love/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/being_in_love/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌“LOVE HURTS” AND OTHER MISUNDERSTANDINGS‌ {#love-hurts-and-other-misunderstandings style=”padding-left: 31pt;text-indent: 0pt;text-align: center;“} Love never hurts anybody. And if you feel you have been hurt by love, it is something else in you, not your loving quality, that feels hurt. Unless you see this you will go on moving in the same circles again and again. What you call love can hide many unloving things in you; the human mind has been very clever, cunning, in deceiving others and in deceiving itself, too.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CHAPTER 6: ATTRACTION AND OPPOSITION</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/being_in_love/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/being_in_love/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌ATTRACTION AND OPPOSITION‌
There are a few very fundamental things to be understood. First, a man and a woman are on the one hand halves of the other, and on the other hand, opposite polarities. Their being opposites attracts them to each other. The farther away they are, the deeper will be the attraction; the more different from each other they are, the more will be the charm and beauty and attraction.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CHAPTER 7: DROPPING OUT OF THE LONELY HEARTS CLUB</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/being_in_love/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/being_in_love/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌DROPPING OUT OF THE LONELY HEARTS CLUB‌
A very intricate, complex thing has to be understood: If you are not in love, you are lonely. If you are in love, really in love, you become alone. Loneliness is sadness; aloneness is not sadness. Loneliness is a feeling of incompleteness. You need someone and the needed one is not available. Loneliness is darkness, with no light in it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CHAPTER 8: SOUL MATES OR CELL MATES?</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/being_in_love/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/being_in_love/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌SOUL MATES OR CELL MATES?‌
We are all living lives according to fictions, poetries, film stories. That has given humanity a wrong impression, the impression that when there is love everything will fit, that there will be no conflict. For centuries poets have been giving the idea that lovers are made for each other. Nobody is made for anybody else. Everybody is different from everybody else.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CHAPTER 9: LOVE AND THE ART OF NON-DOING</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/being_in_love/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/being_in_love/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌LOVE AND THE ART OF NON-DOING‌
There are things which only happen, which cannot be done. Doing is the way of very ordinary things, mundane things. You can do something to earn money, you can do something to be powerful, you can do something to have prestige; but you cannot do anything as far as love is concerned, gratitude is concerned, silence is concerned.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CONTENTS</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/being_in_love/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/being_in_love/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CONTENTS Title Page
Introduction: What Is Love?
PART I. The Journey from “Me” to “We”
Understanding the Nature and Nurture of Love
Beyond Dependency and Domination—Breaking Out of the Shell of the [Ego]{style=” color: #0000ED; font-family:&#34;Times New Roman&#34;, serif; font-style: italic; font-weight: normal; text-decoration: underline; font-size: 14pt;“} {style=” color: #0000ED; font-family:&#34;Times New Roman&#34;, serif; font-style: italic; font-weight: normal; text-decoration: none; font-size: 14pt;“} The Natural Stages of Life and Loving</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>INTRODUCTION: WHAT IS LOVE?</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/being_in_love/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/being_in_love/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌INTRODUCTION: WHAT IS LOVE?‌ It is unfortunate that we have to ask this question. In the natural course of things everybody would know what love is. But in fact nobody knows, or only very rarely does somebody know, what love is. Love has become one of the rarest experiences. Yes, it is talked about. Films and stories are written about it, songs are composed about it, on the television shows you will see it, on the radio, in magazines—a great industry exists to supply you with ideas of what love is.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OSHO INTERNATIONAL MEDITATION RESORT</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/being_in_love/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/being_in_love/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌OSHO INTERNATIONAL MEDITATION RESORT‌ The Osho Meditation Resort is a place where people can have a direct personal experience of a new way of living with more alertness, relaxation, and fun. Located about 100 miles southeast of Mumbai in Pune, India, the resort offers a variety of programs to thousands of people who visit each year from more than one hundred countries around the world.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PART I</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/being_in_love/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/being_in_love/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌PART I‌
The Journey from “Me” to “We” ‌Understanding the Nature and Nurture of Love Love cannot be learned, it cannot be cultivated. The cultivated love will not be love at all. It will not be a real rose, it will be a plastic flower. When you learn something, it means something comes from the outside; it is not an inner growth. And love has to be your inner growth if it is to be authentic and real.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PART II</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/being_in_love/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/being_in_love/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌PART II‌
Love Is a Breeze ‌Making the Most of Romance Don’t think that love has to be permanent, and it will make your love life more beautiful because you will know that today you are together, and tomorrow perhaps you will have to part.
Love comes like a fresh, fragrant breeze into your home, fills it with freshness and fragrance, remains as long as existence allows it, and then moves out.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PART III</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/being_in_love/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/being_in_love/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌PART III‌
From Relationship to Relating—Love as a State of Being The capacity to be alone is the capacity to love. It may look paradoxical to you, but it is not. It is an existential truth: only those people who are capable of being alone are capable of love, of sharing, of going into the deepest core of the other person—without possessing the other, without becoming dependent on the other, without reducing the other to a thing, and without becoming addicted to the other.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TITLE PAGE</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/being_in_love/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/being_in_love/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌[H]{style=” color: #211F21;“}O\&#39;/ [t]{style=” color: #343434;“}O [l]{style=” color: #211F21;“}ove w[ith a]{style=” color: #343434;“}w[aren]{style=” color: #343434;“}ess [and relate ]{style=” color: #343434;“}w[ith]{style=” color: #343434;“}o[ut]{style=” color: #343434;“}[f]{style=” color: #211F21;“}e[ar]{style=” color: #343434;“}‌
0 BEINGINL[OV]{style=” color: #444;“}E
M:irmorrt Boob [Nt&#39;Yo&#39;Yo]{style=” color: #696969;“}[rl:]{style=” color: #444;“}
&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
