<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Secret of Secrets, Vol 2 on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Secret of Secrets, Vol 2 on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 A little bit of sky</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_2/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_2/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
A little bit of sky
27 August 1978 am in Buddha Hall
MASTER LU-TSU SAID: YOUR WORK WILL GRADUALLY BECOME CONCENTRATED AND MATURE, BUT BEFORE YOU REACH THE CONDITION IN WHICH YOU SIT LIKE A WITHERED TREE BEFORE A CLIFF, THERE ARE STILL MANY POSSIBILITIES OF ERROR WHICH I WOULD LIKE TO BRING TO YOUR SPECIAL ATTENTION. THESE CONDITIONS ARE RECOGNIZED ONLY WHEN THEY HAVE BEEN PERSONALLY EXPERIENCED.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Because of love, we are together</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_2/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_2/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
Because of love, we are together
5 September 1978 am in Buddha Hall
The first question:
Question 1
CAN YOU GIVE ME A MESSAGE TO TAKE TO THE WESTERN WORLD SO THAT PEOPLE THERE MIGHT UNDERSTAND YOU AND YOUR FOLLOWERS?
Joey Simons, my message is very simple. That’s why it is difficult to understand. I teach the obvious; it is not complex at all.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 The contemplation of emptiness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_2/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_2/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
The contemplation of emptiness
6 September 1978 am in Buddha Hall
MASTER LU-TSU SAID: IF YOU ARE NOT YET CLEAR, I WILL MAKE IT CLEAR TO YOU THROUGH THE THREEFOLD BUDDHIST CONTEMPLATION OF EMPTINESS, DELUSION, AND THE CENTER.
EMPTINESS COMES AS THE FIRST OF THE THREE CONTEMPLATIONS. ALL THINGS ARE LOOKED UPON AS EMPTY. THEN FOLLOWS DELUSION. ALTHOUGH IT IS KNOWN THAT THEY ARE EMPTY, THINGS ARE NOT DESTROYED, BUT ONE ATTENDS TO ONE’S AFFAIRS IN THE MIDST OF EMPTINESS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Tao is already happening</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_2/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_2/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
Tao is already happening
7 September 1978 am in Buddha Hall
The first question:
Question 1
YES! YES! WAKE ME UP! THIS SILLY, MULTI-SCHIZOPHRENIC, LEAKING, WATERING CAN HAS BEEN DEEPLY AFFECTED BY THESE LECTURES – BUT ONE THING LATELY IS, I AM FEELING MORE AND MORE GROSS. OSHO, I WANT MY LOTUSES TO BLOOM, TO FEEL TAO, BE WORTHY OF TAO, TO BE TAO.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 Where the positive and negative meet</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_2/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_2/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
Where the positive and negative meet
8 September 1978 am in Buddha Hall
THE TAO, THE UNDIVIDED, GREAT ONE, GIVES RISE TO TWO OPPOSITE REALITY PRINCIPLES, THE DARK AND THE LIGHT, YIN AND YANG. FROM YIN COMES THE RECEPTIVE FEMININE PRINCIPLE; FROM YANG COMES THE CREATIVE MASCULINE PRINCIPLE; FROM YIN COMES MING, LIFE; FROM YANG, HSING OR HUMAN NATURE.
EACH INDIVIDUAL CONTAINS A CENTRAL MONAD, WHICH, AT THE MOMENT OF CONCEPTION, SPLITS INTO LIFE AND HUMAN NATURE, MING AND HSING.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 This very world the paradise</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_2/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_2/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
This very world the paradise
9 September 1978 am in Buddha Hall
The first question:
Question 1
YOUR DANCING MEDITATIONS SEEM TO BE BRINGING FORTH AN OVERWHELMING SENSUOUSNESS. ALL THAT HAS NOT BEEN TAKEN, ALL THAT HAS NOT BEEN GIVEN IS REVEALED THEN.THE PLAY OF NATURE ON MY WHOLE BEING, ALL THE BEAUTY THAT
I BEHOLD, ALL THE MUSIC THAT ENCHANTS MY EARS AND MY SOUL, ALL SEEM TO BE EXPRESSED IN VOLUPTUOUSNESS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 The festive dimension</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_2/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_2/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 15
The festive dimension
10 September 1978 am in Buddha Hall
The first question:
Question 1
ONE OF THE CONTROVERSIAL ISSUES ABOUT THE RAJNEESH ASHRAM CONCERNS INDULGENCE IN SEX AND WHAT ARE BEING CONDEMNED AS SEXUAL PERVERSIONS OR ORGIES. WE WOULD LIKE BHAGWAN RAJNEESH TO GIVE US HIS VIEWS ON SEX AND ITS ROLE IN TRANSCENDENCE. – R.K. Karanjia, Editor, BLITZ
My dear Karanjia, the way I teach is the way of life-affirmation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Love is the only friend</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_2/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_2/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
Love is the only friend
28 August 1978 am in Buddha Hall
The first question:
Question 1
OSHO, WHILE IN THERAPY MYSELF, I SPENT MUCH TIME PRAYING. OVER THE YEARS I FELT BETTER. I NEVER KNEW WHETHER IT WAS THE THERAPY OR THE PRAYER. AS A THERAPIST I WANT TO URGE OTHERS TO PRAY BUT FEEL EMBARRASSED.
Sadananda, love is therapy, and there is no other therapy in the world except love.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 The golden flower is opening</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_2/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_2/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
The golden flower is opening
29 August 1978 am in Buddha Hall
MASTER LU-TSU SAID: THERE ARE MANY KINDS OF CONFIRMATORY EXPERIENCES. ONE MUST NOT CONTENT ONESELF WITH SMALL DEMANDS BUT MUST RISE TO THE THOUGHT THAT ALL LIVING CREATURES HAVE TO BE REDEEMED. ONE MUST NOT BE TRIVIAL AND IRRESPONSIBLE IN HEART, BUT MUST STRIVE TO MAKE DEEDS PROVE ONE’S WORDS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Words cannot contain it</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_2/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_2/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
Words cannot contain it
30 August 1978 am in Buddha Hall
The first question:
Question 1
OSHO, I LOVE YOU. I ALSO LOVE YOUR JOKES. I AM VERY SERIOUS THESE DAYS. THIS WHOLE ENLIGHTENMENT GAME IS TOO HEAVY. PLEASE TELL MORE JOKES.
Majida, enlightenment, the very idea of enlightenment, is the greatest joke there is. It is a joke because it is trying to get something which is already there.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 The spirit returns and touches heaven</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_2/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_2/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
The spirit returns and touches heaven
31 August 1978 am in Buddha Hall
MASTER LU-TSU SAID: NOW THERE ARE THREE CONFIRMATORY EXPERIENCES WHICH CAN BE TESTED. THE FIRST IS THAT, WHEN ONE HAS ENTERED THE STATE OF MEDITATION, THE GODS ARE IN THE VALLEY. MEN ARE HEARD TALKING AS THOUGH AT A DISTANCE OF SEVERAL HUNDRED PACES, EACH ONE QUITE CLEAR. BUT THE SOUNDS ARE ALL LIKE AN ECHO IN A VALLEY.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Aloneness is ultimate</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_2/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_2/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
Aloneness is ultimate
1 September 1978 am in Buddha Hall
The first question:
Question 1 MASTER,
AFTER THE TIDAL WAVE OF EVENTS AND WITH THE MEMORY OF A PROFOUND EXPERIENCE, I FACE NEW ALONENESS. EFFORTS TO SHARE OR ESCAPE INTO DISTRACTIONS HAVE BAD RESULTS. WHY DO I CLING TO THIS HABIT OF ESCAPING ALONENESS? A FEW COMMENTS MAY HELP ME FOR THE TASK AHEAD.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 The moon gathers up the ten thousand waters</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_2/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_2/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
The moon gathers up the ten thousand waters
2 September 1978 am in Buddha Hall
MASTER LU-TSU SAID: FOUR WORDS CRYSTALLIZE THE SPIRIT IN THE SPACE OF ENERGY. IN THE SIXTH MONTH WHITE SNOW IS SUDDENLY SEEN TO FLY. AT THE THIRD WATCH THE SUN’S DISK SENDS OUT BLINDING RAYS. IN THE WATER BLOWS THE WIND OF THE GENTLE. WANDERING IN HEAVEN, ONE EATS THE SPIRIT-ENERGY OF THE RECEPTIVE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 I sure dig you, man</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_2/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_2/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
I sure dig you, man
3 September 1978 am in Buddha Hall
The first question:
Question 1
WHAT EXACTLY IS INTELLIGENCE, AND WHAT IS THE RELATION OF THE INTELLIGENCE OF THE HEART TO THE INTELLIGENCE OF THE MIND?
Punita, intelligence is the inborn capacity to see, to perceive. Every child is born intelligent, then made stupid by the society. We educate him in stupidity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 With emptiness, the matter is settled</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_2/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_secret_of_secrets_vol_2/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
With emptiness, the matter is settled
4 September 1978 am in Buddha Hall
MASTER LU-TSU SAID: WHEN THE SILENCE COMES, NOT A SINGLE THOUGHT ARISES; HE WHO IS LOOKING INWARD SUDDENLY FORGETS THAT he IS LOOKING. AT THIS TIME, BODY AND HEART MUST BE LEFT COMPLETELY RELEASED. ALL ENTANGLEMENTS HAVE DISAPPEARED WITHOUT TRACE. THEN I NO LONGER KNOW AT WHAT PLACE THE HOUSE OF MY SPIRIT AND MY CRUCIBLE ARE.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
