<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Light on the Path on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Light on the Path on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 Be unpredictable</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
Be unpredictable
3 December 1985 am in Kathmandu, Nepal
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
YOUR SANNYASINS AND LOVERS ALL AROUND ARE CONCERNED ABOUT YOUR HEALTH. HOW ARE YOU NOW?
My health is good. They tried to harm me but they could not succeed for two reasons: one, the people they had appointed to harass me – to indirectly create situations in which I would be suffering – soon fell in love with me.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 I love the rascal saints</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
I love the rascal saints
9 January 1986 pm in Kathmandu, Nepal
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
IS THERE A POSSIBILITY THAT A SAINT CAN BE A RASCAL?
The question reminds me of a small story – it happened in a Christian monastery. Two monks were discussing in the garden of the monastery – every day they were given one hour to walk in the garden and meditate on God.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 A true master can put you on fire</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
A true master can put you on fire
10 January 1986 pm in Kathmandu, Nepal
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
HOW IS IT POSSIBLE THAT YOU JUST WALK PAST A PERSON AND YOU SET THEM ON FIRE? I HAVE SEEN EVEN PEOPLE WHO DON’T KNOW THAT THEY LOVE YOU BURST INTO FLAMES.
The question is great. Life is not synonymous with logic, particularly the logic that Aristotle has given to the world.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Religiousness is interwoven into existence itself</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
Religiousness is interwoven into existence itself
11 January 1986 pm in Kathmandu, Nepal
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I WAS SITTING IN HOLLAND, AND THROUGH EVERYTHING THAT HAPPENED AROUND YOU, I GOT REALLY WORRIED, SO I JUST DECIDED TO COME. I WANTED TO SEE YOU, I JUST WANTED TO SEE WHETHER YOU ARE OKAY. I WAS SO MAD WHEN I SAW WHAT HAPPENED TO YOU, I GOT SO ANGRY.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 Whenever there is a sannyasin of mine, I am there</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
Whenever there is a sannyasin of mine, I am there
13 January 1986 pm in Kathmandu, Nepal
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHAT IS A BUDDHAFIELD? JUST LIVING TOGETHER, RUNNING BUSINESSES, DOESN’T SEEM TO BE ENOUGH, IT IS NOT SATISFYING. IT FEELS LIKE SOMETHING DEEPER – SOMETHING MORE CHALLENGING FOR THE COLLECTIVE AND THE INDIVIDUAL, IN WHICH BOTH GROW – IS NEEDED.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 Say it with your totality</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
Say it with your totality
14 January 1986 am in Kathmandu, Nepal
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I HAVE BEEN TRYING TO SAY WHAT AN ENLIGHTENED MASTER IS. I TRY FROM EACH ANGLE, AND EVERY MORNING, WHEN I SIT AT MY PIANO, I TRY TO SING THE SONG FROM ANOTHER PERSPECTIVE, WITH ANOTHER TUNE, ANOTHER MELODY.
BUT MY PEOPLE IN THE WEST HAVE NEVER HEARD SUCH STORIES, AND I CAN SEE THAT MY WORDS NEVER REACH THE TARGET.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 With a master the long journey can be cut short</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
With a master the long journey can be cut short
16 January 1986 am in Kathmandu, Nepal
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
A ZEN MASTER SAID, “SITTING SILENTLY, DOING NOTHING, AND THE GRASS GROWS BY ITSELF.” BUDDHA SAID, “BE A LIGHT UNTO YOURSELF.” I AGREE IN TOTO. SO WHAT IS THE NEED FOR A MASTER? CANNOT AN INTELLIGENT AND COURAGEOUS MAN WALK ALONE?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 I want a meeting of east and west</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
I want a meeting of east and west
17 January 1986 am in Kathmandu, Nepal
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
YOU HAVE BEEN USING THE KEY WORD “DEPROGRAMMING” TO DESCRIBE YOUR WORK. THE TECHNIQUES THAT YOU HAVE SUGGESTED DURING THESE YEARS, GO FROM CHAOTIC AND DYNAMIC MEDITATION TO THE MODERN THERAPEUTIC SCHOOL.
I WOULD LIKE YOU TO EXPLAIN IN BRIEF WHY YOU HAD TO CREATE NEW MEDITATION TECHNIQUES LIKE KUNDALINI MEDITATION OR DYNAMIC MEDITATION, EVEN THOUGH THERE IS A TRADITION ALREADY INCLUDING HUNDREDS OF TECHNIQUES FROM YOGA, SUFISM, BUDDHISM ETC.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 No-mind is emptiness and fullness together</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
No-mind is emptiness and fullness together
18 January 1986 am in Kathmandu, Nepal
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
ONCE YOU DESCRIBED YOUR WORK AS A SEARCH FOR THE PSYCHOLOGY OF THE BUDDHAS. YOU EXPLAINED THAT FREUD ESTABLISHED ONLY A PSYCHOLOGY OF PATHOLOGY. THEN CAME MASLOV, JANOV, ASSAGIOLI, PERLS AND THE PEOPLE WHO ELABORATED ON THE PSYCHOLOGY OF HEALTH.
YOU ADDED THAT YOUR WORK WAS GOING FURTHER – TRYING TO ESTABLISH A PSYCHOLOGY OF THE AWAKENED ONE, A PSYCHOLOGY OF THE BUDDHAS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 The mind is a deceiver</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
The mind is a deceiver
19 January 1986 am in Kathmandu, Nepal
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I LOVED THE INTRODUCTION ABOUT THE PSYCHOLOGICAL UNIVERSE THAT YOU GAVE ME YESTERDAY. AND YET I WOULD LIKE TO REPEAT THE QUESTION.
YOU SAY THAT YOU WERE STUDYING US IN ORDER TO FIND OUT WHICH ARE THE DIFFICULTIES THAT THE SEEKER FINDS ON THE PATH TOWARDS REALIZATION OF THE SELF, TOWARDS HIS OWN AWAKENING.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19 The path of truth is only for gamblers</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
The path of truth is only for gamblers
20 January 1986 am in Kathmandu, Nepal
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I HAVE A FEW QUESTIONS THAT ARE CONNECTED TO EACH OTHER. THE FIRST IS: YESTERDAY YOU SPOKE ON THE FUNCTION OF THE MASTER. I WOULD LIKE TODAY IF YOU COULD SPEAK ON THE FUNCTION OF THE DISCIPLE AND, IF THE DISCIPLE NEEDS THE MASTER, DOES THE MASTER NEED THE DISCIPLE?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 The real difficulty is to be with me</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
The real difficulty is to be with me
27 December 1985 pm in Kathmandu, Nepal
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
GREETINGS FROM THE INDIAN “RAJNEESH TIMES” FAMILY AND EVERYONE AT THE RAJNEESHDHAM NEO-SANNYAS COMMUNE. THERE ARE MANY SANNYASINS BOTH IN INDIA AND ABROAD WHO HAVE NEVER SEEN YOU, BUT THEIR LOVE FOR YOU AND THEIR COMMITMENT TO YOUR VISION IS AWE-INSPIRING. HOW EXACTLY DOES THIS HAPPEN – THIS MUCH LOVE, THIS MUCH TRUST?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 Nobody can expect consistency from me</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
Nobody can expect consistency from me
21 January 1986 am in Kathmandu, Nepal
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
THESE QUESTIONS ARE FROM THE DUTCH RAJNEESH TIMES. THE FIRST QUESTION IS: NOW YOU ARE MAKING A WORLD TOUR, FOR THE FIRST TIME THE WELL IS GOING TO THE THIRSTY. IS THE WORLD READY TO RECEIVE THE WELL?
It has been ready for a long time – not the whole world but just the chosen few.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 Nature is not anguish, it is blissfulness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
Nature is not anguish, it is blissfulness
26 January 1986 am in Kathmandu, Nepal
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
SOMETIMES I REALIZE HOW MUCH I AM AFRAID OF THE UNKNOWN. I HAVE EXPERIENCED MOMENTS OF TOTAL TRUST AND MOMENTS OF BLISS.
WHAT ARE THE TRICKS OF THE MIND TO AVOID THESE BEAUTIFUL EXPERIENCES AGAIN AND AGAIN?
The tricks of the mind are very simple.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22 The real remains silent</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
The real remains silent
26 January 1986 pm in Kathmandu, Nepal
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
IN YOUR EXPERIENCE, IS THERE ANY CONNECTION BETWEEN THE QUALITIES OF THE INVENTED SELF, AND THOSE OF THE REAL SELF? IS THE EGO LIKE A SHADOW OR A DISTORTION OF THE AUTHENTIC BEING; OR IS THERE A TOTAL DISCONTINUITY? LOOKING BACK, DO YOU SEE ANY TRACES IN THE ONE YOU ARE NOW OF THE MAN YOU ONCE WERE?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23 Cities have made the human being inhuman</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
Cities have made the human being inhuman
27 January 1986 am in Kathmandu, Nepal
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
AS MOST PEOPLE IN MODERN EUROPE LOOK AT THEIR LANDSCAPE, THEY FIND THAT THE CITIES THEY LIVE IN VARY FROM INHOSPITABLE TO FRANKLY DANGEROUS; THAT THE JOBS THEY DO (IF THEY ARE “LUCKY” ENOUGH TO HAVE ONE) ARE DULL, BORING, AND MEANINGLESS; THAT THE RELATIONSHIPS THEY HAVE ARE TOLERABLE AT THE BEST, AND LOVE IS A RARITY; AND THAT THE FUTURE HOLDS VERY LITTLE TO LOOK FORWARD TO.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 Sex and death: two poles of one energy</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 24
Sex and death: two poles of one energy
28 January 1986 am in Kathmandu, Nepal
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I HAVE HAD A STRONG FEELING OF SEX AND DEATH OVER THE LAST FEW WEEKS. IS IT NECESSARY THAT I UNDERSTAND WHY?
It is always necessary to understand how your mind is functioning, how your heart is doing, what is happening to your interior world.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25 The master creates a lovesphere</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 25
The master creates a lovesphere
29 January 1986 am in Kathmandu, Nepal
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
HOW CAN I FIND OUT WHICH OF THE MANY VOICES INSIDE ME IS THE ONE WHICH COMES FROM THE REAL SELF TO GUIDE ME? HOW CAN I BE SURE IT DOESN’T COME FROM THE UNCONSCIOUS?
It is very simple: none of the voices come from the inner self.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26 The moment you find the truth, everything stops</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 26
The moment you find the truth, everything stops
30 January 1986 am in Kathmandu, Nepal
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I HAVE HEARD YOU SAY THAT SEEKING THE TRUTH IS AS ECSTATIC AS FINDING IT. DOES THAT NOT ELIMINATE THE SEARCH?
It does not eliminate the search. On the contrary, it enhances the search because it makes seeking as important as finding.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27 Dissolving into the universal: a silent song of am-ness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 27
Dissolving into the universal: a silent song of am-ness
31 January 1986 am in Kathmandu, Nepal
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I REMEMBER YOU SAYING ONCE THAT THE GROWTH OF MAN IS DIALECTICAL; AND YOU HAVE ALSO EXPLAINED ABOUT THESIS, ANTITHESIS AND SYNTHESIS. WOULD YOU PLEASE GIVE MORE CLARITY IN THIS REFERENCE ON THE GROWTH TOWARDS ENLIGHTENMENT?
Every growth, growth as such, is dialectical.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28 Act according to your insight</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part28/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 28
Act according to your insight
2 February 1986 am in Kathmandu, Nepal
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WE FIND THAT MANY INTELLIGENT PEOPLE, LIKE SCIENTISTS, PHILOSOPHERS, AND EVEN POLITICIANS, EXPRESS GREAT ADMIRATION AND RESPECT FOR US INDIVIDUALLY AND FOR THE WAY WE LIVE TOGETHER – BUT THEY REFUSE TO UNDERSTAND THAT WE POINT TO YOU AS THE SOURCE OF THIS. WHERE IS THE BLOCK?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>29 Nietzsche: a great freedom or a great danger</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part29/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 29
Nietzsche: a great freedom or a great danger
3 February 1986 am in Kathmandu, Nepal
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
THERE IS A REVIVAL OF INTEREST IN NIETZSCHE ALL OVER EUROPE, FROM BOTH THE PRE-AND POST-WAR GENERATIONS. NIETZSCHE’S APPEAL SEEMS TO LIE IN HIS VIEWS STILL BEING CONTEMPORARY.
COULD YOU PLEASE COMMENT?
It is good news.
Friedrich Nietzsche is one of the philosophers with the most potential in the whole world, not only in the West, not only in Germany.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Now our commune exists all over the world</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
Now our commune exists all over the world
29 December 1985 am in Kathmandu, Nepal
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
THESE QUESTIONS ARE FROM A CENTER IN AMERICA, AND THEY SAY, “WE ARE STARTING A NEW NEWSPAPER IN AMERICA DEDICATED TO YOUR VISION FOR HUMANITY. WE WOULD LIKE TO CALL IT, ‘VISION INTERNATIONAL.’” THEIR FIRST QUESTION IS: DO YOU LIKE THE NAME?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>30 Utopia is possible</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part30/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 30
Utopia is possible
4 February 1986 am in Kathmandu, Nepal
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
SINCE MY CHILDHOOD, MY MOST INTENSE YEARNING WAS TO HAVE A FRIEND. I HAD TO WAIT FOR THIRTY YEARS TO HAVE THIS YEARNING FULFILLED; AND THEN EVERYTHING I WANTED, HAPPENED. NOW, SINCE YOU HAVE OFFERED US THE GIFT OF BEING A FRIEND, I OFTEN ALLOW MYSELF TO FEEL AND LOVE YOU IN A SIMILAR WAY AS I FEEL AND LOVE THIS FRIEND.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>31 The divine is the depth of diving into this moment</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part31/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 31
The divine is the depth of diving into this moment
5 February 1986 am in Kathmandu, Nepal
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
YOU ARE THE ETERNAL, AWESOME SILENCE AND GRANDEUR OF THE HIMALAYAS. AND YET YOU LIVE IN A FRAGILE, HUMAN BODY, WHICH IS SUCH A JOY FOR US TO BE TOGETHER WITH. IN CONNECTION WITH YOU, AND EVEN MORE IN RELATION TO CLOSE FRIENDS, THE QUESTION ARISES: CAN THE PLAYFULNESS OF HUMAN LOVE BE BRIDGED WITH REVERENCE FOR THE DIVINE?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>32 Only your original face can become enlightend</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part32/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part32/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 32
Only your original face can become enlightend
6 February 1986 am in Kathmandu, Nepal
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
YOU DESCRIBE WITNESSING AS A KNACK. OFTEN, LATE AT NIGHT, WHEN I AM IN A VERY RELAXED STATE, WITNESSING HAPPENS. AT OTHER TIMES, THOUGH, IT JUST SEEMS TO BE MIND WATCHING MIND WATCHING MIND.
PLEASE COMMENT ON THIS KNACK.
The moment I say that witnessing is a knack, it implies that there is no way to explain it, no way to teach someone about it, no way to train someone in it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>33 Truth is a dance in the heart</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part33/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part33/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 33
Truth is a dance in the heart
7 February 1986 am in Kathmandu, Nepal
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
PUTTING TOGETHER ALL YOUR STATEMENTS ABOUT ONE SUBJECT OR QUESTION, THERE ARE NOT JUST CONTRADICTIONS, BUT SUCH A RICHNESS OF DIFFERENT VIEWPOINTS AND ANGLES FROM WHICH YOU LOOK AT THE QUESTION... SO MANY COLORS. WHEN YOU TALK ABOUT A CERTAIN SUBJECT, SOMETHING IN ME STARTS DANCING, REMEMBERING SOME OF THE ANSWERS YOU HAVE GIVEN BEFORE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>34 To relate with non-sannyasins is bound to be difficult</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part34/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part34/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 34
To relate with non-sannyasins is bound to be difficult
8 February 1986 am in Kathmandu, Nepal
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHY IT IS SO DIFFICULT FOR SANNYASINS TO HAVE DEEP RELATIONSHIPS WITH NON- SANNYASINS?
It is natural.
To be a sannyasin means you are deprogrammed.
To relate with non-sannyasins is bound to be difficult because they are programmed people. Their programmed minds and your deprogrammed minds cannot have anything in common.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>35 Beyond the mind is your reality</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part35/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part35/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 35
Beyond the mind is your reality
9 February 1986 am in Kathmandu, Nepal
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
DO WE NEED SPECIAL MEDITATIONS FOR WOMEN?
No. Meditation is concerned with your consciousness – and consciousness is neither man nor woman. This is one of the fundamentals I want the world to be aware of.
All the religions have denied the woman any possibility for spiritual growth, thinking that her body is different, her biology is different: she will not be able to reach to the ultimate flowering of consciousness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>36 Enlightenment: the by-product of being in the present</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part36/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part36/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 36
Enlightenment: the by-product of being in the present
11 February 1986 am in Kathmandu, Nepal
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I AM A SOCIOLOGIST. THAT MEANS I DEAL SCIENTIFICALLY WITH THE RELATIONSHIP BETWEEN SOCIAL AND POLITICAL STRUCTURES, AND THE INDIVIDUAL. THOUGH I THINK THERE ARE SOCIOLOGICAL LAWS, AND THAT SOCIOLOGY CAN HELP US TO UNDERSTAND THE PROBLEMS OF SOCIETY BETTER, I AM MORE AND MORE IN DIFFICULTIES WITH SOCIOLOGY, IN THAT WAY OF THINKING, AND WITH THE SOCIOLOGISTS AS WELL.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>37 I don\&#39;t have any disciples, i have only friends</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part37/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part37/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 37
I don’t have any disciples, i have only friends
12 February 1986 am in Kathmandu, Nepal
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
FRITJOF CAPRA, IN AN INTERVIEW WITH SWAMI DEVA OJAS ABOUT THE NATURE OF SPIRITUAL ORGANIZATIONS, SAID, “THE COSMOS DOES NOT KNOW ANY HIERARCHY,” THAT “THE BEST WAY TO ORGANIZE THEM IS AS A NETWORK, IN A LOOSE INTERACTION,” AND THAT “SUCH A NETWORK STRUCTURE SEEMS THE BEST SOIL FOR THE SPIRITUAL GROWTH OF THE INDIVIDUAL, BECAUSE IT ENSURES THE POSSIBILITY OF THE INDIVIDUAL CONTINUING AND GUARANTEES ENOUGH TO DEVELOP HUMAN RELATIONS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>38 Music will remind you of me</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part38/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part38/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 38
Music will remind you of me
13 February 1986 am in Kathmandu, Nepal
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHY DO I ALLOW HABIT TO DOMINATE CONSCIOUSNESS?
Almost everybody does it, unless one becomes enlightened.
The habit is the easier way to do a thing. The whole mechanism of a habit is that you need not be conscious about it. It has become a mechanical part of you, a part of your robot mind: it does things by itself.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Darkness: the substance existence is made of</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
Darkness: the substance existence is made of
31 December 1985 am in Kathmandu, Nepal
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHAT DO YOU HAVE TO SAY ABOUT DARKNESS?
I have much to say about darkness, because nobody has taken notice of the mystery that darkness is.
Much has been said about light, almost nothing about darkness. But darkness is a much deeper phenomenon than light is.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 The strength you feel is the strength of truth</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
The strength you feel is the strength of truth
31 December 1985 pm in Kathmandu, Nepal
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
YOU ARE AT ONCE SUCH AN INCREDIBLE STRENGTH AND SWEETNESS SEEPING THROUGH ME. WHY DO I FEEL THERE IS A NEED TO PROTECT YOU?
It is one of the fundamental laws of life that everything that is higher is very vulnerable. The roots of a tree are very strong, but not the flowers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Follow your inner being, then no government is needed</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
Follow your inner being, then no government is needed
1 January 1986 am in Kathmandu, Nepal
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
IS THERE ANY RELATIONSHIP BETWEEN GNOSTICISM AND ANARCHY?
The word ‘anarchism’ has tremendous implications.
It means that the people are so inwardly disciplined that they don’t need any government. They are so deeply in order within themselves that no order outside is needed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Awareness is magic</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
Awareness is magic
1 January 1986 pm in Kathmandu, Nepal
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
EVERYTHING IN LIFE IS SO EXTRAORDINARY, SO BEAUTIFUL – SNOW CRYSTALS, A BIRD, THE MOVEMENT OF MY OWN HAND. WHY THEN DO I LOSE MYSELF IN IDIOTIC THINGS?
One of the most difficult things, but one of the most fundamental things in life, is not to divide life into beautiful and idiotic things – not to divide life at all.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 Don\&#39;t search for a home, search for yourself</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
Don’t search for a home, search for yourself
7 January 1986 pm in Kathmandu, Nepal
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
IN THESE TIMES OF UNCERTAINTY, THE BEST – AND THE WORST – SEEMS TO BE COMING OUT IN THOSE OF US WHO ARE AROUND YOU. WOULD YOU COMMENT ON THIS?
There are no “times of uncertainty” because time is always uncertain. It is the difficulty with the mind: mind wants certainty – and time is always uncertain.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 The master\&#39;s function is not to save you</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/light_on_the_path/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
The master’s function is not to save you
8 January 1986 pm in Kathmandu, Nepal
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I LOVE TO HEAR YOU CALL US YOUR FRIENDS. WHY IS IT BOTH EXCITING AND CHALLENGING?
It has many implications.
It was twenty-five centuries ago that Gautam Buddha said as a departing message to his disciples before he died: “I will come back after twenty-five centuries.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
