<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Chapter 1.rtf on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Chapter 1.rtf on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 1- The World of Tantra</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Vigyan Bhairav Tantra
Chapter 1: The World of Tantra
SUTRA:
DEVI ASKS:
OH SHIVA, WHAT IS YOUR REALITY? WHAT IS THIS WONDER-FILLED UNIVERSE? WHAT CONSTITUTES SEED?
WHO CENTERS THE UNIVERSAL WHEEL?
WHAT IS THIS LIFE BEYOND FORM PERVADING FORMS?
HOW MAY WE ENTER IT FULLY, ABOVE SPACE AND TIME, NAMES AND DESCRIPTIONS?
LET MY DOUBTS BE CLEARED!
Some introductory points. First, the world of VIGYANA BHAIRAVA TANTRA is not intellectual, it is not philosophical.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 10- Fullfillment through becoming centered</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 10: Fullfillment through becoming centered
Question 1
IS SELF-ACTUALIZATION A BASIC NEED?
There are many questions. The first: IS SELF-ACTUALIZATION A BASIC NEED OF MAN? First, try to understand what is meant by self-actualization. A. H. Maslow has used this term &#34;self-actualization.&#34; Man is born as potentiality. He is not really actual -- just potential. Man is born as a possibility, not as an actuality.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 11- Techniques to penetrate the inner centers</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 11: Techniques to penetrate the inner centers
15. CLOSING THE SEVEN OPENINGS OF THE HEAD WITH YOUR HANDS, A SPACE BETWEEN YOUR EYES BECOMES ALL INCLUSIVE.
16. BLESSED ONE, AS SENSES ARE ABSORBED IN THE HEART, REACH THE CENTER OF THE LOTUS.
17. UNMINDING MIND, KEEP IN THE MIDDLE -- UNTIL.
Man is as if he is a circle without a center. His life is superficial; his life is only on the circumference.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 12- Beyond mind to the source</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 12: Beyond mind to the source
There are many questions. The first question:
Question 1
LAST NIGHT YOU SAID THAT WITH THE DAWN OF ENLIGHTENMENT, THE SPACE BETWEEN THE TWO EYEBROWS, THE THIRD EYE, BECOMES ALL INCLUSIVE. THE OTHER DAY YOU SAID THAT ALL ENLIGHTENED ONES ARE CENTERED IN THEIR NAVEL, AND ON STILL ANOTHER DAY YOU HAVE EXPLAINED ABOUT THE SILVER CORD IN THE MIDDLE OF THE SPINE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 13- Entering the inner centering</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 13: Entering the inner centering
18. LOOK LOVINGLY AT SOME OBJECT. DO NOT GO TO ANOTHER OBJECT. HERE IN THE MIDDLE OF THE OBJECT -- THE BLESSING.
19. WITHOUT SUPPORT FOR FEET OR HANDS, SIT ONLY ON THE BUTTOCKS. SUDDENLY, THE CENTERING.
20. IN A MOVING VEHICLE, BY RHYTHMICALLY SWAYING, EXPERIENCE. OR IN A STILL VEHICLE, BY LETTING YOURSELF SWING IN SLOWING INVISIBLE CIRCLES.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 14- Changing the direction of energy</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 14: Changing the direction of energy
Question 1
IF ENLIGHTENMENT AND SAMADHI MEAN TOTAL CONSCIOUSNESS, COSMIC CONSCIOUSNESS, ALL-PERVADING CONSCIOUSNESS, THEN IT SEEMS VERY STRANGE TO CALL THIS STATE OF COSMIC CONSCIOUSNESS CENTERING, AS THE WORD `CENTERING&#39; IMPLIES ONE-POINTEDNESS. WHY IS COSMIC CONSCIOUSNESS, OR SAMADHI, CALLED CENTERING?
Centering is the path, not the goal. Centering is the method, not the result. Samadhi is not called centering; centering is the technique to samadhi.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 15- Toward the untouched inner reality</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 15: Toward the untouched inner reality
22. LET ATTENTION BE AT A PLACE WHERE YOU ARE SEEING SOME PAST HAPPENING, AND EVEN YOUR FORM, HAVING LOST ITS PRESENT CHARACTERISTICS, IS TRANSFORMED.
23. FEEL AN OBJECT BEFORE YOU. FEEL THE ABSENCE OF ALL OTHER OBJECTS BUT THIS ONE. THEN, LEAVING ASIDE THE OBJECT-FEELING AND THE ABSENCE-FEELING, REALIZE.
24. WHEN A MOOD AGAINST SOMEONE OR FOR SOMEONE ARISES, DO NOT PLACE IT ON THE PERSON IN QUESTION, BUT REMAIN CENTERED.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 16- Beyond the sin of unconsciousness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 16: Beyond the sin of unconsciousness
The first question:
Question 1
THE LAST TECHNIQUE YOU DISCUSSED YESTERDAY SAID THAT WHEN A MOOD AGAINST SOMEONE OR FOR SOMEONE ARISES, NOT TO PLACE IT ON THE PERSON IN QUESTION BUT TO REMAIN CENTERED. BUT WHEN WE EXPERIMENT WITH THIS TECHNIQUE ON OUR ANGER, HATRED, ETC., WE FEEL THAT WE ARE SUPPRESSING OUR EMOTION AND IT BECOMES A SUPPRESSED COMPLEX.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 17- Several stop techniques</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 17: Several stop techniques
1. JUST AS YOU HAVE THE IMPULSE TO DO SOMETHING, STOP.
2. WHEN SOME DESIRE COMES, CONSIDER IT. THEN, SUDDENLY, QUIT IT.
3. ROAM ABOUT UNTIL EXHAUSTED AND THEN, DROPPING TO THE GROUND, IN THIS DROPPING BE WHOLE.
Life has two balances: one is of being and the other of doing. Your being is your nature. It is with you always; you have not to do anything to get it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 18- Remaining with the facts</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 18: Remaining with the facts
The first question:
Question 1
YOU SAID LAST NIGHT THAT MODERN MAN HAS BECOME INAUTHENTIC IN EXPRESSING ANGER, VIOLENCE, SEX, ETC. YOU SAY THAT IN INDIA STUDENTS AND THE YOUNGER GENERATION ARE LESS VIOLENT IN THEIR EMOTIONAL EXPRESSIONS THAN ARE WESTERN YOUTH DOES THIS MEAN THAT WESTERN YOUTH ARE BECOMING MORE AUTHENTIC IN THEIR EXPRESSIONS? IS PERMISSIVENESS IN THE EXPRESSION OF SEX AND ANGER A GROWTH TOWARD BEING AUTHENTIC IN EMOTIONAL EXPRESSIONS?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 19- A technique for the intellectual and a technique for the feeling type</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 19: A Technique for the intellectual and a technique for the feeling type
SUTRAS:
4. SUPPOSE YOU ARE GRADUALLY BEING DEPRIVED OF STRENGTH OR OF KNOWLEDGE. AT THE INSTANT OF DEPRIVATION, TRANSCEND.
5. DEVOTION FREES.
For tantra, man himself is the disease. It is not that your mind is disturbed -- rather, your mind is the disturbance. It is not that you are tense within, but rather, you are the tension.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 2- The Path of Yoga and the Path of Tantra</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 2: The Path of Yoga and the Path of Tantra
Many questions are there. The first:
Question 1
WHAT IS THE DIFFERENCE BETWEEN TRADITIONAL YOGA AND TANTRA? ARE THEY THE SAME?
Tantra and yoga are basically different. They reach to the same goal; however, their paths are not only different, but contrary also. So this has to be understood very clearly.
The yoga process is also methodology; yoga is also technique.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 20- Ordinary love and the love of a buddha</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 20: Ordinary love and the love of a buddha
The first question:
Question 1
IT SEEMS VERY DIFFICULT TO LOVE SOMEONE FOR TWENTY-FOUR HOURS A DAY. WHY DOES IT HAPPEN SO? SHOULD LOVE BE A CONTINUOUS PROCESS? AND AT WHICH STAGE DOES LOVE BECOME DEVOTION?
Love is not an act; it is not something that you do. If you do it, it is not love.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 21- Three looking techniques</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 21: Three looking techniques
6. EYES CLOSED, SEE YOUR INNER BEING IN DETAIL. THUS SEE YOUR TRUE NATURE.
7. LOOK UPON A BOWL WITHOUT SEEING THE SIDES OR THE MATERIAL. IN A FEW MOMENTS BECOME AWARE.
8. SEE AS IF FOR THE FIRST TIME A BEAUTEOUS PERSON OR AN ORDINARY OBJECT.
Tonight&#39;s techniques are concerned with the practice of looking. Before we enter these techniques, something has to be understood about the eyes, because all these seven techniques depend on that.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 22- The third eye and psychic eye power</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 22: The third eye and psychic eye power
The first question:
Question 1
EXPLAIN THE RELATIONSHIP OF THE TWO EYES WITH THE THIRD EYE. IN WHICH WAY DO THE TECHNIQUES CONCERNED WITH LOOKING AFFECT THE THIRD EYE?
Firstly, two points are to be understood. One, the energy of the third eye is really the same as that which moves in the two ordinary eyes -- the same energy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 23- Several more looking methods</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 23: Several more looking methods
9. SIMPLY BY LOOKING INTO THE BLUE SKY BEYOND CLOUDS, THE SERENITY.
10. LISTEN WHILE THE ULTIMATE MYSTICAL TEACHING IS IMPARTED. EYES STILL, WITHOUT BLINKING, AT ONCE BECOME ABSOLUTELY FREE.
11. AT THE EDGE OF A DEEP WELL LOOK STEADILY INTO ITS DEPTHS UNTIL
-- THE WONDROUSNESS.
12. LOOK UPON SOME OBJECT, THEN SLOWLY WITHDRAW YOUR SIGHT FROM IT, THEN SLOWLY WITHDRAW YOUR THOUGHT FROM IT.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 24- Doubt or faith, life or death; the bases of different paths</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 24: Doubt or faith, life or death; the bases of different paths
The first question:
Question 1
I FEEL THAT NEITHER AM I THE FEELING TYPE ALTOGETHER, NOR AM I THE INTELLECTUAL TYPE. I AM A MIXED TYPE. SHOULD I DO TWO DIFFERENT KINDS OF TECHNIQUES ALTERNATIVELY? PLEASE GUIDE.
This is a significant question. Many things will have to be understood. One: whenever you feel that you are neither the intellectual type nor the emotional type, know well that you belong to the intellectual type, because confusion is part of it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 25- From words to pure sounds to being</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 25: From words to pure sounds to being
13. DEVI, IMAGINE THE SANSKRIT LETTERS IN THESE HONEY-FILLED FOCI OF AWARENESS, FIRST AS LETTERS, THEN MORE SUBTLY AS SOUNDS, THEN AS MOST SUBTLE FEELING. THEN, LEAVING THEM ASIDE, BE FREE.
14. BATHE IN THE CENTER OF SOUND, AS IN THE CONTINUOUS SOUND OF A WATERFALL. OR, BY PUTTING THE FINGERS IN THE EARS, HEAR THE SOUND OF SOUNDS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 26- Tantra: an acceptance of the peaks and the valleys</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 26: Tantra: anacceptance of the peaks and the valleys
The first question:
Question 1
LAST NIGHT YOU DISCUSSED THE CENSORSHIP AND SUPPRESSION BY THE CONSCIOUS MIND OF THE UNCONSCIOUS INSTINCTS, AND YOU SAID THAT THE UNCONSCIOUS INSTINCTS BELONG TO THE ANIMAL HERITAGE IN MAN&#39;S EVOLUTION. THEN IS IT NOT GOOD TO CHANNEL AND REGULATE THEM ACCORDING TO THE INTELLIGENCE, DISCRIMINATION AND ART OF LIVING WHICH BELONG TO THE CONSCIOUS MIND?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 27- Soundlessness, soundfulness and total awareness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 27: Soundlessness, soundfulness and total awareness
15. INTONE A SOUND, AS AUM, SLOWLY. AS SOUND ENTERS SOUNDFULNESS, SO DO YOU.
16. IN THE BEGINNING AND GRADUAL REFINEMENT OF THE SOUND OF ANY LETTER, AWAKE.
17. WHILE LISTENING TO STRINGED INSTRUMENTS, HEAR THEIR COMPOSITE CENTRAL SOUND; THUS OMNIPRESENCE.
I wonder whether or not you have heard about the concept of anti-matter. A new concept has entered recently in the world of physics -- the concept of anti-matter.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 28- Meditation: an unburdening of repressions</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part28/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 28: Meditation: an unburdening of repressions
The first question:
Question 1
REPRESSION HAS BECOME AN AUTOMATIC REACTION IN OUR BODIES AND MINDS WHICH WE DO NOT EVEN RECOGNIZE OR WANT TO CHANGE ANY MORE. HOW CAN WE LEARN TO TELL BETWEEN A FALSE IMAGE AND A REAL ONE IN OURSELVES?
Many things have to be understood. One: all your faces are false; you do not have any real face.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 29- Sound methods for the dropping of the mind</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part29/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 29: Sound methods for the dropping of the mind
18. INTONE A SOUND AUDIBLY, THEN LESS AND LESS AUDIBLY AS FEELING DEEPENS INTO THIS SILENT HARMONY.
19. WITH MOUTH SLIGHTLY OPEN, KEEP MIND IN THE MIDDLE OF THE TONGUE. OR, AS BREATH COMES SILENTLY IN, FEEL THE SOUND &#34;HH&#34;.
20. CENTER ON THE SOUND &#34;AUM&#34; WITHOUT ANY &#34;A&#34; OR &#34;M&#34;.
Tantra divides life into two dimensions: one is the SANSAR -- that which is, the world; and the other is MOKSHA -- that which can be, the ultimate, the hidden which can become manifest.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 3- Breath-a bridge to the universe</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 3: Breath-- a bridge to the universe
SUTRAS:
SHIVA REPLIES:
1. RADIANT ONE, THIS EXPERIENCE MAY DAWN BETWEEN TWO BREATHS. AFTER BREATH COMES IN (DOWN) AND JUST BEFORE TURNING UP (OUT) -- THE BENEFICENCE.
2. AS BREATH TURNS FROM DOWN TO UP, AND AGAIN AS BREATH CURVES FROM UP TO DOWN -- THROUGH BOTH THESE TURNS, REALIZE.
3. OR, WHENEVER IN-BREATH AND OUT-BREATH FUSE, AT THIS INSTANT TOUCH THE ENERGY-LESS, ENERGY-FILLED CENTER.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 30- Surrendering to a Master</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part30/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 30: Surrendering to a Master
The first question:
Question 1
LAST NIGHT YOU DISCUSSED THE ATTITUDE OF TOTAL ACCEPTANCE AS THE BASIC GROUND FOR ALL TANTRIC SADHANA -- SPIRITUAL PRACTICE. IF I REMEMBER CORRECTLY, ON ANOTHER DAY YOU SAID THAT THE SCIENCE OF TANTRA TEACHES TO BE IN THE MIDDLE IN EVERYTHING, BEING FREE FROM THE EXTREMES IN LIFE. IN THIS REFERENCE, EXPLAIN HOW ONE CAN COME TO UNDERSTAND THE DIFFERENCE BETWEEN INDULGENCE AND REPRESSION IN ONE&#39;S SEX LIFE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 31- From sound to inner silence</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part31/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 31: From sound to inner silence
21. SILENTLY INTONE A WORD ENDING IN &#34;AH.&#34; THEN IN THE &#34;HH,&#34; EFFORTLESSLY, THE SPONTANEITY.
22. STOPPING EARS BY PRESSING AND THE RECTUM BY CONTRACTING, ENTER THE SOUND.
23. ENTER THE SOUND OF YOUR NAME AND, THROUGH THIS SOUND, ALL SOUNDS.
Tantra is not a philosophy. Rather, it is a science with one difference: science is objective, tantra is subjective.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 32- The path of surrender</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part32/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part32/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 32: The path of surrender
The first question:
Question 1
BELOVED MASTER, PLEASE EXPLAIN WHETHER THE TECHNIQUES YOU HAVE DISCUSSED SO FAR FROM VIGYANA BHAIRAVA TANTRA BELONG TO THE SCIENCE OF YOGA INSTEAD OF TO THE ACTUAL AND CENTRAL SUBJECT MATTER OF TANTRA. WHAT IS THE CENTRAL SUBJECT MATTER OF TANTRA?
This question arises to many. The techniques that we have discussed also belong to yoga.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 33- The spirituality of the tantric sex act</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part33/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part33/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 33: The spirituality of the trantic sex act
AT THE START OF SEXUAL UNION KEEP ATTENTIVE ON THE FIRE IN THE BEGINNING, AND SO CONTINUING, AVOID THE EMBERS IN THE END. WHEN IN SUCH EMBRACE YOUR SENSES ARE SHAKEN AS LEAVES, ENTER THIS SHAKING.
EVEN REMEMBERING UNION, WITHOUT THE EMBRACE, TRANSFORMATION.
ON JOYOUSLY SEEING A LONG ABSENT FRIEND, PERMEATE THIS JOY. WHEN EATING OR DRINKING, BECOME THE TASTE OF FOOD OR DRINK, AND BE FILLED.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 34- \&#34;Cosmic orgasm\&#34; through Tantra</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part34/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part34/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 34: &#34;Cosmic orgasm&#34; through Tantra
BEGIN.…
Before I take your questions some other points have to be clarified, because those points will help you understand more what tantra means. Tantra is not a moral concept. It is neither moral nor immoral. It is amoral. It is a science, and science is neither. Your moralities and concepts concerning moral behavior are irrelevant for tantra.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 35- Turning inward toward the real</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part35/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part35/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 35: Turning inward toward the real
OH LOTUS-EYED ONE, SWEET OF TOUCH, WHEN SINGING, SEEING, TASTING, BE AWARE YOU ARE AND DISCOVER THE EVER-LIVING. WHEREVER SATISFACTION IS FOUND, IN WHATEVER ACT, ACTUALIZE THIS.
AT THE POINT OF SLEEP, WHEN THE SLEEP HAS NOT YET COME AND THE EXTERNAL WAKEFULNESS VANISHES, AT THIS POINT BEING IS REVEALED. ILLUSIONS DECEIVE, COLORS CIRCUMSCRIBE, EVEN DIVISIBLES ARE INDIVISIBLE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 36- From maya to reality</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part36/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part36/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 36: From maya (illusion) to reality
The first question:
Question 1
&#34;IN WHICH WAY CAN THE PRACTICE OF SELF-REMEMBERING TRANSFORM THE HUMAN MIND?&#34;
Man is not centered in himself. He is born centered, but the society, the family, the education, the culture, they push him off-center, and they put him off-center in a very cunning way, knowingly or unknowingly. So everyone becomes, in a sense, &#34;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 37- Techniques to witness the flux-like film of life</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part37/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part37/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 37: Techniques to witness the flux-like film of life
IN MOODS OF EXTREME DESIRE, BE UNDISTURBED.
THIS SO-CALLED UNIVERSE APPEARS AS A JUGGLING, A PICTURE SHOW. TO BE HAPPY, LOOK UPON IT SO.
OH BELOVED, PUT ATTENTION NEITHER ON PLEASURE NOR ON PAIN, BUT BETWEEN THESE.
OBJECTS AND DESIRES EXIST IN ME AS IN OTHERS. SO ACCEPTING, LET THEM BE TRANSFORMED.
The original mind is like a mirror: it is pure, and it remains pure, but dust can gather upon it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 38- Toward the authentic being</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part38/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part38/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 38: Toward the authentic being
The first question:
Question 1
&#34;IN WHICH WAY DOES THE MODERNIZED ORIGINAL MIND BECOME IDENTIFIED WITH THE DUST OF THE PAST KNOWLEDGE AND EXPERIENCE?&#34;
Mind is pure, and no impurity can enter it. That is impossible. The mind is just the buddha-nature -- the ultimate. And when I say &#34;mind,&#34; I don&#39;t mean your mind, I simply mean the mind where no I and you exist.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 39- From the wave to the cosmic ocean</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part39/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part39/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 38: From the wave to the cosmic ocean
SUTRAS
AS WAVES COME WITH WATER AND FLAMES WITH FIRE, SO THE UNIVERSAL WAVES WITH US.
WHEREVER YOUR MIND IS WANDERING, INTERNALLY OR EXTERNALLY, AT THIS VERY PLACE, THIS.
WHEN VIVIDLY AWARE THROUGH SOME PARTICULAR SENSE, KEEP IN THE AWARENESS.
Sri Aurobindo says somewhere that the whole life is yoga -- and it is so.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4- The deceptions of the mind</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 4: The deceptions of the mind
Question 1
HOW IS IT POSSIBLE THAT BY SIMPLY BECOMING AWARE AT A PARTICULAR POINT IN THE BREATHING PROCESS ONE CAN ATTAIN ENLIGHTENMENT? HOW IT IS POSSIBLE TO BECOME FREE FROM THE UNCONSCIOUS BY JUST BEING AWARE OF SUCH A SMALL AND MOMENTARY GAP IN THE BREATHING?
This question is significant, and this question is likely to have occurred to many minds, so many things have to be understood.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 40- Sudden Enlightenment and its obstacles</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part40/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part40/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 40: Sudden Enlightenment and its obstacles
The first question:
Question 1
&#34;YOU SAID THAT EITHER ONE SEES THE WORLD OR THE BRAHMAN AND THAT NO GRADUALLY INCREASING PERCEPTION OF THE BRAHMAN IS POSSIBLE. BUT IN EXPERIENCE WE FEEL THAT AS WE BECOME AWARE AND MORE SILENT AND STILL, THE FEELING OF THE DIVINE PRESENCE BECOMES GRADUALLY CLEARER AND CLEARER. WHAT IS THIS GRADUAL GROWTH AND CLARITY IF THE AUTHENTIC EXPERIENCE IS NEVER GRADUAL, BUT SUDDEN?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 41- Be a witness not a judge</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part41/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part41/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 41: Be a witness not a judge
AT THE START OF SNEEZING, DURING FRIGHT, IN ANXIETY, ABOVE A CHASM, FLYING IN BATTLE, IN EXTREME CURIOSITY, AT THE BEGINNING OF HUNGER, AT THE END OF HUNGER, BE UNINTERRUPTEDLY AWARE. THE PURITY OF OTHER TEACHINGS IS AN IMPURITY TO US. IN REALITY, KNOW NOTHING AS PURE OR IMPURE.
Life is a paradox. To reach near you have to travel far, and that which is already achieved you have to achieve again.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 42- Alertness through tantra - not principles</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part42/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part42/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 42: Alertness through tantra -- not principles
The first question:
Question 1
&#34;IS IT NOT TRUE THAT AN IMMORAL LIFE CREATES HINDRANCES IN MEDITATION?&#34;
What is meditation? It is not your character, it is not what you do. It is what you are. It is not the character, it is the consciousness that you bring to whatsoever you do. The doing is irrelevant.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 43- Finding the changeless through the changing</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part43/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part43/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 43: Finding the changeless through the changing
BE THE UNSAME SAME TO FRIEND AS TO STRANGER, IN HONOR AND DISHONOR.
HERE IS THE SPHERE OF CHANGE, CHANGE, CHANGE. THROUGH CHANGE CONSUME CHANGE.
Northrope says somewhere that the Western mind has been continuously searching for the theoretical component of existence -- the causal link for how things happen, what is the cause, how the effect can be controlled, how man can manipulate nature.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 44- Tantra\&#39;s secrets of love and liberation</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part44/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part44/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 44: Tantra&#39;s secrets of love and liberation
The first question:
Question 1
&#34;IN REFERENCE TO YOUR STATEMENT THAT TANTRA IS A LOVE TECHNIQUE, PLEASE EXPLAIN WHY MODERN MAN AND WOMAN HAVE BECOME INCAPABLE OF LOVE.&#34;
Love is spontaneous. It cannot be controlled. You cannot &#34;make&#34; love; you cannot do anything about it. And the more you do, the more you will miss it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 45- Remaining with the real</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part45/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part45/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 45: Remaining with the real
AS A HEN MOTHERS HER CHICKS, MOTHER PARTICULAR KNOWINGS, PARTICULAR DOINGS, IN REALITY.
SINCE, IN TRUTH, BONDAGE AND FREEDOM ARE RELATIVE, THESE WORDS ARE ONLY FOR THOSE TERRIFIED WITH THE UNIVERSE. THIS UNIVERSE IS A REFLECTION OF MINDS. AS YOU SEE MANY SUNS IN WATER FROM ONE SUN, SO SEE BONDAGE AND LIBERATION.
Hui-neng had asked a person, &#34;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 46- The tantric way to freedom from desires</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part46/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part46/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 46: The tantric way to freedom from desires
The first question:
Question 1
&#34;YOU SAID YESTERDAY THAT THE MOTIVATION TOWARDS LIBERATION OR SAMADHI IS ALSO A TENSION AND A BARRIER, BUT IS IT NOT CORRECT THAT IT IS NOT A DESIRE BUT AN ASPIRATION -- THE INTRINSIC THIRST OF THE HUMAN BEING?&#34;
You must understand what desire means, and religions have confused you much about it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 47- Tantric meditation with light techniques</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part47/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part47/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 47: Tantric meditation with light techniques
CONSIDER YOUR ESSENCE AS LIGHT RAYS FROM CENTER TO CENTER UP THE VERTEBRAE, AND SO RISES &#34;LIVINGNESS&#34; IN YOU.
OR IN THE SPACES BETWEEN, FEEL THIS AS LIGHTNING.
FEEL THE COSMOS AS A TRANSLUCENT EVER-LIVING PRESENCE.
Man can be considered in three ways: in terms of the normal, the abnormal and the supernormal. Western psychology is basically concerned with the abnormal, the pathological, with the man who has fallen down from the normal, who has fallen down from the norm.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 48- The potentiality of the seed</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part48/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part48/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 48: The potentiality of the seed
The first question:
Question 1
&#34;LAST NIGHT YOU SAID THAT A KRISHNA, A CHRIST, A BUDDHA, THEY ARE THE CLIMAX OF HUMAN POSSIBILITY AND GROWTH, AND THEN YOU SAID THAT YOGIC AND TANTRIC PSYCHOLOGY PUT NO IDEAL BEFORE MAN AND THAT TO HAVE AN IDEAL IS A MISTAKE ACCORDING TO TANTRA. IN THIS REFERENCE PLEASE EXPLAIN WHAT IS THE DIFFERENCE BETWEEN AN INSPIRATION AND AN IDEAL.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 49- Conscious doing</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part49/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part49/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 49: Conscious doing
IN SUMMER WHEN YOU SEE THE ENTIRE SKY ENDLESSLY CLEAR ENTER SUCH CLARITY. SHAKTI,
SEE ALL SPACE AS IF ALREADY ABSORBED IN YOUR OWN HEAD IN THE BRILLIANCE.
WAKING, SLEEPING, DREAMING, KNOW YOU AS LIGHT.
AS I LOOK IN YOUR EYES I never see you there -- as if you are absent. You exist absently, and this is the core of all suffering.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 5- Five Techniques of attentiveness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 5: Five Techniques of attentiveness
5. ATTENTION BETWEEN EYEBROWS, LET MIND BE BEFORE THOUGHT. LET FORM FILL WITH BREATH ESSENCE TO THE TOP OF THE HEAD AND THERE SHOWER AS LIGHT.
6. WHEN IN WORLDLY ACTIVITY, KEEP ATTENTION BETWEEN TWO BREATHS, AND SO PRACTICING, IN A FEW DAYS BE BORN ANEW.
7. WITH INTANGIBLE BREATH IN CENTER OF FOREHEAD, AS THIS REACHES HEART AT THE MOMENT OF SLEEP, HAVE DIRECTION OVER DREAMS AND OVER DEATH ITSELF.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 50- Moving to the roots</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part50/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part50/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 50: Moving to the roots
Question 1
LAST NIGHT YOU SAID THAT BY CHANGING THE OUTER, THE INNER REMAINS UNCHANGED, UNTRANSFORMED. BUT IS IT NOT TRUE THAT THE RIGHT FOOD, RIGHT LABOUR, RIGHT SLEEP, RIGHT ACTIONS AND BEHAVIORS ARE ALSO IMPORTANT FACTORS FOR INNER TRANSFORMATION? ISN&#39;T IT A MISTAKE TO IGNORE THE OUTER COMPLETELY?
THE OUTER CANNOT CHANGE THE INNER, but the outer can help, or it can hinder.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 51- Come back to existence</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part51/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part51/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 51: Come back to existence
IN RAIN DURING A BLACK NIGHT
ENTER THAT BLACKNESS AS THE FORM OF FORMS. WHEN A MOONLESS RAINY NIGHT IS NOT PRESENT, CLOSE EYES AND FIND BLACKNESS BEFORE YOU. OPENING EYES, SEE BLACKNESS.
SO FAULTS DISAPPEAR FOREVER. WHEREVER YOUR ATTENTION ALIGHTS, AT THIS VERY POINT,
EXPERIENCE.
Once a doctor, a very well known historian and an eminent scholar, was staying in a village.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 52- Enter this moment</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part52/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part52/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 52: Enter this moment
Question 1
THE OTHER NIGHT YOU SAID THAT PHILOSOPHIES ARE ANTI-MEDITATION. BUT ON THE OTHER HAND YOU AGREE THAT THE EASTERN PHILOSOPHIES SUCH AS TANTRA, YOGA AND VEDANT, ARE THE WRITINGS OF ENLIGHTENED SAGES. WHY DO THE ENLIGHTENED SAGES LEAVE BEHIND THEM A STRONG STRUCTURE OF PHILOSOPHICAL CONTEMPLATION, IF PHILOSOPHIES ARE ANTI-MEDITATION?
Philosophy is not darshan. Darshan is the eastern term.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 53- From death to deathlessness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part53/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part53/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 53: From death to deathlessness
FOCUS ON FIRE
RISING THROUGH YOUR FORM FROM THE TOES UP
UNTIL THE BODY BURNS TO ASHES BUT NOT YOU.
MEDITATE ON THE MAKE-BELIEVE WORLD AS BURNING TO ASHES AND BECOME BEING ABOVE HUMANAS,
AS SUBJECTIVELY,
LETTERS FLOW INTO WORDS AND WORDS INTO SENTENCES, AND AS, OBJECTIVELY,
CIRCLES FLOW INTO WORLDS AND WORLDS INTO PRINCIPLES, FIND AT LAST THESE CONVERGING IN OUR BEING</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 54- The fire of awareness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part54/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part54/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 54: The fire of awareness
Question 1
A MEDITATOR WHO IS VULNERABLE, PASSIVE, OPEN AND RECEPTIVE, FEELS THAT WITH THESE CHARACTERISTICS HE SUFFERS DUE TO THE INFLUENCE OF THE NON-MEDITATIVE, NEGATIVE AND TENSE VIBRATIONS AROUND HIM. PLEASE EXPLAIN HOW HE CAN PRESERVE HIS VULNERABLE PSYCHE FROM THE HARMFUL VIBRATIONS.
If you are really vulnerable, nothing is negative for you -- because the negative is your interpretation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 55- Only the unreal dissolves</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part55/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part55/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 55: Only the unreal dissolves
FEEL: MY THOUGHT, I-NESS, INTERNAL ORGANS -- ME. BEFORE DESIRE AND BEFORE KNOWING,
HOW CAN I SAY I AM?
CONSIDER. DISSOLVE IN THE BEAUTY.
Once a visitor asked many people in a small town about the mayor: `What type of man is your mayor?&#39;
Said the priest, `He is no good.&#39;
Said the filling-station attendant, `He is a bum.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 56- Discovering the emptiness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part56/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part56/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 56: Discovering the emptiness
Question 1
IN MEDITATION, WHEN THE `I&#39; DROPS TEMPORARILY AND AN EMPTINESS IS CREATED WITHIN, AFTER IT A FRUSTRATION IS FELT WHEN THAT EMPTINESS IS NOT FILLED BY THE ENTRY OF THE UNKNOWN. HOW CAN ONE LEARN TO LIVE WITH THAT EMPTINESS?
Emptiness is the unknown. Don&#39;t wait and don&#39;t hope that something is going to fill the emptiness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 57- Searching for freedom</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part57/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part57/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 57: Searching for freedom
TOSS ATTACHMENT FOR BODY ASIDE, REALIZING I AM EVERYWHERE.
ONE WHO IS EVERYWHERE IS JOYOUS.
THINKING NO THING
WILL LIMITED-SELF UNLIMIT.
I have heard a story about an old doctor. One day his assistant phoned him because he was in very great difficulty -- his patient was choking himself to death. A billiard ball was stuck in his throat, and the assistant was at a loss for what to do.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 58- In your hands</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part58/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part58/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 58: In your hands
Question 1
TECHNIQUES ARE SHORTCUTS, REVOLUTIONS, BUT ARE NOT THESE AGAINST TAO, SWABHAV, THE NATURE?
They are. They are against tao, they are against swabhav. Any effort is against shabhav, tao; effort as such is against tao. If you can leave everything to swabhav, tao, nature, then no technique is needed, because that is the ultimate technique. If you can leave everything to tao, that is the deepest surrender possible.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 59- Watching from the hills</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part59/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part59/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 59: Watching from the hills
SUPPOSE YOU CONTEMPLATE SOMETHING BEYOND PERCEPTION,
BEYOND GRASPING, BEYOND NOT BEING.
-- YOU.
I AM EXISTING.
THIS IS MINE.
THIS IS THIS.
OH BELOVED,
EVEN IN SUCH KNOW ILLIMITABLY.
Man is Janus-Faced -- animal and divine both. Animal belongs to his past, divine belongs to his future, and this creates the difficulty. The past has passed, it is no more; just a shadow of it lingers on.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 6- Devices to transcend dreaming</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 6: Devices to transcend dreaming
One friend has asked, Question 1
WILL YOU PLEASE EXPLAIN TO US WHAT ARE SOME OF THE OTHER FACTORS WHICH CAN MAKE ONE CONSCIOUS WHILE DREAMING?
This is a significant question for all those who are interested in meditation, because meditation is really a transcending of the process of dreaming. You are constantly dreaming -- not only in the night, not only while you are asleep; you are dreaming the whole day.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 60- Liberation from yourself</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part60/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part60/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 60: Liberation from yourself
Question 1
YOU SAY THAT RELIGION IS TOTAL FREEDOM OR MOKSHA, AND YOU ALSO STRESS THE IMPORTANCE OF SURRENDER IN RELIGION. BUT ARE NOT FREEDOM AND SURRENDER CONTRADICTORY IN TERMS?
They appear contradictory but they are not. And they appear so because of the language; existentially they are not. Try to understand two things. First: you cannot be free remaining as you are, because as you are is your bondage.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 61- Techniques to become one with the whole</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part61/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part61/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 61: Techniques to become one with the whole
EACH THING IS PERCEIVED THROUGH KNOWING. THE SELF SHINES IN SPACE THROUGH KNOWING. PERCEIVE ONE BEING AS KNOWER AND KNOWN.
BELOVED,
AT THIS MOMENT
LET, MIND, KNOWING, BREATH, FORM, BE INCLUDED.
I have heard one anecdote. In a conservative party rally, Lord Mancroft was invited to speak. He came right on time, reached the rostrum and said to the public -- he was looking a little flustered -- he said, `Forgive me for shortening my speech a little, but the fact is that my house is on fire.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 62- Right now is the goal</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part62/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part62/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 62: Right now is the goal
Question 1
YESTERDAY YOU SAID THAT ONE SHOULD HURRY TOWARDS THE GOAL BECAUSE WHATEVER TIME WE HAVE IS VERY LITTLE. HOWEVER, SOME TIME AGO YOU ALSO SAID THAT THE WHOLE PROCESS OF ATTAINING THE GOAL SHOULD BE AN EFFORTLESS PLAY. HOW WOULD YOU RECONCILE THE TWO WORDS `HURRY&#39; AND `PLAY&#39;? -- BECAUSE THE ONE WHO HURRIES NEVER GETS THE JOY OF PLAYING.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 63- No map to follow</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part63/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part63/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 63: No map to follow
TOUCHING EYEBALLS AS A FEATHER, LIGHTNESS BETWEEN THEM OPENS INTO HEART AND THERE PERMEATES THE COSMOS.
KIND DEVI,
ENTER ETHERIC PRESENCE
PERVADING FAR ABOVE AND BELOW YOUR FORM.
Once it happened in a church that after a very long dry sermon, the minister announced that there would be a meeting, a brief meeting of the board, right after the benediction.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 64- Choicelessness is bliss</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part64/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part64/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 64: Choicelessness is bliss
Question 1
IS IT THAT THERE ARE ONLY TWO ALTERNATIVES BEFORE MAN -- A LIFE OF ABIDING SORROW AND SUFFERING OR ONE OF DIVINITY AND BLISS -- AND THIS CHOICE LIES WITH HIM? HOW IS IT THAT MOST HAVE CHOSEN THE PATH OF SORROW AND SUFFERING?
It is a very significant question, but very delicate also. The first thing to be understood is that life is very paradoxical, and because of that many things happen.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 65- Life is a mystery, not a problem</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part65/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part65/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 65: Life is a mystery, not a problem
PUT MINDSTUFF
IN SUCH INEXPRESSIBLE FINENESS ABOVE, BELOW AND IN YOUR HEART.
CONSIDER ANY AREA OF YOUR PRESENT FORM AS LIMITLESSLY SPACIOUS.
Life is not a problem but a mystery. For science life is a problem, but for religion it is a mystery. A problem can be solved, a mystery cannot be solved -- it can be lived but it cannot be solved.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 66- Enlightenment- the most ordinary</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part66/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part66/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 66: Enlightenment -- the most ordinary
The first question:
Question 1
LAST NIGHT YOU SAID THAT WHEN THERE ARE NO THOUGHTS IN THE MIND, THE MIND BECOMES AN EMPTY SPACE AND THE DOORS TO ALL THE MYSTERIES ARE OPENED. I FEEL THIS INNER SPACE DEEPLY AND CLEARLY BUT THERE IS NOTHING SPECIAL THAT I FEEL AS MYSTERY.
WILL YOU EXPLAIN WHAT YOU MEAN BY THE MYSTERY AND HOW IT IS FELT?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 67- Neither mind nor matter</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part67/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part67/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 67: Neither mind nor matter
FEEL YOUR SUBSTANCE, BONES, FLESH, BLOOD, SATURATED WITH THE COSMIC ESSENCE.
FEEL THE FINE QUALITIES OF CREATIVITY PERMEATING YOUR BREASTS&#39; AND ASSUMING DELICATE CONFIGURATIONS.
Philosophers all over the world have been arguing for centuries about what basic stuff the universe is made of, what the substance is. There have been propositions, systems, that say that matter is the basic reality and mind is just an outgrowth, that matter is basic and mind is just a by-product, that mind is also material, only subtle.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 68- If you get serious you lose the point</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part68/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part68/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 68: If you get serious you lose the point
The first question:
Question 1
IT HAS BEEN SAID THAT NO DESIRE, NEITHER WORLDLY NOR RELIGIOUS, CAN LEAD TOWARDS FREEDOM. BUT A POSITIVE IMAGINATION OF HAPPINESS AND BLISS IS ALSO A SORT OF DESIRE. THEN ISN&#39;T IT TRUE THAT IMAGINATION IS ALSO DESIRE AND HENCE CREATES TENSIONS?
Imagination is not desire. Imagination is just a play.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 69- You are unknown to yourself</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part69/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part69/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 69: You are unknown to yourself
ABIDE IN SOME PLACE ENDLESSLY SPACIOUS, CLEAR OF TREES, HILLS, HABITATIONS. THENCE COMES THE END OF MIND PRESSURES. CONSIDER THE PLENUM TO BE YOUR OWN BODY OF BLISS.
Man is born alone and dies alone, but between these two points he lives in society, he lives with others.
Aloneness is his basic reality; society is just accidental.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 7- Techniques to put you at ease</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 7: Techniques to put you at ease
10. WHILE BEING CARESSED, SWEET PRINCESS, ENTER THE CARESS AS EVERLASTING LIFE.
11. STOP THE DOORS OF THE SENSES WHEN FEELING THE CREEPING OF AN ANT. THEN.
12. WHEN ON A BED OR A SEAT, LET YOURSELF BECOME WEIGHTLESS, BEYOND MIND.
Man has a center, but he lives off of it -- off the center. That creates an inner tension, a constant turmoil, anguish.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 70- Aloneness is pain</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part70/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part70/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 70: Aloneness is pain
The first question:
Question 1
CONFRONTATION OF ONESELF IN ALONENESS IS VERY FEARFUL, VERY PAINFUL. WHAT TO DO?
It is fearful and it is painful, and one has to suffer it. Nothing should be done to avoid it, nothing should be done to divert the mind, nothing should be done to escape form it. One has to suffer it and go through it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 71- Forget the periphery</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part71/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part71/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 71: Forget the periphery
IN ANY POSITION GRADUALLY PERVADE AN AREA BETWEEN THE ARMPITS INTO GREAT PEACE.
FEEL YOURSELF AS PERVADING ALL DIRECTIONS, FAR, NEAR.
Life without is a cyclone -- a constant conflict, turmoil, struggle. But it is only so on the surface -- just as on the surface of the ocean are waves, maddening noise, constant struggle. But this is not all of life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 72- Falling in love with an enlightened person</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part72/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part72/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 72: Falling in love with an enlightened person
The first question:
Question 1
YOU SAID THAT LOVE IS POSSIBLE ONLY WITH DEATH. THEN WILL YOU PLEASE EXPLAIN BUDDHA&#39;S LOVE.
For an ignorant person love is always part of hate, it always goes with hate. For the ignorant mind hate and love are just two aspects of the same coin. For the ignorant mind love is never pure.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 73- Fear of transformation</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part73/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part73/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 73: Fear of transformation
THE APPRECIATION OF OBJECTS AND SUBJECTS IS THE SAME FOR AN ENLIGHTENED AS FOR AN UNENLIGHTENED PERSON. THE FORMER HAS ONE GREATNESS: HE REMAINS IN THE SUBJECTIVE MOOD, NOT LOST IN THINGS.
BELIEVE OMNISCIENT, OMNIPOTENT, PERVADING.
Many people seem to be interested in meditation, but that interest cannot be very deep because so very few are transformed through it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 74- The greater the sensitivity, the greater the detachment</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part74/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part74/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 74: The greater the sensitivity, the greater the detachment
The first question:
Question 1
WITH DEEPENING MEDITATION, ONE BECOMES MORE AND MORE SENSITIVE TO OBJECTS, EVENTS AND PERSONS. BUT DUE TO THIS HEIGHTENED SENSITIVITY ONE FEELS A SORT OF DEEP INTIMACY WITH EVERYTHING, AND THIS USUALLY BECOMES A CAUSE OF SUBTLE ATTACHMENTS. HOW TO BE SENSITIVE AND YET DETACHED?
How to be sensitive and yet detached?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 75- The search for the rhythm of the opposites</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part75/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part75/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 75: The search for the rhythm of the opposites
IMAGE SPIRIT SIMULTANEOUSLY WITHIN AND AROUND YOU UNTIL THE ENTIRE UNIVERSE SPIRITUALIZES.
WITH YOUR ENTIRE CONSCIOUSNESS IN THE VERY START OF DESIRE, OF KNOWING, KNOW.
O SHAKTI, EACH PARTICULAR PERCEPTION IS LIMITED, DISAPPEARING IN OMNIPOTENCE.
IN TRUTH FORMS ARE INSEPARATE. INSEPARATE ARE OMNIPRESENT BEING AND YOUR OWN FORM. REALIZE EACH AS MADE OF THIS CONSCIOUSNESS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 76- Buddha\&#39;s inner orgasm</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part76/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part76/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 76: Buddha&#39;s inner orgasm
The first question:
Question 1
WE HAVE ALWAYS HEARD THAT TANTRA IS BASICALLY CONCERNED WITH SEX ENERGY AND SEX CENTER TECHNIQUES, BUT YOU SAY THAT TANTRA IS ALL-INCLUSIVE. IF THERE IS ANY TRUTH IN THE FORMER STANDPOINT, THE MAJORITY OF TECHNIQUES IN VIGYANA BHAIRAVA SEEM TO BE NON-TANTRIC. IS THIS TRUE?
The first thing is to understand sex energy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 77- Become each being</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part77/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part77/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 77: Become each being
FEEL THE CONSCIOUSNESS OF EACH PERSON AS YOUR OWN CONSCIOUSNESS.
SO, LEAVING ASIDE CONCERN FOR SELF, BECOME EACH BEING.
THIS CONSCIOUSNESS EXISTS AS EACH BEING, AND NOTHING ELSE EXISTS. THIS CONSCIOUSNESS IS THE SPIRIT OF GUIDANCE OF EACH ONE. BE THIS ONE.
Existence as such is one. The human problem arises because of human self- consciousness. Consciousness gives everyone a feeling that they are separate, and the feeling that you are separate from existence creates all the problems.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 78- The inner guide</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part78/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part78/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 78: The inner guide
The first question:
Question 1
SOME OF THE TECHNIQUES IN THE ONE HUNDRED AND TWELVE METHODS SEEM TO BE END RESULTS AND NOT TECHNIQUES, SUCH AS THOSE THAT SAY TO &#34;BECOME UNIVERSAL CONSCIOUSNESS&#34; OR &#34;BE THIS ONE&#34; ETC. IT SEEMS THAT WE NEED TECHNIQUES TO ACHIEVE THESE TECHNIQUES. WERE TECHNIQUES LIKE THESE MEANT FOR VERY ADVANCED PERSONS WHO COULD JUST BECOME COSMIC AT A MERE SUGGESTION?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 79- Sunyawad- the philosophy of emptiness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part79/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part79/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 79: Sunyawad -- the philosophy of emptiness
SUPPOSE YOUR PASSIVE FORM TO BE AN EMPTY ROOM WITH WALLS OF SKIN -- EMPTY.
GRACIOUS ONE, PLAY. THE UNIVERSE IS AN EMPTY SHELL WHEREIN YOUR MIND FROLICS INFINITELY.
SWEET HEARTED ONE, MEDITATE ON KNOWING AND NOT-KNOWING, EXISTING AND NOT-EXISTING. THEN LEAVE BOTH ASIDE THAT YOU MAY BE.
ENTER SPACE, SUPPORTLESS, ETERNAL, STILL.
These techniques are concerned with emptiness -- they are the most delicate, the most subtle.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 8- Total acceptance and non-division</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 8: Total acceptance and non-division
Question 1
WHAT DOES TANTRA MEAN BY PURITY?
One of the things being asked about is: WHAT DOES TANTRA MEAN BY PURIFICATION OF THE MIND, PURITY OF THE MIND, AS A BASIC
CONDITION TO FURTHER PROGRESS? Whatsoever is ordinarily meant by purity is not what is meant by tantra. Ordinarily, we divide everything into bad and good. The division may be for any reason.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 80- All and nothing mean the same</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part80/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part80/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌Chapter 80: All and nothing mean the same
The first question:
Question 1
YOU SAID THAT REALLY THERE IS NO ONE INSIDE US, THERE IS ONLY A VOID, AN EMPTINESS, BUT THEN WHY DO YOU OFTEN CALL IT THE BEING, THE CENTER?
Being or non-being, nothing or all -- they look contradictory but they both mean the same. All and nothing mean the same. In dictionaries they are opposites but in life they are not.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 9- Techniques for centering</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_book_of_secrets/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 9: Techniques for centering
13. OR, IMAGINE THE FIVE-COLORED CIRCLES OF THE PEACOCK TAIL TO BE YOUR FIVE SENSES IN ILLIMITABLE SPACE. NOW LET THEIR BEAUTY MELT WITHIN. SIMILARLY, AT ANY POINT IN SPACE OR ON A WALL -- UNTIL THE POINT DISSOLVES. THEN YOUR WISH FOR ANOTHER COMES TRUE.
14. PLACE YOUR WHOLE ATTENTION IN THE NERVE, DELICATE AS THE LOTUS THREAD, IN THE CENTER OF YOUR SPINAL COLUMN.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
