<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Beloved of My Heart on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/beloved_of_my_heart/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Beloved of My Heart on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/beloved_of_my_heart/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 The Other is never Responsible</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/beloved_of_my_heart/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/beloved_of_my_heart/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
The Other is never Responsible
3 May 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin mother says she is having problems in her relationship: I find myself being very bitchy and nagging sometimes. I feel I’m just asking for a fight all the time.]
Mm mm, love always brings trouble – and it has to be faced. Love cannot be always smooth, and it is good that it is not always smooth, otherwise you would not grow.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Don\&#39;t be Limited by Religion</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/beloved_of_my_heart/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/beloved_of_my_heart/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
Don’t be Limited by Religion
12 May 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A new sannyasin says: I’ve been a university student in theoretical physics. I love it very much. Sometimes you speak against science and sometimes you praise it. What should I do?]
If you want to go inwards you have to leave the scientific attitude completely. If you want to move outwards, the scientific attitude is the only way.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 Innocence is the Base of Spirituality</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/beloved_of_my_heart/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/beloved_of_my_heart/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
Innocence is the Base of Spirituality
13 May 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A visitor said that he felt himself to be like a child inside.]
If one is like a child, many things happen, because one is open, vulnerable, soft, sensitive, and one is innocent.
Innocence is the base of all spirituality. The moment you think you know, you are no more a child.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Love out of Freedom</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/beloved_of_my_heart/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/beloved_of_my_heart/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
Love out of Freedom
14 May 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Shanti Deva. It means goddess of peace. Let it be a remembrance – feel as peaceful as possible. And it is only a question of feeling. If you feel peaceful, you become peaceful. Nobody is barring you; there is no hindrance. The idea becomes the actuality. A continuous thought can be transformed into a thing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 The Religious Attitude is Alchemical</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/beloved_of_my_heart/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/beloved_of_my_heart/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
The Religious Attitude is Alchemical
15 May 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin returning to the West, expressed sadness at the thought of leaving Osho.] Sadness is also good. One has to learn that everything is good.
Goodness is not a quality of anything, it is just your approach, and how you look at it. Sadness is also good because it gives you a depth which no happiness can ever give.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 The Courage of a Madman is Needed</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/beloved_of_my_heart/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/beloved_of_my_heart/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
The Courage of a Madman is Needed
16 May 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin said that he would like to return to the West for a short period as his father had died two days ago and he felt he would be needed at home.]
Help them, because they will need you.
Death is a great experience. If you don’t know how to use it you can be destroyed by it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 Life Should be a Passion</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/beloved_of_my_heart/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/beloved_of_my_heart/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
Life Should be a Passion
17 May 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Sahaj Bharti. Sahaj means spontaneous. That is going to be your work. Be spontaneous. Never act out of the past; always act out of the present moment. This moment is all there is. If you respond from this moment, you respond from your reality.
You are responsible if you respond from your reality in this moment, herenow.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 A Sannyasin has no Future</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/beloved_of_my_heart/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/beloved_of_my_heart/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
A Sannyasin has no Future
18 May 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says: I heard... you said that a sannyasin is one who has no past and no future, and that that could be frightening.]
The future is a great problem and one has to come to grips with it. Firstly the future is nothing but your unlived past, projected.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 Put Yourself Aside</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/beloved_of_my_heart/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/beloved_of_my_heart/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
Put Yourself Aside
19 May 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Dharma Veera.
Veera means courage and dharma means religion, the ultimate truth.
And that is the only courage – to know the ultimate, because in the very process of knowing it, you will dissolve. The ultimate courage is to be ready to dissolve, to disappear, so God can appear and manifest.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 Love Yourself</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/beloved_of_my_heart/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/beloved_of_my_heart/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
Love Yourself
20 May 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A visitor says that he had a problem about sannyas. Osho asked him why the question of sannyas arose... ]
... because if you don’t feel like taking it, there is no problem. And if you feel like taking it, there is no problem. The question arises only if you are feeling a conflict within your heart.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19 Learn to Become a Void</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/beloved_of_my_heart/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/beloved_of_my_heart/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
Learn to Become a Void
21 May 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin who is a healer says: I want to become a better healer, so I can be of better service in helping people.]
Healing is one of the most delicate dimensions. And the delicacy consists in the healer not doing anything in it. The healer is not really a healer because he is not a doer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Let Love be your Life-style</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/beloved_of_my_heart/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/beloved_of_my_heart/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
Let Love be your Life-style
4 May 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin who is returning to the West says: I’m really scared about going back. I wanted to ask you if you’d help me when I’m back there.]
The fear comes to many people because you go back into a world to which you have always belonged and now you don’t belong to it anymore.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 Pain is a Great Awakener</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/beloved_of_my_heart/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/beloved_of_my_heart/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
Pain is a Great Awakener
22 May 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says she that she is feeling very closed and cut off from everything and everybody around her – including the man she is living with.]
That moment comes to every relationship. It is part of life. Sooner or later the romance starts disappearing, and romance is such a thing that it cannot be very lasting.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 Here and Now is not a Goal</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/beloved_of_my_heart/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/beloved_of_my_heart/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
Here and Now is not a Goal
23 May 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin who is leaving for the West says: I’m feeling very happy. I learnt here to believe.]
That’s very good. That’s the most important thing in life – to have trust, the capacity to believe. Even if your belief doesn’t come true sometimes, then too go on believing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22 The Ultimate Criterion is Your Heart</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/beloved_of_my_heart/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/beloved_of_my_heart/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
The Ultimate Criterion is Your Heart
24 May 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
I[A sannyasin says: I find that when you tell me to do something... I guess it’s a cop-out because I won’t do what you say because I feel I should do the opposite of what you say because that seems to be more to the heart of my problem.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23 You are the Master</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/beloved_of_my_heart/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/beloved_of_my_heart/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
You are the Master
25 May 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Hridaya means the heart and deva means divine – the divine heart. And that is the direction for you to grow towards, the height you have to reach.
By a divine heart, I mean a heart which is unconditionally in love – not with somebody in particular, but just in love with anything, any person, anybody whatsoever.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 Love is the Best Drug</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/beloved_of_my_heart/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/beloved_of_my_heart/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 24
Love is the Best Drug
26 May 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says: I’ve been feeling so good in the past few weeks that I can hardly believe it.
But I feel blocked – and that I block other people and myself I have been taking drugs for so long that everything seems to have gone dead.]
Mm, drugs can kill very very deeply.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25 Simply Rejoice Because you Are</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/beloved_of_my_heart/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/beloved_of_my_heart/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 25
Simply Rejoice Because you Are
27 May 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says: when I’m with people I feel I’d like to say something but that nobody is listening. Then I get hostile and put people down.]
Learn to listen rather than talk; then you will enjoy people more. When you are with somebody, become a good listener. There is no need to say much, because in fact there is nothing to say.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26 Celebrate Simplicity</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/beloved_of_my_heart/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/beloved_of_my_heart/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 26
Celebrate Simplicity
28 May 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin who is leaving for the west says: My heart tells me to stay and my head says I have to go back and attend to my business, to work and make money. And it’s not even that it’s a conflict.]
Mm mm, it is not a conflict, that I can see. Just a friendly quarrel between the head and the heart; just two friends fighting, almost a loving nagging.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Life is in Movement</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/beloved_of_my_heart/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/beloved_of_my_heart/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
Life is in Movement
5 May 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Dervish means a sufi mystic, a sufi seeker, and anand means bliss – a blissful seeker. Sufism is a mohammedan path...
It is just like Zen. Zen is the essence of Buddhism and Sufism is the essence of Mohammedanism, Islam, just as Yoga is the very essence of Hinduism. Only the names are different, but if you try to understand them, they are all one: Sufism, Yoga, Zen.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Become Part of my Family</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/beloved_of_my_heart/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/beloved_of_my_heart/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
Become Part of my Family
6 May 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says: I’ve really enjoyed being here. I haven’t really bothered to become integrated with the ashram but I enjoy your lectures very much.]
Next time, try to get in tune with the ashram also. You can enjoy my lectures, you can meditate, but if you are not in tune with all that is going on here and if you don’t mix in totally, you will miss many things.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Man has to Live in Yes</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/beloved_of_my_heart/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/beloved_of_my_heart/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
Man has to Live in Yes
7 May 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says: I feel very good since the Primal group. I feel aware of my feminine part somehow.]
That’s very good. Ordinarily we go on repressing one part of the being because we are taught to be males or to be females. No society allows that man is bi-sexual, that he is both; that man is not a fixed identity, not somehow static, but a dynamic process.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Self-Improvement is a Way to Hell</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/beloved_of_my_heart/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/beloved_of_my_heart/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
Self-Improvement is a Way to Hell
8 May 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin said that she did not have much time left over in her daily life for enjoyment...
Osho suggested that she make it a point each morning to do a forty minute meditation which involves simply sitting and looking]
You can sit anywhere, but whatsoever you are looking at should not be too exciting.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 The First Door is Acceptance</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/beloved_of_my_heart/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/beloved_of_my_heart/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
The First Door is Acceptance
9 May 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says: I’ve got piles. I want to die sometimes... Sometimes I’m so high and singing, and all of a sudden, zoom! I would welcome death.]
It is alright, but you are not finished yet! Death is perfectly alright, there is nothing wrong in it, but right now you are not finished.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 If You Love Me, You are Caught!</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/beloved_of_my_heart/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/beloved_of_my_heart/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
If You Love Me, You are Caught!
10 May 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
If you understand me rightly, never ask my advice for details, because that can become a problem for you. You follow me? Just remain alive and spontaneous and full of feeling. Wherever your sunflower says the sun is, allow the feeling that way. And never listen to any other consideration.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 I Give You a Capacity to Know</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/beloved_of_my_heart/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/beloved_of_my_heart/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
I Give You a Capacity to Know
11 May 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A new sannyasin says: I am confused – about everything. I cannot ask questions; there are so many.]
As I see it, you have so many answers. You think that already you know much. Your confusion is not created by so many questions, but by so many answers.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
