<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Sermons in Stones on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sermons in Stones on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 I belong to my own category</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
I belong to my own category
5 November 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
MANY CONTEMPORARIES AND ENLIGHTENED ONES – RAMAN MAHARSHI, MEHER BABA, GEORGE GURDJIEFF AND J. KRISHNAMURTI – HAVE WORKED WITH PEOPLE, BUT PEOPLE GET MORE OFFENDED BY YOU THAN BY ANYBODY ELSE.
OSHO, WHERE DOES YOUR TECHNIQUE DIFFER FROM THAT OF OTHER ENLIGHTENED ONES?
The question is very fundamental.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 God is because you are full of fear</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
God is because you are full of fear
9 December 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
RECENTLY I DEVELOPED EPILEPTIC FITS – APPARENTLY DUE TO A TINY CYST IN MY BRAIN – WHICH THE SPECIALISTS DON’T UNDERSTAND. BUT FOR ME IT FEELS LIKE SOMETHING AMAZING IS HAPPENING. THE FIRST FIT, IN JUNE, CAME TOTALLY AS A SURPRISE, AND FELT LIKE A BIG HIT ON THE HEAD: WAKE UP!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 I have to be offensive to wake you up!</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
I have to be offensive to wake you up!
10 December 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
YOU CAN’T REALLY MEAN IT WHEN YOU SAY YOU HAVE LOST ALL HOPES AND ILLUSIONS, BECAUSE YOU KNOW PERFECTLY WELL WHERE HUMANITY STANDS TODAY AND YOU KNOW HOW SLOW EVOLUTION IS. I OFTEN WONDERED IF YOU HAD NOT COME A BIT TOO SOON: HUMANITY WAS NOT READY TO UNDERSTAND YOUR LIBERATING MESSAGE, AND SIMPLY MISBEHAVED WITH YOU.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Love is the greatest alchemy</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
Love is the greatest alchemy
11 December 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
YOU HAVE TALKED ABOUT THE SUPERIORITY/INFERIORITY DIALECTIC AS THE BASIS OF AUTHORITARIAN AND FASCIST RELATIONSHIPS. IT IS ONE OF THE MIRACLES OF BEING WITH YOU THAT IN SPITE OF HAVING BEEN CONSTANTLY PERSUADED OF OUR UNWORTHINESS BY OUR PARENTS, TEACHERS AND PRIESTS, YOU ARE ABLE TO SHED LIGHT ON ALL OUR UNCONSCIOUS HABITS WITHOUT EVER MAKING US FEEL BAD ABOUT IT.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 Jealousy \-- the byproduct of marriage</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
Jealousy – the byproduct of marriage
12 December 1986 pm in
Question 1
BELOVED OSHO, MASTER OF MASTERS,
I WANT TO TELL YOU THAT I AM TOTALLY TURNED ON TO YOU, AND IT’S JUST FAR OUT BEING WITH YOU. I HAVE JUST ONE QUESTION, MAYBE IT’S NOTHING SPIRITUAL BUT FOR ME IT’S QUITE SOMETHING – MY JEALOUSY. I HAVE BEEN WITH MY BOYFRIEND FOR TWO YEARS AND WE STILL ENJOY BEING TOGETHER, BUT IF HE GOES WITH OTHER WOMEN I FREAK OUT.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 The psychology of the Buddhas</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
The psychology of the Buddhas
13 December 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHAT DO YOU MEAN BY “THE PSYCHOLOGY OF THE BUDDHAS?” HOW IS IT DIFFERENT FROM THE PRESENT PSYCHOLOGY THAT PREVAILS IN THE WORLD?
The present psychology is not yet comprehensive enough, it touches only the periphery of human individuality. It remains confined to the mind. It is not right to call it “psychology.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 Cancel your ticket, there\&#39;s nowhere to go!</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
Cancel your ticket, there’s nowhere to go!
14 December 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHEN I CAME TO POONA TEN YEARS AGO I WAS A FIFTEEN YEAR-OLD TEENAGE GIRL WITH A HEART FULL OF TRUST AND A LONGING FOR TRUTH. DURING THOSE FEW MONTHS THAT I COULD STAY WITH YOU UNDISTURBED I EXPERIENCED THE MOST BEAUTIFUL TIME OF MY LIFE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 Recognizing the Master</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
Recognizing the Master
15 December 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
CAN YOU SAY SOMETHING ABOUT RECOGNITION? WHY DO WE TAKE YOU FOR GRANTED? WHY WILL WE, YOUR DISCIPLES, NOT RECOGNIZE YOU UNTIL YOUR CRUCIFIXION? WHEN YOU SAID THAT, IT WAS LIKE A SWORD THROUGH ME.
Sudha, the recognition of a master depends on your becoming more conscious, more aware, more alert.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 The poetry of the feminine</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
The poetry of the feminine
16 December 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHY IS IT STILL SO DIFFICULT FOR ME TO SEE THE WORTH OF MY FEMININE QUALITIES? THERE IS STILL SOMETHING IN ME THAT JUDGES THEM AS WEAK AND HAVING A FEELING OF NOT BEING ABLE TO SURVIVE. CAN YOU PLEASE SAY SOMETHING ABOUT THIS?
It is the long condemnation of feminine qualities that has gone deep into the blood and the bones of women.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 Totality: the foundation of freedom</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
Totality: the foundation of freedom
17 December 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
HERE AGAIN, I FIND MYSELF IN THE DISTRESS OF A RELATIONSHIP FINISHING. IT’S STILL THE SAME PATTERN. I FEEL THAT I CANNOT DEAL WITH IT ANY DIFFERENTLY THAN BEFORE. IS THERE NO OTHER WAY THAN PLAYING THE RECORD AGAIN AND AGAIN AND AGAIN AND JUST WATCHING IT? EACH TIME, I THINK, “WITH AWARENESS IT WILL BE DIFFERENT THIS TIME.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19 Silence brings revelations, not words</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
Silence brings revelations, not words
18 December 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
FOR TWENTY YEARS, I HAVE DONE FILM WORK. ALL MY FIRST FILMS ARE WITHOUT SOUND. I NEVER COULD FIND SOUND FOR THEM BUT THE MUTENESS OF THESE FILMS, IN FACT, I COULD NOT ACCEPT. THEY DID NOT SEEM COMPLETE AND ONLY SOMETIMES I PRESENTED THEM TO PEOPLE. WORKING IN THIS WAY, I COULD NOT BE SUCCESSFUL.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 You are the world</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
You are the world
6 November 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
“YOU ARE THE WORLD.” THIS IS ONE OF THE CONFUSING STATEMENTS OF KRISHNAMURTI.
WE DON’T THINK THERE IS ANYBODY ELSE PRESENT ON THE EARTH EXCEPT YOU WHO COULD HELP US TO UNDERSTAND IT, SO WE REQUEST YOU TO SAY SOMETHING ON IT.
Yesterday, there was a question left, left for tomorrow; but just now I realized that tomorrow never comes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 The \&#34;Other\&#34;\... Hell? Or the door to the divine?</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
The “Other”... Hell? Or the door to the divine?
19 December 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I AM BECOMING AWARE MORE AND MORE HOW MUCH I FOCUS ON THE OTHER, WHETHER IT IS A FRIEND, A LOVER, A MOUNTAIN, OR MUSIC. ONE THING REMAINS ALWAYS THE SAME: THE OTHER IS A LONGING WITHIN ME BECAUSE WITHOUT THE OTHER, I CAN NEVER FEEL COMPLETE, RECONCILED.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 This too will pass\...</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
This too will pass...
20 December 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHO WAS THE MASTER WHO DISCOVERED OR INVENTED THE LATIHAN MEDITATION TECHNIQUE? WOULD YOU LIKE EXPLAIN THIS MEDITATION TECHNIQUE?
Latihan is a unique method – unique in the sense that it is the only method that has come out of this century, and unique also because it happened to a man who was not searching for truth, who was not a seeker.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22 The greatest discovery there is</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
The greatest discovery there is
21 December 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
YOU HAVE NOT ONLY A PROFOUND UNDERSTANDING OF HUMAN NATURE BUT ALSO YOU HAVE THE KNOW-HOW TO TRANSFORM IT. YOU ARE A PERFECT MASTER. HOW IS IT THAT WESTERN AND EASTERN PSYCHOLOGISTS ARE NOT RECOGNIZING YOU? DO THESE HUMAN SCIENTISTS FEEL JEALOUS AND OFFENDED BY YOU? PLEASE COMMENT.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23 Being: The most beautiful flower in existence</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
Being: The most beautiful flower in existence
22 December 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I’M OFTEN TORTURED BY THE IDEA THAT I HAVE TO DO SOMETHING SPECIAL TO REALIZE MYSELF. A FEW YEARS AGO, I WAS ON THE POINT OF BECOMING A PSYCHOANALYST. FORTUNATELY, I DROPPED THIS IDEA AND I TOOK SANNYAS. I TRIED TO WORK AS A DOCTOR, BUT I WAS GETTING SO TENSE THAT I WAS NO LONGER LOVING WITH THE PEOPLE WHO WERE COMING TO ME.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 Charisma: a taste of the divine</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 24
Charisma: a taste of the divine
23 December 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHAT IS CHARISMA? ALL SORTS OF PEOPLE HAVE IT, BOTH AWARE PEOPLE AND UNAWARE PEOPLE. ITS SUCH AN INTANGIBLE QUALITY, I CAN SAY WHEN SOMEONE IS CHARISMATIC BUT CAN’T DEFINE WHAT IT IS.
Sudha, charisma is a mystery. It happens only to those people who have centered their being, concentrated their energies, who are no longer falling apart, who are consolidated, who have become one – the very meaning of the word, “individual.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25 Yes is the heartbeat of life</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 25
Yes is the heartbeat of life
24 December 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
JANOV SAYS THAT NEGATIVITY IS ELECTROCHEMICALLY DRIVEN BY ENDOMORPHINS, THE CHEMICAL EFFECT OF PAIN. HOW IS “YES” POSSIBLE WITHOUT EXHAUSTIVE PRIMAL THERAPY?
Primal therapy has contributed something very essential and significant to human growth. But just as other therapies in the West are amateurish, primal therapy also belongs to the same category.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26 The Human Rights Declaration: Hypocrisy of a barbarous society</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 26
The Human Rights Declaration: Hypocrisy of a barbarous society
25 December 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
IT FEELS STRANGE WHEN THE ESTABLISHMENT, WORLDWIDE, WHICH IS EVER BUSY WITH ALL ITS EFFORTS AND RESOURCES TO MAKE SURE IN EVERY POSSIBLE WAY THAT MAN CANNOT REMAIN MAN, ASKS US TO CELEBRATE “HUMAN RIGHTS DAY.” GOODNESS, WHAT IS ALL THIS THAT’S GOING ON?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27 Love is not something to get, love is something to give</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 27
Love is not something to get, love is something to give
26 December 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
AS I AM AN ARTIST, I CAN EASILY PUT MY FEELINGS OF LOVE AND BLISS INTO MAKING SCULPTURES. WHY CAN’T I EXPRESS THE SAME FEELINGS TO HUMAN BEINGS AND BE AS OPEN TO THEM AS I AM IN MAKING SCULPTURES?
It is easy to be a sculptor because you are working with lifeless objects.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28 The full stop never comes</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part28/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 28
The full stop never comes
27 December 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHENEVER I READ FRIEDRICH NIETZSCHE, AND FEEL QUITE RELAXED, IT APPEARS AS IF I HAVE A CONNECTION WITH A SPIRIT WHICH IS ALIVE AND I TALK TO HIM. HE IS NOT DEAD BUT A LIVING FRIEND AND IT DOESN’T SOUND ABSURD AT ALL THAT ALL THE GREAT SPIRITS ARE IN DEEP COMMUNICATION WITH ONE ANOTHER WHETHER THEY ARE DEAD OR ALIVE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>29 Human rights for the new man</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part29/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 29
Human rights for the new man
28 December 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
ON DECEMBER 25TH, YOU SPOKE TO US ON THE DECLARATION OF HUMAN RIGHTS. YOU EXPOSED IT AS A POLITICAL DEVICE TO MAINTAIN MAN IN HIS CURRENT STATE OF PHYSICAL AND PSYCHOLOGICAL SLAVERY, AND TO ENSURE THAT HE REMAINS IGNORANT OF HIS TRUE POTENTIAL FOR GODLINESS. WOULD YOU, TONIGHT, MAKE YOUR OWN DECLARATION OF HUMAN RIGHTS FOR THE NEW MAN?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Old age: A new beginning</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
Old age: A new beginning
7 November 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
SOMETHING FEELS DRASTICALLY WRONG ABOUT THE WAY SOCIETY LOOKS AFTER – OR FAILS TO LOOK AFTER – THE ELDERLY.
YOU HAVE SPOKEN OF THE LEGALIZATION OF EUTHANASIA FOR THOSE WHO ARE SO MENTALLY OR PHYSICALLY DEBILITATED THAT THEY CAN HARDLY BE SAID TO BE LIVING AT ALL. BUT WHAT CAN BE DONE FOR THOSE WHO ARE NOT PHYSICALLY OR MENTALLY INCAPACITATED, BUT ARE RETIRED FROM THEIR PROFESSIONS, AND WHOSE FAMILIES HAVE GROWN UP?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>30 The Master only makes you remember who you are</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part30/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 30
The Master only makes you remember who you are
29 December 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
YOU ARE FOR ME, THE MOST EXTRAORDINARY PERSON I CAN IMAGINE. YET I KNOW THAT YOU FEEL ORDINARY. WHERE IS THE DOOR FOR A TALENTED AND GIFTED PERSON OR A GENIUS TO FEEL AND BECOME ORDINARY? I SEE THAT EACH TIME I FEEL SPECIAL, SOMETHING GOES WRONG.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 The mystery of the knack</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
The mystery of the knack
8 November 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
SOME TIME AGO, IN ANSWER TO MY QUESTION AS TO WHETHER ENLIGHTENMENT IS THE ONLY WAY A DISCIPLE CAN EXPRESS GRATITUDE TO HER MASTER, I HEARD YOU SAY THAT NOTHING COULD EXPRESS THE GRATITUDE. I REALIZED THEN THAT GRATITUDE IS SOMETHING THAT WE USUALLY FEEL ALMOST BURDENED WITH, AND SO WE SEEK TO FIND AN OUTLET FOR IT SO THAT WE ARE RELIEVED OF A DEBT.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Laughter \-- as sacred as prayer</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
Laughter – as sacred as prayer
13 November 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I AM VERY ANGRY WITH WOMEN. I DON’T LIKE WOMAN. WHY IS WOMAN SELFISH? WHY HAS WOMAN NO INTELLIGENCE? WHY IS A WOMAN LIKE A CAT?
OSHO, WHY DO YOU PUT WOMAN ON THE WAY OF TAO?
Woman is what man has made of her. It is a vicious circle.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 At the center we are one</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
At the center we are one
5 December 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I LEFT MY MOTHER TWENTY YEARS, AND MY WIFE OVER FOUR YEARS AGO. WHY CAN’T I LET THEM GO?
One of the mysteries of life is the law of reverse returns. There are things which you cannot do. Although people have done them, although it is possible they may happen to you too, they are always happenings, they are never doings.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Love and centering: one phenomenon</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
Love and centering: one phenomenon
6 December 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
IS IT POSSIBLE FOR A WOMAN TO BE IN LOVE AND STILL CENTERED?
The question has many implications.
First, you do not understand what being centered means.
Second, you also have no experience of the phenomenon of love. I can say this with absolute authority, because your question supplies all the evidence for what I am saying.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 In love, drop the object</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
In love, drop the object
7 December 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WAITING FOR YOU TO GET WELL, THERE CAME A POINT WHERE I WASN’T WAITING ANYMORE FOR SOMETHING – IT SIMPLY BECAME JUST WAITING. DISCOVERING THE BEAUTY AND SWEETNESS OF IT WAS SO PRECIOUS. WAITING NEEDS NO PATIENCE. IT IS LIKE LIVING IN MOONLIGHT – A MYSTERIOUS QUIET JOY, SO NOURISHING AND RESTFUL, BECOMING A WOMB CONNECTED WITH YOU IN A CIRCULAR FLOW OF ENERGY.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 Mind as a Master is a disaster</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sermons_in_stones/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
Mind as a Master is a disaster
8 December 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHEN I LISTEN TO YOUR DISCOURSES, YOU TAKE ME ON AN INDESCRIBABLE JOURNEY. IF AFTERWARDS SOMEONE ASKS ME ABOUT WHAT YOU HAVE SAID, I HARDLY REMEMBER. BUT WHEN PEOPLE ASK ME PERSONAL QUESTIONS, ANSWERS ARE COMING OUT OF MY MOUTH WHICH ASTONISH ME THE MOST. OSHO, AM I BECOMING A PARROT OF YOUR WORDS?</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
