<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Passion for the Impossible on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Passion for the Impossible on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
21 August 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says: When I’m in London working, I am very involved in my work and I feel how could I possibly leave it? So I’m really finding things difficult.]
Your work is good. You are doing good work there, but your own growth is far more important than your work. It is good work; if you continue, there is nothing wrong in it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
30 August 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin had said at his last darshan (see Dance Your Way to God, August 16th, 1976) that he was too much of an egoist, so Osho had told him to give his ego full play for one week – to set himself up as a guru and adopt some followers etc.
Tonight, the sannyasin reported back : I enjoyed it, but I also felt guilty.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
31 August 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
The first thing is to fall in line with me. Just dose your eyes and feel yourself surrounded by me – as if you have entered me, as if I am only a door. Relax, and if something starts happening in your body energy, allow it. Just go with it .…
Geet means song and Govind means God – God’s song.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
1 September 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin who is going back to the West said she ran groups in a mental hospital and also privately, but she worries about being too serious.]
No, don’t do it, because then it becomes almost impossible to live. As humanity is, it needs many lies, many pretensions, many pretexts. If you are talking to a child, you talk in a language that the child understands.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
2 September 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A visitor says: I’ve come here hoping with my heart to be captured by something and I’m still waiting.
I have this idea that I won’t be able to have the drive to follow a path until my heart is captured, so I’m just waiting.]
Mm, I understand. You don’t know your own strength – nobody knows, hence the problem.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
3 September 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A visitor says: I don’t know whether I want to take sannyas or not. I’m troubled about the concept of surrender, because I feel for a long time that I’ve surrendered to a lot of people, and only recently I’ve begun to feel centred.]
You must have a wrong notion about surrender, because whatsoever you have been calling surrender was not surrender.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
4 September 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine and shubha means goodness – divine goodness. Human beings are good, but their goodness is also part of their policy. They say that honesty is the best policy. Even through goodness they want to earn something. It is a bargain. To be good is beneficial, hence they are good. Their goodness is not unconditional; it is conditional.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
5 September 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss and bhairava means god – god of bliss. Bhairava is a name of the god Shiva. He is a totally different god to other gods in the world – life-affirmative, celebrating, not in any way life-negating; not in any way against life, but for it. So he is the god of bliss.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
6 September 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A visitor who had done the Tathata group said he found it easy. Osho suggested he do the Enlightenment Intensive, saying that that would be more intense.]
When you take the challenge of a certain difficult method, you grow. Something easy is not necessarily good. Something may look easy but it does not force any change in you.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
7 September 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[To two resident sannyasins returning for a brief visit to the States to see their parents, Osho spoke about how one could introduce one’s parents to sannyas, meditation, and Osho, in a way that would be acceptable. He said one should not try to argue, but simply let one’s being, one’s happiness, be evidence of one’s new life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
8 September 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, nirvesha means enjoyment, joy, bliss, happiness, divine joy.
And to me, all joy is divine. Joy as such is divine. If one can be joyful, one is in prayer. Then there is no need to do any other prayer. Then you are constantly offering yourself to God. We cannot offer anything else.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
22 August 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[The Tathata group was present.
A group member says: People tell me that their first impression of me is that I’m angry or aggressive or detached, and usually I’m feeling the opposite.
It seems that usually I’m saying one thing and my body and face are saying something else.]
How do you yourself feel?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
9 September 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[To a sannyasin, whose son had just been initiated into sannyas, Osho said that one should respect one’s child, and that now her son was a sannyasin, she should regard him as a brother...
A child is born to you, but he does not belong to you. Always remember that he has come through you.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
10 September 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A new sannyasin says: I’m a nursery school teacher, I teach children of four-and-a-half to five years old.]
Very good work. To be with children is one of the most beautiful things. But one has to learn it, otherwise it can be the most tedious thing in the world. One has to love it, otherwise it is one of the most boring things.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
11 September 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, and tarpana means sacrifice – divine sacrifice, or sacrifice to the divine. And that’s what life really is. Unless it becomes a sacrifice, an offering, you go on missing it. Unless you give your life totally, you miss it. And there is no way ordinarily to give it totally except to give it to God, because only the total can become the receptor of a total gift.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
12 September 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, and bhavana means feeling – the feel of bliss, the feeling of bliss. And remember that blissfulness has nothing to do with thinking. It is a feeling. People who are stuck in their heads can only be unhappy and miserable. For them there is no other way. The head is hell, the very centre of hell.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 24
13 September 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine and vishwa means the universe the divine universe. And that’s exactly how it is. God is not separate. It is not a separate reality. The whole world is divine. The creation and the creator are not two things. They are one, a single unity.
So remember it, and start looking for God everywhere.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 25
14 September 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A visitor said three years of Freudian psychoanalysis helped her, but also made things difficult.]
That too is true, because all the analytical methods are in a way incomplete. They help you only to a certain extent and then they leave you in a limbo. One feels that something has happened, but much is missing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 26
16 September 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin had previously written to Osho about her sexuality, which seemed to have become more intensified lately – mainly been through auto-erotic activity. Guilt feelings surfaced from childhood, about its being a perversion. Osho checked her energy.]
I told you to remain celibate for a few days specifically for this purpose, because once you are celibate for a few days, energy pools; it becomes a reservoir.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 27
17 September 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine and pankaj means lotus – a divine lotus. The lotus is very symbolic in the East because it comes out of dirty mud, and yet so beautiful, so graceful, so other-worldly... is born of the earth but does not belong to the earth. It is unearthly.
So one has to be like a lotus – rooted in the earth but not defined and confined by the earth.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/part28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/part28/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 28
18 September 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[To a sannyasin who is leaving]
... continue to meditate there and come back as soon as possible, because much work has to be done yet. Something has started but it is just a beginning – never forget that. And never be satisfied too soon. Sometimes it happens that we become satisfied too early. As far as worldly things are concerned, never be dissatisfied, and as far as the inner world is concerned, never be satisfied.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
23 August 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Kalpana means imagination and deva means divine – divine imagination. And that you have to remember: that your path will go through imagination. You have a tremendous capacity to imagine. If you can use it, it can be an immense help. If you don’t use it, it can become a barrier. If one has some capacity, one has to use it, otherwise it becomes like a rock on the path.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
24 August 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says: I feel I have a legacy of laziness and escapism. Either I don’t feel energy, or if I do, I find it difficult to just completely let go. I feel a control.]
I feel it is somewhere and has become part of your bio-computer. The mind functions as a computer, and we go on feeding it attitudes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
25 August 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[An indian visitor says: With so many ideas before me, and having to make a decision, I feel that by making a choice I’m locking myself within a definition. By making a choice, I think I define myself, and in a sense imprison myself.]
Mm, I understand. But whether you choose or not, you choose.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
26 August 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says: I’m just getting ready to leave. I had many questions when I arrived, but I don’t remember them.]
That’s very good. That’s how it should be. When you come, you come with many questions. When you go, go without any questions. I’m not saying you will be going with answers, but if you can go without questions, that’s enough.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
27 August 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine and navaneet means essence, essential. Divinity is our essence. We may have forgotten it, but we cannot lose it. We may have become completely oblivious of it, but there is no way to get away from it. It is not accidental, it is essential. Anything accidental can be taken away from you.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
28 August 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A visitor said she had trouble becoming involved in the meditations here, adding that she could not stay much longer as she was a psychiatrist and had patients to see.]
A psychiatrist needs to be meditative more than anybody else – because your whole work is dangerous in a way. Unless you are very calm and quiet, unless you can remain unaffected by things that happen around you, it is very dangerous.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_passion_for_the_impossible/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
29 August 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says she is confused because she sometimes feels lower than ever before: It begins with the fact that I don’t feel anybody loves me or that I’m worthy of being loved. This happened last night, and I’m very frightened of having that experience for a long time when I’m alone.]
Sometimes it happens that you can be more confused here than anywhere else because a possibility for fusion exists here.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
