<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Glimpses of a Golden Childhood on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Glimpses of a Golden Childhood on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
1984 in Lao Tzu House, Rajneeshpuram, USA
It is a beautiful morning. Again and again the sun rises and it is always new. It never grows old. Scientists say it is millions of years old; nonsense! Every day I see it. It is always new. Nothing is old. But scientists are grave-diggers, that’s why I say they look so grave, serious. This morning, again the miracle of existence.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
1984 in Lao Tzu House, Rajneeshpuram, USA
I was looking at some pictures of the marriage procession of Princess Anne, and strangely, the only thing that impressed me in the whole nonsense was the beautiful horses, their joyous dance. Looking at those horses I remembered my own horse. I have not told anyone about it, not even Gudia, who loves horses. But now that I am not keeping anything secret, even this can be told.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
1984 in Lao Tzu House, Rajneeshpuram, USA
Devageet... really good, and after being hit, you have seen stars. I too can see the stars along with you. Okay.
The village where I was born was not part of the British Empire. It was a small state ruled by a Mohammedan queen. I can see her now. Strange, she was also as beautiful as the queen of England, exactly as beautiful.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
1984 in Lao Tzu House, Rajneeshpuram, USA
I have been working the whole night because of a small remark I made which may have been hurtful to Devaraj. He may not have noticed it, but it has been sitting heavy on me all night. I could not sleep. I had said, “No Buddha has ever had a personal dentist, but Gautam the Buddha had a personal physician.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
1984 in Lao Tzu House, Rajneeshpuram, USA
Okay, remove the towel. Ashu, forgive me, because now I have to begin my business, and you can understand that two shirts together on one chest is very difficult for the poor chest, particularly for the poor heart hidden behind the chest. The heart cannot behave in a political or diplomatic way. It is not a diplomat; it is simple and childlike.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
1984 in Lao Tzu House, Rajneeshpuram, USA
Look what an English gentleman I am! Although I wanted to interfere, I didn’t. I had already opened my mouth to speak but I stopped myself. This is called self-control. Even I can laugh. When you whisper it feels so good. Although I know that you are not whispering nonsense, it still sounds nice – although it is technical and what you are saying is perfectly scientific.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
1984 in Lao Tzu House, Rajneeshpuram, USA
I have always loved the story told of Henry Ford. He had made his most beautiful car, and he was showing it to a prosperous, very prosperous and promising customer. It was his latest model, and he took the customer for a ride. After thirty miles the car suddenly stopped.
The customer said, “What! A new car and it stops after just thirty miles?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
1984 in Lao Tzu House, Rajneeshpuram, USA
There are six great religions in the world. They can be divided into two categories: one consists of Judaism, Christianity and Islam; they believe in only one life. You are just between birth and death. There is nothing beyond birth and death – life is all. Although they believe in heaven and hell and God, they are the earnings from one life, a single life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
1984 in Lao Tzu House, Rajneeshpuram, USA
Okay.
The first words that Ajit Saraswati uttered to me last night were, “Osho, I never expected that I would ever make it.” Of course those who were present thought he was talking about coming to live in the ashram. And that too is in a way true, relevant, because I remember the first day he came to see me twenty years ago.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
1984 in Lao Tzu House, Rajneeshpuram, USA
Sigmund Freud was interviewing one of his patients. He asked the man lying on the couch, “Look through the window – can you see the flagpole on the office building across the street?”
The old man said, “Of course. Do you think I am blind? I may be old but I can see the pole, the flag and everything.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
1984 in Lao Tzu House, Rajneeshpuram, USA
Okay.
I said “okay” a little early, just because I was becoming concerned about your worry. At least in the beginning don’t be worried; in the beginning let me have my say. If you are worried, obviously I will say “okay” but that will not be okay at all.
After my grandfather died I was again away from my Nani, but I soon returned to my father’s village.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
1984 in Lao Tzu House, Rajneeshpuram, USA
I just had a golden experience, the feeling of a disciple so lovingly working on his Master’s body. I’m still out of breath because of it. And it also reminds me of my golden childhood.
Everybody talks of his golden childhood, but rarely, very rarely, is it true. Mostly it is a lie. But so many people are telling the same lie that nobody detects it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
1984 in Lao Tzu House, Rajneeshpuram, USA
Wait for my “Okay”
I am standing before the “Elephant Gate” of my primary school.and that gate started many things
in my life. I was not standing alone of course; my father was standing with me. He had come to enroll me at the school. I looked at the tall gates and said to him, “No.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
1984 in Lao Tzu House, Rajneeshpuram, USA
Okay.…
The man I was talking about, his full name was Pandit Shambhuratan Dube. We all used to call him Shambhu Babu. He was a poet, and rare in that he was not eager to be published. That is very rare in a poet. I have come across hundreds of the tribe, and they are all so eager to be published that poetry becomes secondary.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
1984 in Lao Tzu House, Rajneeshpuram, USA
I was just going to say “okay,” but no. One day I said it lightly, just to be polite, and suffered much. Then everything went wrong. So now I’m going to say okay only when it is really okay, otherwise silence is better.…
Okay.
I am reminded again of poor Sigmund Freud. He was waiting in his office for a rich, and of course Jewish, patient.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
1984 in Lao Tzu House, Rajneeshpuram, USA
Now, my work upon you.…
I was telling you about a certain relationship that happened between a child of about nine years of age and an old man of perhaps fifty. The difference in age was great, but love can transcend all barriers. If it can happen even between a man and a woman, then what other barrier could be bigger?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 24
1984 in Lao Tzu House, Rajneeshpuram, USA
I was saying to you that friendship is a higher value than love. Nobody has said it before. And I also say that friendliness is even higher than friendship. Nobody has even mentioned that. I will certainly have to explain.
Love, howsoever beautiful, remains earthbound. It is something like the roots of a tree. Love tries to rise above the earth and all that it implies – the body – but it falls again and again.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 25
1984 in Lao Tzu House, Rajneeshpuram, USA
Okay.
I was quoting Bertrand Russell – this quotation will help like a nail. He said, “Sooner or later everybody will need psychoanalysis because it is so difficult to find anyone to listen to you, to be attentive to you.”
Attention is such a need that if the worst came to the worst one would even pay for it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 26
1984 in Lao Tzu House, Rajneeshpuram, USA
I will have to go in circles, circles within circles within circles, for that’s how life is. And more so in my case. In nearly fifty years, I must have lived at least fifty lives. In fact, I have not done anything else other than living. Other people have many occupations, but from my very childhood I have remained a vagabond, not doing anything, just living.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 27
1984 in Lao Tzu House, Rajneeshpuram, USA
Okay. Do you see the synchronicity? Simultaneously, I and Devageet said, “Okay.” Of course he said it for one thing, I for something else; but the lines cross.
The moment before I came in I was listening to one of the greatest flutists, Hari Prasad. It stirred many memories in me.
There are many types of flute in the world.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part28/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 28
1984 in Lao Tzu House, Rajneeshpuram, USA
Okay. This noise that you are making is enough to make anybody say okay. Thank you. Now I can really say okay.
I was just listening again, not to Hari Prasad Chaurasia, but another flutist. In India the flute has two dimensions: one, the southern; the other, the northern. Hari Prasad Chaurasia was a northern flutist; I was listening to the polar opposite, the southern.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>29</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part29/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 29
1984 in Lao Tzu House, Rajneeshpuram, USA
The whole night the wind went on blowing in the trees. The sound was so beautiful that I played Pannalal Ghosh, one of the flutists that Pagal Baba had introduced to me. Just now too, I was playing his music, but he has a way of his own. His introduction is very long, so before Gudia called me it was still only the introduction.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
1984 in Lao Tzu House, Rajneeshpuram, USA
Again and again the miracle of the morning... the sun and the trees. The world is just like a snow flower: take it in your hand and it melts away. Nothing is left, just a wet hand. But if you see, just see, then a snow flower is as beautiful as any flower in the world.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>30</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part30/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 30
1984 in Lao Tzu House, Rajneeshpuram, USA
I was talking about Pagal Baba and the three flutists he introduced to me. It is still a beautiful memory, the way he introduced me to people – particularly to those who were accustomed to being received, respected and honored. The first thing he would say to them was, “Touch the feet of this boy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>31</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part31/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 31
1984 in Lao Tzu House, Rajneeshpuram, USA
Pagal Baba, in his last days was always a little bit worried. I could see it, although he had not said anything, nor had anybody else mentioned it. Perhaps nobody else was even aware that he was worried. It was certainly not about his illness, old age, or his oncoming death; those were absolutely immaterial to the man.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>32</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part32/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part32/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 32
1984 in Lao Tzu House, Rajneeshpuram, USA
I have always wondered that something went right with me from the very beginning. Of course, there is no such phrase in any language. There is a phrase like “something going wrong,” but not “something going right,” but what can I do? It really has gone right from my very first breath – up to now at least, and I hope it won’t change.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>33</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part33/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part33/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 33
1984 in Lao Tzu House, Rajneeshpuram, USA
Okay.
The other day I told you about Masto’s disappearance. I think he is still alive. In fact I know he is. In the East, this has been one of the most ancient ways, to disappear in the Himalayas before you die. To die in that beautiful part is richer than to live anywhere else; even dying there has something of the eternal.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>34</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part34/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part34/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 34
1984 in Lao Tzu House, Rajneeshpuram, USA
This morning I said a very abrupt goodbye to Masto, and I felt it the whole day. It simply cannot be done, at least in his case. It reminds me of when I was going to college and leaving my Nani after being so long together.
Since my grandfather died and left her there had been no one in her life except me.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>35</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part35/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part35/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 35
1984 in Lao Tzu House, Rajneeshpuram, USA
Okay.
I have heard Ravi Shankar play on the sitar. He has everything one can imagine: the personality of a singer, the mastery of his instrument, and the gift of innovation, which is rare in classical musicians. He is immensely interested in the new. He has played with Yehudi Menuhin. No other Indian sitar player would be ready to do it because no such thing has ever happened before.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>36</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part36/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part36/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 36
1984 in Lao Tzu House, Rajneeshpuram, USA
Just now I was thinking of a story. I don’t know who created the story or why, and I don’t agree with his conclusions either, but I still love it.
The story is simple. You may have heard it, but perhaps not understood it because it is so simple. Everybody thinks he understands simplicity. It’s a strange world.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>37</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part37/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part37/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 37
1984 in Lao Tzu House, Rajneeshpuram, USA
Okay.
We are only at the second day of my primary school. It is going to be like that. Every day opens up so many things. I have not finished even the second day yet. Today I will do my best to finish it.
Life is interlinked, you cannot cut it into neat pieces. It is not a piece of cloth.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>38</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part38/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part38/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 38
1984 in Lao Tzu House, Rajneeshpuram, USA
Okay.
I wanted to tell you a simple truth, perhaps forgotten for its simplicity; and no religion can practice it because the moment you become part of a religion you are no longer simple nor religious. I wanted to tell you just a very simple thing which I have learned the hard way. Perhaps you are getting it too cheap, and the simple is generally mistaken for the cheap.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>39</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part39/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part39/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 39
1984 in Lao Tzu House, Rajneeshpuram, USA
Devageet, I think you are being affected by something. You have to be unaffected. Right? “Right.”
Otherwise who is going to write the notes? The writer has to be, at least, the writer. Okay.
These tears are for you, that’s why they are on the right side. Ashu missed. A little one is coming on the left for her also.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
1984 in Lao Tzu House, Rajneeshpuram, USA
I was telling you of the moment when I met the astrologer who had now become a sannyasin.…
I was nearabout fourteen at the time, and with my other grandfather, that is, my father’s father. My real grandfather was no more; he died when I was only seven. The old bhikku, the ex-astrologer, asked me, “I am by profession an astrologer, and by hobby a reader of many things – lines of the hand, of heads, of feet, and so on.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>40</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part40/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part40/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 40
1984 in Lao Tzu House, Rajneeshpuram, USA
Chapter 41 Chapter title: None
1984 in Lao Tzu House, Rajneeshpuram, USA Okay.
I could not even begin to tell you what I wanted to tell you. Perhaps it was not meant to be, because I tried so many times to bring myself to the point, but in vain, and then everything went sane. But it was a most fruitful session, although nothing was said, and nothing was heard either.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>41</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part41/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part41/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 41
1984 in Lao Tzu House, Rajneeshpuram, USA
Okay.
What was I telling you? I cannot remember it, remind me.
“We were talking about how Morarji Desai and Satyabhakta became your enemies, and the last thing you said was that Morarji Desai had something in his eyes that was slimy and slippery, which you remember.”
Good. It is better to not remember it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>42</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part42/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part42/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 42
1984 in Lao Tzu House, Rajneeshpuram, USA
Okay.
I have always wondered how God could manage to make this world in only six days. And this world! Perhaps that’s why He called His son Jesus! What a name to give to your own son! He had to punish somebody for what He had done, and there was nobody else available. The Holy Ghost is always absent; he is sitting there on the horse seat, that’s why I told Chetana to vacate it, because to ride a horse with somebody already riding on it is not good.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>43</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part43/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part43/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 43
1984 in Lao Tzu House, Rajneeshpuram, USA
I was wondering yesterday how God created this world in six days. I was wondering, because I have not yet been able to even go beyond the second day of my primary school. And what a world He created! Perhaps He was a Jew, because only Jews have circulated the idea.
Hindus don’t believe in a God, they believe in many gods.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>44</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part44/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part44/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 44
1984 in Lao Tzu House, Rajneeshpuram, USA
Okay.
The story of Mahatma Gandhi’s death, and Jawaharlal’s bursting into tears on the radio, stunned the whole world. It was not a prepared speech. He was just speaking out of his own heart, and if tears came, what could he do? And if there was a pause, it was not his fault but his greatness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>45</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part45/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part45/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 45
1984 in Lao Tzu House, Rajneeshpuram, USA
Okay.
I can begin with the second day in my primary school. How long can it wait? It has already waited too long. The second day was my real entry into the school, because Kantar Master had been thrown out and everybody was joyous. Almost all the children were dancing. I could not believe it, but they told me, “You did not know Kantar Master.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>46</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part46/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part46/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 46
1984 in Lao Tzu House, Rajneeshpuram, USA
I was talking about my primary school. I rarely went, and it was such a relief to everybody that I wanted to give it to them as much as possible. Why could I not give them one hundred percent relief? For the simple reason that I loved them too – I mean the people: the teachers, the servants, the gardeners.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>47</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part47/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part47/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 47
1984 in Lao Tzu House, Rajneeshpuram, USA
I was talking about my visits to school. Yes, I call them visits because they were certainly not attendance. I was only there to create some mischief. In a strange way I have always loved to be involved in some mischievous act. Perhaps it was the beginning of how I was to be for my whole life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>48</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part48/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part48/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 48
1984 in Lao Tzu House, Rajneeshpuram, USA
Okay.
I was just trying to remember the man. I can see his face, but perhaps I never bothered about his name so I don’t remember it. I will tell you the whole story.
My Nani, seeing that I was unteachable, and sending me to school was just creating trouble, tried to convince my family, my father and mother, but nobody was ready to listen to her.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>49</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part49/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part49/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 49
1984 in Lao Tzu House, Rajneeshpuram, USA
It is good that I cannot see, but I know what is going on. But what can you do? You have to follow your own technology, and with a man like me, naturally you are in a great difficulty. I am tied and can’t help you.
Ashu, can you do something? Just a little laughter on your side will help him keep quiet.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
1984 in Lao Tzu House, Rajneeshpuram, USA
I was talking about the death of my Nana, my grandfather. Just now I remembered that he never had to go to a dentist. What a fortunate man! He died with all his teeth intact. And look at me. When you were examining my teeth I heard you say that one is missing. That may be why I am so hard: thirty-one teeth instead of thirty-two.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
1984 in Lao Tzu House, Rajneeshpuram, USA
Okay.
My okay is a little sad because Ashu is sad, and the membership of this Noah’s Ark is so small that just one person being sad is enough to change the whole atmosphere. She is sad because her lover is gone and may not be back.
Do you remember a few days ago I asked her, “Where is your love, Ashu?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
1984 in Lao Tzu House, Rajneeshpuram, USA
Devageet, when you sometimes say “Okay” to Ashu, I misunderstand: I think it is okay to me. That’s why she laughs. But still I say, deep within me there is nothing but laughter. You can anesthetize my body, everything, but not me. That is beyond you.
That is the case with you too. Your innermost core is beyond all chemicals and chemistry.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
1984 in Lao Tzu House, Rajneeshpuram, USA
I have been talking about an incident that is absolutely important in order to understand my life and its workings... and it is still alive for me.…
By the way, I was saying I can still remember, but the word “remember” is not right. I can still see the whole incident happening. Of course I was just a young child, but that does not mean that what I said is not to be taken seriously.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/glimpses_of_a_golden_childhood/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
1984 in Lao Tzu House, Rajneeshpuram, USA
Time cannot go back, but mind can. What a wastage – to give such a mind, which cannot forget anything whatsoever, to a man who not only has become a no-mind, but also preaches to others to drop the mind. As far as my mind is concerned – remember, my mind, not me – it is as much a mechanism as the one being used here.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
