<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Don\&#39;t Look Before You Leap on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Don\&#39;t Look Before You Leap on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
1 July 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, renu means dust – love dust.
But once dust is of love it is divine. Love transforms it: then it is no more dust; it is dust only if love is missing. If love is missing then man is nothing but dust. Once love enters into life, dust becomes aflame with the divine.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
10 July 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
The whole of life is a means. And the moment you start thinking of something other than god as a goal, you start going astray.
Money can become the goal, then the person has gone astray. Nothing is wrong in money itself – it is perfectly good, useful – but it should remain the means; it should not become the end.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
11 July 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, unmana means no-mind. The state of no-mind is the state of the divine. God is not a thought but the experience of thoughtlessness. It is not a content in the mind; it is the explosion when the mind is contentless. It is not an object that you can see; it is the very capacity to see.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
12 July 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, uparati means indifference to the non-essential – a divine indifference to the non essential. And that’s the whole work of the seeker. We are caught up in the non-essential, the mundane, the trivial. For the moment it looks so important, and the next moment it appears as if it had not happened at all.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
13 July 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, diwani means madness – love madness. And that’s the only method to god. If one can be mad in love, then all becomes possible, because only in love are we not tethered to the earth. Suddenly the law of gravitation is replaced by the law of grace. We are not being pulled downwards, we are uplifted; hence the euphoria that love brings.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
14 July 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means god, kabiro means great – the great god, or, god is great. Everything else is just a part – god is the whole.
God is not a person but another name for the totality of all. To live as a part against the whole is to live in misery. To live as a part with the whole, as the whole, in the whole, is to be in bliss.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
15 July 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means god or godliness; saguna means with qualities, with form. God can be conceived of in two ways: with qualities or without qualities, with form or without form. The centre of existence is formless but the circumference is full of form. The world is the form of god and god is the formlessness of the world.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
16 July 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, atosha means discontent. One who has divine discontent is the most fortunate, because only those who are afire with a desire to know god will be able to know him. And the fire has to be a total fire; one has to burn at the optimum. Just a little holding back and one misses.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
17 July 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means god, nirguno means unconditional, formless, attributeless, qualityless. God can be conceived of either in the form or in the formless, either as the world, the manifested, or as the seed, the unmanifested. The form arises out of no-form and falls back into the formless again. Everything comes out of nothing and goes back to nothing, so nothing is not against existence; it is the very source of it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
18 July 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means god, nimitta means instrument – an instrument of god. The right way to live is to allow god to live through you. The wrong way to live is to live through will, aggression, violence. The right way is: to be passive, receptive, in a kind of total let-go.
Nimitta means to become a passage for god, to allow him expression through you, to let him live through you.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
19 July 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
And remember that sannyas is a new birth, the beginning of something mysterious in life, something that is very elusive. There is no way to argue it, to prove it, but it is. And unless it starts having its impact on you, your life goes on missing the meaning. Once the unknown has penetrated you, life has meaning, and only then.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
2 July 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, virochan is one of the names of Gautam the Buddha. Literally it means ‘the shining one’. Love radiates, love is light. Whenever there is love in the heart, it shines like a sun inside. And it is not only that you can see the light, but anyone who is ready to receive it will be able to see it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
21 July 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Nirvana means the ultimate enlightenment, the state when the ego disappears, when man is no more separate from existence – not even a thin curtain separates him, not even a transparent glass separates him – when all separation disappears. That meeting with the total, that merger with the whole, that melting into the absolute, is called nirvana.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
22 July 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, sadhano means on the path of. It is a very pregnant word – it can mean the form, the practice, the discipline, and all the three are involved. Love is a path to be followed, to be lived. Love is a practice, an art to be imbibed, a knack to be grown.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
23 July 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, nitamo means virtue – divine virtue. There is a virtue which is nothing but a social formality, it is just social convenience. It differs from age to age, country to country – it has nothing to do with the ultimate law; it is arbitrary. It is just like the rules of the game – if you want to play the game you have to follow the rules – or like the rules of traffic: ‘Keep to the left.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
24 July 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, amito means limitless, infinity, unbounded – divine unboundedness. And that’s how existence is. All limitations are our imagination, because things are not separate; things are parts of each other. You see the tree – it seems so separate standing there alone in the field; it is not. Its roots are in the earth, it is part of the earth.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 24
25 July 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, nartaka means dancer – a divine dancer.
Dance, to me, is closest to the divine, because dance is the most existential activity. Thinking is farthest from existence. Dance is closest. And between the two is singing – singing is half- half; half thinking, half dancing. Thinking creates a barrier between you and existence; dancing dissolves that barrier.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 25
26 July 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, vidroha means rebellion – divine rebellion. Religion is rebellion, and if it is not rebellion, then it is not religion. It is never conformity, it is never convention. Christ is religious because he is a rebel. Christianity is not religion because it is nothing but conformity. Buddha is a rebel, but Buddhism is not.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 26
27 July 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, anupa means unique. And each individual is unique; they are not a repetition of anybody else. And one should not ever imitate. Learn but never imitate. Learn from the whole existence, but never try to become a carbon copy. That is the only way to reach to god. Only when you are yourself can you reach.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 27
28 July 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Krishna is one of the incarnations of god. The Hindu concept of god coming to earth is not like the Christian – not that god has only one son, not that god only comes in one form, as Christ: god comes in many forms, god comes in every age. God comes in every country, every time, because god is not yet in a state of becoming careless towards man, and will never be.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part28/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 28
29 July 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, rupena means form – the form of bliss. Each being is a form, a certain form, a certain manifestation of the ultimate reality, and the ultimate reality consists of nothing but bliss, hence the search. We are searching for our home, we are searching for our original source, our original face.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>29</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part29/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 29
30 July 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, mimanso means enquiry into truth. The full name will mean: loving enquiry into truth... and only a loving enquiry succeeds. One can enquire into truth without love; then one is doomed to fail, there is no possibility of success. Love has to be a necessary ingredient in the enquiry. Without love the enquiry remains lopsided: it remains only logic, arithmetic, science, objective.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
3 July 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin who is leaving says she loves her old mother and grown children and is reluctant to stay here a long time.]
Remember one thing always, that unless you follow your desire towards blissfulness, whatsoever you do will be wrong. If you stay there you will take revenge on those people, because it is for them that you are staying there.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>30</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part30/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 30
31 July 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A mother has brought her baby. Osho reminds her to enjoy being a mother.]
Don’t think of it as a duty. One tends to think of it as a duty sooner or later, and the day you think of it as a duty, something dies, something of immense value disappears; the relationship is broken. Think of it as a celebration.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
4 July 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva is a sanskrit root; it means divine. Hasido is a hebrew root; it means pious – divinely pious. There is a piety that can be cultivated by man, but deep down it remains an ego trip. Only on the surface is it pious. Deep down it is just the opposite. It is the ego playing a new game.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
5 July 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin wants to go home because his father is dying of a brain tumor but is still conscious.]
Then it is good – you go. And help him to die meditatively. Meditation is a bridge between life and death. It is of immense value while one is alive and it is also of immense value while one is dying.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
6 July 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, salama means peace. Bliss can have two expressions: either it can be an ecstasy, overflowing, or it can be silence, peace, stillness. If bliss flows outward it is ecstatic. If it simply remains in then it is peace, and peace is a higher state than ecstasy. Even if one has attained to ecstatic joy, one has to go one step more, because one cannot remain in ecstasy forever; it tires.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
7 July 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho explains the meaning of anand avoda.]
Anand means bliss; it is the ultimate state of nature... Misery is unnatural. That s why nobody wants to be miserable. It is alien. It is an encroachment on your nature; it is something foreign that does not belong to us. We cannot absorb it – it remains like a poison in our being.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
8 July 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, gatya means movement – divine movement. Life is a movement, and misery arises because we don’t go with the movement. Either we start clinging to the past, then we obstruct the movement; or we start planning for the future, then too we obstruct the movement. To be with the movement one needs to be without past and without future.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_look_before_you_leap/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
9 July 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin, who is leaving, says: It’s one year today since I arrived here, and I’m leaving feeling that I haven’t done enough work on myself here.]
It is never enough... and it is good that it is never enough. Growth has no end. It is not a journey with a destination – the journey itself is the destination.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
