<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Sword and the Lotus on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sword_and_the_lotus/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Sword and the Lotus on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/the_sword_and_the_lotus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 An individual revolution</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sword_and_the_lotus/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sword_and_the_lotus/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
An individual revolution
15 January 1986 am in
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
YOU INVITED ME NOT TO GET ANGRY WITH BLIND PEOPLE. I’M NOT – HOW COULD I BE? WHEN I SEE THEIR SADNESS AND THEIR MISERY, I ONLY BECOME INFINITELY SAD. THEY ARE TIRED, AND I OFFER THEM A REST. THEY ARE THIRSTY, AND I OFFER THEM A GLASS OF WATER.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 No question of I</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sword_and_the_lotus/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sword_and_the_lotus/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
No question of I
29 January 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
THE TECHNIQUE OF SELF-REMEMBERING SEEMS EASIER FOR ME THAN WITNESSING. DO THEY BOTH LEAD TO THE SAME GOAL?
They both lead to the same goal, but the technique of self-remembering is harder, longer and dangerous. Only very few people in the whole history of mankind have attained to enlightenment through the technique of self-remembering.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 Godless and yet so godly</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sword_and_the_lotus/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sword_and_the_lotus/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
Godless and yet so godly
31 January 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
KRISHNA SAID TO ARJUNA, “SURRENDER AND I PROMISE YOU MOKSHA.” JESUS ALSO SAID TO HIS DISCIPLES, “COME FOLLOW ME AND I WILL TAKE YOU TO THE KINGDOM, TO GOD.” BUT YOU SAY TO US THAT YOU CAN ONLY SHOW THE FACTS. WHY DON’T YOU PROMISE US NIRVANA?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 The golden mean</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sword_and_the_lotus/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sword_and_the_lotus/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
The golden mean
1 February 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
WHAT ARE YOU DOING AND WHY? HOW IS IT DIFFERENT FROM WHAT WE ARE DOING AND WHY?
I am not doing anything at all. I am not interested in any goal, in any plan, in any future. I am simply living moment to moment, spontaneously.
Just as the flowers are there in the garden, doing nothing, just being there, or as the stars are in the sky, doing nothing, just being there, I am here.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 Almost ready to steal the truth</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sword_and_the_lotus/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sword_and_the_lotus/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
Almost ready to steal the truth
2 February 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
IS THERE REALLY UPANISHAD HAPPENING HERE WHEN WE SIT NEAR YOU AND YOU SAY SOMETHING TO US?
The word upanishad is immensely meaningful. It means sitting by the side of the master, whether he speaks or not. The upanishad can happen in silence. It can happen through words, through gestures, just looking into each other’s eyes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 The last word in meditation</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sword_and_the_lotus/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sword_and_the_lotus/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
The last word in meditation
3 February 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
I UNDERSTAND THAT THE GAP BETWEEN THE IDEALS AND REALITY CAN BE BRIDGED BY ME ON MY OWN ONLY. ON THE OTHER HAND, I AM RECEIVING YOUR IMMENSE HELP. I CANNOT UNDERSTAND THE CONTRADICTION.
There is no contradiction at all. I have been telling you that you have to walk the way, I cannot walk on your behalf.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 A meditator is a rain cloud</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sword_and_the_lotus/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sword_and_the_lotus/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
A meditator is a rain cloud
4 February 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
THE MORE I WATCH THE DESIRES AND NEEDS OF THE MIND, THE MORE I COME TO A SPACE THAT LOOKS LIKE MADNESS. PLEASE COMMENT.
It is madness, but it is higher than what you call sanity. There are two kinds of madness. Madness simply means out of the mind.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 Life is a school</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sword_and_the_lotus/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sword_and_the_lotus/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
Life is a school
5 February 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
WHY ARE PEOPLE ALWAYS READY TO PREACH – NO MATTER TO WHOM, NO MATTER ABOUT WHAT, AND NO MATTER WHETHER ANYBODY RECEIVES IT OR NOT?
Man is very much afraid of being ignorant. The reality is that he is ignorant. Now there are only two ways to get out of it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 A device to find yourself</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sword_and_the_lotus/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sword_and_the_lotus/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
A device to find yourself
6 February 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
WHY HAVE THERE BEEN NO WOMEN ENLIGHTENED MASTERS?
Man suffers from a great inferiority complex because he cannot give birth to children. It is one of the deepest unconscious inferiorities in man. He knows the woman is superior, because in life there can be nothing higher than giving birth to life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 The art of living</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sword_and_the_lotus/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sword_and_the_lotus/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
The art of living
8 February 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
PLEASE MAKE ME UNDERSTAND WHAT IT IS TO LIVE “RIGHTLY.”
There are two ways to live, to be, to know: one is of effort, will, ego; the other is of no effort, no struggle, but being in a let-go with existence.
All the religions of the world have been teaching you the first way, to fight – fight against nature, fight against the world, fight against your own body, fight against the mind.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19 A simple thank you</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sword_and_the_lotus/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sword_and_the_lotus/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
A simple thank you
9 February 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
BUDDHA SAID, “APPA DEEPO BHAVA.” AT THE SAME TIME HIS DISCIPLES WERE SAYING, “BUDDHAM SHARANAM GACHCHHAMI.” IS THERE ANY SEQUENCE IN IT?
Once a great poet was asked by a critic, “Your poetry is beautiful, but it is full of contradictions. Do you have something to say about the contradictions?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Don\&#39;t sow wrong seeds</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sword_and_the_lotus/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sword_and_the_lotus/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
Don’t sow wrong seeds
15 January 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
SIR THOMAS MOORE’S PERFECT SOCIETY, “UTOPIA,” ORIGINATES FROM THE UNEXPLAINED PRESENCE AND INSIGHT OF A MAN NAMED UTOPIAS. WHY DO SUCH VISIONS FOR A HARMONIOUS SOCIETY AMONG MEN DERIVE FROM SUCH MYSTERIOUS INDIVIDUALS? AND WHY HAS THE IDEA OF A PERFECT SOCIETY ALWAYS FIRED MAN’S IMAGINATION YET AVERTED HIS GRASP?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 Reaction never brings freedom</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sword_and_the_lotus/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sword_and_the_lotus/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
Reaction never brings freedom
10 February 1986 am in
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
DURING THE LAST YEARS THE INDIAN SHAMANS HAVE GONE MORE AND MORE INTO PUBLIC WORK.
CAN YOU SAY SOMETHING ABOUT THIS WORK?
It is something complex to be understood, but two points will help. One is – which is a vital point – that the East has suffered tremendously from the Western invasion of the East, creating slavery.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 Something deeper than the mind</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sword_and_the_lotus/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sword_and_the_lotus/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
Something deeper than the mind
10 February 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
GOOD EVENING. ISLAM HAS OFFERED IT WITH THE KORAN, AND CHRISTIANITY WITH THE BIBLE. WHAT IS YOUR OFFER?
They have offered to you because they wanted to purchase you. It was an insult to your humanity.
The very effort to convert anybody is trespassing his spiritual territory. It is an effort to enslave you through some doctrines, logic, but basically it is not a spiritual endeavor, it is political, the politics of numbers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22 The sword and the lotus</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sword_and_the_lotus/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sword_and_the_lotus/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
The sword and the lotus
11 February 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
HOLDING YOUR HANDS AND FEELING YOUR COMPASSION I FEEL LIKE CRYING ALL THE TEARS OF MY BODY, OUT OF TOO MUCH BEAUTY. I CAN’T STAND IT; I AM SHAKING AND SHIVERING. MY INNER WOMAN STARTS COMING TO LIFE. A NEED TO PLEASE, TO EXPRESS MYSELF... MY IDEAS ABOUT THE REAL MAN LIE AT MY FEET, SHATTERED.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23 No beginning \-- no end</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sword_and_the_lotus/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sword_and_the_lotus/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
No beginning – no end
12 February 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
MANY PEOPLE, WHEN THEY TRY TO UNDERSTAND THE ORIGIN OF CREATION, ARE PUZZLED: WHY DOES THE ULTIMATE, WHICH WAS ONE, HAVE TO BE IMMEDIATELY TWO AFTER CREATION? IN OTHER WORDS, POSITIVE AND NEGATIVE, MALE AND FEMALE, AND SO ON. THE ULTIMATE IN ALL ITS POWER, EXISTENCE, FULLNESS, COULD HAVE HELPED CREATION ON A MALE-MALE BASIS, ON A FEMALE-FEMALE BASIS, OR A JOINED TOGETHER BASIS, AS A THEOSOPHIST ONCE EXPLAINED.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 The master is at the door</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sword_and_the_lotus/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sword_and_the_lotus/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 24
The master is at the door
13 February 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
IN MY HEART I FEEL FULL OF DEVOTION AND RESPECT FOR YOU. SLOWLY, SOMETHING INSIDE IS OPENING UP TOWARDS FRIENDSHIP WITH YOU. DO I HAVE TO PASS THROUGH DEVOTION TO BECOME YOUR FRIEND? I SHALL REMAIN RESPECTFUL AND PASS BOTH OF THEM TOGETHER.
They only can exist together. The friendship with a master is no ordinary friendship.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 The science of the inner soul</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sword_and_the_lotus/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sword_and_the_lotus/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
The science of the inner soul
21 January 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
ATOMIC WAR IS ON THE HORIZON, THE DEADLY DISEASE AIDS IS SPREADING FAST, AND SCIENTISTS SAY THE EARTH WILL CHANGE ITS AXIS BY THE END OF THIS CENTURY. BUT WHY ARE THE PRIESTS, POLITICIANS AND GOVERNMENTS NOT AWARE OF THESE FACTS? AND WHY ARE THEY NOT INTERESTED IN MAKING THE PUBLIC AWARE?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 The only secret there is</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sword_and_the_lotus/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sword_and_the_lotus/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
The only secret there is
22 January 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
WHAT IS THE MEANING OF SANNYAS IN THE WORLD TODAY?
The word ‘sannyas’ is one of the most significant in the human language. In the past it was given a wrong meaning. That wrong meaning destroyed its beauty, its joy, its laughter. The wrong meaning was renunciation. Renunciation of what?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Something of the sacred</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sword_and_the_lotus/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sword_and_the_lotus/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
Something of the sacred
24 January 1986 am in
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
WOULD YOU PLEASE EXPLAIN WHAT THE REAL DIFFERENCES BETWEEN MEN AND WOMEN ARE?
The psychology movement is basically male chauvinist, and strangely, it has exploited women more than men.
Most of the differences between men and women are because of thousands of years of conditioning. They are not fundamental to nature, but there are a few differences which give them unique beauty, individuality.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 All is</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sword_and_the_lotus/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sword_and_the_lotus/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
All is
25 January 1986 am in
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER, WHO ARE YOU?
I am not a messiah, nor a prophet, nor a savior. I am simply a human being, with a little difference that you are not awake and I am awake. You can call me the awakened one. I emphatically deny the role of the messiah, the prophet, the savior, for specific reasons.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 The ecology of existence</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sword_and_the_lotus/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sword_and_the_lotus/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
The ecology of existence
25 January 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
WHAT IS SHAKTIPAT, THE TRANSMISSION OF SPIRITUAL ENERGY?
The most fundamental thing to understand is that materialism is dead, that matter no longer exists. All that exists is energy.
The energy in a rock is the lowest form, the most dormant, the most closed, most asleep. Then there is the world of plants, trees.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 Truth is not far away</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sword_and_the_lotus/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sword_and_the_lotus/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
Truth is not far away
27 January 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
WHY ARE YOU SO WIDELY MISUNDERSTOOD?
It is the way of human progress. Whenever there is someone who says something against the tradition, against the establishment – political or religious – he is bound to be misunderstood. But that is not something new.
You can look as far back as possible and you will always find a few people being misunderstood.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 One boat is enough</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sword_and_the_lotus/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sword_and_the_lotus/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
One boat is enough
28 January 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
CAN A MAN START A JOURNEY IN TWO BOATS – REJOICING THE WORLD, AND CHEERING GOD?
Man has been doing that since the very beginning, and he is still doing it. He is riding in two boats, and the result is the misery, the suffering, the anguish all over the world.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
