<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Zorba The Buddha on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Zorba The Buddha on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
1 January 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[An ashram press office representative asks: Osho, what is your message to humanity on this new year’s day?]
My message is simple. My message is a new man, homo novus. The old concept of man was of either/or; materialist or spiritualist, moral or immoral, sinner or saint. It was based on division, split. It created a schizophrenic humanity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
10 January 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Deva Bhavito – god of feeling.] That is going to be your path. Get deeper and deeper into the heart. Forget your head completely. Become headless, as if the head is no more there. Function from the heart. Never do anything unless it is your feeling to do it; never do anything only because you think it is right.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
11 January 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love. Love is god – that is the meaning of [prem theo], and that is the whole meaning of religion.
The moment that religion becomes a law it is no more religion. It has fallen; it is no more part of the world of light, it has already become part of darkness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
12 January 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Prem Udgita – love song]
Love is a song, the song of the heart, the song of your very innermost core; and unless love is born one is not born. It is through love that one attains the soul. It is only through love that one starts feeling something that is beyond the body, beyond matter, beyond form beyond words; and that beyond is god.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
13 January 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho gives sannyas to a ten-year-old.]
Gitika means a small song. If life can become just a small song, that is more than enough. That is enough to satisfy all the longing of the heart, that’s enough to fulfil one’s being.
But rarely a person’s life becomes a song. People turn it into a calculation, it becomes more arithmetic than poetry.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
14 January 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[To a sannyasin couple leaving:]
Help my people there and continue to meditate. If you can make it a point to meditate every day for at least one hour you will not miss me at all. For that one hour you will be here, because meditation is my taste my atmosphere. And whenever, wherever, you meditate, you are close to me.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
15 January 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, aviram means continuity, continuum, flow. Life is a divine continuum, it has no beginning and no end. It is forever and forever; it has always been there and will always be there. Birth and death are only episodes in it; it doesn’t start with birth, it doesn’t end with death. To know it is to know god.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
16 January 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Prem Shozo – love and to rise high.]
Prem means love; and love is the way to rise high. It is the only natural psychedelic that takes you high. Love is the ladder to god. Those who try without love are always bound to fail; it is only through love and as love that one arrives.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
17 January 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand Ali... blissful god. The old god was very serious, hence the world has remained ill, sick. It is good that the old god is dead. But the new has not yet arrived, hence the crisis in all human values, hence the crisis of identity loss. The old is no more valid, in fact it has long been dead.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
18 January 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, udgam means the source. We are already at the source, we are the source. We have never left it, not even for a single moment, yet we have forgotten about it. We have fallen asleep: we have not gone anywhere. God has not been lost, only forgotten; it is a kind of forgetfulness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
19 January 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
In fact there is no meaning to any word; all meanings are arbitrary. Language itself is arbitrary. It is a human invention. We give meaning to words; words don’t have any meaning. Mm? That’s why so many languages are possible. There are three thousand languages on the whole of the earth; and sometimes the same word means one thing in one language, another thing in another language.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
2 January 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means blissful, Sarmad is the name of a Sufi master, one of the greatest Sufis of all ages. He was also killed like Jesus.
When he was being killed he said ‘I am god!’ That’s what he was saying again and again, and that was the cause of his death.
Somebody said ‘You have not learned a lesson at all.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
20 January 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Vadano means music, melody, rhythm. The whole universe is a rhythmic pulsation of energy. Everything is pulsating in a tremendous synchronicity with everything else. Just as waves are pulsating in the ocean! deep in contact with each other – no wave can exist alone, it exists only in a pattern of waves; they all exist together, they are members of each other – so this whole existence is a pulsation of trees, rocks, men, women, stars, mountains, rivers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
21 January 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin with her daughter, newly returned says she had much tension in her chest since her daughter’s illness when she had much anxiety and hatred for people and institutions... ]
Every new relationship brings up many things which are repressed. To be a mother is a beginning of a totally different world. Many things that were never available to you consciously will become available to you when you become a mother.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
22 January 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, rito means the way – the way of love. There are two ways to reach to god: one is that of love, and the other is that of awareness. They are diametrically opposite to each other, but in the end they meet. In the beginning they are as far away from each other as possible, the distance is infinite in the beginning, but as one progresses, the distance becomes less and less.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
23 January 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, hiram is Hebrew: it means most noble. Bliss is noble when it arises spontaneously, without any effort on your part, when it is a sheer gift from god. You have not begged for it, you have not desired it, you have not asked for it. When it is given out of the overflowing energy of existence and you are only a passive receiver, just an empty vessel, just like a womb, feminine – waiting with great expectancy but with no expectations, ready to wait for infinity, for eternity, but not in any way in a hurry to snatch something from existence – that’s nobility of the soul.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 24
26 January 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, sufi has many meanings. One is wisdom, sufiya; philosophy comes from the same root. Another meaning is purity; it comes from sufa. And the third meaning is simplicity. The Sufis lived such simple lives that they used only one shirt made of wool; that was all. It might be summer, it might be winter; that was all that they had.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 25
27 January 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love; persephone is Greek, it means goddess of spring – love, the goddess of spring. And it is only through love that spring comes into man’s life. Without love, life knows nothing of spring; without love, it is a long long wasteland. Weeds may grow but roses are impossible. Without love, life is a desert, and the oasis exists only in a dream.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 26
28 January 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love; sabine is a Latin word, it means an ancient Italian tribe. Your name will mean ancient love. Love is eternal, it is always. Lovers change, love continues. Love is the eternal drama of life: it takes many faces, many forms, but the essential core is the same. It is in the stars, it is in the flowers, it is in men and women, it is in animals, birds; and those who know say that it is even in a rock.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 27
29 January 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, atithi means a guest. Literally atithi means one who comes without informing, one who comes without announcing the date of his coming. That’s how it used to be in the past – there was no way of informing; the guest would suddenly come. And bliss is a sudden guest. When it comes, how it comes, why it comes – no questions can be answered.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part28/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 28
30 January 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love. Love is the only real strength; all other strengths are only pretenders. But love is a paradox too – its strength is not that of violence, that of aggression; its strength is that of receptivity, vulnerability, openness. Its strength consists in surrendering, yielding, giving way.
In the world there is a possibility of two kinds of strengths.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>29</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part29/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 29
31 January 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, the ultimate state of joy – ultimate in the sense that one cannot fall back, ultimate also in the sense that it has not anything in it which opposes it. It is not a composite experience. Ordinarily your happiness contains something of unhappiness in it, and your unhappiness also contains something of happiness in it; they are never pure.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
3 January 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, garima means glory, splendour, grandeur. Love is the only glorious phenomenon on the earth. It is only through love that we become aware of god. Those who miss love are bound to miss god, because there is no other way to become aware of the presence of the divine except through love.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
4 January 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Premdipa:] Man remains an unlit candle unless love comes and engulfs him, overpowers him. It is only the light of love that takes away the inner darkness. Without love the inner world is utterly dark; not even a ray of light is possible without love. And it is not accidental that people don’t look inwards: there is nothing to see; it is all dark, it is frighteningly dark and it is very lonely.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
5 January 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Love is the only true prayer. Prayer is not something formal, it can never be formal; if it is formal it is not prayer. Prayer cannot be taught. and if you learn a prayer you will miss the whole dimension of prayer for your whole life. That’s how people have been mis-educated.
All religious education is a mis-education, because religion cannot be taught.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
6 January 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anurago means pure love, with no desire, with no expectation, with no idea of any return. Then love is pure, then love is god. And the more you give, the more you become capable of giving: it is an inexhaustible source in your being.
Empty yourself in love, and when you have emptied yourself in love, in that space god descends in you.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
7 January 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, amal means pure. Love is love only when it is pure, when there is no other motive in it, when it is just itself, when it is not caused by anything, when it is not a means for something else but the end itself. Love is pure when it has an intrinsic value, when it serves no purpose but is a joy unto itself, when it is a simple overflowing exultation, when it is not part of the world of business – motive, profit, gain, goal – when it is so simple like a rose flower, exulting, exuberant, overflowing, for no other reason, for no reason at all.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
8 January 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, and Francis represents a few things. One: the childlike quality, and that is the most fundamental requirement for going into truth. The knowledgeable never enters; he goes round and round. Only the wondering heart can penetrate to the core of reality, only innocent eyes can see truth. The more learned one is, the less is the possibility of knowing: the more knowledge there is, the less knowing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/zorba_the_buddha/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
9 January 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Udgeya means that which has to be celebrated, that which has to be sung.
Life is a celebration, and unless one understands it as celebration one goes on missing god. To connect with the divine, the only bridge is celebration. It is only in the moments when you are utterly drunk with joy that you are close to god.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
