<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>From Bondage to Freedom on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/</link>
    <description>Recent content in From Bondage to Freedom on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 To be ordinary is the most extraordinary thing in the world</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
To be ordinary is the most extraordinary thing in the world
15 September 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
PLEASE SPEAK ON THE DIFFERENCE BETWEEN MEDIOCRITY AND ORDINARINESS.
Mediocrity is the general state of humanity as it is. It is a retardedness of intelligence. Nobody wants you to be intelligent, because the more intelligent you are, the more it is difficult to exploit you, to enslave you.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Struggling for the new man</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
Struggling for the new man
24 September 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
JUDAS SOLD JESUS FOR THIRTY SILVER COINS, AND AFTER TWO THOUSAND YEARS WE SANNYASINS ARE STILL BEHAVING THE SAME WAY WITH YOU. IS THIS THE LAST EFFORT OF THE POLITICAL MIND ON ITS DEATHBED?
Man has not evolved as far as consciousness is concerned. Thousands of years have passed; man’s stupidity remains the same.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 The dewdrop has disappeared into the ocean</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
The dewdrop has disappeared into the ocean
25 September 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
I FEEL THAT ONLY NOW I BEGIN TO SEE YOU. UNTIL NOW, YOU WERE ANOTHER PROJECTION OF THE FATHER. A REAL MASTER IS NOT EVEN A MASTER. THIS TOTAL FREEDOM SCARES ME, AND I DON’T KNOW HOW TO LIVE IT. WHAT IS A REAL DISCIPLE?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Today we claim the rainbow</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
Today we claim the rainbow
26 September 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
WHAT IS THE DIFFERENCE BETWEEN JUDAS, THE ONLY INTELLIGENT DISCIPLE OF JESUS, BETRAYING HIM, AND SIDDHA, THE VICE-CHANCELLOR OF OUR MEDITATION UNIVERSITY, AND OTHER INFLUENTIAL LEADERS AND POWERFUL PEOPLE OF THE COMMUNE, LIKE PRABODHI, DEEKSHA, SHIVA, MAKIMA, SOMENDRA, SUSHILA, DIVYA, ETCETERA GOING AGAINST YOU?
There is a great difference.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 The world needs to be one</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
The world needs to be one
27 September 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
YOU HAVE BROUGHT ZORBA THE BUDDHA TO LIFE, LOVE AND LAUGHTER, WITH LUMINOUS SILENCE. YOU HAVE ALSO SPOKEN ON THE DISTINCTION BETWEEN REBELLION AND REVOLUTION. IF ZORBA THE BUDDHA WERE IN THIS COMMUNE, HOW COULD HE HAVE RESPONDED TO THE GROWING MENACE OF SHEELA AND HER GANG?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 No master, no disciple</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
No master, no disciple
28 September 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
YOU ALWAYS SAID THAT WOMEN ARE BETTER THAN MEN AS FAR AS RULING AND GOVERNING PEOPLE IS CONCERNED. YOU SAID THAT THEY ARE BETTER THAN MEN BECAUSE THEIR STARTING POINT IS FROM THE HEART.
CONSIDERING RECENT FACTS, DO YOU STILL HAVE THIS OPINION? DO YOU STILL TRUST IN WOMEN?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 Now meditation is needed even more</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
Now meditation is needed even more
29 September 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
I SEEM TO BE BALANCED ON THE TIGHTROPE OF PO. I NEVER BELIEVE NOR DISBELIEVE WHAT YOU SAY IN THAT OUTER POLITICAL WORLD OF FACTS AND FIGURES, THAT MERRY- GO-ROUND OF DIFFERENT VIEWS, THAT SHIFTING MIRAGE OF TRUTHS, HALF-TRUTHS, CONTRADICTIONS, AND PARADOXES THAT SLIP THROUGH MY MIND LIKE AN AUTUMN BREEZE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 This existence is paradise</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
This existence is paradise
30 September 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
WHEN NONSANNYASINS THAT I KNOW ARE NOT DRAWN TO SANNYAS AND DO NOT FALL IN LOVE WITH YOU, I FIND MYSELF FEELING VERY ANGRY, HURT, AND FRUSTRATED ABOUT IT. CAN YOU PLEASE EXPLAIN THIS REACTION OF MINE?
This has been the tragedy of the whole human history. People want to convert other people to their idea, their ideology, without realizing that this is against the freedom of the individual.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 You just need a little courage</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
You just need a little courage
1 October 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
IT IS A RUMOR IN THE AIR THAT YOU ARE BEING ARRESTED TODAY OR TOMORROW. WHAT IS YOUR COMMENT?
Aha! That’s really groovy. That’s the only experience I have missed in my life. And knowing that this is my last life, I would certainly want to be arrested.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 Existential worship</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
Existential worship
2 October 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
WE HAVE DROPPED THE WORD “WORK” BECAUSE OF ITS UGLY CONNOTATIONS. PLEASE SAY SOMETHING ABOUT THE WORD “WORSHIP” AND ITS CONNOTATIONS.
Work is something that you have to do. It is imposed on you by your social circumstances, financial status, political structure. But worship is that which you love to do.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19 A mystic versus America</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
A mystic versus America
3 October 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
WHY IS THERE A MEETING PLACE CALLED RAJNEESH MANDIR? WHY NOT GIVE IT ANOTHER NAME WHEN THERE IS NO RAJNEESHISM ANYMORE?
It is true. There is no Rajneeshism anymore – but Rajneesh is still here. And this question must be from somebody who is from the outside, who does not know the commune of the sannyasins and their heart.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 The work of the serpent</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
The work of the serpent
16 September 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
I’M AMAZED TO SEE HOW MUCH FEAR AND HOW MANY WOUNDS FROM MY HEART EVAPORATED, LISTENING TO YOU TALKING ABOUT SHEELA AND HER GANG LEAVING THE COMMUNE. NOW NOBODY WILL THROW ME OUT, AWAY FROM YOU.
BELOVED MASTER, I’M SO HAPPY THAT I’M LAUGHING AND CRYING TOGETHER.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 The power of the mystic</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
The power of the mystic
4 October 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
I AM ONE OF THE STARGAZERS, IDEALISTS, NAIVE. I LEARNED FROM YOU ABOUT TRUSTING EXISTENCE TOTALLY. BUT I UNDERSTOOD TOTAL TRUST TO MEAN JUST THAT – TOTAL TRUST, TRUST UNTO DEATH. SO I HAD GREAT DIFFICULTY UNDERSTANDING WHEN MY OWN MASTER SUPPORTED PROTECTING OURSELVES WITH GUNS AND SEARCHING VISITORS, OR EVEN JUST BUYING INSURANCE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 Your work should be your joy</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
Your work should be your joy
5 October 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
HOW COME PEOPLE DO NOT SEE THIS AS A MYSTERY SCHOOL, A PLACE OF HEALING, A “RELIGIO” TO ONESELF AND TO THE WORLD ALL AROUND, THE MOST POWERFUL RELIGION THERE IS... A PLACE TO FIND YOURSELF, AND TO FIND YOURSELF LOVED BY YOURSELF AND ALL THOSE AROUND YOU?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22 This whole earth belongs to us</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
This whole earth belongs to us
6 October 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
DO I BETRAY MY REAL SELF, AND ONLY MYSELF, BY NOT LETTING GO?
In this commune, you cannot betray anybody except yourself. In the outside world the situation is different. You can betray Christianity, you can betray Jesus Christ, Moses, Mohammed. You can betray communism, Karl Marx.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23 Religion is dead, religio is born</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
Religion is dead, religio is born
7 October 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
GOD IS DEAD, RELIGION IS DEAD. THEN WHAT REMAINS?
It is an old story.
First, let me tell you the latest death. Last week in the Vatican a Minorite monk, aged fifty-five, constructed a machine for masturbation. His name was Guardiano Alfredo Germonari. Testing the machine, a short circuit happened, and the poor monk died from an electric shock.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 Learn the art of living</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 24
Learn the art of living
8 October 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
OVER THE PAST TEN YEARS I AM AGAIN AND AGAIN REMINDED OF THE WORDS OF KAHLIL GIBRAN: “MAN CANNOT REAP LOVE UNTIL AFTER SAD AND REVEALING SEPARATION AND BITTER PATIENCE AND DESPERATE HARDSHIP.”
PLEASE COMMENT.
It is true about Kahlil Gibran, but not true about love. Kahlil Gibran suffered much despair, anguish.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25 The buddhafield remains</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 25
The buddhafield remains
9 October 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
PLEASE COULD YOU TELL ME THE DIFFERENCE BETWEEN INNOCENCE AND STUPIDITY?
Innocence is the ultimate flowering of your consciousness. Even a child is not innocent; he is simply ignorant. He does not know, but he is not aware that he knows not. The child most probably will become stupid, because the society needs stupid people, the religions need stupid people, the politicians need stupid people.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26 Truth is enough unto itself</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 26
Truth is enough unto itself
10 October 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
I HAVE SPENT THREE BLISSFUL WEEKS HERE, AND NEXT WEEK I RETURN TO GERMANY. I AM NOT A SANNYASIN, BUT I HAVE AGAIN BEEN DEEPLY IMPRESSED BY THE GENUINE SPIRIT OF THIS COMMUNE AND BY YOUR DISCOURSES. IT WAS THE FIRST TIME I HAVE HEARD YOU SPEAK, AND YOUR WORDS HAVE GONE TO MY HEART AS WELL AS TO MY BRAIN.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27 Close your eyes and find me</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 27
Close your eyes and find me
11 October 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
I WORK IN EUROPE AS A JOURNALIST, AND EVERYBODY IS ASKING ME ABOUT SHEELA, “IS IT TRUE THAT SHE BETRAYED HER MASTER?” THE ONLY ANSWER I CAN GIVE IS, “I DON’T KNOW.” WHEN THEY ASK ME WHAT I FEEL ABOUT THE RECENT EVENTS, I SAY THAT I FEEL TREMENDOUSLY GRATEFUL TO SHEELA, WHATEVER SHE HAS DONE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28 You are eternal</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part28/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 28
You are eternal
12 October 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
WHEN AND HOW DO POWER AND FORCE BECOME ONE? MASTER AND DISCIPLE DO NOT COME FROM THIS SPACE AT ALL. PLEASE COMMENT.
Power and force never become one. Power is something that radiates from you. The source is within. Force is violent. Force is interference, a trespass on the freedom of others.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>29 Truth \-- not a highway but a hill track</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part29/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 29
Truth – not a highway but a hill track
13 October 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
GOD IS DEAD, RELIGION IS DEAD; THEN WHAT IS LEFT?
God has never been in the first place. It is the greatest lie that has been told to humanity. When I say God is dead, it simply means the lie is dead, the fiction is dead.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Learn from this experience</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
Learn from this experience
17 September 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
WHEN I LOOKED AROUND ME TODAY AT THE PEOPLE IN THIS COMMUNITY I SAW ONLY INNOCENCE AND LOVELINESS. BUT IF THE UGLINESS YOU SPOKE OF FLOURISHED IN THE HEART OF THIS COMMUNITY, THEN WHAT STRENGTH IS THERE IN INNOCENCE AND LOVINGNESS?
It is one of the most significant questions about life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>30 This beautiful earth</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part30/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 30
This beautiful earth
14 October 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
DOES THE CEREMONY OF OATH IN THE COURTS AROUND THE WORLD HAVE ANY SIGNIFICANCE?
It is sheer nonsense. It is carrying out an ancient superstition. It is ugly to see that even in the twentieth century’s courts we have not been able to get rid of it. In the past people believed in God; they feared hell, they were greedy for heaven.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>31 Democracy means mediocracy</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part31/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 31
Democracy means mediocracy
15 October 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
WHY DOES EVERYBODY WANT TO PROVE AND TO ASSERT? WHAT IS THE PSYCHOLOGY BEHIND PROVING AND ASSERTING ONESELF?
PLEASE EXPLAIN.
The psychology behind assertiveness, behind proving oneself, is very simple. Every child, from his very beginning, is told that he is not what he should be. Disciplines are given, commandments are given; he has to fulfill them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>32 The great accident</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part32/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part32/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 32
The great accident
16 October 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
A PRIEST SETS HIMSELF UP AS A MEDIATOR BETWEEN MAN AND GOD. THE LAWYER’S JOB IS TO MEDIATE BETWEEN MAN AND JUSTICE. AREN’T THESE PROFESSIONS ESSENTIALLY THE SAME? WHY DO WE NEED LAWYERS?
We do not need them. The priest is not needed. You are part of existence, you are already in it; there is no question of any mediation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>33 Dismantle the ego</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part33/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part33/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 33
Dismantle the ego
17 October 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
IS EMPATHY THE CURRENT THAT BRINGS ABOUT THE AWARENESS OF OUR EACH AND EVERY RELATEDNESS, AND VICE VERSA?
The experience of empathy is very rare. You know what sympathy means, you also know what apathy means; but empathy you do not know.
Sympathy and apathy are opposed to each other.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>34 The sound of truth: \&#34;Aha!\&#34;</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part34/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part34/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 34
The sound of truth: “Aha!”
18 October 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
ARE YOU ANSWERING ALL THE QUESTIONS THAT ARE BEING ASKED?
No. I must have answered more than twelve thousand questions, but they are not all the questions that are being asked.
There are questions which are merely of the head. Your head is already full of too much garbage.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>35 Existence is only in the present</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part35/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part35/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 35
Existence is only in the present
19 October 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
THIS IS MY FIFTH VISIT TO RAJNEESHPURAM. I CAME TO SEE MEMBERS OF MY FAMILY WHO LIVE HERE. I CAN SEE HOW HAPPY MY FORMER WIFE IS, LIVING SO CLOSE TO YOU. I FEEL VERY HAPPY AND AM DOING GROUPS AT THE UNIVERSITY. BUT I HAVE A BIG FEAR: WHAT IS GOING TO HAPPEN HERE WHEN YOU DECIDE TO LEAVE YOUR BODY?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>36 To each his own song</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part36/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part36/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 36
To each his own song
20 October 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
I LOVE THE DIFFERENT MEANINGS OF THE WORD “THERAPY.” ITS GREEK ROOT, THERAPEUEIN, SHOWS THE SOCRATIC APPROACH TO EDUCATING A HUMAN BEING. THERAPEUEIN MEANS: ACCOMPANYING THE OTHER, TAKING HIM SERIOUSLY, LISTENING TO HIM PATIENTLY, HELPING HIM TO UNDERSTAND, AND ABOVE ALL, BOWING DOWN IN REVERENCE TO THE OTHER PERSON’S GODLINESS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>37 Doubt is absolutely okay</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part37/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part37/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 37
Doubt is absolutely okay
21 October 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
WHAT IS REBELLION? AND WHAT IS THE DIFFERENCE BETWEEN REACTION AND THE ACTION OF THE REBELLIOUS MAN?
The first thing to be understood is the difference between rebellion and revolution.
Revolution is an organized effort to change the society forcibly, violently. But the trouble is, you cannot change the society through violence, because it is violence that is the very life current of the society.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>38 Enough just to be with me</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part38/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part38/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 38
Enough just to be with me
22 October 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
WHAT IS BEYOND PSYCHOTHERAPY? PLEASE EXPLAIN.
Beyond psychotherapy is your real being. Psychotherapy is confined to the mind – and you are not the mind. The West has always divided man into body and mind. The East, which knows more, knows that there is something beyond this duality of body-mind.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>39 Every child is born a witness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part39/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part39/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 39
Every child is born a witness
23 October 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
IS THE ORIGIN OF DANCE, LOVE AND MEDITATION IN SYNCHRONICITY? WHY HAS DANCE BEEN THROUGHOUT THE AGES THE HIGHEST ART?
PLEASE COMMENT.
Everything that is of authentic value in life has arisen out of meditation. There is no other way. Meditation is the mother of art, music, poetry, dance, sculpture.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Where do we go from here?</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
Where do we go from here?
18 September 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
FOR THE FIRST FEW DAYS AFTER SHEELA AND HER GANG ESCAPED, EVERYONE FELT GREATLY RELIEVED. NOW, AS THE HORROR STORIES UNFOLD, PEOPLE ARE REACTING BY NOT COMING TO WORK/WORSHIP, OR WORKING WITHOUT BEING THERE.
THERE IS SUSPICION, ANGER, RESENTMENT, AND MISTRUST OF THOSE WHO WERE ASSOCIATED WITH SHEELA AND WHO HAVE REMAINED.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>40 Without Zorba there is no Buddha</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part40/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part40/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 40
Without Zorba there is no Buddha
24 October 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
IS THE MEETING OF ZORBA AND THE BUDDHA REALLY POSSIBLE? IF IT IS SO, THEN WHY HAVE OTHER RELIGIOUS LEADERS NEVER THOUGHT ABOUT IT?
The first thing to be understood: I am not a religious leader. A religious leader cannot think, cannot see the way I can – for the simple reason that he has immense investment in religion; I have none.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>41 The psychology of the buddhas</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part41/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part41/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 41
The psychology of the buddhas
25 October 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
PLEASE EXPLAIN THE PSYCHOLOGY OF THE BUDDHAS.
Man can be understood as a seven-story building: three stories are underground, three stories are above ground. One story, the middle one, is half underground and half above ground. This fourth story is where we are. Sigmund Freud calls it conscious mind.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>42 Everything beautiful is absurd</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part42/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part42/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 42
Everything beautiful is absurd
26 October 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
IF YOU ARE NOT OUR LEADER, WHY DO WE GET CLEAR MESSAGES FROM THE MASTER TO DO THIS OR THAT?
I am certainly not your leader, and I never was before. The very word “leader” stinks of politics. In the world of religiousness there are no leaders, no followers, because to be led by someone is to remain blind.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>43 The blessed ones</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part43/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part43/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 43
The blessed ones
27 October 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
YOU SAID BUDDHA IS A STATE OF NO-MIND. THEN HOW CAN THERE BE ANY PSYCHOLOGY OF THE BUDDHAS?
PLEASE EXPLAIN.
There can only be a psychology of the buddhas. The man who is in the mind cannot be objective about it. It is as if a madman were doing research on madness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 The future is open</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
The future is open
19 September 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
YOU SAID BEFORE THAT MEDITATIVE PEOPLE CANNOT BE CORRUPTED BY POWER, BUT HOW COME SHEELA AND HER GANG WERE CORRUPTED BY POWER?
PLEASE SAY SOMETHING ABOUT THE ORGANIZATION OF THE MEDITATIVE PEOPLE.
Meditative people cannot be corrupted – ever. If somebody is corrupted, that only means he was not meditative.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 The meaning of responsibility</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
The meaning of responsibility
20 September 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
HOW DID WE WHO LOVE YOU LET THIS UGLINESS HAPPEN TO YOUR VISION AND TO OURSELVES? I SAW THINGS I THOUGHT WERE UGLY. I’D TELL MYSELF, “THE MASTER MUST WANT IT THIS WAY. I DON’T SEE THE WHOLE PICTURE. I DON’T WANT TO BE NEGATIVE.”
WHAT IS THE BLINDNESS IN US?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Love is not surrender</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
Love is not surrender
21 September 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
LAST MONTH I WAS FACED WITH A RECOGNITION THAT WHERE THERE IS LIGHT THERE IS ALSO A SHADOW SIDE OF DARKNESS. YET UNTIL THE LAST FEW DAYS I STILL CLUNG TO THE ILLUSION OF SOME SEPARATION BETWEEN THEM, IN PARTICULAR THAT HERE ON THE RANCH WITH YOU THERE WAS LIGHT, AND OUTSIDE THERE WAS DARKNESS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 Intelligence is a luxury</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
Intelligence is a luxury
22 September 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
IS CHRISTIANITY THE ONLY RELIGION THAT HAS CAUSED SEX PERVERSION? WHAT DO YOU SAY ABOUT HINDUISM?
Christianity is certainly one of the most perverted of all religions, but it is nothing compared with Hinduism. Hinduism is the oldest religion in the world, and it has caused in its own way many perversions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 Intelligence is a luxury</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/from_bondage_to_freedom/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
Intelligence is a luxury
23 September 1985 am in Rajneeshmandir
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
I AM SO ANGRY RIGHT NOW, AND I DON’T KNOW WHAT TO DO ABOUT IT.
IN SPITE OF WHAT YOU SAID ABOUT RESPONSIBILITY THE OTHER DAY, I CAN’T EVEN GO TO WORSHIP.
PLEASE COMMENT.
This is something basic to be understood. Your love is not love. It is full of hate, anger, jealousy, everything that goes against the qualities of love.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
