<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Sun Behind the Sun Behind the Sun on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Sun Behind the Sun Behind the Sun on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
1 January 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Sat means truth, being, existence, rahasya means mystery, mysteriousness. Truth is mysterious. It cannot be known, it is unknowable... not unknown but unknowable, because the unknown can be known some day, will be known some day, but truth can never be known. That’s its intrinsic quality. Remove one veil and you find another. Remove another and you find still more, and it goes on ad infinitum.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
10 January 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[veet artho – beyond meaning]
Truth has no meaning; all meaning is in man’s imagination, it is man’s projection. Reality simply is. There is no why and there is no way to find its why. But the mind feels very much disturbed by this meaninglessness, because it cannot exist without meaning, it lives on meaning.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
11 January 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[deva jyotsna – divine moonlight.]
The moon and its light is very symbolic. When one comes to one’s own inner light, it is not like the sun: it has no heat in it. It is like the moon, it is cool. The inner energy is not a hot energy. All heat is on the circumference; at the centre there is just coolness, pure coolness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
12 January 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
... That’s my whole teaching, celebration; not worship but celebration. When you worship, you start making a hierarchy; the lower and the higher. When you worship you put something on top of other things. When you worship, something becomes sacred and something becomes profane. When you worship you divide, you split existence. Then something is praised but in the wake of it, something is condemned too.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
13 January 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says: In the last group, leela, the leader told me that I have a lot of energy in my head and in my sexual centre, but there is no connection between the two. I have another question: I am too identified with my emotions.]
It is true: energy is there and the connection is not there.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
14 January 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says: I feel very vulnerable and my emotions keep changing. I feel happy and then it changes and I feel sad. I don’t know how I’m going to cope when I get to the West.]
When you become more sensitive, naturally you can either be made very happy by small things or you can be made very unhappy by small things; people can hurt you.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
15 January 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, guha means secret – the secret bliss. Happiness can be shared, it is always in sharing; bliss cannot be shared, it is utterly private. Happiness happens in a relationship, in love. When you are feeling in tune with somebody there is happiness. When you feel in tune with yourself there is bliss; it happens in utter aloneness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
16 January 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin mother says: I’ve had a really hard time with the children here... If I want to go to meditate, they don’t want me to go and then I feel very torn.]
Children can be very very manipulative. And one has to be very alert not to be a victim of one’s own children, because that way you don’t help them; that way you destroy their future.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
17 January 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, kadamba is a name of a tree – bliss tree. Kadamba is also very symbolic. There are two trees in India which are very symbolic. One is the bodh tree, because Buddha became enlightened under a bodh tree. So the bodh tree became a symbol for meditation.
Kadamba is the other tree which is very symbolic, because krishna used to dance under a kadamba tree.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
18 January 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[veet subpta – beyond words.]
Truth is beyond language. That which can be said is necessarily untrue. Truth is inevitably beyond words; at the most we can indicate through words, but we cannot express it. It cannot be contained in words; words are too small, and the truth is like the sky – it is infinity, unboundedness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
19 January 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, keshava is a name of krishna – it means god – god of love. But literally keshava means ‘the long-haired one’. Krishna is the first hippie! Long hair has always been a symbol of rebellion... a symbol that one wants to go back to nature. Long hair has always stood for nature, for naked nature, against the so-called culture, nurture, civilisation, society, education.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
2 January 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, devayana means the path of the gods – love, the path of the gods. It is through love that god comes; love opens the door. Love makes you vulnerable, love makes you courageous enough to die as you are so that god can be in you. It is only through love that the ultimate can penetrate you.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
20 January 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Veet means beyond, sangati means consistency – beyond consistency.
Life is a paradox, the mind requires consistency, hence the mind can never meet life. The mind is death. Life’s very existence depends on contradictions, it exists through the contradiction. The contradiction creates the challenge: day and night, man and woman, love and hate. Love cannot exist without hate; there is no possibility.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
22 January 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, bija means seed – divine seed. God exists as a seed in every being: in the being of man and the being of a rock too. Whatsoever is, is a seed of god. God is the innermost core of every being and every thing too. And the whole life process is how to help it unfold, how to help the seed to become a sprout and a tree, how to help the seed to come to its realisation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
23 January 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Ananda means bliss, ida means now. Bliss is never then; it is always now. Bliss is never there; it is always here. Bliss knows only one space: the space that is created around the here, and knows only one time: that is created around now. If you think in terms of then and there you will remain miserable; that is the way of misery.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
24 January 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, Pralaya means dissolution, uncreation, disappearance, moving back to the source and disappearing into it. Creation is coming out of the source; uncreation is going back into it. Creation is the seed becoming the tree, uncreation is the tree becoming the seed. The world is creation, nirvana is uncreation. The whole process of religion is how to disappear, how to dissolve, how not to be.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 24
25 January 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says: Help me to surrender.]
How to surrender? You need not do it; it will happen, it is happening. The question arises because it is happening. You would like to have it happen fast but that cannot be done; it comes in its own time. One has to wait and be patient.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 25
26 January 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Pashupatti – lord of the animals.
It is a name of shiva. The idea behind it is that the animal part in life has not to be rejected but to be absorbed. The animal part has not to be repressed, otherwise one loses vitality. If the animal part is condemned in any way, you become split, you become two, and then there is constant conflict within you, a constant inner war, and that war is a wastage of energies.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 26
27 January 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva maitri – a friend of god.
There is nothing more valuable than friendship; that is the purest kind of love. Love knows no other greater height. All other kinds of love have some motive in them, some desire: one gives but only to get. Friendship is the only pure love: it simply gives for the sheer joy of giving.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 27
28 January 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means blissful, nataraj means a god of dance – blissful god of dance; that will be the meaning of the whole name. And let dancing be your meditation here: dance as much as you can and get lost in dancing. The whole point is to get lost, and this is the right age to dance and to get lost.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part28/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 28
29 January 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says he will be away one year because he has to go in the army.]
Finish it, mm? And it is good in a way. Don’t take it like a burden, rather enjoy it... and it makes a lot of difference. The same thing can be a great misery if you go into it reluctantly, if you go against yourself, if you go unwillingly.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>29</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part29/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 29
30 January 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem sandurga – love context.
Man is the opportunity for love to happen, the occasion for love to happen, the context. And if love does not happen, the opportunity is lost. Then you didn’t use it rightly; you were not creative in it.
Love is the flower of human consciousness. A tree is unfulfilled if it doesn’t come to fruition and flower.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
3 January 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, bodha means awareness – divine awareness, an awareness that cannot be cultivated; it can only be received as a gift. Man cannot create it, man can only become a receptacle. There is another kind of awareness that man can create by friction, by struggle, by conflict! but that remains very ordinary, naturally, because man-created things cannot be very extraordinary.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>30</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part30/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 30
31 January 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love and veeta means that which transcends – love that transcends all – conditions, demands, expectations. It is not only that love transcends those things but finally love transcends itself too. Only then does it arrive, because unless love transcends love itself, it remains mingled with hatred. It remains poisoned with anger, possessiveness; it carries the colour of violence.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
4 January 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Gyan anala: knowledge fire]
Knowing is fire. You can use knowledge. Knowledge is something dead in your hands; you can possess it, you can control it. But you cannot possess knowing; knowing is fire, it consumes you. In the knowing the knower disappears: in knowledge the knower remains in control.
When you are in the moment of knowing, you are not.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
5 January 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[To a new sannyasin Osho says:]
This is not for the first time that you are becoming a sannyasin; many times before in many lives you have been attracted again and again and you have followed many paths... but it was never completed. You were never totally in it, so you have tried many times and you have failed many times.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
6 January 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, and anjana literally means ‘eye ointment’ – love, the eye ointment: because love gives you new vision. It cleanses your eyes of the old, makes available to you the present and the future. It transforms your eyesight. In fact, it gives you eyes, otherwise one is blind. So anjana means an ointment that can restore the sight of a blind man.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
7 January 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand Indira. It means god of bliss; anand means bliss, indira is a name of a god. And a few things about you...
There is great potential; you can explode, but you are holding it. You have great energy but it is suffering. You have been repressing and repressing; you don’t allow yourself. You have learned a very dangerous trick of control.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
8 January 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Shubha means good, virtuous; anand means blissful, happy – goodness and blissfulness. And virtue is virtue only when it brings happiness; if it brings sadness and seriousness then something has gone wrong. Then it is the worst kind of sin. And that’s what generally happens: it is very rare to find good and happy people.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_sun_behind_the_sun_behind_the_sun/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
9 January 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, gireesh means a mountain – a mountain of love. And we carry that much love in our hearts, that’s why love always remains dissatisfied. It is always hankering for something bigger; nothing seems enough, everything falls short, because we have as much love as the whole universe can contain and unless we start showering our love on the whole of existence it remains dissatisfied.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
