<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Great Zen Master Ta Hui on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Great Zen Master Ta Hui on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 Clear the mind</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌PROLOGUE
From the Blue Cliff Record of Ta Hui&#39;s teacher, Yuan Wu:
The teacher would not offer a word of explanation, but made Ta Hui express his own view. In every case Ta Hui completely comprehended the subtle meaning. The older master exclaimed, &#34;You must be someone who&#39;s come again!&#34;
Yuan Wu told Ta Hhui, &#34;It wasn&#39;t easy for you to get to this stage -- too bad that having died, you are unable to come back to life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Clinging</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌that is not so important; he is deceiving himself. And this is the case not only with Ta Hui; this is the case with ninety-nine percent of so-called religious scriptures.
I am talking about all this nonsense to make you aware that whenever you come across the same kind of nonsense again somewhere else -- beware! Don&#39;t get caught in it. Enlightened people have been respected so greatly that intellectuals have had a great jealousy, and they have tried in every way to imitate the enlightened people&#39;s statements.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 Emptying</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌whether what he is doing is right ... is it really right? Or, who knows? -- it may not be right. The moralist acts out of confusion. He depends on others who themselves may have been confused.
The last words of Gautam Buddha on the earth were, &#34;Be a light unto yourself. Don&#39;t be bothered about what others say, don&#39;t be bothered about traditions, orthodoxies, religions, moralities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Non-duality</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌awakening stops dreaming. But that is not much of a difference ... dreams are just dreams, they are not even as real as soap bubbles.
To allow such people as Ta Hui and his sutras to be holy scripture is a great misunderstanding on the part of people who have followed the path of Zen. Perhaps they have committed the same fallacy as other religions go on committing: if they see something wrong in their scriptures they ignore it, or they try to patch it up, or they try to interpret it in a way that somehow fixes it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 Nothingness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌If meditation is deep, if awareness is clear, nothing can disturb it. Then everything is ephemeral. Amrapali became one of the enlightened women among Buddha&#39;s disciples.
So the whole question is: wherever you are, become more centered, become more alert, live more consciously. There is nowhere else to go. Everything that has to happen, has to happen within you, and it is in your hands.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 Clarity</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌settle it down he agrees that both Buddha and Jesus are equal, and immediately the restlessness disappears.
Ta Hui is an intellectual. Calling Buddha a barbarian, sooner or later he must have realized that that was going too far -- and it was too ugly.
I hope that he will come back. Even if he can come back at the last moment of his death, everything else can be forgiven.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 Suchness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Truth is simple, obvious, uncomplicated. All that it needs is just a silent awareness, and a great understanding descends on you, an understanding that does not become knowledge, an understanding that deepens your innocence and that deepens the mystery of life.
Okay, Maneesha?
Yes, Osho.
15
Suchness
22 July 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
BELOVED OSHO,
SEE THE TATHAGATA EVERYWHERE
WHERE DO WE COME FROM AT BIRTH?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 Before seeking</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌The teacher thought to himself: &#34;If my name can do such miracles I must be a fool that I have never tried doing miracles myself. I could have been the greatest master in the whole of Tibet.&#34; So he said, &#34;That&#39;s very good. You have got the right secret.&#34; And he told all the disciples, &#34;This is what trust is.&#34;
And he tried to walk on water himself.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 No goal</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌potential, in your own courage, in your own ultimate possibility of a quantum leap from mind to no-mind.
This can be the criterion to judge: if somebody wants you to have faith in him, he is a fraud. And if somebody helps you to have faith in yourself, he is a friend.
A true master is a friend. He is not superior, he is not holier than thou; he is just a friend.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 No guilt</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌In this non-duality, in this meaningless splendor of existence, in this state of unconcern -- not waiting for anything, not desiring for anything -- you become so innocent, so open and so vulnerable, that the greatest experience simply arises in you. You have prepared the ground.
Enlightenment is not a goal; it is your intrinsic potentiality. When you are relaxed, the lotus flower of enlightenment opens its petals.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19 Radiance</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌become broader and broader, and bigger and more valuable. But this has not happened yet, because people are too much past-oriented and too much afraid of changing anything. The reason is that they don&#39;t have the experience about which they are talking.&#34;
I asked Bhadant Anand, &#34;Do you have the enlightenment that Gautam Buddha had? If you don&#39;t have it, then just listen to what I am saying, because I have it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Insight</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌BIRTH IS THUS -- just a happening in a dream. DEATH IS THUS -- just a happening in a dream. VERSE OR NO VERSE
WHAT IS THE FUSS?
He has entered into a realm of ultimate serenity and silence. It does not matter whether it is life or death. It does not matter whether he is following the tradition of writing a verse, or not writing it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 Affliction</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌qualified -- who cares about qualifications? I have come to an inexhaustible source, so even if unqualified people can be benefited, there is no harm. I am not losing anything.
Qualified, or unqualified, deserving or not deserving ... One thing is certain: they have come from far away, from all over the world, and all the governments are trying to prevent them. But something invisible is calling them, and the call is irresistible.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 Understanding</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌He is absolutely in agreement with my idea that nothing should be repressed, everything should be expressed. If you feel like crying, cry; there is no harm in it, it is absolutely in accord with nature. If you feel like doing anything that is arising in you with a great urge, do it, because once done you are freed from it.
If each moment we go on doing everything naturally, we don&#39;t accumulate in the storehouse of consciousness any rubbish, any crap.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22 Witnessing</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌naturally, you are right: wherever you keep your feet, they will be pointing towards God. There is no way to avoid it. Forgive me.&#34;
But the story has a metaphorical ending. The priest is so blind that he calls his men and turns Nanak&#39;s feet almost in a circle, and he is amazed that wherever he turns Nanak&#39;s feet, Kaaba also moves in the same direction.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23 So very close</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌the servants in their own direction. He is absolutely free. Neither mind nor body nor heart -- nothing can dictate to him his lifestyle. He is beyond any dictation from anybody. He is the master of his own destiny, and this is the greatest joy in existence.
Okay, Maneesha?
Yes, Osho.
23
So very close
26 July 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 The inescapable</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌And the moment you are identified with the watcher -- which is your real identity -- the mind loses all its grip on you. Mind no more stirring, you have arrived to the truth.
This small sutra is very significant. Perhaps it may be that Ta Hui spoke it when he realized -- not through his intellectual acumen but through his meditation -- the existential truth.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25 Two awakenings</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌If you can do it even without becoming enlightened, who knows? -- you may become enlightened. Just give it a try!
Okay, Maneesha?
Yes, Osho.
25
Two awakenings
27 July 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
BELOVED OSHO, TWO AWAKENINGS
IN THE OLD DAYS THE VENERABLE YEN YANG ASKED CHAO CHOU, &#34;WHAT&#39;S IT LIKE WHEN NOT BRINGING A SINGLE THING?&#34; CHOU SAID, &#34;PUT IT DOWN.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26 Wordlessness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part28/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌If you can absorb them, in the whole world&#39;s literature there is nothing more important than Zen anecdotes. In everything they are unique. They are small paintings, and just watching them, you will fall into such peace that you cannot conceive of getting from a Picasso. Seeing a Picasso, you will get such nightmares ... but watching a Zen painting, it is very simple; you will have a great peace descending on you.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27 Just being</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part29/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌without any fear, the master&#39;s fire can burn all your rubbish, and your own fire can start being the way it has to be.
Once you have known your own fire, your own light, your own flowering, life is such a contentment. Only one thing remains after that, and that is a constant gratefulness, a gratitude. I call it the only prayer. It has no words, but just a feeling towards existence of deep gratitude.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28 Mindlessness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part30/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌The man of awareness comes to understand that religiousness is needed, but religions are no more needed.
Okay, Maneesha?
Yes, Osho.
28
Mindlessness
15 August 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
BELOVED OSHO,
NOT &#34;KEEPING THE MIND STILL&#34;, BUT MINDLESSNESS
THOUGH YOU MAY NOT FULLY KNOW WHETHER THE TEACHERS OF THE VARIOUS LOCALITIES ARE WRONG OR RIGHT, IF YOUR OWN BASIS IS SOLID AND GENUINE, THE POISONS OF WRONG DOCTRINES WILL NOT BE ABLE TO HARM YOU, &#34;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>29 Faith</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part31/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌The watcher is no one.
It is just pure consciousness.
And this pure consciousness can only bring a new humanity, a new world, where people will not discriminate against each other for stupid reasons. Nations, races, religions, doctrines, ideologies -- those are just for children to play with, not for mature people. For mature people there is only one thing in existence, and that is watchfulness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Power</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌&#34;I am not bothered about my wife; I am bothered about the man she has got hold of. I cannot report it to the police office -- you can understand my problem -- but I am praying every day in the temple. Have mercy on the poor man. Save his life.&#39;&#34;
People are living in such misery. But even if they have been miserable with the wife or the husband, they will not separate.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>30 Be thorough going</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part32/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part32/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌If you look at life -- and this is the way of the seeker -- then you change every affliction into a stepping-stone, every nightmare into a situation for awakening.
&#34;FAITH CAN TRANSCEND THE NUMEROUS ROADS OF DELUSION, AND DISPLAY THE PATH OF UNEXCELLED LIBERATION.&#34;
Feeling oneness with existence ... [Banging sounds from outside are heard.] Now somebody comes with his monkey and with his drum .</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>31 Release</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part33/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part33/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Listen to Ta Hui&#39;s invitation! Become part of the great affair. On this pilgrimage from here to here, just be thoroughgoing; half-heartedness will not do. And then even in a single moment one can become enlightened -- because one is already enlightened.
You just have to gather yourself. You have fallen apart: your hand is lying here, your leg is lying there, somebody is playing football with your head.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>32 Desirelessness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part34/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part34/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌fighting or he would have become angry, saying &#34;This is absolutely absurd! I am asking a question and you are hitting me.&#34; But he took the hit in the same way as Mahakashyapa had taken the lotus flower -- with even more beauty: &#34;HOW EXTRAORDINARY! HOW WONDERFUL!&#34; -- and with great reverence, HE BOWED DOWN AND WITHDREW.
No other question ... everything is solved.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>33 Serenity</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part35/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part35/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Zen is the path of desirelessness. There is nothing to attain, there is no goal to reach. You are simply to relax, be at ease, and you will find that you have always been there, where you wanted to be. You have never left the Garden of Eden. The Christian story is wrong.
I have been talking about the Christian story from so many different angles .</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>34 Enlightenment</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part36/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part36/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Be with him!
Take the risk!
And your reward will be tremendously great. Okay, Maneesha?
Okay, Osho.
34
Enlightenment
18 August 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
BELOVED OSHO, ENLIGHTENMENT: THE KEY
SOME TAKE SITTING WORDLESSLY WITH EYES SHUT BENEATH THE BLACK MOUNTAIN, INSIDE THE GHOST CAVE, AND CONSIDER IT AS THE SCENE ON THE OTHER SIDE OF THE PRIMORDIAL BUDDHA, THE SCENE BEFORE THEIR PARENTS WERE BORN -- THEY ALSO CALL IT &#34;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>35 Discontinuity</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part37/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part37/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Lanka to Buddhism. And when the original tree was destroyed, just when India became free, a branch from Sri Lanka was brought back. It is a descendant that is now in the place where the original tree must have been.
Buddhists were killed, burned alive. Those who could, escaped out of India, and that&#39;s how China became Buddhist, Korea became Buddhist, Taiwan became Buddhist, Japan became Buddhist, Burma became Buddhist, Thailand became Buddhist.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>36 Compassion</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part38/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part38/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Anything that dies is not life; it is only the house in which life was living. The flame of life goes on eternally. Because of your securities and consolations and beliefs you remain unacquainted with the greatest treasure. You live in misery, you die in misery.
It is possible to live in immense bliss and to die dancingly, at ease with existence. Okay, Maneesha?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>37 This moment</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part39/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part39/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌As you get out of your mind you suddenly become aware of your own limitless, unbounded, oceanic consciousness. No word is capable to describe it. You can experience it, but you cannot explain it. You can have it, but you cannot say anything about it. Only your silence may give a little indication of the tremendous vastness of existence, of life, of consciousness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>38 Transformation</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part40/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part40/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌The present moment contains all the mysteries of existence. The present moment is the only temple of God.
Okay, Maneesha?
Yes, Osho.
38
Transformation
20 August 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
BELOVED OSHO,
A TALK TO THE ASSEMBLY (PART FOUR)
IF YOU WERE A MAN, A REAL CH&#39;AN MAN, WHEN YOU HEARD ME SAY, &#34;WHERE ARE THERE OLD ADEPTS APPEARING IN THE WORLD?&#34; YOU SHOULD HAVE SPIT RIGHT IN MY FACE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Trust</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌My own sympathy is not with Ta Hui. My own sympathy is with those &#34;silent illumination&#34; ch&#39;an people. They are the very salt of the earth.
Okay, Maneesha?
Yes, Osho.
4
Trust
16 July 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
BELOVED OSHO,
DO NOT GRASP ANOTHER&#39;S BOW
ACTIVELY TRY TO CLEAR OUT YOUR MIND, THEN YOU WON&#39;T GO WRONG; SINCE YOU DON&#39;T GO WRONG, CORRECT MINDFULNESS STANDS OUT ALONE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Non-attainment</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌all the TALMUDS. A little experience of your own inner being is more valuable than all the buddhas of all the ages.
Truth has to be your own.
Only then is it alive, with a beating heart. Okay, Maneesha?
Yes, Osho.
5
Non-attainment
17 July 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
BELOVED OSHO,
THERE IS NOTHING TO ATTAIN
GENTLEMEN OF AFFAIRS OFTEN TAKE THE MIND, WHICH ASSUMES THERE IS SOMETHING TO ATTAIN, TO SEEK THE DHARMA, WHEREIN THERE IS NOTHING TO ATTAIN.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Innocence</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌somebody else&#39;s pocket; the money is in the pocket -- that&#39;s all. It is not a great loss in any way.
But the people without experience who are pretending to be masters are really harming you spiritually. They are giving you words which are dead -- they mean nothing -- and they are preventing you from finding the right man. When there are so many fake people, the greater is the possibility that you will get caught by some fake person.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 The source</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌these orange clothes.&#34; And then he went out of the bungalow, and jumped from the mountains into the Ganges -- the Ganges flows just nearby, coming down from the mountains. He committed suicide.
But such is the hypocrisy of the society that the same learned people who refused to accept him as enlightened started saying that he had &#34;renounced his body&#34; -- not that he committed suicide, not that he had committed a crime.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 Delusion</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Ta Hui is absolutely wrong. I was thinking to call his teachings, &#34;Teachings of a Great Teacher.&#34; But as I am going into his sutras, I will have to change the title of the book. It will be &#34;Zen Teachings of a Pseudo Teacher -- Ta Hui.&#34;
Okay, Maneesha?
Yes, Osho.
8
Delusion
18 July 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
BELOVED OSHO, ENLIGHTENMENT AND DELUSION</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 Illusion</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌As I went on the podium he stood, touched my feet, and said to the audience, &#34;To be learned is one thing, and to know on your own experience -- face to face -- is a totally different thing. In my long life I have been in high positions, and I have come across so many learned people, and I can say with absolute confidence that learning brings no transformation to their being.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Content</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Osho
The Great Zen Master Ta Hui
Reflections on the Transformation of an Intellectual to Enlightenment Talks given from 15/07/87 am to 20/08/87 pm
English Discourse series 38 Chapters
Year published: 1987
&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prologue</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_zen_master_ta_hui/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Prologue 2
1 Clear the mind 4
2 Insight 18
3 Power 34
4 Trust 49
5 Non-attainment 63
6 Innocence 73
7 The source 86
8 Delusion 97
9 Illusion 109
10 Clinging 117
11 Emptying 132
12 Non-duality 149
13 Nothingness 165
14 Clarity 175
15 Suchness 188
16 Before seeking 197
17 No goal 210
18 No guilt 220
19 Radiance 233</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
