<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Language of Existence on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Language of Existence on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 3 - Seek nothing outside</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 3 - Seek nothing outside‌ 3 Seek nothing outside
1 September 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium OUR BELOVED MASTER,
FOLLOWERS OF THE TAO, SAID RINZAI, THIS MOUNTAIN MONK&#39;S VIEW
DOES NOT DIFFER FROM THAT OF SAKYAMUNI BUDDHA. IN ALL THE VARIETY
OF OUR DAILY ACTIVITIES, IS THERE ANYTHING LACKING? THE SPIRITUAL
LIGHT MANIFESTING THROUGH THE SIX SENSES HAS NEVER BEEN</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 3 - Seek nothing outside</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 3 - Seek nothing outside‌ Now, something serious ...
Maggie Muldoon finally decides to go to see that infamous shrink, Doctor Feelgood.
&#34;Doc,&#34; says Maggie, &#34;my husband is unbearable. He drinks three bottles of whiskey a day, smokes five packs of cigarettes, and screams at me all day and all night to &#39;do this!&#39; and &#39;do that!&#39; He pushes me around, and he can&#39;t keep a job.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 3 - Seek nothing outside</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 3 - Seek nothing outside‌ Now, Nivedano ... Boom! (Drumbeat)
(Gibberish) Nivedano ... (Drumbeat)
Be silent. Close your eyes.
Feel your body to be completely frozen. Look inwards.
This is the way to your innermost being. As your look centers,
you become slowly aware of your real nature. The real nature we have called the buddha.
In this moment you are all buddhas.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 3 - Seek nothing outside</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 3 - Seek nothing outside‌ neither are you the mind. You are simply a watcher.
Just watching, you become more and more centered.
Just watching, you come closer and closer to the universal center.
Just watching, and you have got it:
the eternity of it,
the immortality of it,
the tremendous rejoicing of it.
A man who has experienced buddha within himself, his whole life becomes a festival,</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 3 - Seek nothing outside</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 3 - Seek nothing outside‌ moment when his buddhahood became known to him, he has been watching that every action, every activity, every response is exactly that of Sakyamuni Gautam Buddha.
IN ALL THE VARIETY OF OUR DAILY ACTIVITIES, IS THEIR ANYTHING
LACKING? THE SPIRITUAL LIGHT MANIFESTING THROUGH THE SIX SENSES ...
The six senses have to be noted down. Ordinarily we talk only of five senses; the sixth is dormant.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 3 - Seek nothing outside</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 3 - Seek nothing outside‌ So I would like for you to remember that there are seven senses. The sixth, that Rinzai says is the buddha-sense, I would like to call the seventh. About the sixth Rinzai is as traditional, conventional, as everybody else. It was not his fault, it was never thought that there needs to be a sense of balance. It was only the discovery of the deeper structure of the ear that made it clear to us that we have a certain sense of balance, too.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 3 - Seek nothing outside</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 3 - Seek nothing outside‌ Perhaps Buddha is the only person in the past who has given any credit to creativeness.
Nirmanakaya means the body of creativeness. Nirman means creativeness.
If no-mind shines without any differentiating, your whole energy itself spontaneously starts creating. It does not matter what it creates; you may be a potter, or you may be a musician, or you may be a poet.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 3 - Seek nothing outside</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 3 - Seek nothing outside‌ him, and he was giving to him very generously in order to finally settle that the whole of Indore ...&#34;He may be the king but it is my property.&#34;
I asked him, &#34;What will it do to you? What peace will it bring? You are always anxious, tense, coming to the hospital, asking the psychiatrist about your troubles.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 3 - Seek nothing outside</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 3 - Seek nothing outside‌ (SARDARJI GIVES A LOUD BELLY LAUGH FROM THE BACK OF THE
HALL.) You see, Sardar Gurudayal Singh ... he will have to go and provoke him, that is the problem. Because Maitreya won&#39;t listen to anybody, he will have to be dragged out. And once in a while he comes, still knocks on doors in Lao Tzu House.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 3 - Seek nothing outside</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 3 - Seek nothing outside‌ simple. The simplest thing is that no factories should produce any drug that destroys anything in people&#39;s minds. The drug should be a nourishment and creative of an urge towards meditation. But nobody has even proposed that.
The situation is the same with all our difficulties. Those who are in power are in power only because most of the humanity is sick.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 3 - Seek nothing outside</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 3 - Seek nothing outside‌ The general came to him and asked, &#34;What is the matter, man? Why don&#39;t you do what you are told?&#34;
He said, &#34;What is the point? Finally everybody has to come here where I am standing. All this exercise ... can you tell me the point of it, where they are going? Because finally they fall in, in the line.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 3 - Seek nothing outside</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 3 - Seek nothing outside‌ drugs. And I am saying that something that has not been solved for centuries and has disturbed millions of people&#39;s lives ... It is time that somebody points out to the scientists and to the governments of the world that they are unnecessarily torturing millions of people in jails. The simple thing will be to change the composition of the drugs and make the drugs healthier.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4 - Beyond life-and-death</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 4 - Beyond life-and-death‌ 4 Beyond life-and-death
2 September 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium OUR BELOVED MASTER,
BUKKO SAID:
THE WAY OUT OF LIFE-AND-DEATH IS NOT SOME SPECIAL TECHNIQUE; THE
ESSENTIAL THING IS TO SEE THROUGH TO THE ROOT OF LIFE-AND- DEATH.
THAT ROOT IS NOT SOMETHING THAT FELL FROM HEAVEN OR SPRANG UP
FROM EARTH. IT IS AT THE CENTER OF THE FUNCTIONING OF EVERY MAN, LIVING WITH HIS LIFE, DYING WITH HIS DEATH, BECOMING A BUDDHA, MAKING A PATRIARCH.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4 - Beyond life-and-death</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 4 - Beyond life-and-death‌ Gurdjieff was alive just fifty years ago. He made a point of it that not everybody has a soul, the soul has to be earned. This was a very new idea, that you have to deserve it.
Ordinarily you are just an empty bottle; inside there is nothing. You have to earn, you have to be worthy, you have to gather your consciousness in such a crystallized way that it can pass through death without dying.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4 - Beyond life-and-death</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 4 - Beyond life-and-death‌ is fast asleep, so if you can silently go to sleep without disturbing the other fellow -- because it is against the laws of the hotel -- I can allow you. And in the early morning you will have to leave.&#34;
He said, &#34;I am absolutely willing.&#34; Feeling a great relief, he went into the room. But Mulla was Mulla -- his nature .</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4 - Beyond life-and-death</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 4 - Beyond life-and-death‌ In the same part of Africa where trees move -- sometimes miles from their place
-- another kind of tree also exists: the cannibal tree. It has big leaves and a very intoxicating fragrance so that any bird that comes close is bound to have a little desire to experience it. And the flower is so full of juice that it is irresistible.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4 - Beyond life-and-death</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 4 - Beyond life-and-death‌ what have you been doing for seventy years? Seventy years&#39; training of life ends in a single moment? No, the more accurate account is that you start dying the day you are born.
Every day you are living and dying, living and dying; both processes are together. At a certain point in the journey -- seventy years, eighty years, ninety years -- the energy that was carrying you is finished.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4 - Beyond life-and-death</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 4 - Beyond life-and-death‌ So the first thing is to find the center of your functionings. One thing is certain, that you are functioning: speaking, talking, walking, breathing. One thing is certain -- you are functioning, so we are not moving from any theoretical point.
That is the contribution of Bukko and Gurdjieff both: they always move from a real point, not a point of belief.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4 - Beyond life-and-death</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 4 - Beyond life-and-death‌ He said, &#34;If you pull the other leg he will give you a lecture on the Koran. He has been trained for both religions, so anybody can purchase him, either a Mohammedan or a Christian.&#34;
The bishop said, &#34;This is even better -- just for a change ...&#34; But the bishop said, &#34;I have an inquiry. If I pull both threads together, what will happen?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4 - Beyond life-and-death</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 4 - Beyond life-and-death‌ Issa wrote, on the death of his child:
THIS DEWDROP WORLD -- IT MAY BE A DEWDROP, AND YET ... AND YET ...
He loved his child very much -- the mother had died. He loved his small child and that child also died. On his death he wrote this small haiku ... not saying much, still it says much.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4 - Beyond life-and-death</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 4 - Beyond life-and-death‌ Then, forgetting to turn off the loudspeaker, he turns to co-pilot Cliffski.
&#34;Take over, Cliffski,&#34; says Kurtski, his voice booming through the plane. &#34;I&#39;m going for a cup of coffee, and then I&#39;m going to take that new stewardess, Gertie, and give her all my hot Polish machinery.&#34;
Gertie, the stewardess, hears this in the main cabin of the plane.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4 - Beyond life-and-death</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 4 - Beyond life-and-death‌ General Popov, the Russian officer, and Field Marshal Dogski, the Polack, are discussing courage with General Peckerhead.
&#34;Let me demonstrate real courage,&#34; barks the Russian officer. &#34;Climb up that telephone pole,&#34; he commands one of his men, &#34;and jump straight down.&#34; The soldier obeys immediately, and is carried away by the medical team.
Not to be out-done, the American general yells, &#34;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4 - Beyond life-and-death</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 4 - Beyond life-and-death‌ With this experience life becomes a fulfillment, a great benediction. Now, Nivedano ...
(Drumbeat)
Relax ... let go, just be a watcher.
The body is lying there, the mind is lying there ... You are not the mind, you are not the body,
you are just the watcher.
This watcher is another name for your roots. This watcher is the original man, the buddha.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4 - Beyond life-and-death</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 4 - Beyond life-and-death‌ With deep authority sit down as a buddha.
Slowly slowly it becomes your normal, natural heartbeat.
The rains have come to rejoice with you, and to celebrate with you.
Okay, Maneesha? Yes, Beloved Master.
Can we celebrate the ten thousand buddhas? Yes, Beloved Master.
Osho - The Language of Existence 49
Chapter 5 - The gateway of the buddhas 5</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 9 - Lovers of tao</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 9 - Lovers of tao‌ 9 Lovers of tao
7 September 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium OUR BELOVED MASTER,
RINZAI SAID:
FOLLOWERS OF THE TAO, I AM TALKING ONLY ABOUT THAT WHICH IS
DISTINCTLY SOLITARY AND BRIGHT, AND IS LISTENING TO MY EXPOUNDING
OF THE DHARMA. THIS ONE KNOWS NO OBSTRUCTIONS AND IS OMNIPRESENT
IN THE THREE WORLDS OF EXISTENCE IN THE TEN DIRECTIONS OF SPACE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 9 - Lovers of tao</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 9 - Lovers of tao‌ because of his old training. For an ordinary human being who has not been trained in philosophy it is far easier to understand Zen. Rinzai was unfortunate in the sense that he was professionally a philosopher. So what can be said in a single sentence, he goes on elaborating about, around and around; you have to find that single sentence almost in a forest of words.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 9 - Lovers of tao</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 9 - Lovers of tao‌ concepts which have no evidence of existence at all. This is the only instance in the whole of history, where the lovers of Tao simply welcomed Bodhidharma. They saw that the finger is different but the moon is the same, and to fight for fingers is absolutely idiotic. They are all pointing to the same moon.
Rinzai commits his first mistake because Tao does not allow any followers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 9 - Lovers of tao</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part28/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 9 - Lovers of tao‌ &#34;Watch me, feel me, but don&#39;t follow me.&#34; You have to find your own path alone. And that is a great beauty, that your enlightenment will be fresh and virgin, not second hand.
There are no followers of Tao, but Rinzai is a man of philosophy where there are only followers. In Tao, in Zen, in Dhamma, there are only lovers .</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 9 - Lovers of tao</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part29/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 9 - Lovers of tao‌ And as far as hungry ghosts are concerned, I cannot agree with him. There are hungry people, but hungry ghosts? There is no reason for them to be hungry, they can eat in any restaurant without paying -- and they do it. You cannot see them, so they can enter anywhere; locks and doors don&#39;t matter. This is a stupid idea he must have got from his childhood which is still hanging around -- hungry ghosts!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 9 - Lovers of tao</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part30/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 9 - Lovers of tao‌ philosophers tend to make much fuss about. Philosophy is so much garbage that it is very easy to forget whether the philosopher has found it or not.
Rinzai is counted as a great philosopher in the Japanese history of philosophy. He should not be, but his words give the impression that he is a philosopher. I want to say that he is a mystic who does not know the language of the mystics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 9 - Lovers of tao</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part31/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 9 - Lovers of tao‌ On a very low level the statement is right, but from the heights of a buddha, the ailment is as illusory as the medicine.
You are suffering from illusions. Certainly you need a cure, but the cure has to be as illusory as your suffering; otherwise it will disturb rather than help. Once your ailment is cured you don&#39;t keep the bottle of medicine with you, you throw it away.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 9 - Lovers of tao</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part32/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part32/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 9 - Lovers of tao‌ This is a strange world. When you are able to read there is no point in reading, and when you are incapable of reading you read too much and that goes on creating more confusion in your mind.
I have read Rinzai, and I have found that it is very rare to find such a confused enlightened master.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 9 - Lovers of tao</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part33/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part33/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 9 - Lovers of tao‌ Of course, inside no rain has ever fallen, but still the path is slippery. THE MOSS IS SLIPPERY,
THOUGH NO RAIN HAS FALLEN; PINES SIGH, BUT IT IS NOT THE WIND.
It is not the wind passing through the pines. It is the pines themselves which are sighing.
WHO CAN BREAK FROM THE SNARES OF THE WORLD, AND SIT WITH ME AMONG THE WHITE CLOUDS?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 9 - Lovers of tao</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part34/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part34/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 9 - Lovers of tao‌ In English restaurants, the fly is carefully removed between finger and thumb, placed on the table, and then politely ignored for the rest of the meal.
In France, the fly-finder consumes the soup, but pushes the fly to the side of the plate.
In Scotland, the fly is lifted forcibly out of the soup and squeezed over the plate, then dropped to the ground and trodden into the carpet.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 9 - Lovers of tao</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part35/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part35/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 9 - Lovers of tao‌ (Gibberish) Nivedano ... (Drumbeat)
Be silent. Close your eyes.
Feel your body to be completely frozen. Gather all your energy inwards.
Look, almost like an arrow,
searching deep for your center of being, because your center of being is also
the center of the universe.
One who knows it becomes a buddha. Deeper and deeper ...
This moment is precious.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 9 - Lovers of tao</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part36/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_language_of_existence/part36/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌Chapter 9 - Lovers of tao‌ You have all disappeared into an oceanic love, into an oceanic consciousness,
dissolving your thin boundaries.
Remember this universal experience twenty-four hours, just like an undercurrent. Remain a buddha -- walking or sitting, sleeping or waking.
Nivedano ... (Drumbeat)
Now you can come back, but come back not the same as you had gone in. Come back much more solid,</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
