<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Hsin Hsin Ming. The Book of Nothing on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hsin_hsin_ming_the_book_of_nothing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hsin Hsin Ming. The Book of Nothing on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/hsin_hsin_ming_the_book_of_nothing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 The Great Way</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hsin_hsin_ming_the_book_of_nothing/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hsin_hsin_ming_the_book_of_nothing/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
The Great Way
21 October 1974 am in Buddha Hall
THE GREAT WAY IS NOT DIFFICULT FOR THOSE WHO HAVE NO PREFERENCES.
WHEN LOVE AND HATE ARE BOTH ABSENT EVERYTHING BECOMES CLEAR AND UNDISGUISED.
MAKE THE SMALLEST DISTINCTION, HOWEVER, AND HEAVEN AND EARTH ARE SET INFINITELY APART.
IF YOU WISH TO SEE THE TRUTH THEN HOLD NO OPINION FOR OR AGAINST.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 No Yesterday, No tomorrow, No today</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hsin_hsin_ming_the_book_of_nothing/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hsin_hsin_ming_the_book_of_nothing/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 10
No Yesterday, No tomorrow, No today
30 October 1974 am in Buddha Hall
EMPTINESS HERE, EMPTINESS THERE, BUT THE INFINITE UNIVERSE STANDS ALWAYS BEFORE YOUR EYES.
INFINITELY LARGE AND INFINITELY SMALL; NO DIFFERENCE, FOR DEFINITIONS HAVE VANISHED AND NO BOUNDARIES ARE SEEN.
SO TOO WITH BEING AND NON-BEING.
DON’T WASTE TIME IN DOUBTS AND ARGUMENTS THAT HAVE NOTHING TO DO WITH THIS. ONE THING, ALL THINGS: MOVE AMONG AND INTERMINGLE, WITHOUT DISTINCTION.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 The way is perfect</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hsin_hsin_ming_the_book_of_nothing/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hsin_hsin_ming_the_book_of_nothing/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
The way is perfect
22 October 1974 am in Buddha Hall
WHEN THE DEEP MEANING OF THINGS IS NOT UNDERSTOOD THE MIND’S ESSENTIAL PEACE IS DISTURBED TO NO AVAIL.
THE WAY IS PERFECT LIKE VAST SPACE WHERE NOTHING IS LACKING AND NOTHING IS IN EXCESS.
INDEED, IT IS DUE TO OUR CHOOSING TO ACCEPT OR REJECT THAT WE DO NOT SEE THE TRUE NATURE OF THINGS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Truth cannot be sought</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hsin_hsin_ming_the_book_of_nothing/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hsin_hsin_ming_the_book_of_nothing/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
Truth cannot be sought
23 October 1974 am in Buddha Hall
TO DENY THE REALITY OF THINGS IS TO MISS THEIR REALITY; TO ASSERT THE EMPTINESS OF THINGS IS TO MISS THEIR REALITY.
THE MORE YOU TALK AND THINK ABOUT IT, THE FURTHER ASTRAY YOU WANDER FROM THE TRUTH.
STOP TALKING AND THINKING, AND THERE IS NOTHING YOU WILL NOT BE ABLE TO KNOW.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Return to the root</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hsin_hsin_ming_the_book_of_nothing/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hsin_hsin_ming_the_book_of_nothing/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
Return to the root
24 October 1974 am in Buddha Hall
TO RETURN TO THE ROOT IS TO FIND THE MEANING, BUT TO PURSUE APPEARANCES IS TO MISS THE SOURCE.
AT THE MOMENT OF INNER ENLIGHTENMENT THERE IS A GOING BEYOND APPEARANCE AND EMPTINESS.
THE CHANGES THAT APPEAR TO OCCUR IN THE EMPTY WORLD WE CALL REAL ONLY BECAUSE OF OUR IGNORANCE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 The unity of emptiness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hsin_hsin_ming_the_book_of_nothing/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hsin_hsin_ming_the_book_of_nothing/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
The unity of emptiness
25 October 1974 am in Buddha Hall
WHEN THOUGHT OBJECTS VANISH, THE THINKING SUBJECT VANISHES, AS WHEN THE MIND VANISHES, OBJECTS VANISH.
THINGS ARE OBJECTS BECAUSE OF THE SUBJECT; THE MIND IS SUCH BECAUSE OF THINGS.
UNDERSTAND THE RELATIVITY OF THESE TWO AND THE BASIC REALITY: THE UNITY OF EMPTINESS.
IN THIS EMPTINESS THE TWO ARE INDISTINGUISHABLE AND EACH CONTAINS IN ITSELF THE WHOLE WORLD.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Strive to no goals</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hsin_hsin_ming_the_book_of_nothing/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hsin_hsin_ming_the_book_of_nothing/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
Strive to no goals
26 October 1974 am in Buddha Hall
TO LIVE IN THE GREAT WAY IS NEITHER EASY NOR DIFFICULT, BUT THOSE WITH LIMITED VIEWS ARE FEARFUL AND IRRESOLUTE:
THE FASTER THEY HURRY, THE SLOWER THEY GO, AND CLINGING CANNOT BE LIMITED; EVEN TO BE ATTACHED TO THE IDEA OF ENLIGHTENMENT IS TO GO ASTRAY.
JUST LET THINGS BE IN THEIR OWN WAY AND THERE WILL BE NEITHER COMING NOR GOING.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 All dreams must cease</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hsin_hsin_ming_the_book_of_nothing/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hsin_hsin_ming_the_book_of_nothing/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
All dreams must cease
27 October 1974 am in Buddha Hall
REST AND UNREST DERIVE FROM ILLUSION; WITH ENLIGHTENMENT THERE IS NO LIKING AND DISLIKING.
ALL DUALITIES COME FROM IGNORANT INFERENCE.
THEY ARE LIKE DREAMS OR FLOWERS IN THE AIR: FOOLISH TRY TO GRASP THEM.
GAIN AND LOSS, RIGHT AND WRONG: SUCH THOUGHTS MUST FINALLY BE ABOLISHED AT ONCE.
IF THE EYE NEVER SLEEPS, ALL DREAMS WILL NATURALLY CEASE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 Life in true faith</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hsin_hsin_ming_the_book_of_nothing/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hsin_hsin_ming_the_book_of_nothing/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
Life in true faith
28 October 1974 am in Buddha Hall
CONSIDER MOVEMENT STATIONARY AND THE STATIONARY IN MOTION, AND BOTH THE STATE OF MOVEMENT AND THE STATE OF REST DISAPPEAR. WHEN SUCH DUALITIES CEASE TO EXIST ONENESS ITSELF CANNOT EXIST.
TO THIS ULTIMATE FINALITY NO LAW OR DESCRIPTION APPLIES.
FOR THE UNIFIED MIND IN ACCORD WITH THE WAY ALL SELF CENTERED STRIVING CEASES.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 Neither this nor that</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hsin_hsin_ming_the_book_of_nothing/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hsin_hsin_ming_the_book_of_nothing/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
Neither this nor that
29 October 1974 am in Buddha Hall
IN THIS WORLD OF SUCHNESS THERE IS NEITHER SELF NOR OTHER-THAN-SELF.
TO COME DIRECTLY INTO HARMONY WITH THIS REALITY JUST SIMPLY SAY WHEN DOUBTS ARISE, “NOT TWO.”
IN THIS “NOT TWO” NOTHING IS SEPARATE, NOTHING IS EXCLUDED.
NO MATTER WHEN OR WHERE, ENLIGHTENMENT MEANS ENTERING THIS TRUTH.
AND THIS TRUTH IS BEYOND EXTENSION OR DIMINUTION IN TIME OR SPACE; IN IT A SINGLE THOUGHT IS TEN THOUSAND YEARS.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
