<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>A Rose is a Rose is a Rose on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/</link>
    <description>Recent content in A Rose is a Rose is a Rose on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
28 June 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin leaving for the West says: I feel deep gratitude for all that has happened to me since I’ve been here.]
I knowMuch will be happening, much more, and gratitude prepares the way. Feel as grateful to
existence as possible – for small things, not only for great thingsjust for sheer breathing. We don’t</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
7 July 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho speaks to a sannyasin:]
Much is going to happen. Just allow it. That is the greatest thing. It is very easy to do something because one remains the doer and the ego is fulfilled. But the greatest problem arises when you have to allow something. It is simple but it becomes complex because of the ego.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
9 July 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[As Guru Poornima day was only two days away, Osho’s family, friends and relatives, came to visit and pay their respects to their son, brother, nephew, uncle, friend, colleague – and guru. Most of Osho’s immediate family – and he has nine brothers and sisters – are sannyasins, his father and mother included.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
10 July 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A french sannyasin said that he found passports and all those official kind of papers stupid and bureaucratic.]
Mm... but one lives in a stupid society. Just by throwing the paper in the river, you cannot be helped – and you cannot throw the whole society in the river. Even if they are stupid, it is not very wise to throw them in the river.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌11 July 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
There was no spoken darshan on July 11th as it was Guru Poornima Day. Chapter 13 is a description of the celebration.
&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌12 July 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says: We don’t have any children yet and I have some feeling to have a child. I’m thirty-two now and I feel ready, but I would like your advice.
Osho checks her energy.]
Just one thing. You can become a mother, but whenever you make love, always make love after meditation. Make it a point that you meditate, and only when the energy is very meditative, only then make love.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
13 July 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says: I’m going to be in a place where I’ll have lots of temptation to drugs and sex. I feel as though I’ve really developed some beautiful meditative things for myself and I feel a bit apprehensive... ]
You will have to be a little alert, because when there is nothing like meditation, there is nothing to lose.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
14 July 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prabhu means god and prakash means light – God’s light. And that’s what every human being is. So feel more and more full of light. That’s the way to come closer to the original source. Feel more and more full of light. Whenever you close your eyes, just see light streaming all over your being.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
15 July 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine and mradula means softness – divine softness. And I give this name to you for a certain purpose, so that it becomes a constant remembrance. Be soft.
The soft always overcomes the hard. The soft is alive, the hard is dead. The soft is flower-like, the hard is rock-like. The hard looks powerful but is impotent.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
16 July 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss and bhakta means devotion, a devotee. And that is going to be your path.
[Osho said that Bhakta should make it his very style of life to be loving, whether someone was present or not, for the emphasis should be not on the object of love, but on the feeling of love itself.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
17 July 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says: My mind is very stubborn. I’m leaving tomorrow and I’d like a meditation to help me with my mind.]
I think you are creating the problem. The mind disappears – but never by fighting, never by conflict. Conflict is food for the mind, so if you fight, you feed the mind.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
29 June 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine and punyatam means holy, pure, simple. You have to forget the old name and remember the new. And remember the idea behind it of purity, simplicity. A person can be pure and not simple; then purity is not worth anything. You can force purity on yourself but because you force it, it will not be simple.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
18 July 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin is meeting Osho for the first time. He was ‘sniffed out’ of an earlier darshan. He says: I love you.]
[chuckling] I know, I know. Now you will smell of me!
Shreyas... It is one of the most beautiful words in India. It means ‘the ultimate good’... and that’s the only approach towards God.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
19 July 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin asks about his relationship which is bringing up some hatred and aggression on both sides.]
Mm, it’s natural. When you allow love to come out, hate will also come out. That’s why many people repress their love – because they have been taught to repress their hate and they are both aspects of the same energy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
21 July 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
TUESDAY July 20th
[A sannyasin who is leaving says: I would like to come back. I’m not finished here.]
You are not finished. Nobody is finished here! I simply start things – I never finish them. You have to come back again and again.
It is an eternal journey. There is a beginning but there is no end – and that’s the beauty of it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
22 July 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss and sandesh means a message – a message of bliss... and you have to become one. Walking, sitting, doing something, not doing something, remain blissful. Allow bliss to happen more and more; don’t obstruct it. It is nothing to be positively achieved; only negative barriers should be removed. One needs nothing to be blissful except the readiness to surrender to it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 24
23 July 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine and satyarthi means a seeker of truth – a seeker of divine truth. It has a very specific meaning of great significance. It does not mean a seeker of truth in the sense of a philosopher. That is not the real seeking. The philosopher invents the truth; it is not a discovery.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 25
24 July 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says: I’m leaving tomorrow and I hope to come back as soon as possible.]
If you have the desire, it always happens. The desire becomes the seed. That’s why one should be aware of wrong desires because they also happen. A desire is sowing a seed; then sooner or later it sprouts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 26
25 July 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin asks :I came to say that I’m going back to Scotland. The question comes to me of whether I should make this sort of decision myself or should I come to you and ask?]
When you cannot make the decision, when it seems impossible, only then. If you can make the decision, there is no need.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 27
26 July 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love and upassana means worship. This should be your attitude – of a deep, loving worship, of a worshipful love. The attitude of worship is something which has to be felt. Ordinarily it has disappeared from the world. People have completely forgotten what worship really means.
It is an approach towards reality with a child’s heart – not calculating, not cunning, not analysing, but full of awe, of a tremendous feeling of wonder, a feeling of mystery surrounding you.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/part28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/part28/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 28
27 July 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love and vatya means whirlwind – a whirlwind of love. It is a beautiful word and it gives the sense of the wildness of love. Love is wild, and the moment one tries to domesticate it, it is destroyed. It is a whirlwind of freedom, of wildness, of spontaneity. You cannot manage it and control it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
30 June 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin, said she was unable to communicate with her sister, who is also here. She said she felt her sister had some jealousy towards her which she did not understand.]
There may be many hidden things involved. Some childhood jealousies are bound to be there. You repressed them, she repressed them, because we are taught to be nice to each other, and that is one of the most dangerous things.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
1 July 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A visitor: I’m not sure if I want to take sannyas or not because I’m not sure exactly what it means. I’m not sure whether I can surrender because it would be putting you before Christ. And I know you speak much about Christ so I really don’t know yet how I feel.]</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
2 July 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss and Rudra is one of the names of Shiva. The Hindus have a trinity of gods. Brahma is the creator god, or God’s creative function. Vishnu is one who maintains the existence, or God’s maintaining function. And Shiva or Rudra is one who destroys the world when it is no more needed; God’s destructive functioning.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
3 July 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin asks about the way in which people misunderstand what Osho is teaching, particularly in reference to sex.]
It has always been so. People live in such an unconscious state that it is almost impossible for them to understand anything. Misunderstanding comes natural to them. The mind functions as a distorting mechanism. They cannot see what is.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
4 July 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin, said he felt a lot of jealousy at the possibility of his girlfriend having sexual relations with anyone else. He said he tried to just witness the fear of her leaving him for someone else, but it still persisted.]
Nothing is wrong in the fear because that is always possible – she may go to somebody else, she may be taken by somebody else.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
5 July 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss and divyo means divine – divine bliss. And that has to be remembered. I give you the name so it becomes unconsciously an undercurrent of remembrance – that wherever there is bliss, there is the divine.
Bliss is the manifestation of the element divine. So become more blissful if you want to become more God-full.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/a_rose_is_a_rose_is_a_rose/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
6 July 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho recommended that a newcomer undertake the course of Rolfing, saying:]
When the mind is melting and changing, it is very simple to go into Rolfing, and great is the benefit because the body can change very easily with the mind. Something changes in the mind and, parallel to it, the body has to readjust, or if something changes in the body, the mind has to readjust.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
