<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Let Go! on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Let Go! on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
1 April 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, Madhyama means the middle – the divine middle. The extreme is the disease, and the mind lives through the extremes. The mind always thinks in terms of either/or, and reality is just exactly in the middle. It is never either/or; it is both/and. It is neither day nor night, neither life nor death, neither body nor soul.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
10 April 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A new sannyasin says he has been on many paths and doesn’t know if he should follow the path of will or surrender – if it would help to clarify this.]
You have not followed anything up to now. It was just a game that you were in. First pass through a few group therapies then I will decide what path you can follow.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
11 April 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, Geet means song – a song of love. Life is barren unless the song of love arises in you. Life cannot become a fulfilment unless the song of love happens. Life in itself remains meaningless. It is love that gives meaning to it. Make love as deep as possible; that very depth becomes God one day.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
12 April 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means blissful, Kali is a name of the mother goddess. The name is very significant. It comes from the root ‘kal’; kal means time, and ali means one who eats time, who destroys time. And that is the whole process of meditation: to go beyond time, to go beyond the past, the present, the future.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
13 April 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A couple with their child take sannyas. The mother asks about her relationship with the child: I get very emotionally involved around him – I find it hard to remain in my centre.]
Love is really going out of your centre. Love means getting involved, love means getting lost, love means losing yourself in the other.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
14 April 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin and her three-year-old son are present. She says her energy is divided between what she wants to do in the ashram and what her son demands. She says she is scared of some violence which is surfacing.]
Love always contains some violence. The people who say ‘Make love not war’ are right, but when you make love, war comes in.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
15 April 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Bodhi means enlightenment, awakening, awareness, intelligence, prem means love – love for enlightenment. And there is a deep search in you, very deep; you may not be even aware of it. It is not part of your conscious mind. Some rumours may be reaching to the conscious mind but it is rooted in the deep unconscious and not only in the unconscious but in what Jungians call the ‘collective unconscious’.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
16 April 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin asks if fasting would be of any valve to him.]
No need for long fasts but small fasts will be good just once in a while for not more than twenty hours, not more than twice a month. Don’t go on long fasts – that is destructive to the body – but once in a while, after two weeks, you can go on a one-day fast.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
17 April 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, Vasanto means spring – love spring. And the spring has come. That’s what sannyas is all about. In India orange is the colour of the spring. It is the colour of joy, youth, newness, love, life, celebration.
In the spring nature celebrates, but it can celebrate only in spring. It is an unconscious phenomenon.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
18 April 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Jaya means victory, dip means light – light of victory. And it is not the victory that comes from the outside, because that victory brings only darkness and nothing else. The victory that brings light comes from within. It is not conquering the other, it is conquering oneself. And I use the expression ‘conquering oneself’ very hesitatingly because in fact it is not a conquering at all: there is nobody to be conquered, there are not two persons inside.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
19 April 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, Narayana means God – love is God. And all else is just pseudo. All that goes on in the name of religion is just counterfeit... except love. Love is the real phenomenon that transforms. All else is just ritual. The ritual pacifies, consoles, but does not transmute. People need it, it is a kind of tranquilliser.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
2 April 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Samarpano. It means absolute surrender, utter let-go. The mind is always in conflict with something or other; it needs conflict to exist. It can exist only in conflict and through conflict. It is a constant war, it is violence. It either fights with others or it starts fighting with itself, but one thing is certain about it, that it cannot exist without fight.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
20 April 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Veet means beyond, Vivarta means argument. Truth is beyond argument. It cannot be proved, it cannot be disproved either. All argumentation about truth is utterly futile. Hence philosophy goes on missing the point. That’s the difference between philosophy and religion: philosophy argues, religion experiences. Through argument you go about and about, round and round in circles, but you never penetrate the core of the problem.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
21 April 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin, who is leaving, asks if Osho has anything to say to him. Osho asks him which meditation he likes best. He replies: Kundalini. Osho checks his energy.]
Kundalini can still go very deep but you have not allowed it as totally as possible. You are enjoying it but you have not been allowing it totally.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
22 April 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says his wife, who was a sannyasin, is with a master they knew before, and he feels to join her. He has many doubts which he wants to expose... ]
Nothing to be worried about. It is always good to be exposed to doubts. It strengthens you, it becomes a challenge. And if you trust because you are not exposed to doubts, that trust is not of much value.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
23 April 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho explains the meaning of Swami Samma: one who comes to effortlessness through effort, one who comes to surrender through will.]
First you will have to go deep in effort, you will have to do all that can be done, all that is humanly possible. Only when you have done all that is humanly possible will you be able to drop it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 24
24 April 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho explains the meaning of subiro: the courageous one. The inner journey needs great courage, first because you are alone there, you cannot take anybody with you. Secondly, the deeper you go inside, the more you start disappearing; it is a kind of death.]
Devaraj means: the divine king. And I declare you, this moment, a divine king as everybody else is too.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 25
25 April 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Ramen. It is a name of God. Remember it: respect yourself, love yourself, worship yourself because deep inside God is residing. We are temples of God. Only the forms are different, the shapes and sizes of the temples are different, but the deity that resides inside is the same. There is only one God.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 26
26 April 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A mother and nine-year-old daughter are present. She tells Osho she has done a Woman’s Lib type group in the West.]
I will take you out of your womanhood and manhood both! One has to go beyond both because both are imprisonment. One should not be so attached to the biology. One should start freeing oneself from biology, then from psychology and then ultimately even from spirituality.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 27
27 April 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, Arpana means surrender – divine surrender. There is a surrender which one can manage; that is a human surrender. It is surrender only for the name’s sake because the door remains the human mind and anything that is done by the human mind cannot be surrender. Deeply hidden behind, the controller is still existing and if at any moment the mind decides it wants to, the surrender will disappear, it can be taken back.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part28/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 28
28 April 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means God, Gulam means a slave – a slave of God. And that is the highest peak of freedom. When one disappears into God, one becomes a slave on the one hand and on the other one becomes God Himself. Looked at from the human standpoint it is a slavery because you don’t have a will of your own any more.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>29</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part29/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 29
29 April 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin had previously written to Osho about getting money from her parents to be financially viable while in the commune. Osho tells her to go back and play the game with them. She says sometimes she is afraid of them.]
No, I will help you. Once you understand that something is a game, it is never heavy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
3 April 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A woman, with a six-year-old child, takes sannyas. She says she is worried about her child who is very closed.]
She is a born meditator! Don’t make a problem out of it. Allow her her own space. Let it be so: if she enjoys being inside herself, allow it. Don’t force and drag her out, that will be destructive.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>30</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part30/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 30
30 April 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means God, Viramo means interval, pause, period. God is in the interval, in the pause between two words, two thoughts, two desires, two emotions, two feelings – wherever there is a pause: between sleep and waking or between waking and sleep, in the pause; between body and soul, in the interval. When love turns into hate, the pause when it is no more love, it is not yet hate.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
4 April 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin is leaving with her two children. She says: I really love you, and I feel a lot has happened here.]
And this love is such that it is going to grow every day – it knows no end. Love remains only if it goes on growing. Remember, the moment it stops, it starts dying.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
5 April 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin was leaving to start a new job but wonders if he should finish things there and return as soon as possible.]
Just finish things there and come back, because things have started moving. Now much more is on the way; it is not the time to get into anything else. You have come to the final trip so there are no other trips left!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
6 April 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Nasim means the morning breeze, just before the sunrise – that particular breeze. It is a metaphor for purity, freshness, aliveness. And a man has to be that purity, that aliveness, that early morning freshness. Only through that freshness can God be contacted. People are very very dusty: they go on gathering dust, they are dust collectors.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
7 April 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, Mudra has many meanings. The most fundamental meaning is gesture, the literal meaning is gesture. God happens in a certain gesture, in a certain state of mind, in a certain state of body when everything is in tune and all is harmonious, when there is no conflict within and no fragmentation either.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
8 April 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin, who is leaving with his wife and child, says he has been feeling negative about India and the ashram – maybe because he just recovered from hepatitis.]
It is natural: sometimes the negative comes. In fact, it is a miracle that the positive also comes sometimes, because the negative is the natural state of the mind.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/let_go/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
9 April 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, Veeno means a musical instrument – a musical instrument of love. Man’s heart is a musical instrument, it contains great music. It is asleep but it is there, waiting for the right moment to be struck, to be expressed, to be sung, to be danced. And it is through love that that moment arrives.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
