<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Cypress in the Courtyard on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_cypress_in_the_courtyard/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Cypress in the Courtyard on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/the_cypress_in_the_courtyard/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_cypress_in_the_courtyard/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_cypress_in_the_courtyard/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
29 May 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin returning to the West, said that he was feeling ‘okay’ about himself.]
Okay is not enough... feel blessed. Okay is not a very ecstatic word; it is just lukewarm. So feel blessed – and it is a question of feeling. Whatsoever you feel, you become. It is your responsibility.
If you are not feeling good, that’s how you have created it in the past.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_cypress_in_the_courtyard/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_cypress_in_the_courtyard/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
13 June 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[To a newly initiated sannyasin, who said he was a Primal therapist, Osho spoke about the difference between groups here and in the West, adding that it would be helpful for to be a participant rather than a leader for a little while]
... and the milieu here is totally different. In the West it is a therapy and the relationship is between a doctor and a patient, the healer and the healed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_cypress_in_the_courtyard/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_cypress_in_the_courtyard/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
14 June 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A newly arrived sannyasin says: So much has happened in the past few months. I just don’t understand. Everything’s changed.]
Once it starts happening, and if you don’t create any obstacle for it, it goes on happening. It is a chair. thing. You only have to take the first step and then things follow.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_cypress_in_the_courtyard/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_cypress_in_the_courtyard/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
15 June 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[To a new sannyasin who had told Osho of the various groups and therapies she had experienced in the States]
No method is for all persons – and no method can be. For each person something suits, but something else does not. Sometimes the method that suits somebody may be very destructive to somebody else.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_cypress_in_the_courtyard/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_cypress_in_the_courtyard/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
16 June 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss and Samadhan means one whose problems are all solved. So from this moment this is going to be your constant awareness: that there is no problem. And in fact there is none.
All problems are our illusions. First we create a problem and then we start seeking solutions. The first step is wrong.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_cypress_in_the_courtyard/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_cypress_in_the_courtyard/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
17 June 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin, who is returning to Italy, said that his mind had been working less and less so that now he felt he had no centre, that he was dead and had no mental life.]
Nothing to be worried about. It’s nothing to do with life and death. It is just because you have not used the mind for so many months, that’s all.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_cypress_in_the_courtyard/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_cypress_in_the_courtyard/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
18 June 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin said that he felt a confusion because whatever he tried to verbalise was never what he really meant. He said he would like some meditation that would help him clarify things.
The problem is a very common one. People have impossible notions of being happy, so whatsoever happens is never satisfactory. Whatsoever happens is just so-so because of their ideas that something extraordinary and great has to happen.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_cypress_in_the_courtyard/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_cypress_in_the_courtyard/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
19 June 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Dharma Bodhi. It means awareness of the ultimate law. Dharma means the ultimate law that holds everything together and bodhi means awareness.
The concept of dharma is very very significant and needs to be understood. Something invisible is holding everything visible. It is not a person. It is just the very energy of the cosmos.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_cypress_in_the_courtyard/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_cypress_in_the_courtyard/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
20 June 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A visitor says that before he came here he found it difficult to cry. Over the past few days he has been crying a lot.]
Mm mm, something has broken inside and you should be happy about it. Some ice has broken, some coldness has broken, some dead layer has broken. Whenever it happens, one starts crying because one again becomes a child.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_cypress_in_the_courtyard/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_cypress_in_the_courtyard/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
21 June 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin said that he was a high school counsellor and teacher of Karate...
Osho suggested he do some groups while he was here as they provided a balance, being just the opposite to Karate]
One needs to move between the polarities because then life becomes more intense. Otherwise if you remain at one pole, life becomes monotonous and richness is lost.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_cypress_in_the_courtyard/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_cypress_in_the_courtyard/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
22 June 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine and tanmaya means absorbed; absorbed in the divine. That is going to be your continuous work on yourself. Feel, wherever you are, that you are absorbed in the divine. Everything is divine. The air that surrounds you, the clouds that move in the sky, the trees, the earth, the people, the stars; everything is divine.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_cypress_in_the_courtyard/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_cypress_in_the_courtyard/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
5 June 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin said: I experienced something very strange after the Enlightenment Intensive group. I felt I was disconnected from myself – I was here and my body was down there. It was very scarey. I ate a sandwich and that made me feel better but it was a very strange feeling.]
The first time it happens it is always very, strange because you cannot figure out what it is.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_cypress_in_the_courtyard/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_cypress_in_the_courtyard/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
23 June 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says: When I look at you a reflection always comes back to me. I see myself.]
That’s right. That’s the only way to see me – if you go on seeing yourself. My whole functioning is to be a mirror to you. That’s the only way. If you know yourself, you know me.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_cypress_in_the_courtyard/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_cypress_in_the_courtyard/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
24 June 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love and vedika means the innermost shrine of the divine; love, the innermost shrine of the divine.
And love is the innermost shrine of the divine. That is going to be your path. Just be loving. Make it the very climate of your being. Whatsoever you are doing just touching something – make it a deep love.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_cypress_in_the_courtyard/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_cypress_in_the_courtyard/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
26 June 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin had written a letter about relationship with his girlfriend, who was living in London, and who wished to be married to him. He was uncertain as to what was the best thing to do as he had reservations about marriage but was in love with her.]
One thing – don’t get married.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_cypress_in_the_courtyard/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_cypress_in_the_courtyard/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 23
27 June 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva Salila.
Salila means a river and deva means divine – a divine river. And I give you this name to help you remember always that life should never be allowed to stagnate. It should always remain riverlike, flowing. Flow should be the motto. And whenever you feel that something is getting stuck, something is beginning to stagnate, then do whatsoever you can do to break it, to go beyond it, whatsoever the cost, but never surrender to stagnancy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_cypress_in_the_courtyard/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_cypress_in_the_courtyard/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
6 June 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says: I don’t want to miss while I’m here. Is there any direction or anything that you see for me ?]
The only thing that can be done is to allow, to let it happen. Positively there is nothing to be done and nothing can be done. But negatively you can do much.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_cypress_in_the_courtyard/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_cypress_in_the_courtyard/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
7 June 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says: Since I’ve been doing Zazen, I find I’ve been resisting the body wanting to move... I’ve been wondering if I should go on with allowing the movements or should resist them ?]
Both are good, so make a synthesis out of both. First for twenty minutes allow all movements. Whatsoever happens – sway, move, let the energy have its play.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_cypress_in_the_courtyard/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_cypress_in_the_courtyard/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
8 June 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss and prashantam means a very very deep silence, peace.
To be deeply peaceful is going to be your sadhana that you have to create around you. It is just a knack. Whenever you remember, just be deeply relaxed and feel peaceful as many times in the day as possible. The more you do, the better.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_cypress_in_the_courtyard/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_cypress_in_the_courtyard/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
9 June 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine and anuragi means lover – a lover of God.
And that is going to be your path. Love is going to be your path. It is easy and yet it is difficult. Easy if you can allow yourself to surrender. Difficult if the ego goes on resisting, showing defense. It is in your hands.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_cypress_in_the_courtyard/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_cypress_in_the_courtyard/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
10 June 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A visitor said that while he was very happy to be here, he was missing his girlfriend.
Osho said that it was good in a love relationship for lovers to sometimes be apart so an appetite arose to be together.]
In fact the very word ‘love’ simply means to desire. You may not be aware but the word ‘love’ comes from a sanskrit root; the word is not basically english.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_cypress_in_the_courtyard/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_cypress_in_the_courtyard/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
11 June 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
It means divine awareness. Deva means divine and bodhi means awareness. Only awareness is divine, and all awareness is divine. The moment you are not aware, you are in the world, unconscious, moving like a somnambulist in deep sleep, doing things with no awareness of why... as if you are being driven by the unconscious.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_cypress_in_the_courtyard/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_cypress_in_the_courtyard/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
12 June 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin actor said that in rehearsing for a play, one encountered many emotions which one had to deal with, so he felt he had been doing a similar sort of thing to what happens in groups.]
... but it is, in a way, totally different. In acting you falsify. It is not your emotion.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
