<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Don\&#39;t Bite My Finger, Look Where I\&#39;m Pointing on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Don\&#39;t Bite My Finger, Look Where I\&#39;m Pointing on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
1 March 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho initiates the new baby of a sannyasin.]
Deva means divine, sangam means meeting. Each child is a meeting of the sky and the earth. Each child is a miracle. Something happens that should not ordinarily happen: the meeting of matter and consciousness, the meeting of the visible and the invisible. So think of him as a miracle.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
11 March 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Maya means illusion, veet means beyond – beyond illusion. Maya in itself is not good. Maya means that which only appears but is not; it is an hallucination. The English word ‘magic’ comes from this root ‘maya’... Veet Maya – it means one who has gone beyond illusion, mm? Good, Maya!
Nirguno means the formless, the attributeless, the quality-less.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
12 March 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss or blissfulness; iti means this or thisness – this is it. Bliss is not far away, it is close by; not even close by but within you, not even within you: you are it. The mind always thinks of that; the existence is this. The mind always desires the far away, the distant, and hence it goes on missing; it becomes too obsessed with the far away.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
13 March 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, lali means redness – redness of love. Red represents life, it represents blood, it represents passion. It is not only the colour of the flowers, it is not only the colour of the rising sun; it is also the colour of rising consciousness, of blooming consciousness. It is not only the colour of blood and the blood circulation; it is the colour of life flowing, circulating, moving.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
14 March 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho gives sannyas to someone.]
Come here! Close your eyes. Just listen to the sounds, all the sounds – the flute, the dog barking – and if something starts happening in your body, any shaking, trembling, swaying, go with it. If your breathing changes, you allow it. Listen.…
Chandra means the moon. The moon represents a few things.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
15 March 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin and her young son are present. She says: It’s very difficult for me – I feel he is very strong and I don’t feel strong at all. I don’t know what to do in certain situations.]
Let him be strong! Why should you be worried about his strength? It is good. He has to be strong and the mother has to be soft.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
16 March 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Aseem means the unbounded, the infinite. Start living in the infinite, because that is our true reality. The idea that we are finite is just an idea, it does not correspond to reality; hence it creates much misery. Once you start thinking of yourself as finite you are constantly in struggle with the infinite.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
17 March 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Swanirodha. Swa means self, ego, nirodha means cessation – cessation of the self. And the only problem is the self; all other problems are by-products of it. People go on becoming too concerned about other problems. They try to solve them, but they cannot be solved because they are not the real problems... just by-products, shadows.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
18 March 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho gives someone sannyas.]
Come here! Close your eyes, and just feel me. Feel surrounded by my energy, and open all the doors, all the windows. If your breathing wants to change, allow it to, because with the change of feeling, the breathing changes, and unless the breathing changes, the feeling can’t change. So simply allow the change if any comes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
19 March 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Sindhu means the ocean. The small is beautiful, but the small is not really small; the small is big. Every atom contains the whole universe and every drop, the ocean, because only one exists – in the drop, in the ocean. Only the form is different, the content is not. Even in the smallest grass leaf, the earth and the clouds and the sun and the far-away stars, are contained.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
20 March 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin with terminal cancer and a few weeks to live is returning to the west. Osho blesses him.]
Don’t be worried... don t be worried. I am coming with you; don’t be worried at all.
You have taken it really as it should be taken. I have been very happy. Just accept everything, and something is possible through that acceptance.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
3 March 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Swatantra means freedom, sarjano means creativity. Freedom is true only if it creates. Creativity is the indication of a true freedom, and creation is true only if it comes out of freedom. Creativity without freedom is not true creativity, it is imitation, it is borrowed. It can be very skilful, it can be technically perfect, but something essential will be missing in it: the soul will be missing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
22 March 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[March 21st was Enlightenment Day when everyone could come to celebrate darshan in Osho’s silent presence.]
Madhuban means the garden. The garden is a metaphor of joy... celebration, flowering, of life, of vitality, of flow, of change. These two metaphors are very symbolic, the garden and the desert; they are polar opposites.
In the past religions have existed more like a desert.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
23 March 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[An Israeli, who is studying at a college in Poona for one year, takes sannyas.]
Use this time for meditation also. That will be far more significant than any study. Meditation is self-study. And that is the central core of one’s whole life: if one can become rooted in meditation then all else becomes a blessing, everything starts becoming as it should be.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
24 March 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Nirjara. It is one of the most important words in the Eastern search for truth. It comes from the Jaina tradition. That tradition is very much unknown in the West but is one of the most important in the East, as important as the Buddhist tradition. But it never gathered too many followers so it remained almost unknown.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
25 March 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin, who is returning to his job as a therapist in the west says: I fear really giving a lot of energy and never getting any of that love back. It’s something I realise that I really need since I’ve been hereWhat do I do?]
Go with this new understanding and try to live in the new way.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 24
26 March 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Krishna is one of the names of god. And one has to remember constantly that at the innermost core of our being god abides, lives, that we are shrines of god, that we live only because we live in god. We may not be aware of it – we are not – but life is not possible without god.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 25
27 March 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
And remember that the change of a name is not just a change of the name: it means much. It orients you towards the future instead of the past. The old name belongs to the past, it contains your whole past; it holds your whole past like a thread, running through all the events and all the memories.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 26
28 March 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
We are alone, all togetherness is just a dream, because in fact there are not two to be together: only one exists. So all relationship is illusory. There is nobody to relate to – only consciousness exists – that is the meaning of kaivalya; and to understand it is to understand all. That is the ultimate peak of understanding.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 27
29 March 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Chandrakirti is one of the greatest Buddhist philosophers. He is not only a philosopher but also a Buddha himself, part of that great chain that Buddha created, and one of the most important links in that chain. There are no traditions which have produced as many enlightened people as Buddhism. And Buddha’s disciples have bloomed in such great numbers that it has never happened before or since.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part28/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 28
30 March 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin who is leaving says: It’s like a step into the unknown, to go back. I don’t know what’s happening and I don’t know how I’m going to live anymore.]
Yes, it is... it is. You will be back soon. Once you have lived with me you cannot live anywhere else. Sooner or later every sannyasin has to come to me and be here forever.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>29</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part29/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 29
31 March 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyas couple who are part of a music centre in the west tell Osho they want to start a meditation centre. He gives them a name: Malar – It means melody, music, rhythm.]
And to be in music is to be in meditation, to become music is to be in meditation. There is a kind of music that you hear from the outside; there is also another kind of music that is heard within.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
4 March 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho gives someone sannyas:]
This will be your new name... and a new beginning, a new birth. Count yourself as being alive from this moment. Up to now you have been a caterpillar, only living in a kind of shell. That’s how everybody is living; their lives are at the minimum, and real life happens only at the maximum.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
5 March 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, satta means a teacher – a teacher of bliss. It is not that you have to teach bliss, but your whole life has to become a teaching. You should live in such a way that even if a stranger passes by he can feel your bliss. That is the real teaching of bliss.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
6 March 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin brings her five-year-old daughter to take sannyas. Osho tells her: Help her to get into dancing as much as possible; that will become her meditation, Osho then tells her. Children can enter into meditation through dance very easily, because dance is not anything unnatural, artificial; man is born with the faculty of dance.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
7 March 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Premmurti. It means image of love. Open your heart more, think less. Get down from the head to the heart, feel more. Through feeling more one gets to the being; through thinking more one gets away from the being. Thinking creates distance from yourself; feeling destroys the distance. The ultimate in thinking is schizophrenia, you become two; the distance is so much that it becomes unbridgeable.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
8 March 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
The message is to never think about yourself in any way which condemns. One has to learn to respect oneself; that is the beginning of a great change. We have been taught to condemn, to despise, to hate. We have been told to love others but we have not been told to love ourselves, so we don’t have a good image of ourselves.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
9 March 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Asango means absolute aloneness. It does not mean loneliness. Loneliness is a negative state, it is miserable. You are hankering for the other and the other is not available; you would like to be with the other but you are forced to be lonely. Loneliness is enforced, it is empty. Aloneness is positive; it is not forced.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_bite_my_finger_look_where_im_pointing/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
10 March 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Veet means beyond, ama means darkness – beyond darkness. And everybody is living in darkness. Until god has happened to you, you are in darkness, because god is the only light there is. One can be rich in darkness, one can be poor, one can be educated, one can be uneducated; one can be famous and one can be absolutely unknown, anonymous; one can be successful, one can be a failure – that doesn’t make much difference – but we all live in darkness till god happens.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
