<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Sat Chit Anand on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sat Chit Anand on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 Everybody can be a mystic</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
Everybody can be a mystic
22 November 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
IS THERE ANY DEFINITION OF THE ULTIMATE EXPERIENCE OTHER THAN SATYAM-SHIVAM- SUNDRAM – “TRUTH, GODLINESS AND BEAUTY”?
The experience of the ultimate, Maneesha, is always the same. But the expression can be different. The expression depends on the mystic; the experience does not depend on him.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Each moment is the goal</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
Each moment is the goal
26 November 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
IS NOT THE INQUIRY INTO ‘SACHCHIDANAND’ THE SAME AS BADARAYANA’S “ATHATO BRAHMA JIGYASA”?
Maneesha, Badarayana’s statement, “athato brahma jigyasa” is one of the most potential statements ever made. It means, “Now begins the inquiry into the ultimate.” It is the first statement in his BRAHMASUTRA: MAXIMS ABOUT THE ULTIMATE, one of the greatest mystic books in the world.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 Each living being sooner or later is going to become a god</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
Each living being sooner or later is going to become a god
27 November 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHY IS COMMUNICATION SO DIFFICULT, PARTICULARLY BETWEEN LOVERS?
Premda, communication as such is difficult. Of course it is more difficult between lovers. But first you have to understand the general difficulty of communication. Each mind has been conditioned by different parents, different teachers, different priests, different politicians.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 I am the ultimate</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
I am the ultimate
27 November 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
THE MOST FUNDAMENTAL UPANISHIDIC STATEMENT IS AHAM BRAHMASMI. IS IT CONNECTED IN ANY WAY TO SACHCHIDANAND?
Anando, the statement in the UPANISHADS, aham brahmasmi, is perhaps the most fundamental and the most essential experience of all the mystics of the world. The UPANISHADS are the only books which are considered not to belong to any religion, yet they are the very essence of religiousness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 Diplomacy is a contagious disease</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
Diplomacy is a contagious disease
28 November 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
AGAIN AND AGAIN, EVERYTHING I WANT TO SAY SEEMS UNSAYABLE. QUESTION AFTER QUESTION BURNS FIERCELY AND VANISHES AS QUICKLY. AND YET, THERE’S AN UNCONTROLLABLE LONGING FOR YOU TO POINT ME IN THE RIGHT DIRECTION. OTHERWISE, HOW CAN I KNOW THAT I’M NOT ALREADY ASTRAY?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 Spiritual pregnancy</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
Spiritual pregnancy
28 November 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
OFTEN THESE DAYS I FEEL AS IF I AM PREGNANT. IT IS NOT A DOWN-PULLING BURDEN. IT RATHER FEELS LIKE A WEIGHTLESS, BUT EXPANSIVE SOMETHING IN MY BELLY AND MY CHEST. IT IS A VERY STRANGE SENSATION FOR A MAN. I AM NOT SHOWING ANY SIGNS OF PREGNANCY YET – MY BELLY IS STILL FLAT AS USUAL BUT NOW I HAVE EXPOSED MYSELF, AND THERE IS NO HOLY GHOST TO BLAME AND I AM CERTAINLY NOT THE VIRGIN MARY.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 The impossible is only an idea of the mind</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
The impossible is only an idea of the mind
29 November 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHAT IS THE GENERATION GAP?
Vimal, the generation gap is a very new thing in the world. Just half a century ago, nobody had ever even heard the term ‘generation gap’. And man has been here for thousands of years. But no society, no culture, no civilization was bothered with the generation gap.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 God is your concentrated fear</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
God is your concentrated fear
29 November 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHEN I WAS COMING FOR DISCOURSE, MY HEART WAS TREMBLING WITH FEAR; I FELT AS IF I WAS GOING TO DIE. DEATH SEEMED TO BE VERY CLOSE.
LATER IN THE DISCOURSE, I FELT AN INFINITE JOY FROM SOME UNKNOWN SOURCE. ARE THESE JUST TWO COLORS OF LOVE FOR YOU, OR IS IT SOMETHING ELSE?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 Politicians are great criminals</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
Politicians are great criminals
30 November 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
IS THERE ANY DIFFERENCE BETWEEN THE CRIMINALS AND THE POLITICIANS?
Amrito, the criminal is poor; he is uneducated, unsophisticated and simple-hearted. The politician is a hypocrite – cunning, diplomatic, sophisticated. But their essential reality is the same. In other words, the criminal is a politician who could not succeed, and the politician is a criminal who has succeeded in attaining power.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 The only riches are of the heart</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
The only riches are of the heart
30 November 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
YOU ARE RUNNING WITHIN ME LIKE SILENT WATER, MERGING ME SLOWLY INTO AN INNER SMILE!
THANK YOU FOR BEING WITH US!
Satyadeva, the path of a seeker is full of beautiful spaces, and is also full of desert-like moments. It is full of joy, just as you see in the morning when the sun is rising and the birds start singing and the flowers smile all over the earth.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19 Whenever you close your umbrella you have glimpses</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
Whenever you close your umbrella you have glimpses
1 December 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
IS THERE ANY DIFFERENCE BETWEEN THE STATE OF NO-MIND AND BEING PRESENT?
Shunyam Kaveen, it is an intellectual question, nothing to do with your experience; because if you have experienced even a glimpse of no-mind, all questions including this will simply disappear.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Gratitude is the only prayer</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
Gratitude is the only prayer
22 November 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
CAN ONE REALLY MISS YOU? WHEN LOVE AND THIS INCREDIBLE PULL ARE THERE, CAN ONE REALLY GO ASTRAY?
Prem Anugraho, it seems almost impossible to miss the goal when you are just one foot away, but people have missed even then. How far away was Judas from Jesus?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 Response ability</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
Response ability
1 December 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
THANK YOU FOR LETTING US TASTE FROM YOUR OCEAN OF CONSCIOUSNESS. BOTH KRISHNAMURTI AND GURDJIEFF WERE TALKING ABOUT THEIR WAVES OF CONSCIOUSNESS.
BELOVED MASTER, ARE THEY THE WAVES OF YOUR OCEAN?
Shridhar, J. Krishnamurti and George Gurdjieff are not just two waves in the ocean of consciousness. They are the very ocean of consciousness itself.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 Seriousness is a sickness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
Seriousness is a sickness
2 December 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
IS THERE LAUGHTER IN THE MYSTERIOUS SILENCE OF SACHCHIDANAND? THERE MUST BE, BECAUSE YOU ARE SUCH A LAUGHTER; OR IS YOUR LAUGHTER JUST FOR US?
Devageet, the cosmos is full of laughter, but a laughter that is very silent, a laughter that you can feel but cannot hear, a laughter that spreads all over your being.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22 Mind is a con man</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
Mind is a con man
2 December 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
DURING THE AWARENESS WALK IN THE VIPASSANA GROUP TODAY, I OBSERVED THAT MY SPEED WAS SLOWING DOWN AND HAD STOPPED. THERE SEEMED TO BE NO NEED FOR MOVING. TO WHERE, FOR WHAT? THERE WAS SIMPLY NO GOAL ANYMORE.
OSHO, WOULD YOU TALK ABOUT THE SECRET OF BEING IN A BODY AND WHAT KEEPS IT MOVING?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23 The great love affair with the universe</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
The great love affair with the universe
3 December 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I LOVE TO CRY AND TO FEEL THIS SWEET PAIN OF LONGING IN MY HEART THAT HAS BEEN VISITING ME FOR A WHILE. IT SEEMS TO BE A TREASURE THAT IS BRINGING ME BACK AFTER HAVING BEEN LOST IN THE MIND. I HAVE EXPERIENCED A STILLNESS BEYOND THIS PAIN AND TEARS; YET, SOMETIMES IT FEELS AS IF I WOULD LOVE TO CRY MY WAY TO GOD.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 The energy field of the master is a womb</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 24
The energy field of the master is a womb
3 December 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
THE OTHER DAY IN DISCOURSE, YOUR BEING, YOUR BEAUTY, STRUCK ME LIKE A HUGE WAVE. I WAS AGAIN A CHILD, LOOKING WITH BIG EYES. IT WAS LIKE A WINDOW OPENING TO SOMETHING UNKNOWN, YET KNOWN.
BELOVED MASTER, WOULD YOU LIKE TO SPEAK ON THIS EXPERIENCE?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25 Nobody is planning except man</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 25
Nobody is planning except man
4 December 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I ALWAYS HEAR YOU SAYING NICE THINGS ABOUT THE WOMEN. COULD YOU NOT STICK UP FOR THE MEN ONCE IN A WHILE?
Anand Heeren, it is a very difficult question. I could not sleep the whole night. I tried and tried hard to find something nice about men, but I have to admit to you there is nothing that can be said.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26 Nobody is a German</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 26
Nobody is a German
4 December 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
ENJOYING LIFE SEEMS TO BE THE ONLY THING I DO, AND I FORGET THAT I AM A SEEKER. BUT WHEN I THINK ABOUT IT, A QUESTION ARISES: WHAT AM I SEEKING FOR?
Deva Charu, enjoying life is in itself a beautiful experience, but it is not enough.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27 Crossianity</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 27
Crossianity
5 December 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
YOUR INNER BEAUTY I CAN ONLY FEEL AS FAR AS I HAVE DISCOVERED MYSELF. BUT FOR TEN YEARS, WHENEVER I SEE YOU ENTERING THE AUDITORIUM, THERE IS THIS SURPRISE ABOUT YOUR UNBELIEVABLE OUTER BEAUTY TOO.
OSHO, IS THE OUTER APPEARANCE ALWAYS JUST A REFLECTION OF THE INNER?
Pragito, the outer beauty comes from a different source than the inner.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28 Existence needs you</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part28/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 28
Existence needs you
5 December 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHAT IS THE TRANSCENDENTAL?
Deva Paro, the moment you start witnessing yourself, you will see three layers of existence within you. One is the outermost; anybody can observe it; it is objective; it is material; it is your body.
The second layer behind it is your mind, your thoughts, your dreams, your expectations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>29 The master is death</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part29/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 29
The master is death
6 December 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
IF, IN A STILL AND CALM AND SILENT MOMENT, I WHISPER, “KILL ME NOW,” WILL YOU DO IT?
Anand Rakesh, I have every intention to kill you, because without killing you you can’t have a new life. You will go on living the old, rotten personality, which keeps you company and gives you a certain consolation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 We are the pilgrims of the unknowable</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
We are the pilgrims of the unknowable
23 November 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
SITTING IN FRONT OF YOU, I FEEL SOMETHING TREMENDOUS IS HAPPENING TO ME, WHICH I DON’T UNDERSTAND AT ALL. I FEEL SO THANKFUL, BUT I DON’T KNOW WHY AND FOR WHAT. TEARS ARE COMING, BUT I CANNOT SEE ANY REASON. I LEAVE DISCOURSE WITH UNSTEADY KNEES, AS IF I HAD DONE TWENTY-FOUR HOURS’ HARD WORK.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>30 Be Adam and Eve</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part30/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 30
Be Adam and Eve
6 December 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHAT IS THE RESPONSIBILITY OF LOVE?
Gyan Raga, the mind creates questions. They may look very relevant and rational, but they are against experience, against existence. And because the whole world is communicating with each other only through the mind, nobody raises his voice against such questions, that they are basically wrong.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 You can be showered by flowers of bliss</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
You can be showered by flowers of bliss
23 November 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHEN I LOOK AT MY LIFE, IT IS RICHER AND MORE FULFILLED THAN I COULD HAVE EVER EXPECTED. I AM FILLED WITH GRATITUDE THROUGH ALL THE LOVE, UNDERSTANDING AND SHEER JOY THAT BEING WITH YOU HAS BROUGHT ME. WHY THEN, BELOVED OSHO, DO I THINK OF DEATH SO LONGINGLY?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Existence must be laughing at man</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
Existence must be laughing at man
24 November 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
FINALLY I HAVE COME HOME TO MYSELF WITH A SILENCE AND SERENITY NEVER KNOWN BEFORE. I FEEL LIKE A FLOWER BUD READY TO OPEN, YET I DO NOT FEEL IN TOUCH WITH THE ENERGY OF LOVE AND JOY THAT WOULD ALLOW THIS FLOWER TO BLOOM.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 I have found my people</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
I have found my people
24 November 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
SITTING WITH YOU IN DISCOURSE A FEELING OF MAGNIFICENCE AND UTTER LUXURIOUSNESS, WHICH FEELS SO DIFFERENT FROM MATERIAL LUXURY, KEEPS ON ARISING IN ME.
MOST PRECIOUS MASTER, WOULD YOU LIKE TO TALK ABOUT THE LUXURIOUSNESS OF BEING WITH A LIVING MASTER?
Sadhan, there are two worlds side by side: the world of matter and the world of consciousness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 A bird with two wings</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
A bird with two wings
25 November 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
SAT-CHIT-ANAND ... MEANING OR NO MEANING, JUST THE SOUND OF IT TOUCHES MY HEART DEEPLY.
Vimal, sat-chit-anand is included in those few words of all the languages of the world which have descended from the highest peak of consciousness. They are pure music, they are absolute poetry, they are no ordinary words.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 You\&#39;re not plugged in</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
You’re not plugged in
25 November 1987 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHAT IS MISUNDERSTANDING?
Devageet, misunderstanding is obviously the mother superior of mistakes. Man lives almost half awake, half asleep. Hence whatever he understands is only half. With each of his understandings there is a shadow, a deep unconsciousness which continues to misinterpret, to distort, to confuse whatever small light, whatever small consciousness he has got.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 Skies beyond skies</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/sat_chit_anand/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
Skies beyond skies
26 November 1987 am in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
THE BEAUTIFUL STATEMENT SAT-CHIT-ANAND HAS TRUTH FIRST, CONSCIOUSNESS SECOND AND BLISS THIRD. IS THERE SOME INEVITABLE SEQUENCE AMONGST THEM?
Amrito, there is no sequence amongst truth, consciousness and bliss. They are not steps of a hierarchy, but they come one after another. Neither of them is higher than the other two, so in the way we understand it, sequence is not there.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
