<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Won\&#39;t You Join the Dance on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Won\&#39;t You Join the Dance on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
1 February 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, christopher means Christ-bearer. The story is that Saint Christopher bore the Christ child across the river. But it can become a tremendously significant metaphor for the inner journey. The meaning that I would like to give it is that each person, man or woman, is a Christbearer in the sense that everybody is pregnant with Christ, that we are carrying the child in our womb.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
10 February 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Veet means beyond, sandeh means doubt.
To go beyond doubt is the most fundamental step towards god. Doubt is a tremendously important method of enquiry into matter, but not into consciousness. It is utterly valid as far as matter is concerned, and utterly invalid as far as consciousness is concerned.
If you use trust in science, there will be no science at all.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
11 February 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss. Lotte is Teutonic; it means human being – a blissful human being.
Man is not man just because of his physical shape and form. It has to be earned; one has to become human. Man is born only as a potentiality to be man; it is not already the fact, it is still to happen.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
12 February 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, anupam means uniqueness. It is a paradox – but existence itself is a paradox – that each individual is both universal and unique. It is very illogical, because if we are all one, then how can we all be unique? – we will be similar. But that is not the case.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
13 February 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss; mario can have two meanings, because it can either be derived from Latin or from Hebrew. In Latin it means god of Mars or god of war; in Hebrew it means rebellion. Choose the Hebrew meaning – god of war is ugly. If one wants to be a god, one should be a god of peace.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
14 February 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem Satish – god of love and truth.
These are the two most significant things in life. Truth has to be realised and love has to be lived. Truth happens in the innermost core; love is the flow outwards of the same energy. When you are full of truth, you can’t help being loving; love starts overflowing, but the energy is that of truth.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
15 February 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine; petra is Greek, it means rock– divine rock. The temple of life has to be built on the rock of god. People build their houses either in the air or at the most on the sands. If one makes one’s houses in the air, one is simply wasting time, energy, life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
16 February 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, carina has two meanings; one is a star, a star of the constellation Orion–a love star.
Love is always a possibility, always a potential, and the potential is such that it cannot be actualised absolutely; it is inexhaustible. So it is always a far-away distant star; you are always arriving closer and closer, but you can never say ‘I have arrived.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
17 February 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss; giglio is from Latin, it means a lily flower. A blissful flower – that’s what man has to become. All the potential is there; it only has to be challenged, it only has to be remembered. It is a forgotten treasure. We have not lost it, it is still with us.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
18 February 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Antar is Sanskrit it means the inner, and Victoria is Latin; it means the victorious. The full name will mean: the inner victory, the victory over the inner. To win the other is not difficult it is not really a great challenge. The real challenge arises from the inner: how to win oneself, how to be a master of one’s own being.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
19 February 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love; ida is Teutonic, it means happy– happy love. Love can be born either out of blissfulness or out of misery. When love is out of misery it creates more misery; it takes you deeper and deeper into hell. When love is out of blissfulness it gives you wings; you start soaring high.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
2 February 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss; sue is Hebrew, it means white lily. The full name will mean a blissful white lily. The lily is a strange flower, the poorest and the richest at the same time. Hence Jesus’ statement to his disciples: Look at the lilies – even Solomon was not so beautiful, attired in all his grandeur, as these poor flowers are.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
20 February 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, Odin means god of poetry – god of love and poetry. Good, Odin. Keep it with you.
Anand means bliss, viresha means courageous. Bliss is only for those who are courageous. It needs tremendous courage to drop misery because we have invested in misery for so long. Our ego subsists on misery, our whole life is rooted and based in misery, so to drop it means to die as you have known yourself To drop it means to destroy the identity that you have always thought you are.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
21 February 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love; almiro is Arabic, it means exalted. Love is the most exalted state of being. It is just next to God: one step more and God is reached. Love is the last thing; beyond that is the infinite, the eternal. Love is our boundary; if we remain on this side, we remain in the world.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
22 February 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Anand Yuri – farmer of bliss.]
Gautam the Buddha used to say again and again: I am the farmer, I sow the seeds of bliss. There is a way of inner farming, of creating a garden of the inner. Many never become aware of it; they are the unfortunate ones. Otherwise it is just so close – just a one-hundred-and-eighty-degree turn and it is in front of you.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
23 February 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love; roger is Teutonic, it means spear. Love is like a spear: the moment it penetrates the heart it is the greatest agony possible, but beyond the agony is the ecstasy. Love is pain, pure pain, but out of the fire of pure pain, bliss is born. The pain is the price we pay for the bliss.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 24
24 February 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva is Sanskrit. it means god. Lars is Scandinavian, it means symbol of victory – god, the symbol of victory. Remember, unless god is achieved, nothing is achieved. Unless god is realised, we are failures, utter failures. It is only with the realisation of god that victory arrives; there is no other victory. All are cover-ups for defeats.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 25
25 February 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, vincent means victory – victory that comes through love, the victory that love is. Any other kind of victory is only apparent, only love gives you the real thing, because every other kind of victory is forced, violent; sooner or later there is going to be vengeance, revolt, reaction. Only love knows no revolt, because love is not an enforcement: it is a gift.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 26
26 February 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, regis means wise. Love brings wisdom. Wisdom is the shadow of love; without love there is no wisdom. Without love knowledge is possible, much knowledge is possible, but wisdom impossible. Wisdom is the function of the heart, and without love the heart remains dormant. It is the force of love that moves the dynamo of the heart and once the heart is stirred, the seed of wisdom that we are carrying within us starts growing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 27
27 February 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin arriving with her children says she doesn’t know how long she will stay here.]
Be here. There is no need to know! Just be here. This is not a place to know anything! This is a place to become as ignorant as possible.
There is a knowledge which is ignorant, and there is an ignorance which knows.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/part28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/part28/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 28
28 February 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, eberhard means brave. Love is the most courageous quality of human consciousness, because love can risk all. It is the very centre of courage, because it can even encounter death. The man of fear cannot love and cannot even allow anybody to love him. The man who can love and can allow himself to be loved, slowly slowly forgets what fear is; fear becomes a forgotten language.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
3 February 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means blissful; raphael is Hebrew, it means healed by god, or a divine healer, or a medicine of god. Raphael is also the name of one of the angels, one of the four angels that surround god’s throne. He represents one dimension of god’s being.
Existence is four-dimensional. Three dimensions are very visible, the fourth dimension is invisible.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
4 February 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, tim is a short form of Timotheus. It is a Greek name; it means worshipping god, honouring god. And bliss is possible only if you become related with the existence in a personal way. That’s what the word ‘god’ implies – a personal relationship with existence.
The person who does not believe in god does believe in existence but there is no personal bridge, there is no love affair.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
5 February 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand is Sanskrit, it means bliss or blissful. Arno is Teutonic. it means the eagle. Anand Arno will mean: the blissful eagle. It is a message.
Plotinus says: The search for god is a flight of the alone to the alone. It is a flight, and it is the greatest flight there is, because you are not simply changing one place for another, you are changing one space for another.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
6 February 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love; leon is Latin, it means lion, or lionlike.
Love is the greatest courage, because it needs total sacrifice. It wants you to die so that you can be reborn. It is a death and the beginning of an eternal life; but death is first, hence the courage needed. One has to be really lionlike, ready to take the risk.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
7 February 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love. Asa is Hebrew; it means healed by god. God heals, all healing is through god, god is the only healer: all those meanings are involved in it.
Prem Asa will mean: the god of love heals.
Prem means love. Simone is Hebrew; it means god has heard. Prem Simone will mean: love that has been heard by god.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
8 February 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, the ultimate state of consciousness where no content exists, not even a ripple of experience. Where all experiences have been dissolved, where only the experiencer is without any experience, that state is of bliss. There is no happiness, no unhappiness, because they are all experiences, they come from the outside. They are all disturbances.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/wont_you_join_the_dance/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
9 February 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love. Christina is Greek, it is from Christ. Christ is Greek for messiah, the one who has arrived; it is exactly the equivalent of the Buddha.
We are in the journey. Life is a pilgrimage, and only very few have arrived at the goal. These few are called the messiahs, the Buddhas, the Christs.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
