<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Believing the Impossible Before Breakfast on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/believing_the_impossible_before_breakfast/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Believing the Impossible Before Breakfast on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/believing_the_impossible_before_breakfast/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/believing_the_impossible_before_breakfast/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/believing_the_impossible_before_breakfast/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
1 February 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho gives sannyas:]
Just raise your hands, close your eyes, and feel utterly open. These hands are the gestures of openness. Feel receptive, because sannyas has to be received; you cannot take it, you can only receive it. It is a gift: you can allow it to happen. There is no need to grab it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/believing_the_impossible_before_breakfast/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/believing_the_impossible_before_breakfast/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
10 February 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Bodha means awareness, ananda means bliss – awareness, bliss. Misery consists of unawareness. Misery has no outer cause for it, the cause is inner. You go on throwing the responsibility outside, but that is just an excuse. Yes, it is triggered from the outside but the outside does not create it. Somebody insults you: the insult comes from the outside but the anger is inside you.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/believing_the_impossible_before_breakfast/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/believing_the_impossible_before_breakfast/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
11 February 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Dhyana means meditation. And this is the right age when you should start meditating, just when you are coming closer to your fourteenth year. You are twelve; these two years will be of immense value to you. After each seven years the mind changes. The fourteenth year will be one of great change, so if one is ready much becomes possible; if one is not ready then one goes on missing the change.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/believing_the_impossible_before_breakfast/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/believing_the_impossible_before_breakfast/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
12 February 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, nityam means eternal. Eternity is not non-ending time, eternity means no-time. Eternity is not the continuity of time forever; that is the meaning in the dictionaries: forever and forever. But forever is part of time – prolonged time, indefinitely prolonged, but it is still time. Eternity is jumping out of time; it is non-temporal, it is no-time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/believing_the_impossible_before_breakfast/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/believing_the_impossible_before_breakfast/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
13 February 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Osho gives the name Deva Sura and says that god is the ultimate intoxicant, the ultimate lsd. When people are searching for intoxicants, they are really searching for god. Drink god, and you are drunk forever. Life can be transformed into eternal wine: one can live so utterly drunk that one walks on the earth yet flies in the sky, one lives in the world but the world does not live in one.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/believing_the_impossible_before_breakfast/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/believing_the_impossible_before_breakfast/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
14 February 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin, recently returned, says she feels rather neutral at the moment.]
Don’t be worried about the neutrality and don’t think that it is something that should not be. We have become accustomed to ups and downs, so both are okay: when we are up we feel good, when we are down we feel bad.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/believing_the_impossible_before_breakfast/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/believing_the_impossible_before_breakfast/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
15 February 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A new sannyasin said he had done an encounter group in the west: It was not very pleasant but I think it gave me a lot.]
Mm mm. Encounter cannot be pleasant. If it is true, it is going to be painful; if it is untrue, it can be pleasant. It is an effort to uncover all that which we are hiding.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/believing_the_impossible_before_breakfast/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/believing_the_impossible_before_breakfast/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
16 February 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss and megha means path...
Man has to become a path of bliss. Bliss comes from the unknown, from the blue. Just as the sun- rays come from far away, so does bliss; from the centre of the universe, bliss radiates. But we are closed to it; we don’t allow the way, we don’t open the door.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/believing_the_impossible_before_breakfast/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/believing_the_impossible_before_breakfast/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
17 February 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, ashad means joy, enjoyment, happiness; all kinds of joys are included in it, from the lowest to the highest. There are bodily joys, there are psychological and there are spiritual joys. Ashad takes them altogether, in one unity. It cannot be exactly translated into English because there are different joys. Somebody may enjoy eating but that’s a physical phenomenon.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/believing_the_impossible_before_breakfast/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/believing_the_impossible_before_breakfast/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
18 February 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, akal means timelessness – divine timelessness. And that has to become your target. The mind is time; when the mind disappears, time disappears. In a state of no-mind there is no experience of time. All is, but nothing moves; everything simply stops. There comes a great pause: that pause is meditation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/believing_the_impossible_before_breakfast/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/believing_the_impossible_before_breakfast/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
19 February 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, ullas means celebration. And that has to be the key for you: celebration has to become your religion. Misery is sin; sadness, seriousness, are companions of misery. Joy is virtue, and all that helps joy should be nourished, cherished, invited.
Let your life be integrated at the centre of celebration. Only choose that which is celebrating, joyous.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/believing_the_impossible_before_breakfast/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/believing_the_impossible_before_breakfast/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
2 February 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, niyati means destiny – bliss destiny. And that is everybody’s destiny: the destiny of rocks, of trees, of animals, of birds, of man, of stars. We arise out of bliss; that is our source, and we are searching for the source again. Everything moves back to its own source because only back in the source is there rest.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/believing_the_impossible_before_breakfast/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/believing_the_impossible_before_breakfast/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
20 February 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means blissful, narangu means the orange colour – blissful orange (a wave of appreciative laughter). And orange is a very significant metaphor. It means many things, but the most fundamental is that red is the colour of life, yellow is the colour of death, and orange is just in the middle of both.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/believing_the_impossible_before_breakfast/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/believing_the_impossible_before_breakfast/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
21 February 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, satori means insight – insight into love. And the insight into love is the window into god. If one can understand what love is, one has started moving towards god. Love is the first glimpse, the first flower of spring. The coming of the first flower heralds the spring, announcing that it will be here soon.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/believing_the_impossible_before_breakfast/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/believing_the_impossible_before_breakfast/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
22 February 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A couple and their baby are present. The mother says: I feel much more relaxed. In the last ten days or so I realised how much tension I usually carry and I just keep telling myself I need to relax more and more.]
Mm, if one starts taking note of the tension it starts disappearing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/believing_the_impossible_before_breakfast/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/believing_the_impossible_before_breakfast/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
23 February 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, mouna means silence. And silence is going to help you tremendously, so drop as much inner talk as possible. Start renouncing thoughts, don’t get identified with them. Start creating a distance between you and the constantly moving traffic of thought. Neglect, ignore, be indifferent to them. Let them be there as uninvited guests if they want.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/believing_the_impossible_before_breakfast/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/believing_the_impossible_before_breakfast/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 24
24 February 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[The tantra group is present. One participant said she was sick and had many pains. She had been a devotee of a swami in Rishikesh for three years. She had served him, become pregnant by him and had an abortion. She still loves him and is afraid of him. She would prefer to remain in Poona.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/believing_the_impossible_before_breakfast/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/believing_the_impossible_before_breakfast/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 25
25 February 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means god, surati means remembrance – remembrance of god. God has not to be searched for but only remembered; because we have not lost him, he is not to be found. We have simply forgotten him; he is just to be remembered. God is there within you, but you are asleep. The moment you awake, you are god.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/believing_the_impossible_before_breakfast/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/believing_the_impossible_before_breakfast/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 26
26 February 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, girisha means of the mountains – bliss of the mountains. Mountains represent that which is natural, that which is ancientmost and yet as fresh as dewdrops. Mountains represent the silence, the eternal silence, of existence, the height of ecstasy and a depth. Mountains are the most mysterious things in the world; and those mountains exist within you.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/believing_the_impossible_before_breakfast/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/believing_the_impossible_before_breakfast/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 27
27 February 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Veet means beyond, nisha means night.
The night is just ending, the dawn is entering. The night is taking itself away. We cannot do anything to disperse it; it comes and goes on its own. But we can do one thing: even when the morning is there, already there, and the sun has risen, we may not open our eyes; then inside us the night still continues.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/believing_the_impossible_before_breakfast/part28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/believing_the_impossible_before_breakfast/part28/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 28
28 February 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, kavina means poet. Poetry is the way to god – not logic, not mathematics, but poetry. The vagueness of poetry, the mystery of poetry, opens the door. To have poetic eyes is to have a religious vision. All those who have attained were poets. Whether they wrote poetry ever or not is immaterial, but the way they looked at life was the way of poetry – aesthetics, sensitivity, love.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/believing_the_impossible_before_breakfast/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/believing_the_impossible_before_breakfast/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
3 February 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says she’s pregnant. She’d decided to have an abortion and thought she was happy with the decision, but since then, whenever she thinks about it she feels a tremendous amount of sadness.]
Mm mm. This will be a momentary sadness. If you want to become a mother then you want to get into deeper troubles, because it is not a question that can be easily solved once the child is there.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/believing_the_impossible_before_breakfast/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/believing_the_impossible_before_breakfast/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
4 February 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss and citta means mind – bliss mind. In English you don’t have many words for the mind but in Sanskrit we have many words for the mind to denote different qualities. The only way to translate citta is. mind with a capital ‘M’. It is not ordinary mind, it is the cosmic Mind.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/believing_the_impossible_before_breakfast/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/believing_the_impossible_before_breakfast/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
5 February 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, somen means the moon god, the god of the moon. The god of love and the moon is to be the meaning of the whole name. The moon and love are deeply related, the sun and reason are deeply related. In man there are two currents of energies. In the East, we call one current the sun energy and the other current the moon energy The sun energy is reason, logic, arithmetic.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/believing_the_impossible_before_breakfast/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/believing_the_impossible_before_breakfast/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
7 February 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, mahakavi means a great poet – a great poet of bliss. Bliss is available only to those who can create great poetry in their being. Bliss is an experience of inner poetics, it is poetry. The logical mind never knows it; the logical mind is debarred, by its very premises it is closed to bliss.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/believing_the_impossible_before_breakfast/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/believing_the_impossible_before_breakfast/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
8 February 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Bodhi means awareness, intelligence, meditativeness, enlightenment. It is one of the most potential words, it has many aspects to it. The word ‘buddha’ comes from bodhi; because he attained bodhi he is called Buddha. And that has to be your life’s work. Nothing less than that can ever satisfy a man.
Only in Buddhahood is there contentment; all other forms of contentment are just consolations, just comforts at the most, illusions created by the mind.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/believing_the_impossible_before_breakfast/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/believing_the_impossible_before_breakfast/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
9 February 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says he has trouble knowing what country to identify with for his parents are Pakistani, his upbringing English.]
It should not be a problem – you should be happy that you are neither. There is no need for anyone to identify with India or with England; those identifications are all pathological. An Englishman is naturally less than a man and an Indian is less than human.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
