<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Just Around the Corner on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Just Around the Corner on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
1 May 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Hans means God’s gracious gift, Ananto means infinite. The full name will mean God’s infinite gracious gift.
Life has no beginning and no end. It is eternity, and that is God’s gift. God has given himself in the gift, because life is God.
All that is needed is a certain awakening in your heart so you can see it, feel it, taste it, touch it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
10 May 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, Arie means black – divine blackness. Black is symbolic of death. It is also symbolic of infinity, of the mysterious, of the uncaused.
Light has to be caused. Light needs fuel; once the fuel is finished light is gone. Darkness is eternal. It needs no cause, no fuel: it is simply there.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
11 May 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, Alan means harmony. Harmony is bliss; bliss is another name of harmony. Misery is discord. Existence is always in harmony – it is only man who falls apart because of the ego, because of the idea of “I am”. He wants to create a world of his own, separate, private, hence he becomes a small island and loses contact with the total.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
12 May 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, Anne means prayer – love is prayer. Those who pray without love, their prayers are empty, hollow of meaning. Their prayers are without wings. Their prayers will never reach to God. Only when love throbs at the heart inside the prayer is it alive, significant, and has it the energy to reach to God.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
13 May 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, Barbara means a stranger. Love is a stranger in this world; hate is not. hate is part of the very fabric of this world; love comes from the beyond. Hate belongs to the earth; love is part of the sky. Hate gravitates downwards; love soars upwards. Love is a stranger, and because love is a stranger, love becomes the vehicle to God.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
14 May 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, Tineke means pure – pure bliss. Bliss is impure if it is dependent on something; bliss is pure when it is absolutely independent. Bliss is impure if it is conditional; bliss is pure if it is unconditional. The bliss that arises in love is not pure because the other is needed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
15 May 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[To Bob, Osho adds Anand – making him the blissful and shining one.]
Bliss has its own luminosity, it shines forth. You cannot hide it: it is like a lamp lit; it will show, it will shine, it will declare itself. Of course, utterly silent is its declaration. Non-aggressive is its declaration. but it cannot remain unmanifested.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
16 May 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Veet means going beyond, transcending, surpassing. Peter means a rock, a stone. Man is born as a rock but has to become a flower. Unless the rock of the heart opens and becomes a lotus life is in vain. And that’s what happens in most cases: people are born as rocks, they live as rocks, they die as rocks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
17 May 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, Roy has two meanings. One comes from the French; it means the king. The other comes from the Celtic; it means red. Both are beautiful. Bliss makes you a king. Without bliss one may be Alexander the Great but one remains poorer than the poor. One of the most naked fakirs of all ages, Diogenes, laughed at Alexander.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
18 May 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, Sindhu means ocean. Love can only be oceanic; it cannot be small. It cannot be small because it cannot be a closed phenomenon. It is an open, wide sky. Love knows no limitations.
Love is not attachment. Love is not possessiveness. When love becomes possessive and love becomes attachment it is no more love; it is simply a corpse.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
19 May 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Maria comes from Hebrew; it means rebellion. And rebellion is the very flavor of sannyas, rebellion is my message. But remember the distinction – and the distinction is great – between rebellion and revolution. Revolution is an organized effort; rebellion is individual. Revolution becomes automatically political; rebellion remains religious, rebellion is part of spirituality.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
2 May 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, Gudrun means divine wisdom. Wisdom is not knowledge. It has nothing to lo with knowing. It is a feeling, and ultimately it is being. These are three planes: knowing, feeling, being.
Knowing is the most superficial, feeling is in the middle, and being is at the very core. Ultimately wisdom is being, but in the beginning it is feeling, moving towards being.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
20 May 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Vedant means that which is beyond scriptures; Satyam means truth. The full name will mean truth which is beyond scriptures.
Truth is not something that can be described. Truth is not a theory: it is an experience, an experience so deep, so tremendously intense, so infinite, so mysterious, that no word is adequate to explain it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
21 May 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says he is trying to live up to his new name: Now I feel very happy and hope I am strong enough to do it in Germany.]
Good! Sometimes small changes can bring great changes. Just a small pebble in the lake can create millions of ripples. Life is so interconnected that they say if you destroy a small leaf of grass even the faraway stars are affected.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
22 May 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
First a few words to the mediums and the others also...
Albert Einstein is reported to have said that life’s most incomprehensible thing is that it is comprehensible. Yes, there are moments when life is comprehensible – very rare moments, peaks of consciousness.
Ordinarily life is incomprehensible. There is no way to figure it out, you cannot make any head nor tail of it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
23 May 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, Derek means ruler. Let love rule your life, let love be the ruler. Let everything else be just the supreme God of love.
There is no other God. All other gods are just myths, inventions of man out of fear and greed. All other gods are false, fictitious. But love is not man’s invention; love is natural.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 24
24 May 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Veet means beyond, Shastro means scriptures. Truth is beyond all scriptures, beyond all words, beyond all theories, philosophies. That is one of the most fundamental things to remember because man gets lost in words, and words can prove very dangerous, very fascinating, very alluring, very hypnotizing.
The word “God” has become so important that people are ready to die for it or to kill for it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 25
25 May 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
This is your new name: Swami Anand Prartho. Anand means blissful, Prartho means prayer. The word “prayer” comes from the same root as Prartho – a blissful prayer. And that is the most incredible thing that can happen in life to a man. Even love is not that far out; even love falls short, even love remains human.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 26
26 May 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Enough of war! Man has lived too much in violence. The time has come, it is absolutely the right time to take the quantum leap from war to love. Either man decides to take the quantum leap or he’ll have to commit suicide. Only love can save him.
War is utterly meaningless today. In the past it was not so meaningless because it was not total.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 27
27 May 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Man is a bridge, a bridge between the animal and God, a bridge between two infinities – matter and consciousness. Man is not a being but a bridge.
A being is complete; man is not complete. Man has to become bridged, man has to go a long way yet. Man is only a passage to be passed over, to be surpassed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part28/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 28
28 May 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss; Jorrit means a Farmer.
Once a farmer asked Buddha “I never see you doing anything. What is your work? What are you doing in the world?” Buddha laughed and he said “I am also a farmer, but my farming is invisible. I sow the seeds of bliss and love and truth.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>29</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part29/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 29
29 May 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss; Pujan means worship. Bliss is worship. To be blissful is to be prayerful. To have the capacity to celebrate life is religiousness.
But down the ages the so-called religions have done Just the opposite: they have made religion a very serious, somber affair. They have made it almost pathological, morbid. They have made it utterly negative: life denying, love denying, bliss-denying.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
3 May 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, Laurel is a symbol of two things; one is victory, the other is immortality. Love brings both: it brings victory, it brings immortality. Love is the only experience in which defeat is impossible because the very first requirement of being in love is to be surrendered. If a person is surrendered how can he be defeated?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>30</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part30/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 30
30 May 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, Anna means grace – grace that is a byproduct of bliss. Grace follows bliss as a shadow. One cannot achieve grace directly, there is no way to it. It comes via bliss. If somebody tries to be graceful without being blissful he will only be pretending, he will be at the most a good actor.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>31</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part31/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 31
31 May 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love; Helmut means great courage. Love is the greatest courage in life.
It really needs guts to be in love. It needs a capacity to die into the love, to disappear into love. It needs courage because the ego has to be surrendered. Hence many people would like to love and be loved, but cannot dare.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
4 May 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Veet means going beyond, transcending, Christian means a follower of Christ. Go beyond following, that’s the only way to be a Christ. Go beyond following, and that’s the only way to be a Buddha. The follower never reaches the goal. Love Christ but don’t follow, don’t imitate, don’t be a shadow, don’t be a carbon copy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
5 May 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, Eli means light – a blissful light. The light is there, it has not to be enkindled. We bring it with us. We are made of it, it is our innermost core, but we are keeping our back to it. And because we go on keeping our back to the inner light, our life becomes dark, unnecessarily dark.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
6 May 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Gyan means wisdom, prem means love – wisdom through love. There is a knowing that is possible only through love. All other kinds of knowing are only acquaintances from the outside. Love takes you to the very inside of a thing.
The scientist can say many things about a rose flower but all that is from the outside.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
7 May 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, Marian means rebellion and grace. Mary means rebellion; Ann is part of Hannah, it means grace. Your full name will mean love, rebellion, grace.
Love is rebellion and love is grace too. Love is rebellion because it is the expression of your innermost core. It is not imitation, it is not being a carbon copy; it is your originality.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
8 May 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, das means a servant – a servant of love. But to be a servant of love is the way to become a master. One who is ready to surrender to love becomes immensely powerful. It is not a defeat; it is a victory.
The way of love is very illogical. If you surrender you are victorious.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/just_around_the_corner/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
9 May 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin asks: Can you see where there’s something wrong with my feelings? – because up to now I have not been able to feel the energy.
Osho checks his energy.]
It will open – nothing to worry about. Just be here with no desire, not even the desire of opening the heart. Just be here with no motive, because every motive becomes a hindrance – even the motive to open.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
