<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Miracle on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Miracle on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 3 - Unhitch the Universe</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 3 - Unhitch the Universe‌ 3 Unhitch the Universe
4 August 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium OUR BELOVED MASTER,
ON ONE OCCASION, RINZAI SAID:
STUDENTS OF TODAY FAIL TO ACHIEVE THEIR ENDS. WHAT IS THEIR
FAULT? IT LIES IN NOT HAVING FAITH IN THEMSELVES. BY LACK OF FAITH
YOU FALL INTO A STATE OF UNCERTAINTY, IN WHICH YOU CONFORM TO ALL</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 3 - Unhitch the Universe</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 3 - Unhitch the Universe‌ an evening walk, just to see what is happening outside the gate -- that could be dangerous. By the time you come back somebody else may have entered. You can also enter, but it is a very difficult situation when there are two spirits in one body.
Once in a while those cases happen, then you say the person is possessed by a ghost.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 3 - Unhitch the Universe</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 3 - Unhitch the Universe‌ MY UP-DOWN CAREER: BUDDHAS NOR PATRIARCHS CAN CONVEY IT.
He is saying that causality is the basis of science, but your being is not within the area of causality. You are not caused by anything, you are here from eternity to eternity. And the experience of this is something even buddhas cannot express. He is saying, &#34;I am a poor poet.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 3 - Unhitch the Universe</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 3 - Unhitch the Universe‌ Yes, Maneesha. This kind of society can exist only if it makes you feel inadequate. This kind of society, the structure, needs people who are suffering, or made to suffer, from inferiority, who deep down are carrying a conditioning that they are unworthy, undeserving.
This kind of society can exist only if it makes every child inadequate, because this society needs exploitation, this society has invested itself in exploiting human beings.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 3 - Unhitch the Universe</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 3 - Unhitch the Universe‌ This vision, if it spreads, is bound to create a new man and a new society. A new man can only be an enlightened man.
A new man can only be a buddha.
And if there are just a few buddhas around the world, we can create the wildfire.
It has never been tried, but it is just like .</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 3 - Unhitch the Universe</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 3 - Unhitch the Universe‌ Mr. Samosa, one of Poona&#39;s most successful businessmen, is a rubberware manufacturer.
He invites guests from an International Management Conference for a tour of his factory.
Proudly, he introduces his different products, everything from tractor tires to baby-bottle nipples. He is especially proud of his fully automatic condom making machine, with a special electronic leakproof tester.
By the side of the machine, a man is sitting and carefully punching holes in the condoms with a needle.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 3 - Unhitch the Universe</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 3 - Unhitch the Universe‌ When she comes back five minutes later, he asks her next to produce a feces sample in the same cup.
&#34;Good,&#34; says Spook when Mrs. Grumblebum returns. &#34;Now stick your finger in the cup, stir it around and then drink all of it.&#34;
Obediently doing as the doctor tells her, Mrs. Grumblebum downs the concoction.
Immediately, she is violently sick.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 3 - Unhitch the Universe</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 3 - Unhitch the Universe‌ Nivedano ... (Drumbeat) Relax.
Let go.
Just be dead. This is simply a way to concentrate your energy
at the very center of your being. This moment you are the buddha.
Let this moment stretch through all your life.
Just go on reminding yourself who you are.
And this reminding
is going to bring a revolution; not only to you,</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 3 - Unhitch the Universe</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 3 - Unhitch the Universe‌ Come back.
Sit down for a few moments remembering the space you have been in. Okay, Maneesha?
Yes, Osho.
Can we celebrate the ten thousand buddhas? Yes, Osho.
Osho - The Miracle 49
&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 3 - Unhitch the Universe</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 3 - Unhitch the Universe‌ In this sense all the religions have committed a great crime against humanity, because they all want you to be saints, great saints. They have categories of austerities, they have categories of respectability. The so-called religions of the world are part of the same game that is being played in the marketplace, that is being played by the politicians.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 3 - Unhitch the Universe</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 3 - Unhitch the Universe‌ He said, &#34;It is good that that examination was made by me, because anybody else would have become very angry. You answered beautifully and freshly, your answers were simply answers; everybody else was quoting the text books. You had no idea what was written in the text books, you have never seen them. Obviously, you had to be original.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 3 - Unhitch the Universe</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 3 - Unhitch the Universe‌ I said, &#34;That does not matter. You showed your weakness in cutting me by one percent.&#34;
He said, &#34;You are strange. Nobody fights with me, especially after ten years. Now what can I do?&#34;
I said, &#34;You can at least say &#39;I&#39;m sorry&#39;.&#34;
There were at least twenty professors who were sitting with him. He had become almost a holy place, where every kind of professor and intellectual gathered.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 3 - Unhitch the Universe</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 3 - Unhitch the Universe‌ Whatever has to happen has already happened, you have just to discover it. It is not an achievement. It is not a goal somewhere far away, that you have to travel to that place. It is just in your very being, in your very silence. You don&#39;t have to achieve it. It is a miracle that you have forgotten it .</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 3 - Unhitch the Universe</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 3 - Unhitch the Universe‌ achieve. He is doing it all out of his unconscious love, but unconscious love is not love -- it is blind. With all good intentions, it does harm. The child who is being forced to become a doctor, if he was left alone to grow according to his own nature ... one never knows what kind of beauty or joy, what kind of individuality, he would have contributed to the world.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 3 - Unhitch the Universe</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 3 - Unhitch the Universe‌ At this moment another man, bound to another pillar, who had been tortured there for one month, shouted, &#34;That man is wrong, Omar. Don&#39;t believe him! I have never sent anybody after Mohammed! I have come myself.&#34;
He was God himself. He had been jailed one month earlier.
If you don&#39;t have faith in yourself, you are going to have faith in some madman who proclaims to be God&#39;s messenger or God himself, or proclaims that he is a reincarnation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 3 - Unhitch the Universe</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 3 - Unhitch the Universe‌ pine trees and rosebushes. They are on the way to buddhahood; sooner or later they will also be human beings. But whether they know it or not, it does not matter. As far as their innermost nature is concerned, it remains the same.
The difference between the buddha and the rest of existence is simply that the buddha has awakened to his reality.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 3 - Unhitch the Universe</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 3 - Unhitch the Universe‌ that is running the body. That heart is the center of the body. To complete the distinction, behind this heart there is another heart which in China they used to call the &#34;inner heart.&#34;
In India just a few years ago, there was a man, Brahmayogi, who had practiced for almost half a century to bring his breathing to a complete stop.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4 - This harvest moon</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 4 - This harvest moon‌ 4 This harvest moon
5 August 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium OUR BELOVED MASTER,
DOGEN WROTE:
QUIETLY CONSIDER THE FACT THAT IF THIS WERE A TIME WHEN THE TRUE
DHARMA HAD NOT YET SPREAD THROUGHOUT THE WORLD, IT WOULD BE
IMPOSSIBLE FOR US TO COME INTO CONTACT WITH IT, EVEN IF WE WERE
WILLING TO SACRIFICE OUR LIVES TO DO SO.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4 - This harvest moon</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 4 - This harvest moon‌ I have to remind you that at some point Dogen must have become a master. We have discussed the sutras written when he had become enlightened. It is a good comparison ... to see in a single man what enlightenment brings and what the impediments are. Even to a man like Dogen with such immense and unique intelligence .</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4 - This harvest moon</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 4 - This harvest moon‌ I said, &#34;With me nothing is polite, either this way or that way. If you are not a buddha, then how is a conversation possible? I am a buddha, you are a mere scholar.&#34;
He said, &#34;That seems to be true. When I heard you for the first time in a Buddhist conference in Bodhgaya you told a story.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4 - This harvest moon</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 4 - This harvest moon‌ water was not drinkable, and Ananda was in a difficulty: what to do? This water he cannot take for his master. So he went back. Buddha was sitting under a tree and asked, &#34;Have you brought the water?&#34;
He told what happened. Buddha said, &#34;You are stupid. You just go there and sit by the side of the stream.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4 - This harvest moon</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 4 - This harvest moon‌ scholarship is always useless; but the scholars find it immensely difficult to take the jump beyond their mind, because their mind is so precious to them. It contains so many beautiful scriptures, it is their respectability, it is their honor, it is their dignity, it is the whole treasure they have.
It is a strange fact that the more you know, the more you are filled with borrowed knowledge, the less is the possibility of your knowing the truth.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4 - This harvest moon</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 4 - This harvest moon‌ Have you watched sheep? They always move in a crowd, a big crowd, almost stepping on each other. Just the feeling that everybody else is there, there is no need to be afraid ... But nobody has seen a lion moving in a crowd of lions. A lion moves alone. The very word
&#39;crowd&#39; is dishonorable.
These scholars want you to understand that you can only be a follower.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4 - This harvest moon</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 4 - This harvest moon‌ But Rajendra Anuragi is not to go back. Going back is very cowardly. And all these threats
-- they have not taken the house, they have not cut the telephone -- all these threats are simply so that his wife becomes afraid. She has had a heart attack, she has been hospitalized, the children must be worried -- naturally the government must be thinking that Rajendra Anuragi, seeing the situation, will come back.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4 - This harvest moon</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 4 - This harvest moon‌ The master can be a help if he is just a friend, a presence in which you can learn to be yourself, a presence which can encourage you to fly into the sky. But he can be a hindrance if he promises, &#34;I will deliver you from your sins.&#34;
Jesus was continually asked when the day of judgment would come, because on the day of judgment all the souls will wake up from their graves and God will decide who is a sinner and who is a saint.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4 - This harvest moon</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 4 - This harvest moon‌ laughing, seeing these idiots standing on two legs. This is not natural -- abnormal monkeys, stubborn ... adamant outcasts, unfit monkeys rejected by the society perhaps.
Jesus says you are sheep and he is the shepherd. All these people are consistently trying to take away your dignity as human beings.
I say to you that you are the ultimate consciousness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4 - This harvest moon</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 4 - This harvest moon‌ predecessors are not needed, you are enough unto yourself. It is just a question of awakening.
So everybody will wake up -- how long can you sleep? We will go on harassing you.
IF THE BUDDHAS AND PATRIARCHS HAD NOT DIRECTLY TRANSMITTED THE
DHARMA, HOW COULD IT HAVE COME DOWN TO US TODAY?
Absolute bullshit! -- but very scholarly, supported by the scriptures.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4 - This harvest moon</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part28/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 4 - This harvest moon‌ A haiku by Basho: ALONG THE MOUNTAIN ROAD SOMEHOW IT TUGS AT MY HEART:
A WILD VIOLET.
Now, he is saying more than any scholar can say. A WILD VIOLET.
SOMEHOW IT TUGS AT MY HEART:
ALONG THE MOUNTAIN ROAD.
A man of silence and understanding, a man of consciousness, understands the beauty of existence, even of a wild flower.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4 - This harvest moon</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part29/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 4 - This harvest moon‌ And I absolutely support Ryota. There have been many buddhas in many different places, of different races, from different countries. They may not have been called buddhas, they may have spoken different languages, they may not have spoken at all; their existence may not have been recorded. But it is impossible to believe that in four million years there has been only one man who attained to the highest peak of consciousness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4 - This harvest moon</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part30/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 4 - This harvest moon‌ Question 1 Maneesha has asked:
OUR BELOVED MASTER,
WHAT IS IT ABOUT MAN TODAY THAT HE IS NOT ONLY LACKING IN THE
SIMPLICITY AND INNOCENCE OF THE PEOPLE WE HEAR ABOUT IN THESE ZEN
DISCOURSES, BUT THAT HE IS SO WARY OF COMMITMENT?
IT IS AS IF WE ARE AFRAID TO HAVE ALL OUR EGGS IN ONE BASKET; OR</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4 - This harvest moon</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part31/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 4 - This harvest moon‌ &#34;I beg your pardon, sir?&#34; replies Mabel, the teller.
&#34;Listen, damn it,&#34; repeats Chester. &#34;I said I want to open a goddamn current account.&#34;
&#34;I am sorry, sir,&#34; says Mabel. &#34;But we don&#39;t tolerate language like that in this bank.&#34;
Then she leaves the window, walks over to the bank manager and whispers in his ear. The two of them return to where Chester is waiting.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4 - This harvest moon</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part32/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part32/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 4 - This harvest moon‌ only the buddha is. One consciousness,
one oceanic consciousness, and you are drowned in it.
Drink this experience as much as you can. Let it sink into your every cell,
into your breathing, your heartbeat,
so that it remains twenty-four hours with you, just like an undercurrent.
This moment there is no time, no space. This moment</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4 - This harvest moon</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part33/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part33/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 4 - This harvest moon‌ the buddha. Nivedano ... (Drumbeat)
Come back from your inner journey, silently, slowly.
There is no hurry. Sit down for a few moments, reminding yourself you are a buddha.
This reminding every day that you are a buddha
will become just like breathing. You don&#39;t have to remember; just like the heartbeat
you don&#39;t have to remember. One becomes simple, nobody,</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 6 - Cages of gold</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part34/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part34/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 6 - Cages of gold‌ 6 Cages of gold
7 August 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium OUR BELOVED MASTER,
SEIGEN SAID:
IF NOW YOU COMPREHEND IT, WHERE IS THAT WHICH YOU DID NOT
COMPREHEND BEFORE? WHAT YOU WERE DELUDED ABOUT BEFORE IS WHAT
YOU ARE NOW ENLIGHTENED ABOUT, AND WHAT YOU ARE NOW
ENLIGHTENED ABOUT, IS WHAT YOU WERE DELUDED ABOUT BEFORE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 6 - Cages of gold</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part35/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part35/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 6 - Cages of gold‌ Seigen is saying that you have to be free from ignorance and you have to be free from enlightenment. This is called the lion&#39;s roar. Even enlightenment is not going to be his imprisonment. He wants the whole universe without any limits.
An enlightened person has a tiny flame. But if that tiny flame makes him feel special, greater and better than others, it has already become a fetter.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 6 - Cages of gold</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part36/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part36/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 6 - Cages of gold‌ This is how you can determine whether a man really knows. Even from his words you can see some glimpses. Compare it with Jesus&#39; statement, &#34;Seek and ye shall find.&#34; Seigen will say, &#34;Seek and you shall never find.&#34;
The seeker has already gone away from himself; in search of himself he has left himself far behind. Jesus says, &#34;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 6 - Cages of gold</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part37/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part37/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 6 - Cages of gold‌ I said to these people, &#34;Don&#39;t make distinctions.&#34; Let me remain simply a nobody, with no power, with no domination. Because every subtle desire to be special is a desire for power.
You gather money to be powerful, you go into politics to be powerful, you search for enlightenment again for power. Enlightened you will be worshipped. Perhaps enlightenment is the most dangerous disease of all, because who wants to be unenlightened once he has become enlightened?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 6 - Cages of gold</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part38/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part38/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 6 - Cages of gold‌ go anywhere. Wherever you are, you are in the holy universe. There are not certain places which are holy and certain places which are not holy. If the whole universe is divine then everything is holy.
Another haiku:
THE BAMBOO SHADOWS ARE SWEEPING THE STAIRS, BUT NO DUST IS STIRRED:
THE MOONLIGHT PENETRATES DEEP INTO THE BOTTOM OF THE POOL,</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 6 - Cages of gold</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part39/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part39/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 6 - Cages of gold‌ is still on the mountain your question will not be answered. If he is still on the way going towards the mountain all that he can say will be mere words.
You have to find a man who has been to the ultimate peak and then came down to be amongst you. Then he is at ease, he has no tensions, he is at home.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 6 - Cages of gold</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part40/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part40/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 6 - Cages of gold‌ &#34;Okay,&#34; says Sally. &#34;But it will cost you fifty dollars.&#34;
Father finger agrees and pays the money in advance. Then Sally undresses slowly, and next she undresses the priest and tells him to lie down.
&#34;I&#39;m going to start your lesson with the sixty-nine position,&#34; she says. But when she climbs on top of him, she accidentally farts in his face.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 6 - Cages of gold</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part41/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part41/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 6 - Cages of gold‌ (Drumbeat) Relax ... let go.
You are not the body nor the mind, but just a watcher, a witness,
a pure consciousness unscratched.
And this consciousness has no boundaries. It is one with the universe.
At this moment your heartbeat is the heartbeat of the universe. There is no distinction.
Rejoice in it. Remember it.
Slowly slowly</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 6 - Cages of gold</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part42/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part42/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 6 - Cages of gold‌ It is only a question of recognizing,
of being courageous and declaring to yourself that you have found your home.
You don&#39;t need anybody&#39;s certificate. You don&#39;t need anybody&#39;s recognition. You are complete unto yourself.
This is the miracle of Zen. Okay, Maneesha?
Yes, Beloved Master!
Can we celebrate the gathering of the buddhas? Yes, Beloved Master!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 7 - The mysterious one</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part43/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part43/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 7 - The mysterious one‌ 7 The mysterious one
8 August 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium OUR BELOVED MASTER,
RINZAI SAID:
IF YOU WANT TO BE COMFORTABLY INDEPENDENT, FREE FROM BIRTH AND
DEATH AND FREE TO GO OR STAY, YOU SHOULD RECOGNIZE THE ONE WHO IS
HERE NOW LISTENING TO MY EXPOUNDING OF THE DHARMA. THIS ONE HAS
NEITHER FORM NOR SHAPE AND NEITHER ROOTS NOR BRANCHES; THIS ONE</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 7 - The mysterious one</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part44/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part44/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 7 - The mysterious one‌ The master&#39;s whole position should be such that your trust deepens and is not disturbed. If the master disturbs your trust he is taking you farther away from yourself, because your undisturbed being -- settled, centered, at home -- is the realization of truth.
So I have to be very careful with all these old masters. They use the language of their times.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 7 - The mysterious one</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part45/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part45/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 7 - The mysterious one‌ The art of meditation is the art of listening with your total being. This very moment, in this silence,
your boundaries drop, your defenses drop.
You become one whole.
There are not ten thousand people, but just one ocean of consciousness.
Just listen so deeply that you disappear,
and only the essential and the eternal in you remains.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 7 - The mysterious one</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part46/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part46/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 7 - The mysterious one‌ Just metaphors. All that he is saying is: any rise of thought in you, and you have missed the point. A single thought is an obstruction to your inner space. It takes you away. Whether it is a thought of love or mind or anger or greed -- it does not matter what the quality of the thought is.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 7 - The mysterious one</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part47/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part47/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 7 - The mysterious one‌ But he got out of the boat from the other side and immediately started drowning and shouting, &#34;Help! Help!&#34;
So the rabbi asked the other bishop, &#34;Should we tell the old boy the right way to walk on water? It has to be on this side of the boat. There are stones ... you have to know exactly where the stones are.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 7 - The mysterious one</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part48/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part48/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 7 - The mysterious one‌ This pure space is the origin of you and of all. This pure space has never changed, it is always here and now. It knows no time, no space. It fills the whole universe, which is infinite.
Once you have known it, your life changes. IF YOU HOLD SUCH A VIEW ...
Remember, it should not only be a view.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 7 - The mysterious one</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part49/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part49/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 7 - The mysterious one‌ Bunan wrote: REMAIN APART,
THE WORLD IS YOURS -- A BUDDHA IN THE FLESH.
Just remember the buddha in your flesh and the world is yours. You don&#39;t have to conquer it, it is already yours. But find out the buddha in the flesh. Just a few words, and a whole philosophy ... REMAIN APART ... That is what I mean when I say, be a witness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 7 - The mysterious one</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part50/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part50/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 7 - The mysterious one‌ I have to tell you the jokes just because you will not laugh without a reason. They are unnecessary; if you start laughing without a reason, that will be more spontaneous and fresh.
Soon there will come a time that just a drumbeat, and everybody goes one hundred percent.
These jokes are only for beginners. The old sinners don&#39;t need them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 7 - The mysterious one</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part51/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part51/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 7 - The mysterious one‌ &#34;He may recover,&#34; replies the doctor, &#34;but frankly, for the rest of his life he will be a vegetable.&#34;
Olga Kowalski wins the draw, and is selected to be a contestant on the famous TV game show &#34;Popular Polacks.&#34;
It is the end of the show, and the excited emcee announces the final category of questions and the grand prize of one million dollars.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 7 - The mysterious one</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part52/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part52/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 7 - The mysterious one‌ has always found him, without any exception.
To make it deeper and more clear, Nivedano ... (Drumbeat)
Relax, let go.
Feel the body apart from you, the mind apart from you.
You just be a watcher.
This watcher is the buddha. This blissful evening,
and thousands of buddhas make this place
the holiest one, this moment the most miraculous.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 7 - The mysterious one</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part53/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_miracle/part53/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌Chapter 7 - The mysterious one‌ a little courage to look within yourself. Okay, Maneesha?
Yes, Beloved Master.
Can we celebrate all the buddhas? Yes, Beloved Master!
Osho - The Miracle 101
Chapter 8 - Joy in the morning 8
Joy in the morning
9 August 1988 pm in Gautam the Buddha Auditorium OUR BELOVED MASTER,
YUN-MEN SAID:
MY DUTY COMPELS ME TO ATTEMPT THE IMPOSSIBLE. EVEN IN TELLING</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
