<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Hammer on the Rock on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hammer on the Rock on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
10 December 1975 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[To the leader of the Tathata group (Unconditional Acceptance Seminar)]
It has to be remembered that the leader is not, in fact, a manipulator. He should not be. If you manipulate, then it is something from the mind, and that which comes from the mind cannot go deeper than the mind. So the leader has to be open to the beyond.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
23 December 1975 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says: I’ve been really rebellious and resistent to you. Whenever you say something in the lecture that I don t like, I cough. It is not as deliberate as all that, but I’ve discovered there’s a very close connection.]
Very good! This is a good discovery! [The sannyasin continues: And I like you]</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
24 December 1975 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[The Arica group came to darshan tonight. One of the leaders said he had felt there had been a lot more love, compared to groups he had been in in the States. He had also found that he was on a powertrip.]
Techniques work only when there is deep love. Left alone, techniques never work, because in fact it is love that works, not the technique.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
26 December 1975 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin, looking close to tears as he talked, told Osho that he was feeling very sad and was easily hurt, and had felt like this for several weeks but he was unable to say what he felt was the reason for this.
Osho asked his wife, who was also present, if she could comment, as her husband was not very clear about what was happening.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
28 December 1975 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin artist from Berlin says: I think some new things are starting in me, but I have not started... ]
It is always difficult to start anything new, because the mind always tries to postpone. With the old, mind fits perfectly. With the new, there is a certain uneasiness. But don’t postpone.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
29 December 1975 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[The Primal Therapy group, halfway through their therapy, were at darshan.
Osho has described it as not so much a therapy as a situation where people can let go into their fears and madnesses, their obsessions and secret hankerings, in a safe and protected environment and where help can be given to see beyond them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
30 December 1975 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin who had been celibate for several months on Osho’s suggestion, said she had been feeling very sexual lately and did not know what she should do about it.]
Just do one thing whenever it happens again. Sit straight – on a chair or on the floor – with the spine straight, but loose and not tense.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
31 December 1975 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Dharma means the Ultimate Law that sustains life; what in Chinese they call Tao. Ananda means bliss. Dharmananda means bliss that comes if you live according to the Law. If you fall in tune with the Ultimate Law, suddenly there is bliss. In fact all misery is because you are not in tune with the Law, you go astray from it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
1 January 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin brought his guitar to darshan and sang and played to Osho. He sang a song full of hare krishnas and LSD, kama sutras and cosmic consciousness. Osho commented that it was good, but could have been better]
You bring too much of the mind in; it should be more of the heart.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
2 January 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin said he needed to return home as he was unwell. He was apprehensive about going, and felt he would miss Osho’s physical presence. He was also afraid that he would fall back into his old patterns again.]
No, no. I will not allow that, don’t be worried. That is my responsibility, mm?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
3 January 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin asked about a friend who was paralysed, and wondered if anything could be done to help. Osho suggested the friend should become a sannyasin, and then continued.]
If you are lying in bed all day and you can’t move, you will continuously want to, because movement is life. Nothing else is so important as movement.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
12 December 1975 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
THURSDAY, DECEMBER 11TH:
[The birthday of Osho Shree. A mass darshan for thousands of seekers from India and abroad... ] FRIDAY, DECEMBER 12TH:
[Members from the Enlightenment Intensive group were present] [To a sannyasin who had just learnt that her father died]
... how are you feeling? Your father had been ill at all?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
4 January 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A woman says she has been doing yoga in the West.]
Good, very good. So you are ready, now meditate. Yoga in itself is not enough. It is a good preparation, but preparation for something else.
It prepares your body/mind, but if you go on preparing and preparing and never doing the thing for which yoga was preparing you, then it can become an obsession.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
5 January 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A girl, not yet a sannyasin, had sent a letter to Osho about her relationship with a sannyasin with whom she had been having a relationship in England.]
I read your letter. I can understand your inner indecisiveness. Whenever there is something very important the mind always hesitates, because anything more important than the mind is always a danger to it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
6 January 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin said that he was feeling much better since last darshan, when Osho had suggested he undertake much physical activity – running, walking, swimming, or whatever he enjoyed.]
You have much energy and you had not been using it creatively. Whenever energy is not used creatively it becomes destructive, stagnant, and by and by a prison of solid rock is created around you.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
7 January 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin asked Osho if the religious movement he was involved in in America was doing anything generally positive for the spiritual development of the world, and whether he should remain in it.
He said that on the positive side he felt the people involved in it were really interested in bringing God to people, but on the negative side he felt they were rather moralistic and had rigid and fixed characters.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 24
8 January 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says: I just don’t have any control over what happens anymore. I don’t even know who I am anymore.]
No need to know! That need is the trouble. There is no need to know. One should just move wherever life takes one. Trust life! This is mind interfering and trying to control; to manage and to manipulate.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 25
9 January 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says: I have difficulty accepting other people s looks of disapproval, particularly now that I’m wearing orange. I seem very sensitive to it. I was wondering if you could suggest something I could do.]
That’s the whole purpose of orange – so that you cannot hide yourself, and so that you stand out.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 26
10 January 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says: I’m isolating myself – and I feel I should be doing something else. At first I felt good alone, but now it’s changed.]
Then move out of it! One should always be watchful, because if one is not feeling happy in any situation, in any mood, then one should come out of it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 27
11 January 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[An Indian sannyasin had come before darshan to talk to Osho about a frightening experience he had had recently while meditating. As people arrived for the darshan Osho was saying:]
... one gets really scared. Really, it came too early and you weren’t yet ready. It can happen that suddenly a key fits, and then the experience of deep meditation is exactly like death.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part28/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 28
12 January 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[The sannyasins who had done the Aum marathon had darshan this evening.
The groupleader says: I’ve been a leader in the West... I’ve never had anyone to account to. I started to look at what I’m doing, and I realise that a lot is wanting to please you, to get your approval. I think that was important for me.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>29</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part29/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 29
13 January 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says: My mind is doing a beautiful job of driving me crazy! But I feel that mostly I’m witnessing, rather than doing anything about it.]
Just be a witness. Don’t do anything about it, because anything that you do can never be very deep.
It can be at the most a temporary arrangement.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
13 December 1975 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[The first sannyasin Osho addressed had sent him a letter earlier saying that she was in a deep loving relationship with her husband, but at the same time she felt attracted to someone else.]
Two things to remember. The first: love grows only in deep intimacy and trust. If you change persons, from A to B, from B to C, it is as if you are transplanting your being from one place to another.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>30</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part30/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 30
14 January 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin said that when she meditated, many pictures would emerge which she liked to draw and become involved with.]
If pictures come it is a good release, so paint them; you continue it. Just go wild in it, and don’t paint through reason.
Don’t be worried about what you are making, because it is not a performance.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>31</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part31/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 31
15 January 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin said that since his girlfriend, also a sannyasin, had been involved in a serious car accident some months ago, she had changed quite dramatically, and seemed no longer to be the woman he had known before.
Osho said he felt that she was in a very deep crisis, and in need of much tolerance and care.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
14 December 1975 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Now a few things have to be understood, mm? No relationship can be secure. It is not the nature of relationships to be secure. And if any relationship is secure, it will lose all attraction.
So this is a problem for the mind. If you want to enjoy a relationship, it has to be insecure.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
15 December 1975 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[An elderly woman, the mother of a sannyasin who was also present, says: I turned my back on religion many years ago, so I’ve been saying no for a very long time.]
That’s very good! I was talking about you this morning! (Osho had talked about yea-sayers and no-sayers that morning in the discourse.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
16 December 1975 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says she is feeling anxious about leaving.]
Mm mm... just relax and don’t become anxious about it because anxiety disturbs everything. It doesn’t help in any way; it creates only more and more hindrances. If you love and anxiety comes in, it creates a distance and then the relationship becomes a burden.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
19 December 1975 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Rikta means emptiness, deva means divine – divine emptiness.
That is how you, by and by, have to imbibe the spirit of emptiness in you. Inside there is just emptiness, mm? That is how I feel your seed is. The more empty you feel, the more empty you can become. And you can feel it easily, it will not be difficult; it will just come naturally.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
21 December 1975 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A visitor – not a sannyasin – asked through a translator if Osho could explain to her the meaning of an experience she had had two years ago.
She described the experience as one in which she felt like an empty box, nothing was there. It reached a point where she couldn’t remember her name, or who she was.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/hammer_on_the_rock/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
22 December 1975 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Two sannyasins, who were returning to England and wanting to start a centre, asked Osho if they should approach the local mental hospital to introduce the meditations to the patients.]
Yes, you can help them to do some dynamic types of meditations. That will help very much because mad people need nothing else but catharsis.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
