<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Wings of Love and Random Thought on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/wings_of_love_and_random_thought/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wings of Love and Random Thought on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/wings_of_love_and_random_thought/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chapter #1</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/wings_of_love_and_random_thought/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/wings_of_love_and_random_thought/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter #1‌ Chapter title: Wings of Love, pages 1 to 26 Date Unknown
Archive code:
6900000
ShortTitle:
RANDOM01
Audio:
No Video: No
REAL TRUTH IS WHAT IS EXPERIENCED AS SUCH
Realization of Truth, of the Supreme Soul, and of what we really are, is not a matter of intellectual deliberation or mental reflection. Only those of us are able to comprehend Truth who nurture their worthiness and receptivity by ceaseless practice.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter #2</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/wings_of_love_and_random_thought/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/wings_of_love_and_random_thought/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter #2‌ Chapter title: Wings of Love, pages 27 to 48 Date Unknown
Archive code:
6900000
ShortTitle:
RANDOM02
Audio:
No Video: No
SECOND LINK -- LOVE OF OTHERS
What is the second link in this upward flight of love? The first link, as we have seen, is the love of oneself. The second one is loving others. You will never be successful in your progress towards that love which takes you to God, unless you have abundant good will, unlimited love, overflowing kindness and plenty of grace towards all living beings.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter #3</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/wings_of_love_and_random_thought/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/wings_of_love_and_random_thought/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter #3‌ Chapter title: Random Thoughts, pages 49 to 76 Date Unknown
Archive code:
6900000
ShortTitle:
RANDOM03
Audio:
No Video: No
1. To which religion do I belong? To none. Dharma in the sense of virtue, piety, justice, equity, decorum etc. has a real existence. But in the sense of religious cults and sects it has no existence whatsoever. The unreal existence of the so- called cults and sects has obstructed the manifestation of the real dharma.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter #4</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/wings_of_love_and_random_thought/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/wings_of_love_and_random_thought/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter #4‌ Chapter title: Random Thoughts, pages 77 to 105 Date Unknown
Archive code:
6900000
ShortTitle:
RANDOM04
Audio:
No Video: No
34. We live life only when we touch our ultimate depth.… Otherwise we simply exist.
The difference between simple existence and living life is as much as the difference between dying and living.
35. What is the meaning of dharma? It means the movement from the mud to the lotus.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter #5</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/wings_of_love_and_random_thought/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/wings_of_love_and_random_thought/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌Chapter #5‌ Chapter title: Random Thoughts, pages 106 to 143 Date Unknown
Archive code:
6900000
ShortTitle:
RANDOM05
Audio:
No Video: No
159. Wherever I cast my eyes I see the thrill and throb of life. Every bit is vibrating with life. And the minutest atom is excited with the love to live. Behold the dance of life and hear the music of being. Even if you neither see nor hear, there is the titillating, pulsating, experience of life.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
