<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Don\&#39;t Let Yourself Be Upset by the Sutra, rather Upset the Sutra Yourself on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Don\&#39;t Let Yourself Be Upset by the Sutra, rather Upset the Sutra Yourself on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
1 August 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem Birgitta. Prem means love; birgitta means strength, power, energy.
Love makes you strong, makes you powerful, because love transforms your possibilities into actualities. It transforms the seed into a sprout, it transforms the potential into the real. Without love one is empty, with love one is overflowing. Without love one is a beggar, with love one is an emperor.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
10 August 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem Anastasia. Prem means love; anastasia means resurrection.
Love is the only energy that never dies. Each death only becomes a new birth. Everything else is momentary, except love: love is timeless.
That’s why Jesus says love is God. Love is our only experience through which we can have a glimpse of what God is.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
11 August 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says he has had many professions but always felt “It’s not that.” He asks Osho what to do to find his way.]
It has nothing to do with what you are doing but with what mind you are doing it. With the same mind nothing will satisfy you. You can go on changing but you remain the same.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
13 August 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand Liesbeth. Anand means bliss; liesbeth means one who worships God. The full name will mean a blissful worshipper of God.
God can be worshipped either out of fear or out of love. If the worship is out of fear it is false, it is a sheer wastage of time. The worship is true and significant only when it is out of love, when it is out of bliss, when it is out of gratitude.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
14 August 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem Lin. Prem means love; lin means beautiful.
Love is always beautiful. Love cannot be otherwise; if it is, then it is not love. Then something else is hiding behind it; then love is only a facade, a deception, a pretension. If love is really there it is bound to be beautiful. Not only that it is beautiful: whatsoever it touches becomes beautiful, it creates beauty.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
15 August 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva Margaret. Deva means divine; margaret means a pearl – a divine pearl.
Man is oblivious of his own treasures because he never looks within; his eyes are focused on the outside. He goes on searching everywhere except into his own self. The search is bound to be futile because the treasure is within; it is not without.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
16 August 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva Werner. Deva means divine; werner means a friend.
Friendship is one of the most significant qualities, particularly for a seeker of truth, because truth can be known only if you befriend existence. If you antagonize existence, existence will not allow you its innermost secrets. You have to befriend nature, both without and within; you have to be in a loving relationship with all that is.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
17 August 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem Lyn. Prem means love; lyn comes from a German word “lindy”; lindy means serpent. It is a symbol of wisdom. The serpent power is our intrinsic power. It is called serpent power because it is coiled up like a serpent at the root of our being. It can uncoil, and the uncoiling of it is the real growth.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
18 August 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva Marc. Deva means divine; marc means war – divine war.
There is a constant war between the evil and the good, between the forces of darkness and the forces of light, between that which brings you down and that which uplifts you.
One has to be very conscious in choosing sides. And it is an every moment affair.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
19 August 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Das Satyen. Das means a slave; satyen means truth – a slave of truth. And swami means a master.
It is a paradox, but existence is full of paradoxes. In fact if something is not paradoxical it cannot have much value, it cannot have much depth, it cannot be profound. If something looks very logical it means it is very superficial.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
20 August 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Atmo Kim. Atmo means the innermost self, the supreme self; not the ego, but the self.
The ego is superficial. It is in fact given by others to you; it is not yours. It is based on the opinion of others. Somebody says you are beautiful, somebody says you are intelligent, somebody says you are kind, compassionate, and the ego is gathering.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
2 August 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva Giacinta. Deva means divine; giacinta means beautiful – divine beauty. All beauty is divine; God expresses himself as the beautiful. It may be the beauty of a poet, the beauty of music, the beauty of a painting, the beauty of a flower or the clouds. Wherever beauty is, God is; beauty is his main expression.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
21 August 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva Ethel. Deva means divine; ethel means noble.
Man remains an animal unless something of the divine penetrates him. Man is just an animal without God. But the uniqueness of man consists in his being able to become available to God; no other animal can become available. All other animals remain closed; they live a closed life, absolutely preconditioned, destined.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
22 August 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva Martha. Deva means divine; and Martha was a disciple of Jesus and has a very special thing about her: she was the greatest hostess in Jesus’ life. She cared for, served, looked after Jesus; hence her name has become the symbol of a great host. And that’s what everybody has to become: a great host to God.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
23 August 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand Friederike. Anand means bliss; friederike means rule of peace. Your full name will mean rule of bliss and peace. Peace alone can become cold, can become unloving, can become a kind of death, can easily go negative. There is every possibility that it will be the peace of a cemetery – not of life but of death.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
24 August 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand Barbara. Anand means bliss; barbara means a stranger.
The world becomes misery if you start thinking that you are part of it; if you become identified with it, then it is going to become a misery. Identification is the root cause of all misery. If you can remember that you are a stranger here, a visitor, a tourist, only for a few days, and the world is not more than a caravanserai – we stay the night and in the morning we go – if you can remain alert of this phenomenon, that we come from somewhere else and one day we have to go back to the original source, then bliss starts growing in you like roses in a rosebush.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 24
25 August 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva Louis. Deva means divine; louis means glory – divine glory. It is a seed in us, hence we are unaware of it. It is yet a potential, that’s why we are oblivious of it. It has to be realized. It is a journey to be made; it is a promise to be fulfilled.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 25
26 August 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem Maria. Prem means love; maria means rebellion. Love is the greatest rebellion because it is rebellion against the head, rebellion against logic, rebellion against all that is mundane.
Love means entering into the temple of the heart. One has to renounce the head. Love means entering into the world of paradox. One has to drop the whole logical structure of the mind.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 26
27 August 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem Els. Prem means love. Els comes from the Hebrew root “el”; it means divine, godly.
Love is the most divine phenomenon in existence. It is the highest peak. Nothing is higher than love. It opens the doors to all the mysteries of existence, it is the master key. One who knows love is bound to know God sooner or later.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 27
28 August 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand Terry. Anand means bliss, terry means wealth and peace. Bliss is both. It is wealth, the real wealth, wealth that cannot be stolen; not even death can take it away. And it is peace, it is ultimate peace, indestructible. There is no way to disturb it. Disturbances can be created but they will remain just the cyclone – and bliss remains the center of the cyclone, absolutely undisturbed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part28/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 28
29 August 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand Phillip. Anand means bliss, and Phillip is the name of one of the disciples of Jesus, one of the twelve apostles – a blissful disciple.
One can become a disciple only through blissfulness. Disciplehood is not born out of sadness. It is the most cheerful phenomenon possible because it is love in is highest form.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>29</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part29/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 29
30 August 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva Pim. Deva means divine; pim means resolution.
The mind is always indecisive. That is one of the basic characteristics of the mind, indecisiveness. The moment a resolution arises in you the mind disappears. To be decisive is to go beyond the mind; to remain indecisive, hesitant, divided, is to live in the mind.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
3 August 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem Bernardina. Prem means love. Bernardina literally means a bear’s heart, but metaphorically it means the sacred heart... because in ancient Teutonic mythology the bear was thought to be a sacred animal, just as in India they think the cow is a sacred animal. Your full name will mean love, the sacred heart.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>30</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part30/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 30
31 August 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand Silke. Anand means bliss; silke comes from a Latin word “cecilia. Cecilia was a virgin martyr, and she became very famous because while she was tortured she danced and she sang. She died with a song; singing she died, hence she became the patron saint of music. That’s the way to live and die, singing</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>31</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part31/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 31
1 September 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Bliss is what we are after, Osho is saying.]
Even if people are seeking God, they are seeking in order to find bliss. If by finding God you find a state of misery, you will not seek God. Hence God is not really the goal of the search but only a means to attain bliss.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>32</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part32/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part32/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 32
2 September 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Love is the only thing on the earth which is heavenly. Everything else is earthly, hence love is the only door to God. Those who love are bound to find God. It has never happened to persons who have not known love.
Start remembering it from this very age; this is the time when children get corrupted.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>33</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part33/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part33/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 33
3 September 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Dhyan Anna.]
Prayer without meditation remains part of the imagination. You create a kind of hallucination around yourself. You don’t know what God is but you start having a dialogue with him. This dialogue is not really a dialogue, it is a monologue you are talking to yourself. It is a kind of religious neurosis – it is not true prayer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>34</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part34/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part34/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 34
4 September 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Dhyan Annette. Dhyan means meditation, a state of no-mind, a state of no-thought... just a pure sky of your consciousness, with no clouds of emotions, thoughts, memories, imagination, dreams. All clouds have gone, the sky is utterly empty. That is the state of dhyan, meditation. And Annette means mercy.
Out of this state of no-mind, mercy flows, compassion arises.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>35</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part35/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part35/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 35
5 September 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[God is everywhere, except in the temple, Osho explains.]
Bliss is the only experience that gives you a taste of God. For a moment it transports you into another world where you are worldly no more; for a moment you are human no more, you are divine. The moment of bliss is the moment of God penetrating you and of you penetrating God; it is an orgasmic experience with God.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>36</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part36/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part36/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 36
6 September 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Anand means bliss Osho tells him, and manuel means God is with us.]
That’s the very foundation of being blissful, that God is with us. Without God we are lonely, without God existence is empty; without God there can be no meaning, no significance. We can be blissful because God is. And God is always with us.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>37</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part37/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part37/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 37
7 September 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Satyam Jon: truth, Gods gracious gift]
We are it, hence one has not to seek it somewhere else. Seeking it is a sure way of missing it. All seeking is desire, and desire takes you farther away from yourself. Desire is nothing but a way of going away from oneself. Desire is escaping from oneself – even the desire for God or the desire for truth.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>38</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part38/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part38/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 38
8 September 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Adam represents rebellion, Osho tells the ten year old boy.]
He rebelled against God, he rebelled against the authoritarian forces. He is not only the first man, he is the first revolutionary too. And I have tremendous respect for rebellion, because one grows only through rebellion; one becomes oneself only through – by going into – deep rebellion.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>39</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part39/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part39/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 39
9 September 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem Alice. Prem means love; alice means truthful one, noble one, cheerful one. They are all the three great qualities – truth, nobility and cheerfulness – but they all come through love!
Bliss is the ultimate goal of life, and the people who become blissful, naturally become messengers of God; not that they have to do something – their very blissfulness becomes a message to the world, their very cheerfulness is heard far and wide.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
4 August 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin accompanies her fourteen-year-old daughter to take sannyas.]
Anand Erika. Anand means bliss; erika means brave, courageous. Bliss is only for the courageous. The coward lives in misery. The coward has to live in misery because he clings to the past, he clings to that which is already known, he clings to the familiar.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>40</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part40/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part40/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 40
10 September 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Sannyas is an upsurge from the heart, not a rational conclusion]
The mind can conclude but can never be resolute, because every conclusion is only hypothetical: maybe it is true, maybe it is not. And any new fact found tomorrow may change the whole thing. Science works through hypothesis, but each hypothesis is only true for the time being.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>41</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part41/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part41/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 41
11 September 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Love is the source of wisdom, mind... ]
It is worldly, it can’t be sacred. The sacred arises out of the heart; it is intuitive, not intellectual. It is less logical, more paradoxical. It is rooted in love, not in logic, and love is the greatest mystery in existence. Love becomes the door to the divine.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>42</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part42/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part42/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 42
12 September 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Disconnect yourself from love and you miss God]
Love connects you with the source of all the energies. That source is God. Without love we live in a disconnected state, hence a very tiny amount of energy remains available to us. That too is in spite of us, because we cannot be absolutely disconnected from God, otherwise we will die.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>43</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part43/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part43/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 43
13 September 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand Vincent. Anand means bliss and vincent means a conqueror – one who has conquered bliss. That the real conquest in life; all else is just rubbish. Money power, prestige, all those things are for insane people The sane person conquers bliss.
Prem Ron. Prem means love: ron means mighty power. Power has two dimensions: the masculine and the feminine the aggressive and the receptive, the destructive and the creative.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>44</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part44/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part44/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 44
14 September 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Blanka means white, the most paradoxical of colors]
In one sense it is a color and in one sense it is not. It is a color because it contains all the colors; the whole spectrum of the rainbow is contained in white. And yet it is not a color at all because it is neither red nor blue, nor green – it is a transcendence of colors.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>45</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part45/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part45/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 45
15 September 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Become a prayer of rejoicing. Jesus says again and again to his disciples: Rejoice, rejoice, I say unto you, rejoice! He is telling them the true meaning of prayer: dance it, sing it, let it be a gratitude, a great thankfulness. Then it reaches, it succeeds, it is heard. Then it becomes a communion between you and God, it becomes a bridge.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>46</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part46/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part46/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 46
16 September 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Dhyan Andrea: great courage is needed for meditation]
In fact the greatest courage, because it is the journey into the unknown, the uncharted, and one has to go without any map and one has to go without any guide. One has to go utterly alone, because it is an inner journey: you cannot take any companion with you.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>47</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part47/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part47/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 47
17 September 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[The church equates sadness and sobriety with saintliness]
Because of that, religion become more and more crowded by pathological people. Healthy people started avoiding religion, because health is bliss and health is cheerfulness. It is only the unhealthy – physically or psychologically – who are sad; sadness is a symptom of disease. But for so many centuries we have respected sadness, we have made it the most fundamental quality of a saint.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>48</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part48/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part48/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 48
18 September 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[We are trying to grasp that which we already have.]
Everyone is blessed by the divine. A few know it; many more remain oblivious of the fact, hence there is so much misery. Misery is fictitious, it is not real. It is only there because we have not known our blessedness. It is the absence of our knowing that we are already blessed that makes us miserable, and then we try to find bliss, joy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>49</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part49/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part49/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 49
19 September 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand Gerard. Anand means bliss; gerard mean brave, courageous, and it also means a loyal heart – a blissful, courageous, loyal heart. And these are the basic qualities of a religious consciousness.
Religion has nothing to do with seriousness; seriousness is pathology. Religion is playful, sportlike, it is fun. Prayer is playing with God, and it is possible only if one remembers that one has to continuously choose to be cheerful.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
5 August 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand Gitta. Anand means bliss; gitta comes from a root which means bridge.
Bliss is the bridge. Nobody ever has entered into God without being blissful. The doors are closed for miserable people. Those who cling to misery will remain without God, because misery disconnects you from existence, it isolates you. Misery makes you an ego.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>50</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part50/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part50/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 50
20 September 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Prem Paula]
The moment you say God, it creates an idea of a person, which is dangerous because there is no person, there is no God as a person. When you say love it does not give you any idea of a person; it simply gives you a vision, a vision of loving energy – a presence, not a person.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>51</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part51/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part51/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 51
21 September 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Veet Richard – to go beyond all hardness. Hardness has been revered in the past, but all it does is desensitize you... ]
It creates a good soldier but does not create a good human being. It makes a man violent, and to be violent is to fall below humanity. Man is man only because he is capable of love, and love arises only when the heart is soft, not hard.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>52</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part52/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part52/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 52
22 September 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Sitting silently, doing nothing, spring comes]
But there are things which cannot be achieved through effort, which are achieved only through effortlessness. Those are the things of the inner world the other world; they don’t belong to this shore. Bliss, love, prayer, God – they can’t be achieved through human effort.
Human effort is so small, it cannot contain such vast experiences.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>53</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part53/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part53/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 53
23 September 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand Gulab... Anand means bliss; gulab means a rose – a rose of bliss. Bliss is a flowering. Without bliss a man remains a tree without flowers. Only when you become blissful do you come to fulfillment – so remember it. This is the right time to begin remembering it, then it goes very deep.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>54</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part54/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part54/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 54
24 September 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho gives sannyas to two boys and addresses the parents]
Anand Binghi: bliss brother... Anand means bliss, and that has to become his education. Help him to be more and more blissful; avoid anything that creates misery. If we are a little more conscious, ninety percent of misery-creating patterns can be avoided by children.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>55</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part55/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part55/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 55
25 September 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Bodhi Patricia. We are all somnambulists unless bodhi happens, unless enlightenment happens. We are only awake for the name’s sake. Deep down there is sleep, an undercurrent of sleep continues, because an undercurrent of dreaming continues. You can catch hold of it any moment – close your eyes and see what is going on: there are dreams and dreams floating, a long procession of desires, thoughts, memories.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>56</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part56/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part56/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 56
26 September 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Benoit... God’s giving and our ingratitude.]
Each moment is so precious and brings so many surprises, but we are fast asleep. The guest comes, but the host is asleep. The guest knocks at the door, but the host is deaf. Otherwise the whole existence is continuously giving us a thousand and one gifts, and we are not even thankful to it; we go on complaining.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>57</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part57/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part57/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 57
27 September 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand Norbert... The three dimensions of bliss
The first dimension is peace, absolute peace, as if the lake of consciousness is without any waves, without any ripples even.
The second dimension is joy: joy for no reason at all, joy not caused by anything from the outside, joy simply arising out of you mysteriously, for no reason, with no cause at all – uncaused joy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>58</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part58/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part58/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 58
28 September 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, but love with a difference – not the love that we know but a love that is almost unknown to people.
People misunderstand their lust as love. The biological urge is not equivalent to love. Love is not biological, but spiritual. The biological urge can become a foundation for it, and it is a very solid foundation, but it is not all.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>59</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part59/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part59/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 59
29 September 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin asks of her three-year-old daughter, that she hates going to school and what to do?]
That’s very good! Every alive child hates school and education... just teach her whatsoever you can; no need to send her to school. In fact if all the schools, colleges and universities are closed for at least one hundred years humanity will be far better.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
6 August 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Chit Karin. Chit means consciousness; karin means clean.
Mind is like a mirror. Meditation is nothing but a cleansing of consciousness. It gathers dust: the dust of experience, the dust of thoughts, the dust of memories, the dust of desires; layers upon layers of dust. And it is natural: each mirror gathers dust, and mind is a mirror.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>60</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part60/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part60/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 60
30 September 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand Upale... Bliss is the object of our search...
The problem is that the more you seek it, the less you have it; everybody is seeking it, hence everybody is missing it. It is not something to be sought, it is not something that can be sought, it cannot be made a goal. For certain intrinsic reasons bliss is irreducible to a goal, because the goal is in the future and bliss is always in the present.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
7 August 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand Victor. Anand means bliss. Bliss is the purest form of happiness. Ordinary happiness is always followed by unhappiness as a shadow. Ordinary happiness is a mixed phenomenon, it is never without unhappiness. They are almost like two sides of the same coin: wherever one is, the other is also.
Bliss means: where unhappiness has disappeared completely, where the coin has only one side; the other side exists no more.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
8 August 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand Mark. Anand means bliss. Linguistically bliss gives the idea of happiness, joy, pleasure, but existentially it is something higher than happiness, greater than joy, deeper than pleasure. All those three things – happiness, joy and pleasure – are part of it, but it is not just the sum total of them. The total is more than the sum total of all the parts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_let_yourself_be_upset_by_the_sutra_rather_upset_the_sutra_yourself/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
9 August 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Veet Charlie. Veet means going beyond; charlie means man. Man is the only being in existence who can go beyond himself. This is man’s distinctive character. It defines him.
Aristotle says that man is a rational animal He thought that reason separates man from other animals he was wrong. Animals also have reason; the difference is only of quantity.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
