<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>That Art Thou on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/</link>
    <description>Recent content in That Art Thou on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 Sarvasar Upanishad</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Sarvasar Upanishad
8 January 1972 pm at Matheran Meditation Camp, India
AUM, SUPREME ONE, GUARD US (MASTER AND DISCIPLE) TOGETHER.NOURISH US TOGETHER.LET BOTH OF US STRIVE TOGETHER.LET OUR LEARNING SHINE BRIGHTLY. LET US NOT HATE ANYONE.AUM, SHANTI, SHANTI, SHANTI (PEACE).
To know and to be are one and the same. To be is the only way to know. And there are two dimensions of growth: one of knowledge and one of being.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Sarvasar Upanishad</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
Sarvasar Upanishad
13 January 1972 am at Matheran Meditation Camp, India
THAT WHICH IS AWARE OF THE CREATION AND DISSOLUTION OF THE KNOWER, THE KNOWN AND THE KNOWABLE, BUT IS ITSELF BEYOND CREATION AND DISSOLUTION IS CALLED THE sakshi OR THE WITNESSING SELF.
THAT WHICH DWELLS IN THE MINDS OF ALL BEINGS, FROM BRAHMA (THE CREATOR) DOWN TO AN ANT, AND WHICH LIVES EVERLASTINGLY EVEN AFTER THE DESTRUCTION OF THEIR GROSS AND SUBTLE BODIES IS CALLED THE KUTASTHA OR THE CREST- INDWELLER.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 Sarvasar Upanishad</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
Sarvasar Upanishad
13 January 1972 pm at Matheran Meditation Camp, India
WHEN THE SELF AS CONSCIOUSNESS, WHICH IS TRUTH, KNOWLEDGE, INFINITY, AND BLISS, DEVOID OF ALL ITS ATTRIBUTES, SHINES LIKE PURE GOLD FREED FROM ALL ITS FORMS SUCH AS A BANGLE AND A CROWN, IT IS CALLED TWAM OR THOU.THE BRAHMAN IS TRUTH, INFINITY AND KNOWLEDGE. THAT WHICH IS INDESTRUCTIBLE IS TRUTH.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Sarvasar Upanishad</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
Sarvasar Upanishad
14 January 1972 am at Matheran Meditation Camp, India
ETERNAL CONSCIOUSNESS, ITSELF BEYOND CREATION AND DESTRUCTION, IS KNOWN AS KNOWLEDGE.
THE CONSCIOUSNESS THAT IS WHOLE AND ALL-PERVADING, AND THAT PERMEATES THE ENTIRE COSMOS LIKE CLAY PERMEATING THE ARTICLES MADE OF CLAY, AND LIKE GOLD PERMEATING ARTICLES MADE OF GOLD, AND LIKE YARN PERMEATING ARTICLES MADE OF YARN, IS CALLED THE INFINITY.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 Sarvasar Upanishad</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
Sarvasar Upanishad
14 January 1972 pm at Matheran Meditation Camp, India
THESE FOUR (TRUTH, KNOWLEDGE, INFINITY AND BLISS) ARE THE CHARACTERISTICS, AND THAT WHICH IS CHANGELESS, IN SPITE OF SYMBOLIC OBJECTS LIKE SPACE, TIME, ET CETERA, IS CALLED TAT OR THAT, WHICH IS THE EQUIVALENT OF PARAMATMA OR THE SUPREME SELF.
That which is separate even from such definitive distinctions as thou and that, and which is as subtle as the sky and existence or being is, whose nature is called parabrahma or ULTIMATE BEYOND ULTIMATE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 Sarvasar Upanishad</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
Sarvasar Upanishad
15 January 1972 am at Matheran Meditation Camp, India
THAT WHICH IS BEGINNINGLESS AND YET WHICH ENDS, WHICH IS NEITHER BEING NOR NON-BEING AND WHICH IN ITSELF IS SEEN AS THE PUREST OF ENERGIES IS CALLED MAYA OR THE MAGICAL WORLD.
IT CANNOT BE DESCRIBED IN ANY OTHER WAY EXCEPT THIS.
THIS MAYA IS IGNORANCE-LIKE, PETTY AND UNREAL, BUT IS SEEN BY THE DELUDED PERSONS AS REAL AT ALL TIMES – PAST, PRESENT, AND FUTURE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 Sarvasar Upanishad</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
Sarvasar Upanishad
15 January 1972 pm at Matheran Meditation Camp, India
I AM NEVER BORN AS A BODY. I AM NOT THE TEN SENSES. AND I AM NEITHER INTELLECT, NOR MIND NOR EVERLASTING EGO
I AM ETERNALLY PURE SELF-NATURE WITHOUT VITAL BREATH AND MIND. I AM THE WITNESS WITHOUT INTELLECT, AND I AM THE EVERKNOWING SELF-NATURE. THERE IS NO DOUBT, WHATSOEVER, ABOUT IT.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 Sarvasar Upanishad</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
Sarvasar Upanishad
16 January 1972 am at Matheran Meditation Camp, India
I AM NOT THE DOER. I AM NOT THE CONSUMER. I AM SIMPLY THE WITNESS OF NATURE. AND JUST BECAUSE OF MY NEARNESS, THE BODY, ET CETERA, HAVE THE FEELING OF BEING CONSCIOUS, AND THEY ACT ACCORDINGLY.
BEYOND A SHADE OF DOUBT, I AM STILL, ETERNAL, EVERLASTING BLISS – EVERKNOWING PURE SELF OR SOUL.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 Sarvasar Upanishad</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
Sarvasar Upanishad
16 January 1972 pm at Matheran Meditation Camp, India
I AM THE BRAHMAN KNOWN BY THE WHOLE VEDANTA (THAT WHICH IS BEYOND ALL KNOWLEDGE). AND I AM NEITHER ETHER NOR AIR, NOR ANYTHING THAT I APPEAR TO BE.
I AM NEITHER FORM, NOR NAME, NOR ACTION, BUT ONLY BRAHMAN WHICH IS SATCHIDANANDA EXISTENCE, AWARENESS, AND BLISS).
I AM NOT THE BODY, SO HOW CAN I BE SUBJECT TO BIRTH AND DEATH?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 Kaivalya Upanishad</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
Kaivalya Upanishad
25 March 1972 pm at Mt Abu Meditation Camp, India
AUM.
MAY THE DIFFERENT LIMBS OF MY BODY – MY VOICE, MY NOSE, MY EYES, MY EARS, AND MY STRENGTH, AND ALSO ALL THE OTHER SENSE ORGANS BE NOURISHED, AND BECOME INTELLIGENT.
ALL THE UPANISHADS ARE MANIFESTATIONS OF BRAHMAN ITSELF. MAY I NEVER DENY BRAHMAN; MAY BRAHMAN NEVER DENY ME.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19 Kaivalya Upanishad</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
Kaivalya Upanishad
26 March 1972 am at Mt Abu Meditation Camp, India
THE SAGE ASVALAYAN APPROACHED THE LORD PARAMESHWAR, THE CREATOR BRAHMA, AND SAID, BHAGAVAN, TEACH ME BRAHMAVIDYA, THE HIGHEST SCIENCE OF REALITY, THE PATH TREADED ALWAYS BY THE GOOD PEOPLE, WHICH IS EVER A HIDDEN SECRET TO A MAN. DUE TO WHICH, DISCARDING ALL THEIR PAST SINS, THE WISE MEN REACH THE HIGHEST PURUSHA, THE BUDDHA-SELF.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Sarvasar Upanishad</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Sarvasar Upanishad
9 January 1972 am at Matheran Meditation Camp, Indi
WHAT IS BONDAGE? WHAT IS FREEDOM?
WHAT IS VIDYA (RIGHT LEARNING) AND AVIDYA (FALSE ONE)?
WHAT ARE THESE FOUR STATES: WAKING, DREAMING, SLEEPING AND TURIYA (THE FOURTH)?
WHAT ARE THESE FIVE KOSHAS (BODIES): SHEATHS OF FOOD, BREATH, MIND, KNOWING AND BLISS?
WHAT IS THE MEANING OF THE DOER, LIVING BEING, PANCHVARGA (FIVE GROUPS), KSHETRAGYA (KNOWER OF THE FIELD), SAKSHI (WITNESS), KUTASTHA (THE SUPREME) AND ANTARYAMI (THE IMMINENT)?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 Kaivalya Upanishad</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
Kaivalya Upanishad
26 March 1972 pm at Mt Abu Meditation Camp, India
NEITHER BY WORK NOR BY PROGENY NOR BY WEALTH, BUT BY RENUNCIATION ALONE IMMORTALITY IS ATTAINED.
HIGHER THAN HEAVEN, THE ULTIMATE TRUTH ABIDES IN THE CAVE OF THE HEART, SHINING, AND THE SINCERE SEEKER ATTAINS.
For religion, death is the basic problem – not life, because life IS. Life is not a problem; you have it, you are it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 Kaivalya Upanishad</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
Kaivalya Upanishad
27 March 1972 am at Mt Abu Meditation Camp, India
THOSE WHO HAVE PURIFIED THE MIND BY THE PRACTICE OF SANNYAS AND YOGA, AND THOSE WHO HAVE COME TO UNDERSTAND THE EXACT MEANING OF THE SPIRITUAL SCIENCE INDICATED IN THE UPANISHAD’S VEDANT, THEY IN THE END BECOME CAPABLE OF ATTAINING BRAHMALOK – THE WORLD OF BRAHMAN. AND LIBERATING THEMSELVES FROM EVERYTHING, THEY STRIVE TO ACHIEVE IMMORTALITY.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22 Kaivalya Upanishad</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
Kaivalya Upanishad
27 March 1972 pm at Mt Abu Meditation Camp, India
THEY HAVE UNDISTURBED SPACE, RESTING IN A COMFORTABLE POSTURE, CLEAN AND PURE, WITH THE NECK, HEAD, AND BODY IN ONE LINE; HELD ERECT, IN A MENTAL ATTITUDE OF SANNYAS, HAVING CONTROLLED ALL THE SENSES, SALUTING ONE’S OWN TEACHER, GURU, DEVOTEDLY, MEDITATE WITHIN THE LOTUS OF THE HEART; THE UNTAINTED, THE PURE, THE CLEAR AND THE TRANSPARENT, THE GRIEFLESS PRINCIPLE OF DEVOTION.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23 Kaivalya Upanishad</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
Kaivalya Upanishad
28 March 1972 am at Mt Abu Meditation Camp, India
THUS, BY MEDITATION, THEY ACHIEVE THE ULTIMATE REALITY , WHICH IS UNTHINKABLE, UNMANIFEST; THE ONE OF ENDLESS FORMS, THE EVER-AUSPICIOUS, THE PEACEFUL, THE IMMORTAL, THE ORIGIN OF THE CREATOR, THE ONE WITHOUT A BEGINNING, A MIDDLE AND AN END; THE ONLY ONE, THE NON-DUAL, THE ALL-PERVADING, THE CONSCIOUSNESS, THE BLISS, THE FORMLESS, THE WONDERFUL.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 Kaivalya Upanishad</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 24
Kaivalya Upanishad
28 March 1972 pm at Mt Abu Meditation Camp, India
BY MEDITATING UPON THE LORD PARAMESHWAR, CONSORTED BY MOTHER UMA, THE HIGHEST LORD, THE ALL-POWERFUL, THE THREE-EYED, AND THE EVER-SILENT, THE MEDITATOR REACHES HIM WHO IS THE SOURCE OF ALL MANIFESTATION, THE WITNESS OF ALL, AND WHO IS BEYOND ALL IGNORANCE.
Meditation is object-less. If you use any object, then it is not meditation; it becomes thinking.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25 Kaivalya Upanishad</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 25
Kaivalya Upanishad
29 March 1972 am at Mt Abu Meditation Camp, India
HE IS BRAHMA, HE IS SHIVA, HE IS INDRA. HE IS INDESTRUCTIBLE, THE SUPREME, THE SELF-LUMINOUS.
HE ALONE IS VISHNU, HE IS PRANA. HE IS SUN, FIRE; HE IS THE MOON. HE ALONE IS ALL THAT WAS AND ALL THAT WILL BE, THE ETERNAL.
KNOWING HIM ONE GOES BEYOND THE STING OF DEATH; THERE IS NO OTHER WAY TO REACH COMPLETE FREEDOM.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26 Kaivalya Upanishad</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 26
Kaivalya Upanishad
29 March 1972 pm at Mt Abu Meditation Camp, India
WISE MEN MAKE THEIR CONSCIENCE THE LOWER ARONY, THE CHURNING STICK, AND AUM, THE UPPER CHURNING STICK.
AND WITH THE HELP OF THESE TWO, THEY PRACTICE THE CHURNING OF KNOWLEDGE. IN THE FIRE OF KNOWLEDGE, BORN OUT OF
THIS FRICTION, THEY BURN ALL THEIR BLEMISHES AND BECOME FREE.
With the natural, the spontaneous, the spiritual voice, everything is total.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27 Kaivalya Upanishad</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 27
Kaivalya Upanishad
30 March 1972 am at Mt Abu Meditation Camp, India
THE SELF, DELUDED BY MAYA, IDENTIFIES WITH THE BODY AND DOES ALL ACTIONS. IN THE WAKING STATES IT IS HE, THE SAME SELF, WHO FINDS
GRATIFICATION THROUGH THE VARIOUS OBJECTS OF ENJOYMENT, SUCH AS WOMEN, FOOD, WINE,
ET CETERA.
IN THE DREAM STATE THAT VERY SAME INDIVIDUALIZED EGO EXPERIENCES PLEASURE AND PAIN IN A FIELD OF EXPERIENCES CREATED BY ITS OWN MAYA, THE LEAST APPREHENSIVE OF REALITY.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28 Kaivalya Upanishad</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part28/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 28
Kaivalya Upanishad
30 March 1972 pm Mt Abu Meditation Camp, India
URGED BY THESE ACTS DONE IN PREVIOUS BIRTHS, THE JIVA AGAIN COMES BACK FROM THE DEEP SLEEP TO THE DREAM OR THE WAKEFUL STATE.
THE JIVA, EMBODIED SOUL, THUS BORN IN THE THREE CITIES – GROSS, SUBTLE, AND CAUSAL BODY; FROM WHERE ALL DIVERSITIES HAVE SPRUNG UP. WHEN THESE THREE BODIES HAVE DISSOLVED COMPLETELY, ONLY THEN THIS SOUL BECOMES FREE FROM MAYA, AND ATTAINS ETERNAL BLISS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>29 Kaivalya Upanishad</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part29/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 29
Kaivalya Upanishad
31 March 1972 am at Mt Abu Meditation Camp, India
THAT WHICH IS THE SUPREME BRAHMAN, THE SELF IN ALL, THE ANCIENT SUPPORT OF THE UNIVERSE, SUBTLER THAN THE SUBTLE, AND ETERNAL, THAT ALONE THOU ART. THOU ALONE ART THAT.
THAT WHICH ILLUMINES THE WORLD OF RELATED EXPERIENCES LIVES IN THE WAKING, DREAM, AND THE PROFOUND SLEEP STATE.
ONE WHO REALIZES THAT BRAHMAN AND ARE I ARE ONE, IS LIBERATED FROM ALL BONDAGES.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Sarvasar Upanishad</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
Sarvasar Upanishad
9 January 1972 pm at Matheran Meditation Camp, India
THE SELF OR SOUL IS BOTH GOD AND LIVING BEING. BUT THE BODY, WHICH IS NOT THE SOUL, GETS INFECTED WITH A SENSE OF EGO, AND THAT IS WHAT IS CALLED LIVING BEING’S BONDAGE.
THE CESSATION OF THIS EGO IS WHAT IS CALLED FREEDOM.
THAT WHICH GIVES RISE TO THE EGO IS CALLED AVIDYA (FALSE LEARNING).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>30 Kaivalya Upanishad</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part30/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 30
Kaivalya Upanishad
31 March 1972 pm at Mt Abu Meditation Camp, India
DIFFERENT FROM ALL THAT CONSTITUTES THE EXPERIENCER, BHOKTA, THE EXPERIENCED – BHOGYA, AND THE EXPERIENCING – BHOGA, IN THE OF WAKING, DREAM, AND DEEP SLEEP.
I AM THE WITNESS, THE EVER-AUSPICIOUS, THE PURE CONSCIOUSNESS. I AM THE NON-DUAL BRAHMAN.
IN ME ALONE IS EVERYTHING BORN; IN ME ALONE THAT EVERYTHING EXISTS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>31 Kaivalya Upanishad</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part31/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 31
Kaivalya Upanishad
1 April 1972 am at Mt Abu Meditation Camp, India
I AM SMALLER THAN THE SMALLEST; I AM ALSO THE MOST VAST. I AM THE MARVELOUS COSMOS.
I AM THE ANCIENT ONE, PURUSHA – THE BASE OF ALL. I AM HIRANYAMAYA, THE EFFULGENT ONE, THE EVER- PERPETUAL.
Mind can reason, mind can think, but thinking is a limitation – and reason also.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>32 Kaivalya Upanishad</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part32/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part32/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 32
Kaivalya Upanishad
1 April 1972 pm at Mt Abu Meditation Camp, India
I AM THE INCOMPREHENSIBLE SHAKTI (ENERGY), I AM WITHOUT HANDS AND FEET.
I CAN SEE WITHOUT EYES, HEAR WITHOUT EARS, KNOW WITHOUT INTELLECT.
DEVOID OF ALL FORMS, I KNOW ALL; BUT THERE IS NONE WHO KNOWS ME,THE EVER PURE CONSCIOUSNESS.
This has been one of the most foundational questions for a religious seeker: whether the divine can be known, whether the divine can become an object, whether the divine can be encountered, whether I can meet him.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>33 Kaivalya Upanishad</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part33/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part33/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 33
Kaivalya Upanishad
2 April 1972 am at Mt Abu Meditation Camp, India
I, ALONE, AM THE THEME TAUGHT IN THE VARIOUS VEDAS. I AM THE REVEALER OF THE UPANISHADS, THE VEDANTA, AND OF THE VEDAS. I ALONE AM THE REAL KNOWER.
FOR ME THERE IS
NEITHER VIRTUE, PUNYAM, NOR SIN, PAPA.
I SUFFER NOT DESTRUCTION, NEITHER HAVE I BIRTH, NOR BODY, NOR SENSES AND MIND.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>34 Kaivalya Upanishad</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part34/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part34/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 34
Kaivalya Upanishad
2 April 1972 pm at Mt Abu Meditation Camp, India
FOR ME THERE IS NEITHER EARTH, NOR WATER, NOR FIRE, NOR AIR, NOR ETHER, AKASHA. THUS REALIZING THE NATURE OF PARAMATMA, THE SUPREME SELF, THE ONE WHO IS IN THE CAVITY OF THE HEART, WHO IS WITHOUT FORM, WITHOUT COMPARISON, ADVIDYA THE WITNESS OF ALL, BEYOND BOTH EXISTENCE AND NON-EXISTENCE, ONE ATTAINS THE SUPREME SELF.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>35 Adhyatma Upanishad</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part35/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part35/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 35
Adhyatma Upanishad
13 October 1972 pm at Mt Abu Meditation Camp, India THIS IS THE INVOCATION OF SHANTIPATH: AUM, LET THE SUN BE BENEFICENT TO US. LET VARUNA BE BENEFICENT TO US. LET ARYA BE
BENEFICENT TO US. LET INDRA AND BRAHASPATI BE BENEFICENT TO US. LET VISHNU BE BENEFICENT TO US.
SALUTATION TO THAT SUPREME, THE BRAHMAN.
O AIR, SALUTATIONS UNTO YOU, FOR YOU ARE THE IMMEDIATE BRAHMAN, THE SUPREME.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>36 Adhyatma Upanishad</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part36/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part36/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 36
Adhyatma Upanishad
14 October 1972 am at Mt Abu Meditation Camp, India
IN THE CAVITY OF THE HEART, WHICH IS SITUATED
IN THE BODY, DWELLS THE UNBORN WHO IS ETERNAL.
THE EARTH IS ITS BODY. IT DWELLS IN THE EARTH, BUT THE EARTH DOES NOT KNOW IT. WATER IS ITS BODY. IT DWELLS IN WATER,BUT WATER DOES NOT KNOW IT.
FIRE IS ITS BODY.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>37 Adhyatma Upanishad</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part37/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part37/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 37
Adhyatma Upanishad
14 October 1972 pm at Mt Abu Meditation Camp, India
BY KNOWING ONESELF AS THE INDIVIDUAL WITNESSING SELF OF THE INTELLECT, AND ALL ITS MOODS, AND CULTIVATING SUCH FEELINGS AS “I AM THAT,” ONE SHOULD RENOUNCE ANY IDENTIFICATION WITH ALL THINGS EXCEPT THE SELF.
AFTER CEASING TO FOLLOW OTHERS, ONE SHOULD CREATE A DISTANCE WITH ONE’S OWN BODY. THEN ONE SHOULD STOP FOLLOWING SCRIPTURES AND GIVE UP ONE’S IDENTIFICATION WITH THE SELF ALSO.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>38 Adhyatma Upanishad</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part38/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part38/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 38
Adhyatma Upanishad
15 October 1972 am at Mt Abu Meditation Camp, India
THIS BODY IS BORN OUT OF EXCRETA OF THE MOTHER AND THE FATHER, AND IS FULL OF FILTH AND FLESH; THEREFORE DISCARDING IT LIKE CHANDALA, THE LOWLY PERSON, BECOME ONE WITH BRAHMAN AND BE FULFILLED.
O SAGE, JUST AS AN INNER SPACE OF A POT IS MERGED WITH THE OUTER SPACE, ONCE THE POT IS BROKEN, MERGE YOUR OWN SELF WITH THE UNIVERSAL SELF; BECOME INDIVISIBLE AND ATTAIN ETERNAL SILENCE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>39 Adhyatma Upanishad</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part39/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part39/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 39
Adhyatma Upanishad
15 October 1972 pm at Mt Abu Meditation Camp, India
HE ALONE REALIZES THE SELF, WHO IS FREE FROM THE CLUTCHES OF EGOISM, AND SPOTLESS LIKE THE MOON; HE REMAINS EVER-BLISSFUL AND SELF-ILLUMINED.
CESSATION OF ACTION LEADS TO THE CESSATION OF ANXIETY, AND CESSATION OF ANXIETY LEADS TO THE ENDING OF DESIRE.
THE ENDING OF DESIRE IS FREEDOM, AND THIS IS WHAT IS CALLED JIVAN MUKTI, OR FREEDOM IN LIFE ITSELF.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Sarvasar Upanishad</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
Sarvasar Upanishad
10 January 1972 am at Matheran Meditation Camp, India
THE STATE IN WHICH THE SOUL, WITH THE HELP OF THE ENERGIES OF THE SUN AND OTHER GODS, AND THROUGH THE INSTRUMENTALITY OF THESE FOURTEEN: MIND, INTELLECT, MIND STUFF, EGO, AND THE TEN SENSE ORGANS – BECOMES SENSITIVE TO SOUND, TOUCH AND SUCH OTHER GROSS OBJECTS, IS CALLED THE WAKING STATE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>40 Adhyatma Upanishad</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part40/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part40/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 40
Adhyatma Upanishad
16 October 1972 am at Mt Abu Meditation Camp, India
ONE WHO HAS ATTAINED TO THE ETERNAL ABSOLUTE SHALL REMAIN SO EVEN AFTER DEATH. SO, OH INNOCENT, ATTAIN SAMADHI, THE HIGHEST STATE OF UNITY WITH THE SUPREME, AND BE FREE OF THE CHOICES.
THE KNOT OF IGNORANCE IN THE HEART IS DESTROYED, THE MOMENT ONE ACHIEVES SELF-REALIZATION, THROUGH NIRVIKALP SAMADHI, CHOICELESS AWARENESS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>41 Adhyatma Upanishad</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part41/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part41/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 41
Adhyatma Upanishad
16 October 1972 pm at Mt Abu Meditation Camp, India
THE APPEARANCE OF THINGS HAS ONLY BEEN IMPOSED UPON ONESELF. BY ELIMINATING IT, THE SELF BECOMES ABSOLUTE brahman, WHO IS THE WHOLE, ONE WITHOUT A SECOND AND WITHOUT ACTION.
THE APPEARANCE OF THE SELF IN THE FORM OF THE WORLD OF DIVISION IS FALSE, BECAUSE ONE THAT IS WITHOUT CHANGE, FORM, AND ORGANS CANNOT HAVE ANY DIVISIONS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>42 Adhyatma Upanishad</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part42/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part42/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 42
Adhyatma Upanishad
17 October 1972 am at Mt Abu Meditation Camp, India
DESIRELESSNESS IS THE PERFECT KNOWLEDGE.
AND THE PEACE THAT FLOWS FROM THIS EXPERIENCE OF INNER BLISS IS THE PROOF OF DESIRELESSNESS.] THAT WHICH DOESN’T HAPPEN IN SUCCESSION FROM AMONG THE ABOVE-MENTIONED STEPS INDICATES THAT THE STEP PRECEDING IT HAS BEEN FRUITLESS.
TO SHUN THE OBJECTS OF ENJOYMENT IS THE HIGHEST CONTENTMENT, AND THE BLISS OF SELF IS ITSELF INCOMPARABLE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>43 Adhyatma Upanishad</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part43/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part43/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 43
Adhyatma Upanishad
17 October 1972 pm at Mt Abu Meditation Camp, India
THE SUPREME SELF IS FORMED BY THE WORD “THAT” WHICH HAS MAYA, ILLUSION, AS ITS DISGUISE – WHICH IS THE SOURCE OF THE WORLD, WHICH IS INVESTED WITH THE QUALITY OF OMNISCIENCE, OMNIPRESENT, ET CETERA; WHICH IS MIXED WITH THE INDIRECTNESS, AND WHICH IS REALITY ITSELF.
AND THAT WHICH IS THE SHELTER OF THE I-EXPERIENCE, AND OF THE WORD “I” AND WHOSE KNOWLEDGE ABOUT HIS OWN INNER BEING IS FALSE, IS CALLED BY THE WORD “THOU” – TWAM.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>44 Adhyatma Upanishad</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part44/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part44/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 44
Adhyatma Upanishad
18 October 1972 am at Mt Abu Meditation Camp, India
THE ENQUIRY ABOUT THE ONENESS OF THE SOUL AND THE BRAHMAN TO THE GREAT SAYING LIKE “THAT ART THOU” IS KNOWN AS THE RIGHT LISTENING.
AND THINKING IN THE RIGHT WAY ON THE MEANING OF WHAT HAS BEEN LISTENED TO IS KNOWN AS RIGHT CONTEMPLATION.
AND TO HARMONIZE AND CENTER ONE’S MIND WITH THE MEANING, SHORN OF ALL DOUBTS – THAT WHICH IS DERIVED FROM RIGHT LISTENING AND RIGHT CONTEMPLATION IS WHAT IS KNOWN AS MEDITATION.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>45 Adhyatma Upanishad</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part45/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part45/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 45
Adhyatma Upanishad
18 October 1972 pm at Mt Abu Meditation Camp, India
AT THE TIME OF THIS SAMADHI, THE MOODS OF THE MIND TAKE THE FORM OF THE SOUL, AND THEREFORE THEY ARE NOT APPARENT.
BUT AFTER THE MEDITATOR HAS COME BACK FROM HIS SAMADHI, THOSE MOODS WHICH HAD DISAPPEARED, ARE INFERRED BY MEMORY.
IN THIS WORLD, WHICH IS WITHOUT A BEGINNING, ONE ACCUMULATES MILLIONS OF KARMAS CONDITIONING FROM ACTIONS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>46 Adhyatma Upanishad</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part46/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part46/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 46
Adhyatma Upanishad
19 October 1972 am at Mt Abu Meditation Camp, India
WHEN DESIRES DO NOT ARISE EVEN IN THE FACE OF THE OBJECTS OF ENJOYMENT, KNOW IT AS THE STATE OF VAIRAGYA – NON-ATTACHMENT, DESIRELESSNESS.
AND WHEN THE EGO CEASES TO RISE, KNOW IT AS THE HIGHEST STATE OF KNOWLEDGE.
WHEN THE MOODS THAT HAVE BECOME EXTINCT DO NOT ARISE AGAIN, THAT STATE IS KNOWN AS ONE OF THE INDIFFERENCE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>47 Adhyatma Upanishad</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part47/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part47/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 47
Adhyatma Upanishad
19 October 1972 pm at Mt Abu Meditation Camp, India
ONE WHO DOES NOT EVER DISCRIMINATE THROUGH INTELLECT BETWEEN THE INDIVIDUAL SELF AND THE SUPREME SELF ON THE ONE HAND, AND BETWEEN THE SUPREME AND THE UNIVERSE ON THE OTHER, IS CALLED A JIVANMUKTA.
ONE WHO TREATS EQUALLY BOTH THE NOBLE PERSON WHO DOES HIM HONOR, AND THE IGNOBLE WHO OFFENDS HIM, IS CALLED A JIVANMUKTA.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>48 Adhyatma Upanishad</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part48/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part48/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 48
Adhyatma Upanishad
20 October 1972 am at Mt Abu Meditation Camp, India
THE YOGI, BEING ALONE AND INDIFFERENT LIKE THE SKY, DOES NOT EVEN IN THE LEAST ATTACH HIMSELF WITH THE FUTURE.
EVEN AS THE ETHER INSIDE A WINE JAR REMAINS UNTOUCHED BY THE SMELL OF WINE, SO THE SELF, EVEN IN ASSOCIATION WITH ITS COVERING, REMAINS UNCONTAMINATED BY ITS NATURE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>49 Adhyatma Upanishad</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part49/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part49/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 49
Adhyatma Upanishad
20 October 1972 pm at Mt Abu Meditation Camp, India
PRARBDHAKARMA FULFILLS ITSELF ONLY WHEN ONE IDENTIFIES THE SELF WITH THE BODY, BUT IT IS NO GOOD IDENTIFYING WITH THE BODY. WHO WANTS TO SEVER THIS IDENTIFICATION AND FREE HIM SELF OF PRARBDHAKARMA, ILLUSION OF THE BODY IS THE BASIS FOR THE PROJECTION OF THE PRARBDHAKARMA.
BUT THAT WHICH IS PROJECTED OR IMAGINED BY ILLUSION CAN NEVER BE REAL.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Sarvasar Upanishad</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
Sarvasar Upanishad
10 January 1972 pm at Matheran Meditation Camp, India
THE SLEEPING STATE IS ONE IN WHICH ALL THE FOURTEEN ORGANS ARE STILL AND TRANQUIL, AND WHEN – FOR LACK OF REAL KNOWLEDGE – THE SELF OR SOUL IS INSENSITIVE TO SOUND, TOUCH AND SUCH OTHER OBJECTS. AND THE ONE WHICH IS AWARE OF THE CREATION AND DISSOLUTION OF THESE THREE STATES – WAKING DREAMING AND SLEEPING – BUT WHICH IS ITSELF BEYOND CREATION AND DISSOLUTION, IS KNOWN AS TURIYA – THE FOURTH STATE OF CONSCIOUSNESS, THE STATE OF TURIYA.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>50 Adhyatma Upanishad</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part50/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part50/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 50
Adhyatma Upanishad
21 October 1972 am at Mt Abu Meditation Camp, India
THE SCRIPTURES DO NOT SAY THAT THE BODY IS REAL FOR THE KNOWER, BUT THEY SAY SO FOR THE IGNORANT.
IN REALITY, THERE IS ONLY THE NON-DUAL SUPREME, WHICH IS ONE WITHOUT A SECOND, AND NOTHING ELSE EXISTS EXCEPT IT.
AND THE SUPREME IS KNOWN AS SOMETHING WITHOUT BEGINNING AND WITHOUT END – IMMEASURABLE, PURE, INNOCENT, EXISTENTIAL, CONSCIOUS, ETERNAL, BLISSFUL, IMPERISHABLE, ALL-PERVADING, NON-DUAL, ESTABLISHED ALWAYS IN ONENESS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>51 Adhyatma Upanishad</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part51/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part51/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 51
Adhyatma Upanishad
21 October 1972 pm at Mt Abu Meditation Camp, India
BY LISTENING TO THESE ABOVE TEACHINGS THE DISCIPLE ATTAINED KNOWLEDGE AND HE EXCLAIMED, “WHITHER HAS THAT WORLD GONE? WHITHER HAS GONE THAT WORLD I HAVE JUST SEEN? WHO DID IT TAKE AWAY? AND IN WHAT WAY HAS IT DISSOLVED? IS IT NOT IMMENSELY ASTONISHING THAT IT IS NOT?
WHAT HAVE I NOW TO RENOUNCE IN THIS GREAT OCEANLIKE BRAHMAN, WHICH IS WHOLE AND FULL OF A NECTAR OF BLISS?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Sarvasar Upanishad</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
Sarvasar Upanishad
11 January 1972 am at Matheran Meditation Camp, India
A COLLECTION OF SHEATHS COMPOSED OF NOURISHING FOOD, IN THE FORM OF THE PHYSICAL BODY IS CALLED THE ANNAMAYA KOSH, OR THE FOOD BODY.
THE FOURTEEN KINDS OF WINDS, LIKE THE VITAL ENERGY, ET CETERA, CIRCULATING THROUGH THE FOOD BODY, ARE CALLED THE PRANAYAMA KOSH, OR THE VITAL BODY.
Now, we have to go into an enquiry about the bodies.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Sarvasar Upanishad</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
Sarvasar Upanishad
11 January 1972 pm at Matheran Meditation Camp, India
WHEN THE SELF – LIVING INSIDE THE FOOD BODY – AND THE VITAL BODY THINKS THROUGH THE INSTRUMENTALITY OF THE FOURTEEN ORGANS LIKE MIND, ET CETERA, ABOUT OBJECTS LIKE SOUND, SMELL, TOUCH, ET CETERA IT IS CALLED THE MANOMAYA KOSHU OR THE MENTAL BODY.
WHEN THE SELF, UNITED WITH THESE THREE BODIES, KNOWS THROUGH INTELLIGENCE, IT IS CALLED THE VIGYANMAYA KOSHA OR THE KNOWING BODY.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 Sarvasar Upanishad</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
Sarvasar Upanishad
12 January 1972 am at Matheran Meditation Camp, India
IN THE CONTEXT OF PLEASURE AND PAIN, THE DESIRE FOR PLEASURABLE THINGS IS CALLED THE SENSE OF PLEASURE, AND AVERSION TO PAINFUL THINGS IS CALLED THE SENSE OF PAIN. AND BECAUSE OF WHAT ONE DOES TO GAIN PLEASURE AND SHUN PAIN, ONE IS CALLED A DOER.
SOUND, TOUCH, FORM, TASTE, AND SMELL – THESE FIVE OBJECTS ARE CAUSES OF PLEASURE AND PAIN.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 Sarvasar Upanishad</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/that_art_thou/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
Sarvasar Upanishad
12 January 1972 pm at Matheran Meditation Camp, India GROUPING OF MIND, VITAL BREATH, DESIRE, ESSENCE AND VIRTUE WITH THE ASSOCIATES IS CALLED PANCHVARGA, OR THE FIVE GROUPS.
A LIVING BEING IDENTIFIED WITH THE NATURE
OF THE PANCHVARGA CANNOT BE FREE OF THEM WITHOUT KNOWLEDGE OR KNOWING.
THE DISEASE ARISING OUT OF THE SUBTLE ELEMENTS LIKE THE MIND AND THE REST OF IT SEEMS TO BE COVERING THE SELF, AND IT IS CALLED THE SEED BODY; IT IS ALSO KNOWN AS THE KNOT, OR COMPLEX OF THE HEART.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
