<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Silent Period on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/silent_period/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Silent Period on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/silent_period/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/silent_period/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/silent_period/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌May 1982 pm in Lao Tzu House, Rajneeshpuram, Oregon, USA
[NOTE: This was published in THE RAJNEESH TIMES, 5th November 1982, while Osho was in silence.]
ED BRADLEY OF THE 60 MINUTES TEAM VISITED RANCHO RAJNEESH IN MAY TO GET FOOTAGE FOR LAST SUNDAY’S PROGRAM. SINCE IT WAS NOT POSSIBLE FOR HIM TO INTERVIEW OSHO DIRECTLY, HE SENT OSHO A LETTER CONTAINING FOUR QUESTIONS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/silent_period/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/silent_period/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌14 October, 1982 in INS Portland Oregon
[NOTE: This was published in THE RAJNEESH TIMES, 26th August 1983 while Osho was in silence.]
OSHO’S VISIT TO THE U.S. IMMIGRATION AND NATURALIZATION SERVICE WAS IN CONNECTION WITH AN APPLICATION FOR PERMANENT RESIDENCE IN THE USA, FILED ON HIS BEHALF A YEAR EARLIER. THESE EXTRACTS ARE HIGHLIGHTS OF WHAT OSHO SAID ABOUT HIS WORK AND VISION.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/silent_period/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/silent_period/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌1983 in Lao Tzu House, Rajneeshpuram, Oregon, USA
[NOTE: This was published in THE RAJNEESH TIMES, 19th August 1983 while Osho was in silence.]
INTERVIEW WITH KIRK BRAUN
Q: WHAT IS YOUR VISION FOR THE FUTURE OF RAJNEESHISM?
Osho: Rajneeshism is not a religion like Christianity, Hinduism, Mohammedanism, Buddhism, etc. The name should not be misunderstood. It simply shows a poverty of language – to be exactly true, Rajneeshism is a religionless religion.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/silent_period/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/silent_period/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌1983 in Lao Tzu House, Rajneeshpuram, Oregon, USA
[NOTE: This was published in THE RAJNEESH TIMES, 2nd September 1983 while Osho was in silence.]
OSHO EXPLAINS THE COMING CRISIS (IN A MESSAGE GIVEN BY SHEELA?)
Beginning next year, the world will face 15 years of catastrophic natural and man-made disasters – including nuclear war. Tokyo, San Francisco, Los Angeles, New York and Bombay all will be destroyed – but the holocaust to come will not be confined to these major population centers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/silent_period/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/silent_period/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌1983 in Lao Tzu House, Rajneeshpuram, Oregon, USA
[NOTE: This was published in THE RAJNEESH TIMES, 28th October 1983 while Osho was in silence.]
RAJNEESHISM ALLOWS EVERYONE INTO ITS FOLD, STATES OSHO
Our religion should not be categorized with any other religion of the world because it has not tradition or dogma and it allows everybody without any discrimination into its religious fold.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/silent_period/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/silent_period/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌19 August 1984 Rajneeshpuram, Oregon, USA
[NOTE: This was published in THE RAJNEESH TIMES, 24th August 1984 while Osho was in silence.]
EXCERPTS FROM THE WORDS OF OSHO DURING HIS DEPOSITION WITH MR. MCMURRAY
Your Honor, before I take the oath, I have to say few things, otherwise the oath will be a fraud. The first thing – I have always been against the ritual of oath-taking for the simple reason that if a man is capable fo lying he can lie even while he is taking the oath.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/silent_period/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/silent_period/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 7
1984 in Lao Tzu House, Rajneeshpuram, Oregon, USA
[NOTE: This was published in THE RAJNEESH TIMES, 26th October 1984 while Osho was in silence.]
Q: THIS MORNING SOME JOURNALISTS ASKED, “WHY DO YOU CALL YOURSELF A RELIGION?”
Osho: Ours is the only religion, first religion in the history of the world. All other religions were only experiments that failed. So not only say to them that we are a religion, say to them that we are the only religion.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
