<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>The First Principle on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_first_principle/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The First Principle on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/the_first_principle/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 6 - The Irrational Rationalist</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_first_principle/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_first_principle/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 6 - The Irrational Rationalist‌ 6 The Irrational Rationalist
16 April 1977 am in Buddha Hall Question
OSHO, DR. ABRAHAM KOVOOR HAS ATTACKED YOU IN AN ARTICLE
PUBLISHED BY THE WEEKLY CURRENT. WHAT DO YOU HAVE TO SAY ABOUT
IT?
I enjoyed it. It was sheer delight. It was delicious. It was simply far out. I enjoyed it because nobody else has complimented me so highly as he has done.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 6 - The Irrational Rationalist</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_first_principle/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_first_principle/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 6 - The Irrational Rationalist‌ And the mystics are the voyeurs par excellence. They penetrate to the very mystery of God.
You can ask Sigmund Freud. He says that the male energy starts seeking the female energy. That is natural. That&#39;s why the woman waits and the man takes the initiative. Even small children will play the game of doctor. And the woman will be the patient and the boy will be the doctor -- the voyeur!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 6 - The Irrational Rationalist</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_first_principle/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_first_principle/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 6 - The Irrational Rationalist‌ I am absurd.
You will think that Dr. Kovoor uses all these terms in a very condemnatory sense. That is his business -- that is his problem. I am a religious man. If I can find a rose flower, I don&#39;t bother about the thorns. If I can see that the black cloud has a white, silver lining, I dance for the silver lining; and I feel thankful for the black cloud also because without it the silver lining cannot exist.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 6 - The Irrational Rationalist</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_first_principle/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_first_principle/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 6 - The Irrational Rationalist‌ genius. He laughed and blew the candle out, and he said, &#34;Right now it has gone. Where? You have seen it! Where has it gone? &#34;
The coming and going is not from somewhere to somewhere. We arise out of the cosmic consciousness; we fall back into the cosmic consciousness. We arise again; we fall back again.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 6 - The Irrational Rationalist</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_first_principle/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_first_principle/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 6 - The Irrational Rationalist‌ If these are ill people, then who is healthy? Adolf Hitler? Mao Tse-Tung? Genghis Khan?
Tamurlane? Nadir Shah? Who is healthy?
He says meditation only creates derangement. He does not know even the ABCD of meditation. He has not even read about it. Experience is not the question at all; he has not even read about it. Or whatsoever he has read must have come from some people who are just like him.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 6 - The Irrational Rationalist</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_first_principle/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_first_principle/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 6 - The Irrational Rationalist‌ Even in sleep you go on chasing the mosquitoes. If an insect crawls on you, you throw it away, and sleep is not disturbed. Something keeps alert, surrounds you.
This is in ordinary life. When you become a meditator, this awareness becomes deeper, more crystallized. A point comes when you can sleep and yet remain awake.
I would like to invite Kovoor into my sleep, but my sleep is subjective.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 6 - The Irrational Rationalist</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_first_principle/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_first_principle/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 6 - The Irrational Rationalist‌ all what is truth and is adamant not to listen to anything which can disturb his dogmatic ideas, ideologies.
Now, a few nonserious questions. Question
OSHO, LIFE IS BEAUTIFUL, BUT I AM UNHAPPY. YOU ARE GIVING MUCH
LOVE, BUT I CANNOT TAKE IT. WHAT YOU SAY IS TRUE, BUT I CANNOT
FOLLOW IT. I WANT TO BE TRANSFORMED, BUT WHAT IS PREVENTING ME?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 6 - The Irrational Rationalist</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_first_principle/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_first_principle/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 6 - The Irrational Rationalist‌ You have enough time. And don&#39;t be so afraid of committing mistakes! That is the only mistake one has to avoid -- the only mistake, I say, that a man can commit in life -- and that is: becoming afraid of committing mistakes. Then you never grow, then you never go anywhere, then you never do anything. Then by and by you will slip into dullness and deadness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 6 - The Irrational Rationalist</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_first_principle/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_first_principle/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌Chapter 6 - The Irrational Rationalist‌ then comes back slowly, a little sad, sits back, starts eating. Rukamani asks, &#34;What is the matter? What happened? Where were you going so suddenly, as if there was some emergency? And now suddenly you turn back from the door and you are sad. What happened?&#34;
Krishna says, &#34;One of my lovers, one of my devotees, is passing through a capital and people are throwing stones at him and blood is flowing from his head and he has wounds, but he remains utterly helpless -- not a condemnatory word on his lips, not even in his mind.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 6 - The Irrational Rationalist</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_first_principle/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_first_principle/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 6 - The Irrational Rationalist‌ It is absurd. It cannot be so according to ordinary logic. But if you ask the physicist he says, &#34;What can we do? We are helpless. It is so. We cannot change the reality. Just to adjust to your logic, we cannot change the reality. And the reality does not believe in your Aristotles.
It does not suffer from Aristotle-itis.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 6 - The Irrational Rationalist</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_first_principle/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_first_principle/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 6 - The Irrational Rationalist‌ the effect. We cannot see them, but we can see their effect.&#34; The same say the mystics: &#34;God is not observed objectively, but we can see the effect.&#34;
Can&#39;t you see the universe running so intelligently? Can&#39;t you see tremendous intelligence permeating the whole?
And it is not only the mystics who say the universe is full of intelligence.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 6 - The Irrational Rationalist</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_first_principle/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_first_principle/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 6 - The Irrational Rationalist‌ never an objective fact for the father. Dr. Kovoor&#39;s wife may know to whom the son belongs, but not Dr. Kovoor. Dr. Kovoor, you may be misguided by your wife! And women are very strange creatures. What objective proof have you that this is your son? There is no possibility of any objective proof. You trust, you believe.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 6 - The Irrational Rationalist</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_first_principle/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_first_principle/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 6 - The Irrational Rationalist‌ Certainly somebody else is there hidden behind the breathing process: a witnessing intelligence.
That&#39;s what meditation is all about: to know the witness, to know the SAKSHIN, to know the observer.
Even if life comes out of chemicals, out of oxidization, even if life is prolonged by oxidization, one thing is certain: that life is far superior to these things.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 6 - The Irrational Rationalist</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_first_principle/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_first_principle/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 6 - The Irrational Rationalist‌ Can you find the dance when the dancer has gone? Or can you call a person a &#34;dancer&#34;
when he is not dancing? They are always together; the dance and the dancer are together. They are two aspects of one energy. Creation and creator are together.
In fact, my own choice is that I don&#39;t like calling God a &#34;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 6 - The Irrational Rationalist</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_first_principle/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_first_principle/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 6 - The Irrational Rationalist‌ form, that&#39;s what religions say. They say, &#34;God is hidden and is getting more and more expressed.&#34;
Man is yet the highest expression of that intelligence. The tree is a lower expression; the rock a still lower expression. But all are expressions of the same intelligence. Man, as far as we know on this earth, is the highest expression of that intelligence.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 6 - The Irrational Rationalist</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_first_principle/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_first_principle/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 6 - The Irrational Rationalist‌ The scientists say the whole earth can be reduced to the size of one orange. It is very porous. The whole of existence -- all the matter that exists in the whole of existence -- can be reduced to such a small size that you can carry it in your suitcase. All is porous; much space exists.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 6 - The Irrational Rationalist</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_first_principle/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_first_principle/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter 6 - The Irrational Rationalist‌ Second compliment: he says Rajneesh is an ignoramus. Perfectly true, sir. I don&#39;t claim any knowledge. I only claim ignorance, utter ignorance ... but that&#39;s what the Upanishads have been saying: those who say that they know, know not. That&#39;s what Socrates has been saying: &#34;I know only one thing: that I know nothing.&#34; These are all ignoramuses, and I am happy with this company -- the Upanishads, the Taoists, the Zen people, the Sufis.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
