<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Great Nothing on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_nothing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Great Nothing on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_nothing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_nothing/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_nothing/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
19 September 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin who is leaving says: I am facing new things which I have not faced before.]
Very good. This new space is your reality. Whatsoever you have known up to now was not really you. It was the identity given by others – the parents, the society, the world. Now you are coming to encounter yourself.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_nothing/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_nothing/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
28 September 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A visitor, motioned forward to take sannyas, asked first if he could say something: I have a very strong faith in Jesus Christ and this strength brought me out of a very deep bondage. I haven’t been able to discharge this help, so what I wanted to do was to build this love up more.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_nothing/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_nothing/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
29 September 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[To a visitor]
One thing has always to be remembered – that we are not to control the energy. We are just to help it wherever it is moving. We are not to direct it into a certain direction. We are just to help it wherever it is going. We have to go with it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_nothing/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_nothing/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
30 September 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine and naveen means new. The divine is never old, and that which is old is never divine. The divine is eternally new – it is divine because of its eternal newness.
So the whole effort, the whole purpose of sannyas, is to make you unconditionally new. It is not something that happens once and forever – it is something that is going to happen every moment of your life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_nothing/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_nothing/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
1 October 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A visiting journalist asked Osho if he could suggest a meditation technique or some hypnosis that would help a person who was conditioned against success, who would do everything to thwart any likelihood of succeeding.
Osho asked him if he had ever meditated, to which he replied that he was a Freemason and was currently involved in writing a treatise on a system of meditations for the organisation to which he belonged.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_nothing/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_nothing/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
2 October 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine and prasadam means a gift, a divine gift.And one should learn to treat one’s life as a divine gift. It is of immense value and one should not waste it. Because it has been given free we should not waste it. It has been given free because it is beyond value – but ordinarily people think it is valueless, as if there is no value to it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_nothing/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_nothing/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
3 October 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin said she went back to the West because her fifty-five-year-old father was dying of cancer.]
Not very old... but death makes no distinctions between the old and the young. Whenever it has to come, it comes. We are helpless against death, and that helplessness has been the very source of all religion.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_nothing/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_nothing/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
4 October 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says: I wrote you a letter about doing the healing during the camp. (See ‘Get Out of Your Own Way’ April 22nd, 1976, where Osho talks about healing, and a description of healing during the meditation camps.) I found out that it was not only giving to others, but that it also helped my need too.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_nothing/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_nothing/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
5 October 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine and vineet means humbleness. Humbleness is going to be your work. And when I say humbleness, I don’t mean what the word ordinarily means. Ordinarily it means a person who tries to subdue his ego, who tries to control his egoistic mind, who tries never to assert himself – a non-assertive person.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_nothing/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_nothing/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
6 October 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
The inner growth is not something that you can do anything about. At the most you can stop obstructing it, that’s all. Positively, nothing can be done. But if you stop hindering it, it goes on its own accord.
It is as if there is a small plant and you put a certain pressure on it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_nothing/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_nothing/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
7 October 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss and vandan means blessing. Bliss is a blessing – it is not something that you can do anything about. It is not something that depends on your effort – it is a gift. One has just to open towards it, that’s all. One has just to be available to it. If you don’t create any barriers for it, it will reach you.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_nothing/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_nothing/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
20 September 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says: I choose to be on my own to work, but then when I am alone I can’t bear it. I’m just tension and terror.
I’ve struggled for so many years with my neurosis, trying to survive, trying to make creative use of it – and everything’s gone.]
Your problem is that you don’t have any problems – you create them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_nothing/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_nothing/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
8 October 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine and shraddhan means trust. But remember that it doesn’t mean belief. Belief is a pseudo substitute for trust. Belief in fact is just the opposite of trust – notwithstanding what the dictionaries say. Belief is a head thing, and trust is of the heart. Belief is dead and borrowed – trust is alive and kicking.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_nothing/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_nothing/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
9 October 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine and mansukh means that your mind is your happiness. Manu means mind and suhka means happiness. So heaven is not somewhere else, it is just within you – and so is hell. They are not two geographical situations – they are inner attitudes... you create them. They are not things – they are just your mind trips.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_nothing/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_nothing/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
10 October 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A visitor says about taking sannyas: That’s the big fear – not the fear of being a sannyasin, but the fear of the betrayal of my previous initiation. It’s still there lingering on and I feel like a Judas or something.]
Not at all... not at all. That’s a very wrong attitude to take about things.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_nothing/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_nothing/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 23
11 October 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine and chitsukha means consciousness in bliss. Chit means consciousness, sukh means bliss; divine consciousness of bliss. And this you have to imbibe by and by into your being – the spirit of it – that just to be conscious is blissful. Whenever you lose consciousness, you descend into misery. Whenever you are unaware, you are miserable – or vice versa.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_nothing/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_nothing/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
21 September 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love and moradhi is one of the names of the god, Krishna. It means god, god of love. And to me the god of love is the only god. In fact love itself is the only god – all else is ritual. Love is the only true religion; and if you can love, you start growing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_nothing/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_nothing/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
22 September 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine and Bharat is the real name of India. It means divine India – and I give you this name because you have been in India in your previous life.
India is not this country’s real name; it is a given name – the real name is Bharat. The name comes from a very great emperor who renounced his kingdom and became a sannyasin.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_nothing/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_nothing/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
23 September 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A visitor says: The way I feel at the moment there is that there is no such thing as sannyas... Who is there to be a sannyasin?]
That’s the point to be understood. If you can understand that you are also not there, then you have understood rightly. But if sannyas is not there, religion is not there, meditation is not there, and you remain there, then you have not understood at all.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_nothing/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_nothing/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
24 September 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A visitor said she had never meditated before.]
Never? Then you can become a very good meditator! People who are never interested are very clean, and there is no loadedness in their mind. They can simply go into it. People who have been interested in meditation, who have been doing this and that, reading and philosophising, going to this guru and that, become too confused.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_nothing/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_nothing/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
25 September 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A couple ask Osho about their relationship. The man asked Osho what to do when one partner in the relationship is not interested in sex. He said he had tried following the advice Osho had given him before about the same situation – which was to follow his feelings – but it disturbed him that his partner felt hurt and upset.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_nothing/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_nothing/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
26 September 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A visitor said he had done Zazen; he liked Zazen but felt it was too mental, too much ‘in the head’.]
Mm.… One has to come into the body before one can go beyond the body. It looks a little paradoxical, but unless you come deep into the body, you can never be free of the body.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_nothing/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_great_nothing/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
27 September 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin said that he experienced difficulty in concentrating in meditations.]
The first thing – you should not try to concentrate. Concentration is not going to help you at all. Concentration will create a tension in the mind. Relaxation is going to help – not concentration. There are two types of people: there are people who can be helped by concentration, and there are people who can be helped only through relaxation – and both processes are different.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
