<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Long, the Short and the All on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_long_the_short_and_the_all/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Long, the Short and the All on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/the_long_the_short_and_the_all/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 Knowledge and understanding</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_long_the_short_and_the_all/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_long_the_short_and_the_all/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
Knowledge and understanding
Date Unknown
YOU ASK WHAT MY MESSAGE IS? It is a brief one indeed: those who are awake are alive; those who are asleep miss everything.
NO MAN IS GIVEN MANHOOD READY-MADE. He has to build it by himself. This is both a blessing and a bane. It is a blessing because there is always the possibility he will die without ever having become a man.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Truth and science</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_long_the_short_and_the_all/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_long_the_short_and_the_all/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
Truth and science
Date Unknown
THE EXPERIENCE OF TRUTH is neither a thought nor a feeling. It is a vibrating and a throbbing of all the vital components of your entire being. It is not in you; you are in it. It is your whole being, not just an experience that is happening to you. It is in you yourself, but it is larger than you because the whole of existence is included in it as well.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Religion and education</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_long_the_short_and_the_all/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_long_the_short_and_the_all/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
Religion and education
Date Unknown
WHAT IS THE AIM OF RELIGION? It is to awaken the slumbering superman in the ordinary man. This and this alone is religion’s goal.
YOU ASK FOR PROOF OF THE EXISTENCE OF GOD? Isn’t the existence of consciousness sufficient proof? Doesn’t a drop of water prove there is an ocean?
AT DAWN I watched the sparkling drops of dew gently and lovingly settling on the petals of the flowers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Thought and vision</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_long_the_short_and_the_all/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_long_the_short_and_the_all/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
Thought and vision
Date Unknown
I KNOW ONLY TWO TYPES OF MEN – those who have turned their backs on truth and those who have opened their eyes to truth. There are no other types of men.
THE POWER OF THOUGHT IS AS GREAT AS THE POWER OF ELECTRICITY. We have
understood the power of electricity, but most of us know nothing at all about the power of thought.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Life and death</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_long_the_short_and_the_all/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_long_the_short_and_the_all/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
Life and death
Date Unknown
WHEREVER I LOOK I SEE THE THRILL OF LIFE, the pulse of life. Everything is throbbing with life. Even the tiniest atom vibrates with the love of life. All around you the dance of life goes on; everywhere the symphony of existence is playing. Even if you can neither see it nor hear it, the delightful, exhilarating rhythm of life is there!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Love and happiness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_long_the_short_and_the_all/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_long_the_short_and_the_all/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 6
Love and happiness
Date Unknown
When I roam the lofty mountains I feel like my soul is raised on high and covered like the peaks in never melting caps of snow. And when I descend into the valleys I feel deep and profound like them and my heart fills with mysterious shadows. The same thing happens at the edge of the sea. There I merge with the surging waves; they pound and roar within me.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
