<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Path of the Mystic on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Path of the Mystic on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 Thoughts are always subversive</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
Thoughts are always subversive
4 May 1986 pm in Punta Del Este, Uruguay
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
YOU HAVE HAD PROBLEMS STAYING IN SOME COUNTRIES. IS IT BECAUSE YOUR THOUGHTS ARE SUBVERSIVE?
Thoughts are always subversive.
Only people who do not think are not subversive. Thinking is a crime. Jesus is crucified, Socrates is poisoned, Gautam Buddha is stoned. These people have not harmed anybody.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 You are not to be somebody</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
You are not to be somebody
9 May 1986 am in Punta Del Este, Uruguay
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
CAN YOU TALK MORE ABOUT THE RELATIONSHIP BETWEEN THE CONSCIOUS AND THE UNCONSCIOUS MIND? IT SEEMS THAT THE BRAIN HAS THE CAPACITY TO STORE AN EXPERIENCE, SAY, IN A MEMORY BANK. NOW IF THAT MEMORY ENDS UP IN THE UNCONSCIOUS, WHAT HAPPENS? IS IT THAT THE CONSCIOUS MIND REPRESSES IT AND TABS IT “CENSORED” OR DOES THE UNCONSCIOUS DO THE CENSORING?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 Ego is the greatest bondage</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
Ego is the greatest bondage
9 May 1986 pm in Punta Del Este, Uruguay
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHEN I LOOK AT A PERSON I SEE QUALITIES LIKE KINDNESS, INTELLIGENCE, SINCERITY, INNOCENCE, HARMLESSNESS, STRENGTH, HUMILITY, THAT SEEM TO BELONG TO THE BEING, AND NO MATTER WHAT THEY DO, THESE QUALITIES REMAIN. WHEN I SHARE THESE THINGS WITH PEOPLE THEY ALWAYS SEEM AMAZED AND DON’T REALIZE THAT THESE QUALITIES ARE THEIRS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Mind is the whole problem</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
Mind is the whole problem
10 May 1986 am in Punta Del Este, Uruguay
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
YOU SPOKE THE OTHER MORNING ABOUT RISING THROUGH THE DIFFERENT LEVELS OF CONSCIOUSNESS AND BRINGING LIGHT TO THEIR RESPECTIVE COUNTERPARTS IN THE UNCONSCIOUS. ARE SPECIAL TECHNIQUES NEEDED FOR THIS, OR WILL WATCHFULNESS OF THE MIND, THE BODY, AND THE EMOTIONS SIMPLY BRING US THROUGH THESE DIFFERENT LEVELS?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 Misery is nothing but choice</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
Misery is nothing but choice
10 May 1986 pm in Punta Del Este, Uruguay
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHEN I MEET WITH SOMEONE IN THE HEART I BECOME COMPLETELY INTOXICATED BY THE EXPERIENCE. IN THOSE MOMENTS I FEEL GLORIOUSLY FULFILLED AND ECSTATIC. A TREMENDOUS AMOUNT OF ENERGY STARTS MOVING IN MY BODY AND I FEEL TO GO TOTALLY WITH IT, TO LOSE MYSELF IN IT.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 Just by celebrating</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
Just by celebrating
11 May 1986 am in Punta Del Este, Uruguay
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
YOU HAVE TOLD US THAT THERE HAVE BEEN MANY ENLIGHTENED BEINGS WHO HAVE NEVER BECOME MASTERS. IT SEEMS ALMOST EASIER FOR ME TO UNDERSTAND THAT THAN WHY OR HOW SOMEBODY BECOMES A MASTER. WHEN I SEE THE WAY YOU ARE BEING TREATED, I WONDER. GOVERNMENTS FIGHT YOU, DON’T ALLOW YOU ENTRY, AND PUT YOU IN JAIL.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 The real riches</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
The real riches
11 May 1986 pm in Punta Del Este, Uruguay
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHEN RELAXING AND TURNING INWARDS THERE IS A MOMENT WHEN I EITHER BECOME SHARPLY AWARE, BEING AT THE SAME TIME TOTALLY RELAXED AS IF NOT THERE, OR I FALL ASLEEP. I DON’T KNOW WHAT TRIGGERS THE FIRST STATE RATHER THAN THE SECOND. COULD YOU PLEASE EXPLAIN?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 Treasures or dragons</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
Treasures or dragons
12 May 1986 am in Punta Del Este, Uruguay
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I HEAR YOU OFTEN SAYING THAT THE UNCONSCIOUS IS THE BASEMENT OF OUR MIND WHERE WE THROW ALL UNPLEASANT AND REPRESSED PARTS OF THE EXPERIENCES WHICH WE HAVE GONE THROUGH IN MANY LIVES BECAUSE OUR CONDITIONING DIDN’T ALLOW IT TO BE PART OF THE CONSCIOUS SPHERE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 Existence has no hurry</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
Existence has no hurry
12 May 1986 pm in Punta Del Este, Uruguay
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
SINCE I HAVE BEEN HERE WITH YOU AND LISTENING TO YOU SO CLOSELY, I SEE MY BODY – AND THE FEELINGS I HAVE TOWARDS IT – CHANGING A LOT. THE WAY I WALK, THE WAY I LOOK AT MYSELF WHEN TAKING A SHOWER, THE WAY I FEEL IN MY BODY – EVERYTHING SEEMS SO DIFFERENT TO ME THAT I CAN ONLY RECOGNIZE IT WITH AN ASTONISHED FACE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 Intelligence is our only treasure</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
Intelligence is our only treasure
13 May 1986 am in Punta Del Este, Uruguay
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
RAISED BY A FATHER WHO WAS PERFECTIONISTIC, OUTWARDLY NONJUDGMENTAL AND INWARDLY HYPERCRITICAL OF EVERYTHING AND EVERYONE, I NOW SEE MY CONDITIONING AS VERY MUCH OPERATING AT CROSS PURPOSES. I WAS HIT FOR BEING JUDGMENTAL AND OPINIONATED, YET URGED TO BE “DISCRIMINATING.” NOW I FEEL THAT SOMETHING IN MY INTELLIGENCE IS BLOCKED, IMPAIRED, HESITANT AND AFRAID.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19 The bliss of aloneness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
The bliss of aloneness
13 May 1986 pm in Punta Del Este, Uruguay
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
IT SEEMS THAT ONE OF THE GREATEST HURDLES THAT FACES A HUMAN BEING IS TO BE ALONE, TO STAND ALONE IN THE FACE OF THE OPINIONS OF THE WORLD, TO STAND ALONE IN THE FACE OF THE LIES OF THE WORLD, TO BE ABLE TO BE PHYSICALLY ALONE, AND, ULTIMATELY, TO BE ALONE WITHOUT EVEN OUR MINDS – THE COMPANION OF LAST RESORT.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Start the journey from the heart</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
Start the journey from the heart
5 May 1986 am in Punta Del Este, Uruguay
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHEN YOU SPEAK SO BEAUTIFULLY OF ENLIGHTENMENT, AWAKENING AND DREAMING, FOR ME THE DREAMING IS SO REAL THAT EVEN IMAGINING AWAKENING SEEMS IMPOSSIBLE. I WONDER AT YOUR BEAUTY, YOUR GRACE, YOUR LOVE, YOUR UNDERSTANDING, BUT TO BE IN YOUR PRESENCE SEEMS A SITUATION SO UNLIKELY FOR ME THAT IT MUST BE EITHER A DREAM OR SOME BIZARRE ACCIDENT.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 Tears of gratitude</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
Tears of gratitude
14 May 1986 am in Punta Del Este, Uruguay
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHEN I LISTEN TO YOU TALK ABOUT SUPERCONSCIOUSNESS AND THE BEAUTIFUL EXPERIENCES AHEAD OF US, I OFTEN FEEL LITERALLY UPLIFTED, AS IF MY BODY BECOMES WEIGHTLESS. ONLY MY HURTING BACK REMINDS ME THAT I AM STILL HERE! THIS EXPERIENCE IN YOUR PRESENCE IS SO PRECIOUS. BUT THIS FEELING CAN TURN INTO A PAIN WHICH IS NOT PHYSICAL.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 Only if love allows</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
Only if love allows
14 May 1986 pm in Punta Del Este, Uruguay
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHAT ARE YOUR VIEWS ON SEXUAL ETHICS?
My views on sexual ethics are against all the views that have been held up to now. They were all repressive of sex; they were condemnatory and created a split in the human mind. The whole schizophrenia and all the perversions of man are rooted in those wrong sexual ethics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22 The watcher is not amused</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
The watcher is not amused
15 May 1986 am in Punta Del Este, Uruguay
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
HOW DOES THE MAN OF ZEN TAKE HIS TEA?
For the man of Zen everything is sacred – even taking a cup of tea. Whatever he does, he does as if he is in a holy space.
There is a story about Moses. When he went on Mount Sinai to meet God and to receive the Ten Commandments, he saw a miracle happening: a green bush, lush green, and inside it a beautiful flame, fire.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23 Fall into trust</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
Fall into trust
15 May 1986 pm in Punta Del Este, Uruguay
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
IN THE SIXTIES AND SEVENTIES NEUROLOGISTS BECAME VERY INTERESTED IN AN AREA OF THE BRAIN STEM CALLED THE “RETICULAR FORMATION.” IT IS SAID THAT THIS IS THE AREA THAT FILTERS INPUT INTO THE BRAIN WHILE WE ARE ASLEEP. THUS, A MOTHER SLEEPS THROUGH ALL SORTS OF NOISES, BUT WAKES THE INSTANT HER CHILD CRIES – THIS FUNCTION WAS SAID TO BE ACHIEVED BY THE RETICULAR FORMATION.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 Meditation is a revolution in religion</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 24
Meditation is a revolution in religion
16 May 1986 am in Punta Del Este, Uruguay
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHEN I FIRST HEARD YOU SAY, “SITTING SILENTLY, DOING NOTHING, THE SPRING COMES AND THE GRASS GROWS BY ITSELF,” MY WESTERN MIND THOUGHT THIS WAS A METAPHOR, AND SOUGHT TO FIND THE MEANING. THEN I THOUGHT YOU REALLY MEANT TO SIT SILENTLY – AND I FELT IT WAS IMPOSSIBLE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25 Stealing the truth</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 25
Stealing the truth
16 May 1986 pm in Punta Del Este, Uruguay
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHEN YOU WERE RESPONDING TO THE QUESTION ABOUT WHETHER THE WATCHER IS AMUSED, I FOUND I SLIPPED INTO THE SPACE OF A WITNESS WHILE LOOKING INTO YOUR EYES AND FELT A MEETING HAPPENED. IT WAS SUCH A CLEAR, COOL MEETING, AND IN COMPARISON I SAW HOW STICKY, CUMBERSOME AND CONFINING ARE ANY OF THE EMOTIONS I HAVE EVER FELT FOR YOU AND THROUGH WHICH I THOUGHT I COULD MEET YOU.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26 I don\&#39;t answer your questions, I answer your hearts</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 26
I don’t answer your questions, I answer your hearts
17 May 1986 am in Punta Del Este, Uruguay
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
DURING THE DISCOURSES YOU GAVE IN POONA, YOU WERE OFTEN TALKING ABOUT SURRENDER. WHEN YOU WERE IN SILENCE SHEELA WAS MISUSING THE SENSE OF SURRENDER TO MAKE PEOPLE OBEDIENT, AND THEN, EVEN HEARING THE WORDS “JUST SURRENDER” MADE ME FEEL CLOSED.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27 Something that knows no going back</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 27
Something that knows no going back
17 May 1986 pm in Punta Del Este, Uruguay
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHAT DID YOU DO IN THOSE YEARS IMMEDIATELY AFTER YOUR ENLIGHTENMENT?
It is a difficult question. The first thing was that a great silence, almost unbreakable, followed the experience, as if the mind had stopped functioning. There was nothing to do about it – except to watch.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28 Nowhere to go</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part28/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 28
Nowhere to go
18 May 1986 am in Punta Del Este, Uruguay
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I RECEIVED A LETTER FROM ONE OF YOUR SANNYASINS IN EUROPE. SHE SAYS THERE IS NOWHERE TO GO EXCEPT TO BE WITH YOU. MEANWHILE SHE ENJOYS BEING ALONE AND DOING SMALL THINGS AND IS GRATEFUL THAT AT LEAST WE ARE ALL UNDER THE SAME SKY.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>29 New skies to fly in</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part29/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 29
New skies to fly in
18 May 1986 pm in Punta Del Este, Uruguay
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
ONE OF THE GREAT IRONIES OF OUR RECENT EXPERIENCES OF SO-CALLED CHRISTIAN COUNTRIES IS SEEN IN RELATION TO THE IDEA CONTAINED IN THE STORY OF JOSEPH, AND MARY, WHO IS ABOUT TO GIVE BIRTH TO JESUS, FINDING “NO ROOM AT THE INN.”
THIS STORY IS USED AS A BASE FOR THE FUNDAMENTAL CHRISTIAN TENET OF “CHARITY,” AND TO “LOVE THY NEIGHBOR.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Enchanted with the unknown</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
Enchanted with the unknown
5 May 1986 pm in Punta Del Este, Uruguay
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I FEEL LIKE MY MIND IS GOING CRAZY THESE DAYS. IT IS AS IF IT IS TRYING TO GRASP ANYTHING IT POSSIBLY CAN, ESPECIALLY DURING DISCOURSE AS I SIT IN SILENCE WITH YOU. IT FEELS LIKE IT’S HAVING LESS AND LESS TO HOLD ON TO, LESS AND LESS TO THINK ABOUT, SO IT’S CREATING THE CRAZIEST THINGS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>30 The name is love, but the game is politics</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part30/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 30
The name is love, but the game is politics
19 May 1986 am in Punta Del Este, Uruguay
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WOULD YOU PLEASE TALK AGAIN ABOUT LOVE, HOW YOU SEE IT? IN KATHMANDU, I WAS SO TOUCHED WHEN YOU WERE SPEAKING ABOUT GOING BEYOND THE POLARITY OF LOVE-HATE. I FEEL SO GRATEFUL TOWARDS YOU BECAUSE YOU TOLD ME THAT GIVING LOVE WILL BE MY MEDITATION.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>31 I cannot leave my garden unfinished</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part31/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 31
I cannot leave my garden unfinished
19 May 1986 pm in Punta Del Este, Uruguay
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHEN THINGS BECOME DIFFICULT FOR ME I TAKE REFUGE IN THE HERE AND NOW. IN THE MOMENT ALL IS STILL, AND IT IS THE ONLY WAY FOR ME TO STAND ON THE RAZOR’S EDGE. AND YET A DOUBT COMES IN THAT I AM ESCAPING WHAT IS REALLY HAPPENING: I MAY SIMPLY BE WEARING BLINKERS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>32 My vision is of the whole</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part32/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part32/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 32
My vision is of the whole
20 May 1986 am in Punta Del Este, Uruguay
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
JAPAN IS ABOUT TO SURPASS THE UNITED STATES IN PER CAPITA INCOME. IT IS ALREADY AN ECONOMIC SUPERPOWER, DOMINATING LARGE SECTIONS OF WORLD TRADE, AND HAS RECENTLY BEGUN TO DOMINATE THE FINANCIAL MARKETS. IN FACT, THE ONLY MATERIAL THING THAT JAPAN’S ONE HUNDRED AND TWENTY MILLION PEOPLE DO NOT HAVE MUCH OF, IS LAND.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>33 More dangerous than nuclear weapons</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part33/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part33/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 33
More dangerous than nuclear weapons
20 May 1986 pm in Punta Del Este, Uruguay
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
AN AMERICAN AMBASSADOR REPORTEDLY SAID, IN REFERENCE TO YOU, TO A FOREIGN HEAD OF STATE, “HE IS EXTREMELY INTELLIGENT, AN ANARCHIST, AND VERY DANGEROUS BECAUSE HE CAN CHANGE MEN’S MINDS. HE WILL DESTROY YOUR WHOLE SOCIETY.”
HOW CAN WE SAFEGUARD AGAINST AMERICA AND ITS ALLIES STOPPING YOUR EFFORTS TO AWAKEN MEN?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>34 The word cannot be crucified</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part34/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part34/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 34
The word cannot be crucified
21 May 1986 am in Punta Del Este, Uruguay
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
YOU SPOKE THE OTHER DAY ABOUT THE GREAT RESPONSIBILITY WE HAVE TO GET YOUR WORDS OUT TO THE WORLD. CAN YOU SAY SOME MORE?
The most important need of humanity today is to be made aware that its past has betrayed it. There is no point in continuing the past, it will be suicidal.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>35 Nothing to lose</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part35/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part35/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 35
Nothing to lose
21 May 1986 pm in Punta Del Este, Uruguay
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHAT HAPPENED TO GURDJIEFF WHEN HE HAD HIS CAR ACCIDENT?
The system of George Gurdjieff is a little bit strange, and it is certainly different from all other, old approaches. His whole work was concentrated on creating an absolute feeling of distinction between the body and consciousness – not just as a philosophical idea but as an actual experience.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>36 A tiger is also a guest</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part36/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part36/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 36
A tiger is also a guest
22 May 1986 am in Punta Del Este, Uruguay
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
ONCE YOU SAID THAT WE HAVE SHOWN COURAGE IN BEING WITH YOU – BUT IT DOESN’T FEEL LIKE THAT TO ME. TO ME IT FEELS LIKE THE EASIEST AND THE ONLY THING TO DO. IT RATHER FRIGHTENS ME TO THINK OF LIVING IN THIS WORLD AWAY FROM YOU.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>37 A silent equilibrium</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part37/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part37/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 37
A silent equilibrium
22 May 1986 pm in Punta Del Este, Uruguay
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
SINCE I HAVE BEEN A SANNYASIN, I HAVE THOUGHT THAT I NEEDED TO USE MY MIND LESS IF I WAS TO BE IN TOUCH WITH MY HEART. YET I HEARD YOU SAY THE OTHER DAY THAT WE SHOULD TRAIN OUR MINDS TO KEEP OUR INTELLIGENCE ALIVE AND HELP IT BECOME SHARPER AND SHARPER.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>38 Death is others\&#39; opinion about you</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part38/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part38/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 38
Death is others’ opinion about you
23 May 1986 am in Punta Del Este, Uruguay
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
FIFTEEN YEARS AGO I WAS A POLITICAL MILITANT, AND I WAS TRYING TO CHANGE THE SOCIETY BY SPREADING IDEAS. FAILURE AND FRUSTRATION BROUGHT ME TO YOU. NOW THAT YOUR PEOPLE CANNOT REACH TO YOU, CAN SPREADING YOUR IDEAS AND PUBLISHING YOUR BOOKS AND TAPES BE ENOUGH TO GIVE BIRTH TO THE NEW MAN?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>39 My words are only indicators towards silence</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part39/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part39/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 39
My words are only indicators towards silence
23 May 1986 pm in Punta Del Este, Uruguay
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHAT WOULD YOU SAY TO THE GOVERNMENTS OF THE COUNTRIES THAT HAVE REJECTED YOUR PRESENCE UNDER THE ILLUSION OF BEING POLITICALLY AND ECONOMICALLY INDEPENDENT FROM AMERICA, WHEN IN FACT WE KNOW THINGS ARE TO THE CONTRARY? MAYBE SOME OF THESE GOVERNMENTS HAVE BEEN EFFECTIVELY DECEIVED AND SHOULD LOOK INTO WHAT IS REALLY HAPPENING AND SEE HOW THEY ARE BEING USED FOR AMERICA’S ABOMINABLE CRIME AGAINST WISDOM.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Reality is always fragile</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
Reality is always fragile
6 May 1986 am in Punta Del Este, Uruguay
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
IN THE LAST DAYS I OFTEN HAVE THE FEELING THAT THE GROUND IS GOING BENEATH MY FEET. IT SEEMS TO ME AS IF ALL THAT I LOVE OR LOVED IN THE PAST IS BEING DESTROYED.
THE RECENT DISASTER IN THE SOVIET NUCLEAR STATION MAKES PAINFULLY CLEAR HOW FRAGILE AND MORTAL EVERYTHING IS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>40 The thought of silence excites nobody</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part40/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part40/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 40
The thought of silence excites nobody
24 May 1986 am in Punta Del Este, Uruguay
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
FOR YEARS I HAVE BEEN A “GROUPIE” SEARCHING FOR WAYS TO UNDERSTAND MYSELF. I HAVE BEEN IN SUCH MISERY THAT ALMOST NOTHING ASKED OF ME WAS TOO MUCH IF IT HELD A CHANCE OF ALLEVIATING MY DISTRESS.
NOW YOU OFFER MEDITATION AS A MEANS FOR LEAVING MY MISERY BEHIND, AND ALL I DO IS RESIST.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>41 The secrets of life are very simple</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part41/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part41/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 41
The secrets of life are very simple
24 May 1986 pm in Punta Del Este, Uruguay
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
IN ‘NEWSWEEK’ I READ A JOKE WITHIN AN ARTICLE ON SO-CALLED QUICK-FIX THERAPY. A MIDDLE-AGED MAN HAD BEEN THE DESPAIR OF HIS FAMILY FOR YEARS BECAUSE OF HIS COMPULSIVE HABIT OF TEARING PAPER TO BITS AND SCATTERING THE PIECES ALL OVER THE GROUND WHEREVER HE WENT.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>42 Politics is a disease</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part42/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part42/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 42
Politics is a disease
25 May 1986 am in Punta Del Este, Uruguay
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
YOU SAID LAST NIGHT THAT WHEN YOU FIND A PLACE TO SETTLE YOU WILL BEGIN EXPOSING THE HYPOCRISY OF THE WORLD’S GOVERNMENTS AND POLITICIANS ONE BY ONE.
I AM NOT EXPOSED YET. HAVE I MISSED MY CHANCE?
Milarepa, you are not a politician. You don’t need any exposure.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>43 Unnecessarily barking at each other</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part43/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part43/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 43
Unnecessarily barking at each other
25 May 1986 pm in Punta Del Este, Uruguay
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I LOVED HEARING ABOUT YOUR MEETINGS WITH THE OLD ENLIGHTENED SAND SCULPTOR FROM BOMBAY. DID YOU COME ACROSS OTHER ENLIGHTENED INDIVIDUALS IN YOUR TRAVELS?
I have come across a few very remarkable individuals but they were not enlightened: they were just on the verge.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>44 I am talking to transform your heart</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part44/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part44/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 44
I am talking to transform your heart
26 May 1986 am in Punta Del Este, Uruguay
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I AM REMEMBERING THE STORY YOU TOLD THE OTHER DAY ABOUT THE ARCHER. CAN YOU TELL US MORE ABOUT HOW TO HAVE THIS ATTITUDE WHEN SPREADING YOUR WORDS IN A WORLD OF NEGATIVITY AND OPPOSITION TOWARDS YOU? IS THERE A FIGHTLESS FIGHT?
There is a fightless fight, an actionless action, an effortless effort.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 The moment truth compromises, it dies</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
The moment truth compromises, it dies
6 May 1986 pm in Punta Del Este, Uruguay
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
IN URUGUAY, EVENING HAS COME. A SMALL GROUP OF FRIENDS LISTEN AS SILENCE SPEAKS.
BELOVED MASTER, WHAT IS THE ESSENCE OF ZEN?
It is one of the most significant questions that can be asked. The small word ‘zen’ contains the whole evolution of religious consciousness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 The flower of discipleship</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
The flower of discipleship
7 May 1986 am in Punta Del Este, Uruguay
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
NOT INFREQUENTLY, WHEN I BEGIN TO WAKE IN THE MORINIG, I HAVE SUCH A STRONG SENSE OF HOW ARBITRARY IT IS THAT I AM BACK IN MY PARTICULAR FORM. I RECOGNIZE THE PERSON I SLIP BACK INTO: I KNOW HER MANNERISMS, HER LIKES AND DISLIKES.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Between these two dreams\...</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
Between these two dreams...
7 May 1986 pm in Punta Del Este, Uruguay
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I’VE ALWAYS BEEN FASCINATED BY THE STATE OF BARDO AS DESCRIBED IN ANCIENT TIBETAN SCRIPTURES. COULD YOU SAY SOMETHING ABOUT THIS?
Bardo is a simple method but with great significance. Only people who have meditated a little bit in their lives can be benefited by it, and Tibet was one of the countries where almost everybody was devoting some time to meditation – just to be alone, silent, not doing anything, just witnessing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 A longing for the beyond</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
A longing for the beyond
8 May 1986 am in Punta Del Este, Uruguay
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I OFTEN HEAR YOU SAYING THAT EVERY CHILD COMES TO THIS WORLD WITH AN EMPTY MIND, AS A TABULA RASA. HOW IS IT POSSIBLE THAT WE, IN SPITE OF THIS, CARRY MEMORIES AND CONDITIONINGS FROM PAST LIVES? WOULD YOU PLEASE SAY SOMETHING ABOUT THIS?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 Grateful to existence</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_path_of_the_mystic/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
Grateful to existence
8 May 1986 pm in Punta Del Este, Uruguay
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
ARE YOU SURE YOU WEREN’T BORN ENLIGHTENED? YOU SEEM TO HAVE LIVED YOUR WHOLE LIFE WITH SUCH CLARITY, COURAGE AND A COMMITMENT NEVER TO COMPROMISE YOUR INTEGRITY THAT IT SEEMS SOME QUALITY OF AWAKENING HAS BEEN WITH YOU ALL THE TIME. IF FOR TWENTY YEARS YOU WERE NOT ENLIGHTENED, WAS ANYTHING A SUFFERING FOR YOU?</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
