<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>What Is, Is, What Ain\&#39;t, Ain\&#39;t on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/what_is_is_what_aint_aint/</link>
    <description>Recent content in What Is, Is, What Ain\&#39;t, Ain\&#39;t on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/what_is_is_what_aint_aint/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/what_is_is_what_aint_aint/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/what_is_is_what_aint_aint/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
1 February 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
This will be your new name... and the end of the old life and the beginning of the totally new. Let it be totally new. Sometimes a thing is new, but not totally new – then it doesn’t work. Then it is just a modification of the old, a continuity with the past. Only the discontinuous works – absolute discontinuity with the past; only that is radical.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/what_is_is_what_aint_aint/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/what_is_is_what_aint_aint/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
10 February 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means the ultimate state of silence, peace, joy. It is all three together. It is not just joy, because joy can be very maddening. It is very clam and quiet; it has no excitement in it. Joy can have much fever, passion. So it is joy with a totally different quality to it – very silent joy, not like laughter but just like a smile.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/what_is_is_what_aint_aint/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/what_is_is_what_aint_aint/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
11 February 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love and adarsha means the first-day moon. Literally the word means that which cannot be seen but yet is. The first-day moon cannot be seen. From the second day you can see it a little; by the third day it is very clearly seen; on the fifteenth day it is perfect. On the first day it is there but almost like a potentiality – not yet actual.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/what_is_is_what_aint_aint/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/what_is_is_what_aint_aint/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
12 February 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Shanti means peace and garbha means womb – peace womb. This name is a seed-meditation for you. Think of yourself as a womb which is going to give birth to peace. Imagine, visualise yourself as being a womb, and that the peace child is growing within you. Whenever you are sitting, not doing anything, just visualise it – just sit silently.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/what_is_is_what_aint_aint/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/what_is_is_what_aint_aint/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
13 February 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love and atharva means fire – love fire. And that’s the fire that keeps us alive, and that’s the fire that runs the whole existence. That’s the fire that one has to experience to know what god is.
Physicists say that the existence consists of nothing but electricity, and they are approximately true, because electricity is a form of fire.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/what_is_is_what_aint_aint/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/what_is_is_what_aint_aint/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
14 February 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss and swantandra means freedom – bliss freedom. And they are both two aspects of the same phenomenon – on one side is bliss, on another side is freedom; they always come together. Attain to one and the other follows. So either become blissful, then you are free, or become free, then you are blissful.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/what_is_is_what_aint_aint/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/what_is_is_what_aint_aint/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
15 February 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A visitor said she was traveling in India because: it’s warm, and I like travelling very much and... of course there must be some other reasons too, but who knows?]
Mm, there are! (a pause) There are layers and layers of reasons in the mind, and we are aware only of the first layer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/what_is_is_what_aint_aint/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/what_is_is_what_aint_aint/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
16 February 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, anada means soundlessness – loving soundlessness. And that is a map for your inner journey: become as soundless as possible. The inner chattering has to be completely dropped. The mind goes on creating sound, continuously – day in, day out; whether awake or asleep, the mind goes on creating more and more sounds, more words.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/what_is_is_what_aint_aint/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/what_is_is_what_aint_aint/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
17 February 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, anugita means a small song – a small song of love. That’s what life is meant to be. Life consists of small things, so I don’t call it a very big song – I call it a small song. Song, not with a capital ‘S’ – a lower case ‘s’. Life consists of very small things, and one has to learn the small song of life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/what_is_is_what_aint_aint/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/what_is_is_what_aint_aint/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
18 February 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, anakula means calm, quiet. Ordinarily love is hot, feverish, obsessive. Ordinarily, love is more like a disease than like health. It disturbs you... it distracts you from your centre. It helps you to become intoxicated, infatuated with the other – you forget yourself. In that very forgetfulness you miss the beauty of love.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/what_is_is_what_aint_aint/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/what_is_is_what_aint_aint/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
19 February 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, and vimarsha means reflection – divine reflection. And it has to be understood in a certain way. Ordinarily, reflection is understood as if it is just a synonym for thinking; it is not. A mirror reflects – there is no thinking. It simply says whatsoever is; there is no interpretation. It does not colour, it does not add, it does not delete.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/what_is_is_what_aint_aint/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/what_is_is_what_aint_aint/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
2 February 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[The Enlightenment Intensive group is present. One member says: At first I didn’t like it, bu the second half of the group I liked very much.]
Always remember that even if you don’t like a certain thing, it is not necessarily bad. Liking and disliking makes no difference. Sometimes the thing that you like may be harmful, and vice versa: the thing that you don’t like at all may prove a great transformation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/what_is_is_what_aint_aint/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/what_is_is_what_aint_aint/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
20 February 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, godly, anila means the breeze – divine breeze. And meditate on the phenomenon of the breeze. There are a few things to be understood about it: there is no way to manipulate it – it comes when it comes. Suddenly it is there, suddenly it is gone.
Exactly in the same way god comes – suddenly he is there, and suddenly he is gone.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/what_is_is_what_aint_aint/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/what_is_is_what_aint_aint/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
21 February 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, and vimarsho means reflection. It is a special step in prayer. In the western languages, the closest term that can come to it is contemplation, but that too is not exactly the translation – just very close to it.
Reality can only be known when one is a mirror. When you think about it, you go astray.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/what_is_is_what_aint_aint/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/what_is_is_what_aint_aint/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
22 February 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means god, the divine element – not exactly god, but godly. God is more of an energy than a person, so in the east, rather than saying that god exists, we have been saying that the world is divine. God is not a separate element from the world but is its intrinsic quality, an inner presence – not somebody who has created the world and then either has forgotten all about it or is no more interested, or has become interested in some other projects.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/what_is_is_what_aint_aint/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/what_is_is_what_aint_aint/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
23 February 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, anunada means vibration. You have to meditate much on vibrations and you have to learn how to vibrate in tune with the whole. When a person is too self-conscious he vibrates against the whole. When a person is no more self-conscious, simply conscious with no self in it, then he vibrates with the whole.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/what_is_is_what_aint_aint/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/what_is_is_what_aint_aint/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 24
24 February 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love and mariam is the hebrew name of Jesus’ mother, Mary. It means rebellion – love rebellion. And in the old languages – particularly hebrew, sanskrit, arabic – each name is very symbolic. It is not just coincidence that jesus is born out of a woman whose name is ‘rebellion’. Jesus can be born only out of rebellion, he cannot be born out of tradition.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/what_is_is_what_aint_aint/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/what_is_is_what_aint_aint/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 25
25 February 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss and sagaresh means god of the ocean – the full name will mean god of the ocean of bliss.
You have to become one! Consciousness is almost an ocean – there is no limitation to it. The body is limited, the mind is limited, but the consciousness that resides behind the body and behind the mind is almost oceanic.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/what_is_is_what_aint_aint/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/what_is_is_what_aint_aint/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 26
26 February 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Hari priya. It means beloved of god. And there are two things which are the most difficult in life: one is to love and another is to allow love to happen, to allow somebody to love you. And the second is far more difficult than the first. To love is difficult because one has to flow and one has to give, one has to share.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/what_is_is_what_aint_aint/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/what_is_is_what_aint_aint/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 27
27 February 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, god, avesha means possessed by – possessed by god... and from now onwards I will possess you!
So relax and be possessed! Don’t fight with me, because that is sheer wastage of energy. If you remain in a let-go, much is going to happen. If you allow me, nothing is impossible, but the whole thing depends on your allowing me; that is the very core of it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/what_is_is_what_aint_aint/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/what_is_is_what_aint_aint/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
3 February 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin reports on doing the nadabrahma meditation for nine months, including during his job as a pilot. He finds it a great source of energy.]
It is... it is a great source of energy. We don’t know our own sources and we don’t know how to connect with those sources. When you are humming a sound you fall into harmony.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/what_is_is_what_aint_aint/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/what_is_is_what_aint_aint/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
4 February 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin told Osho about a centre sannyasins were starting in Holland.
Osho encouraged Niketana to go back and help the centre in holland, saying that wherever people are doing his work, he is there]
It is the greatest creativity possible when you help people to grow. Nothing else is more creative – because you create consciousness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/what_is_is_what_aint_aint/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/what_is_is_what_aint_aint/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
5 February 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Gurudas. Guru means the master, and das means the servant – the servant of the master. And it is very significant in the east. The very concept of guru is eastern; the word cannot even be rightly translated. When we translate it as ‘master’ much of its meaning is lost, because a master means a teacher – the guru is not a teacher.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/what_is_is_what_aint_aint/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/what_is_is_what_aint_aint/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
6 February 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Shanti means peace, bhadra means grace – peace and grace, peace that comes through grace. There are two types of peace possible: one that man can cultivate – that is not of much meaning; the other that comes from god as a gift, that which cannot be cultivated; that is real peace.
So remember it: one can cultivate peace and look peaceful, and may not be peaceful.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/what_is_is_what_aint_aint/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/what_is_is_what_aint_aint/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
7 February 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem sarvesh. The meaning is: the god of love and totality. Prem means love, sarv means total and esh means god – and that has a message for you. Two things have to be remembered: love and totality. Both help each other, because it is only love that can be total. It is only through love that one can come to feel what totality is.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/what_is_is_what_aint_aint/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/what_is_is_what_aint_aint/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
8 February 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho gave a new sannyasin the name ‘deva sarvahara’ – saying that the meaning was ‘one who has lost all’.
Osho said that Jesus’ saying – ‘Blessed are the poor in spirit’ – meant that those who had nothing, who were nothing, were blessed. This did not imply that one should live an impoverished life; one should live beautifully, but one should not be possessed by one’s belongings.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/what_is_is_what_aint_aint/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/what_is_is_what_aint_aint/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
9 February 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine and chirantana means eternal; divine eternity. And a few things have to be understood. First, eternity is not duration: it is not time going on and on and on. Eternity has nothing to do with time. Eternity is something totally different than time – diametrically opposite, rather.
[Osho said time is a distortion of eternity.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
