<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Vedanta. Seven Steps to Samadhi on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vedanta_seven_steps_to_samadhi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vedanta. Seven Steps to Samadhi on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/vedanta_seven_steps_to_samadhi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 Towards the Truth</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vedanta_seven_steps_to_samadhi/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/vedanta_seven_steps_to_samadhi/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
Towards the Truth
11 January 1974 pm in Mt. Abu, Rajasthan, India
AUM, MAY MY SPEECH BE ROOTED IN MY MIND, AND MY MIND ROOTED IN MY SPEECH.
O SELF-ILLUMINED BRAHMAN, BE MANIFEST UNTO ME. SPEECH AND MIND FORM THE BASIS OF MY KNOWLEDGE, SO PLEASE DO NOT UNDO MY PURSUIT OF KNOWLEDGE. DAY AND NIGHT I SPEND IN THIS PURSUIT.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Sublime is the Spontaneous</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vedanta_seven_steps_to_samadhi/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/vedanta_seven_steps_to_samadhi/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
Sublime is the Spontaneous
16 January 1974 am in Mt. Abu, Rajasthan, India
THERE ARE TWO KINDS OF NONATTACHMENT:
THE ORDINARY AND THE SUBLIME.
THAT ATTITUDE OF NONATTACHMENT TO THE OBJECTS OF DESIRE IN WHICH THE SEEKER KNOWS THAT HE IS NEITHER THE DOER NOR THE ENJOYER,
NEITHER THE RESTRAINED NOR THE RESTRAINER, IS CALLED ORDINARY NONATTACHMENT. HE KNOWS THAT WHATEVER FACES HIM IN THIS LIFE IS THE RESULT OF THE DEEDS OF HIS PAST LIFE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 One in the Many</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vedanta_seven_steps_to_samadhi/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/vedanta_seven_steps_to_samadhi/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
One in the Many
16 January 1974 pm in Mt. Abu, Rajasthan, India
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
IF EVERYTHING IS SIMPLY HAPPENING, THEN CAN THERE BE ANY ULTIMATE PURPOSE TO IT ALL, OR IS LIFE JUST AN ACCIDENT? CAN IT BE SAID THAT LIFE IS EVOLVING TOWARDS SOME ULTIMATE GOAL?
It is very difficult, particularly for the Western mind, to understand that life is purposeless.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Only Knowing Remains</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vedanta_seven_steps_to_samadhi/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/vedanta_seven_steps_to_samadhi/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
Only Knowing Remains
17 January 1974 am in Mt. Abu, Rajsthan, India
THE FIRST STAGE, TO WHICH CONTENTMENT AND BLISS
IMPART SWEETNESS, SPRINGS FROM THE INNERMOST RECESSES OF THE SEEKER’S HEART, AS IF NECTAR HAS ISSUED FORTH FROM THE HEART OF THE EARTH.
AT THE INCEPTION OF THIS STAGE THE INNERMOST RECESS BECOMES A FIELD FOR THE COMING OF THE OTHER STAGES.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 When the Coin Disappears</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vedanta_seven_steps_to_samadhi/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/vedanta_seven_steps_to_samadhi/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
When the Coin Disappears
17 January 1974 pm in Mt. Abu, Rajasthan, India
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
SOME MYSTICS HAVE BEEN VERY INTROVERTED AND SILENT. IN YOUR OWN CASE, YOU APPEAR TO BE MOVING BOTH INTROVERTEDLY AND EXTROVERTEDLY WITHOUT ANY DIFFICULTY. PLEASE EXPLAIN HOW THIS IS POSSIBLE.
The mind goes on dividing on every level of being. Wherever the mind looks immediately it divides; division, to divide, is the nature of the mind.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 The Motionless Flame of a Lamp</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vedanta_seven_steps_to_samadhi/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/vedanta_seven_steps_to_samadhi/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
The Motionless Flame of a Lamp
18 January 1974 am in Mt. Abu, Rajsthan, India
ON THE ATTAINMENT OF THE FIFTH STATE, THE MIND OF THE SEEKER CEASES, LIKE CLOUDS IN AN AUTUMN SKY, AND ONLY TRUTH REMAINS.
IN THIS STATE, WORLDLY DESIRES DO NOT ARISE AT ALL.
DURING THIS STATE ALL THOUGHTS OF DIVISION IN THE SEEKER ARE STILLED AND HE REMAINS ROOTED IN NONDUALITY.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 God Seeks You</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vedanta_seven_steps_to_samadhi/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/vedanta_seven_steps_to_samadhi/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
God Seeks You
18 January 1974 pm in Mt. Abu, Rajasthan, India
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I FEEL LOST IN YOU WITHOUT REASON OR DIRECTION. QUESTIONS AND DESIRES FALL IN CONFUSION BEFORE YOU. OVERPOWERED BY SENSELESS FAITH AND LOVE, LISTLESSLY I WAIT, FEELING LIKE A FOOL. ARE THERE DIFFERENCES BETWEEN BLIND FAITH, LOVE AND SURRENDER?
There is a state when you certainly feel like a fool, but this is the beginning of wisdom.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 The Art of Dying</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vedanta_seven_steps_to_samadhi/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/vedanta_seven_steps_to_samadhi/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
The Art of Dying
19 January 1974 am in Mt. Abu, Rajasthan, India
IN THIS SEVENTH STAGE, THE STATE OF VIDEHAMUKTI,
LIBERATION WHILE LIVING IN THE BODY IS ACHIEVED. THIS STAGE IS TOTALLY SILENT AND CANNOT BE COMMUNICATED IN WORDS.
IT IS THE END OF ALL STAGES, WHERE ALL THE PROCESSES OF YOGA COME TO THEIR
CONCLUSION. IN THIS STAGE, ALL ACTIVITIES – WORLDLY, BODILY AND SCRIPTURAL – CEASE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 Valleys and Peaks</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vedanta_seven_steps_to_samadhi/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/vedanta_seven_steps_to_samadhi/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 17
Valleys and Peaks
19 January 1974 pm in Mt. Abu, Rajasthan, India
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
MANY TIMES I FEEL SO MERGED IN YOU THAT IT IS AS IF I HAVE DIED AND ONLY YOU ARE. BUT THIS FEELING DOESN’T REMAIN CONSTANT, AND ALWAYS THE EGO RETURNS. THIS HAPPENS WHENEVER I HAVE TO AGAIN COMMUNICATE WITH OTHERS OR RETURN TO ACTIVITY. WHY DOESN’T THE EGO REMAIN DEAD?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Attaining Real Eyes</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vedanta_seven_steps_to_samadhi/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/vedanta_seven_steps_to_samadhi/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
Attaining Real Eyes
12 January 1974 am in Mt. Abu, Rajasthan, India
THE SAGE SANKRITI ONCE VISITED ADITYALOK, THE ABODE OF THE SUN GOD, AND BOWING TO HIM HE WORSHIPPED HIM WITH WHAT IS KNOWN AS CHAKSHUSMATI VIDYA.
AUM, SALUTATION TO THE SUN GOD WHO ILLUMINES THE ORGAN OF VISION! SALUTATION TO THE SUN WHO IS A GREAT WARRIOR!
SALUTATION TO THE SUN WHO REPRESENTS THE THREE CONDITIONINGS: TAMAS, RAJAS AND SATTVA (DARK, RED AND WHITE)!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 With Your Total Heart</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vedanta_seven_steps_to_samadhi/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/vedanta_seven_steps_to_samadhi/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
With Your Total Heart
12 January 1974 pm in Mt. Abu, Rajasthan, India
One friend has said that he is a devotee of Sai Baba, and therefore he is reluctant to call anyone else Beloved Master, but he wants my help, guidance. He says:
Question 1
I FEEL I HAVE SURRENDERED TO SAI BABA, BUT STILL I FEEL THE NECESSITY OF WORKING WITH ANOTHER TEACHER OR GURU.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 The Supreme Knowledge</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vedanta_seven_steps_to_samadhi/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/vedanta_seven_steps_to_samadhi/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
The Supreme Knowledge
13 January 1974 am in Mt. Abu, Rajasthan, India
THE SAGE SANKRITI THEN SAID TO THE SUN GOD:
O LORD, PLEASE TEACH ME THE SUPREME KNOWLEDGE. THE SUN GOD SAID:
I SHALL NOW EXPLAIN TO YOU THIS MOST RARE KNOWLEDGE, UPON THE ATTAINMENT OF WHICH YOU WILL BECOME FREE WHILE YET DWELLING IN THIS BODY. SEE IN ALL BEINGS THE BRAHMAN, WHO IS ONE, UNBORN, STILL, IMPERISHABLE, INFINITE, IMMUTABLE AND CONSCIOUS; SO SEEING LIVE IN PEACE AND BLISS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 In Deep Patience</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vedanta_seven_steps_to_samadhi/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/vedanta_seven_steps_to_samadhi/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
In Deep Patience
13 January 1974 pm in Mt. Abu, Rajasthan, India
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
NEED ONE BE ABSOLUTELY SURE ABOUT A GURU TO BECOME HIS DISCIPLE?
You can never be absolutely sure about a guru, and that is not needed. What is needed is that you should be absolutely sure about yourself. How can you be sure about a master?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 With the Grace of the Sages</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vedanta_seven_steps_to_samadhi/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/vedanta_seven_steps_to_samadhi/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
With the Grace of the Sages
14 January 1974 am in Mt. Abu, Rajasthan, India
NOW FOLLOW THE TRAITS OF SEEKERS OF THE SECOND STAGE, CALLED THE STAGE OF THOUGHT.
HE LIVES IN THE CARE OF LEARNED MEN WHO EXPLAIN BEST WHAT LISTENING, REMEMBERING, RIGHT CONDUCT, CONTEMPLATION –
DHARANA – AND MEDITATION ARE. HAVING ACQUIRED KNOWLEDGE OF SUCH SCRIPTURES AS ARE WORTH LISTENING TO, HE EFFICIENTLY DISCRIMINATES BETWEEN WHAT IS DUTY AND WHAT IS NOT, AND HE KNOWS WELL THE DIVISION BETWEEN A WORD AND THE THING IT SYMBOLIZES.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 You Become the Offering</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vedanta_seven_steps_to_samadhi/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/vedanta_seven_steps_to_samadhi/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
You Become the Offering
14 January 1974 pm in Mt. Abu, Rajasthan, India
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
CONTEMPLATING YOU FLOODS ME WITH A DEEP ECSTASY, AND I FEEL THE GRACE. YOU SAY YOU ARE NOT DOING ANYTHING TO CREATE THIS ECSTASY IN US, BUT IT IS FOR SURE THAT I ALSO AM NOT DOING ANYTHING. THEN FROM WHERE IS THIS BLISS COMING AND HOW IS IT HAPPENING IF NEITHER YOU NOR I ARE DOING ANYTHING?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 The Unwavering Mind</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vedanta_seven_steps_to_samadhi/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/vedanta_seven_steps_to_samadhi/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
The Unwavering Mind
15 January 1974 am in Mt. Abu, Rajasthan, India
AFTER THIS THE SEEKER ENTERS THE THIRD STAGE OF YOGA
WHICH IS KNOWN AS NONATTACHMENT. HE FIXES HIS MIND UNWAVERINGLY ON THE MEANING OF SCRIPTURAL WORDS.
HE LIVES IN THE MONASTERIES, ASHRAMS, OF SAINTS WELL ESTABLISHED IN AUSTERITIES. HE OCCUPIES HIMSELF WITH THE DISCUSSION OF THE
SCRIPTURES AND SLEEPS ON A ROCKY BED.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 The Means is the End</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/vedanta_seven_steps_to_samadhi/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/vedanta_seven_steps_to_samadhi/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
The Means is the End
15 January 1974 pm in Mt. Abu, Rajasthan, India
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
IS VAIRAGYA, NONATTACHMENT, A METHOD, A MEANS, AN INTERMEDIATE STAGE, OR AN END IN ITSELF?
It is all – because means and ends are not two things. The way and the goal are not two things. The way is just the beginning of the goal, and the goal is just the ending of the way.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
