<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Above All Don\&#39;t Wobble on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Above All Don\&#39;t Wobble on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
16 January 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says: I’m changing all the time... Since the group, I don’t know... I don’t like talking, I don’t like laughing... I feel like crying... ]
Whatsoever happens, accept and enjoy, and don’t force anything. If you feel like talking, talk. If you feel like being silent, be silent – just move with the feeling.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
25 January 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[The Encounter Group are at darshan. The leader says it was nothing special... every group is different.]
Mm, it has to be so because the group depends on the people. It should depend more on the people who participate... and no rigid structure should be given to it – so it remains loose, flexible.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
26 January 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin had previously told Osho he had powerful experiences of death in his meditation. Osho had suggested he do the humming meditation. Tonight he says he is having problems with it: I feel morose. I don’t feel happy. I used to feel happy before, but now I’m just going into my shell. I don’t feel like doing anything.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
27 January 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho spoke first to a woman, a mother of a sannyasin, saying that her leaving was premature because she had just started to move in from the periphery and things would have started happening.
She asked wasn’t it possible for things to happen anywhere, if they were going to happen at all, but Osho said for the first glimpse one needs a suitable situation, and after that ‘you have a thread in your hands.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
28 January 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin, upset and tearful, told Osho that she had left the group she was doing to return home to Holland as her daughter was missing her. She said she had received a letter from her saying she was longing for her so she is leaving.]
Children are true, they always say whatsoever they feel.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
29 January 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Satsang is a very significant word – it means the presence of the master. It cannot be translated into English because there has never been such a thing as satsang in English.
In India, in the whole of the East, this is the most precious thing – just to be in the presence of the master; not doing anything, just being there.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
30 January 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin, recently returned from the West, said he was experiencing difficulty in maintaining a relationship as well as meditating and moving deeper into his ‘inner world’.]
When you move on an inner pilgrimage, the energies turn inwards, the same energies that were moving outwards, and suddenly you find yourself alone like an island.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
31 January 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Nitya means eternal and anand means bliss – eternal bliss...
And this is going to be your constant remembrance... to just feel as if you are eternal. In the beginning it is ‘as if’. By and by you become more and more aware that this is a truth. In the beginning you start with an hypothesis – as if – but soon glimpses start coming.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
1 February 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A visitor says that he was at John Bennett’s school in England, where they did Gurdjieffian exercises: Actually I left there quite confused – I suppose there’s no way out of that. I never had much ability to do any of the exercises or things like that.]
It may not have suited you because Gurdjieff’s work is for a particular type, the will type – people who can work hard and very persistently, almost madly.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
2 February 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says: I’ve been able to open up to people in a way I’ve never experienced before, and people have come to me. I’d just like to say thank you.]
One never knows. One never knows unless it happens, because we remain confined with our past experiences, with all that we have known before.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
3 February 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin, newly arrived from America, said she was constantly thinking of her husband whom she had left for someone else. She expressed a sense of guilt because she felt she was the reason for their separating.]
Mm, never think much about the past. That which is gone, is gone; you cannot undo it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
17 January 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin asked just what was happening here, with Osho, in relation to human psychological growth.]
We are trying to present a new synthesis between East and West. The eastern methods are more individualistic, more inward-going, and more concerned with solitude, aloneness, and the person. They are meditative methods, more concerned with the person and his integrity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
4 February 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
People who had done the Aum marathon had darshan tonight. Veeresh, one of the leaders, said that he followed Osho’s advice: “Let Veeresh not be there”; and when he got stuck to close his eyes, relax, and think of Osho. Veeresh recounts three incidents in the group when this had happened.]
Mm, really fantastic it has been.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
5 February 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A visitor says she is a painter.]
Very good. Things will go well with me!
Religion is the greatest art... and unless you understand religion something will be always missing in your art, something will remain incomplete, because whatsoever you do without religion, you are the doer. Once religion enters your life you are no longer the doer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
6 February 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin recently returned said that he didn’t feel Osho in the West but as soon as he arrived in India he felt Osho’s presence.]
That too, is possible. It depends on the personality. It may be so with you.
There are two types of persons: one person – who is never in the present – is the common type.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
7 February 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin returned to darshan after having over-eaten consciously for seven days as Osho had suggested, as she was concerned that she was stuffing herself. She says: Well I’m not interested in food anymore!]
Good. That’s how the mind works: if you want not to eat, then the desire arises to eat too much.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 24
8 February 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin sings a love song in French to Osho. She has brought a translator with her. ] When one talks about love, there is no need to translate it.
... A few things can be understood without knowing the language, and those are the same few things that cannot be translated.
That’s why poetry is impossible to translate, and a song still more difficult, because the words can be translated but not the rhythm.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 25
9 February 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Dharma means the ultimata law, the very base of life, the very ground of existence. and Kaya means body – the body of the ultimate law. This is a buddhist term, very meaningful...
[A couple come with a relationship problem: She has a black eye and complains of lack of privacy in the room they share; and he wants more freedom to move with others.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 26
10 February 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Sudheer means infinitely patient, and prem means love. Love is patient and everything else is impatient. If there is no patience, there is no love. Passion is impatient, love is patient. and once you understand that to be patient is to be loving, and to be patient is to be in prayer, then everything is understood.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 27
11 February 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
This will be your name, so forget the old, forget it completely, as if it never belonged to you. A discontinuity is needed with the past so that one can start from ABC; fresh, with a clean sheet. That is the meaning of the new name – so that you can forget the old, and then with the old, the whole past disappears.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/part28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/part28/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 28
12 February 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Marga means the path, the way, and deva means the divine – the divine path.
We are just to be a path for the divine to come... just a passage for Him to come to us, just a door. and the whole effort is not how to travel the path, but how to become the path. The traveller is false.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
18 January 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says: When I was doing the Gourishankar (a meditation) I had a terrible feeling of death come over me, and I guess I immediately associated it with my mother. I’ve really been worrying about it, and I wonder if everything is okay back home.
Osho checks her energy.]
Mm, nothing to worry about your mother.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
19 January 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says: I find you inaccessible – as a man. As a force I find you very powerful.] (laughing) But you can know me only as one. (a pause) I am both.
That is the problem of the human mind: if I am too accessible as man, many things that I can do for you will not be possible.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
20 January 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin asks: How is it possible always to remain centred? There is a tendency to go astray...
]
Don’t create any conflict about going astray and being centred. Float. If you create a conflict, if you become afraid of going astray, then there is more possibility that you will go astray – because whatsoever you try to suppress becomes very significant.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
21 January 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says: I am a little homesick. I saw an old friend of mine yesterday, and he brought me all the West, all the remembrances... Sometimes I am very very happy, and there are magic moments. Sometimes I would like to go, to be independent, to go on my way]
Mm mm, it is natural, and nothing to worry about.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
22 January 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Vasant means spring and prem means love, mm?
Remember always that love is going to be your path. So become a spring of love inside, more and more. Just be one, make it part of your being. If you look, look with deep love in your eyes. If you touch, touch with deep love, with great sensitivity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
23 January 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[The Aum Marathon group leader, said about the group: ... it was... fantastic.
I kept leaving the door to the group room open so you wouldn’t have any trouble coming in!
I think what happened is that last time, in the last darshan when you said like, that we’re all your family... I figured I’m your family too, and therefore the group is my family and I have a right to say that.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/above_all_dont_wobble/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
24 January 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says things are going better]
There is no end to it. Things go on bettering and bettering, and that’s the beauty of it. That’s why life is eternal and has no death. Once a thing is perfect, finished, it is dead. Love remains unfinished. Imperfection is intrinsic to it, and that’s its eternal life.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
