<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Ultimate Alchemy Volume 1 on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_1/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Ultimate Alchemy Volume 1 on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 The Tradition of the Upanishads and the Secrets of Meditation</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_1/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_1/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
The Tradition of the Upanishads and the Secrets of Meditation
15 February 1972 pm in Bombay, India
AUM TASYA NISHCHINTANAM DHYANAM
AUM MEDITATION IS THE CONSTANT CONTEMPLATION OF THAT.
THERE are some points to ponder over before we step into the unknown. The unknown is the message of the Upanishads. The basic, the most foundational, always remains unknown; that which we know is always superficial.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 The Secret of Totality</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_1/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_1/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
The Secret of Totality
24 February 1972 pm in Bombay, India
Question 1
OSHO, IN REFERENCE TO THE SUBJECT OF OFFERING TO THE DIVINE, PLEASE EXPLAIN WHAT IS THE SIGNIFICANCE OF WILL AND SURRENDER? WHAT ARE THE SIMILARITIES AND DIFFERENCES BETWEEN WILL AND SURRENDER?
THE END is always the same, but the beginning differs, and all the differences belong always to the beginning.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 Light, Life and Love</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_1/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_1/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
Light, Life and Love
25 February 1972 pm in Bombay, India
SADAADEEPTIH APAAR AMRIT VRITTIH SNAANAM
TO BE CENTERED CONSTANTLY IN THE INNER ILLUMINATION AND IN THE INFINITE INNER NECTAR IS THE PREPARATORY BATH FOR THE WORSHIP.
LIGHT IS the most mysterious thing in the universe – for many reasons. You may not have felt it like that, but the first thing about light is that light is the purest energy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 You are responsible</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_1/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_1/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
You are responsible
26 February 1972 am in
Question 1
OSHO, WHEN ONE EXPERIENCES DIFFERENT FORMS OF LIGHT AND COLOURS IN MEDITATION – SUCH AS RED, YELLOW, BLUE, OCHRE, ETC. –
HOW CAN ONE KNOW TO WHICH LAYERS OF BEING THEY BELONG? IS THERE ANY GRADUAL SEQUENCE OF COLOUR AND LIGHT EXPERIENCES BEFORE REACHING THE ULTIMATE LIGHT EXPERIENCE?
LIGHT itself is colourless.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 Transcendence Through Being</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_1/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_1/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
Transcendence Through Being
1 June 1972 pm in Bombay, India
SARVATRA BHAVANA GANDHAH
THE FEELING OF THAT EVERYWHERE IS GANDHA – THE ONLY FRAGRANCE.
THE INDIAN metaphysics divides Existence into two realms. One is “this” – that which can be pointed out; and another is “That” – that which is beyond this, which cannot be pointed out. The Sanskrit word for Truth is SATYA.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 Facing the Reality</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_1/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_1/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
Facing the Reality
2 June 1972 pm in
Question 1
OSHO, YOU SAID LAST NIGHT THAT TO REALIZE THE THAT, THE TRANSCENDENTAL TRUTH EVERYWHERE, ONE MUST FIRST REALIZE IT AT ONE’S OWN CENTER OF BEING. THEN YOU SAID THAT A CENTERING FOR THIS IS NEEDED. IS THIS CENTERING THE SAME AS THAT OF GURDJIEFF’S CRYSTALLIZATION?
PLEASE TELL US HOW THIS CENTERING OR CRYSTALLIZATION IS DIFFERENT FROM STRENGTHENING ONE’S OWN EGO, AND HOW DOES IT LEAD TO THE TRANSCENDENTAL TRUTH, THE THAT?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 Witnessing: The Base of all Techniques</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_1/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_1/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
Witnessing: The Base of all Techniques
3 June 1972 pm in Bombay, India
DRIK SWAROOP AWASTHANAM AKSHATAHA
TO BE ESTABLISHED IN ONE’S OWN WITNESSING NATURE IS AKSHAT – THE UNPOLISHED AND UNBROKEN RICE USED FOR THE WORSHIP.
WITNESSING is the technique for centering. We discussed centering. A man can live in two ways: he can live from his periphery or he can live from his center.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 Will or Surrender</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_1/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_1/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
Will or Surrender
6 June 1972 am in Bombay, India
Question 1
OSHO, LAST NIGHT YOU SAID THAT THE MIND CANNOT DO TWO THINGS TOGETHER – THAT IS, THINKING AND WITNESSING. IT SEEMS THEN THAT WITNESSING IS A MENTAL FACULTY AND AN ACT OF THE MIND. IS IT SO? PLEASE EXPLAIN. IS THERE ANYTHING LIKE PARTIAL WITNESSING AND TOTAL WITNESSING?
WITNESSING is not a mental activity; thinking is a mental activity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 Towards a Total Flowering of Consciousness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_1/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_1/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
Towards a Total Flowering of Consciousness
6 June 1972 om in Bombay, India
CHIDAAPTIH PUSHPAM
WHAT ARE THE FLOWERS FOR THE WORSHIP? – TO BE FILLED WITH CONSCIOUSNESS.
Man is a seed, a possibility, a potentiality. Man is not only what he is – he is also what he can be. Whatsoever man is, it is just a situation, just an opening, just a becoming.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 The Light of Awareness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_1/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_1/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 18
The Light of Awareness
6 June 1972 pm in
Question 1
OSHO, WE FEEL THAT TO PENETRATE AND TRANSFORM THE DEEPER LAYERS OF THE UNCONSCIOUS ONLY THROUGH AWARENESS IS DIFFICULT AND NOT ENOUGH. WHAT ELSE SHOULD ONE DO OTHER THAN THE PRACTICE OF AWARENESS? PLEASE EXPLAIN MORE ABOUT THE PRACTICAL DIMENSIONS ON THIS MATTER.
THE UNCONSCIOUS can be transformed only through awareness. It is difficult, but there is no other way.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Dissolution into the Cosmic</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_1/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_1/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
Dissolution into the Cosmic
16 February 1972 pm in Bombay, India
Question 1
OSHO, YOU SAID LAST NIGHT THAT THOSE WHO HAVE BECOME VOID, VALLEY-LIKE, DO NOT REACT BUT THEY RESPOND, AND THAT THE RESPONSES OF THESE DIFFERENT ENLIGHTENED ONES WILL BE DIFFERENT – THAT THE VALLEY WILL REECHO IN ITS OWN UNIQUE AND INDIVIDUAL WAY.
NOW A QUESTION ARISES WHETHER THOSE WHO BECOME ABSOLUTELY VOID, NOTHINGNESS, STILL HAVE A PERSONALITY AND INDIVIDUALITY.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Desirelessness: An Opening to the Unknown</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_1/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_1/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
Desirelessness: An Opening to the Unknown
17 February 1972 pm in Bombay, India
SARVA KARMA NIRAAKARANAM AAWAHANAM
CESSATION OF THE CAUSE OF ALL ACTIONS IS AAWAHANAM – THE INVOCATION.
RELIGION is not ritual. Really, when a religion dies it becomes ritual: the dead body of a religion becomes the ritual. But everywhere ritual is to be found. If you go to find religion, you will find ritual.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Desire: The Link with Life</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_1/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_1/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
Desire: The Link with Life
18 February 1972 pm in Bombay, India
Question 1
LAST NIGHT YOU SAID THAT DESIRES MOVE BETWEEN THE DEAD PAST AND THE IMAGINARY FUTURE. PLEASE EXPLAIN HOW AND WHY THIS DEAD PAST PROVES SO DYNAMIC AND POWERFUL THAT IT COMPELS A PERSON TO FLOW INTO THE PROCESS OF ENDLESS DESIRE. HOW CAN ONE BE FREE FROM THIS DYNAMIC PAST, THE UNCONSCIOUS AND THE COLLECTIVE UNCONSCIOUS?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 A still Mind: The Door to the Divine</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_1/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_1/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
A still Mind: The Door to the Divine
19 February 1972 pm in Bombay, India
NISCHAL GYANAM ASANAM
NON-WAVERING KNOWING IS ASANA – THE POSTURE
MAN IS neither a body, nor a mind alone – he is both. Even to say that he is both is wrong in a way because body and mind are separate only as two words. Existence is one.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Encountering the Unconscious</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_1/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_1/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
Encountering the Unconscious
20 February 1972 pm in Bombay, India
Question 1
CONSIDERING THE EXAMPLE OF SENSUAL INSTINCT, KINDLY EXPLAIN WHAT ARE THE PRACTICAL WAYS TO ENCOUNTER THE UNCONSCIOUS MIND, AND HOW CAN ONE KNOW THAT ONE HAS BECOME FREE FROM IT?
THE UNCONSCIOUS is not really unconscious. Rather, it is only less conscious. So the difference between conscious and unconscious is not of polar opposites, but of degrees.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 The upward Flow of the Mind</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_1/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_1/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
The upward Flow of the Mind
21 February 1972 pm in Bombay, India
UNMANI BHAAVAH PADDYAM
THE UPWARD FLOW OF THE MIND IS PADDYAM – THE WATER OF DIVINE WORSHIP.
THE MIND is the bridge between matter and consciousness, between without and within, between the gross and the subtle. When I say mind is the bridge, I mean many things. Man comes to the world through mind; man comes to the body through mind; man comes to desires through mind.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 The Complementariness of Opposites</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_1/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_1/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
The Complementariness of Opposites
22 February 1972 pm in Bombay, India
Question 1
OSHO, YOU SAID LAST NIGHT THAT TO HAVE AN UPWARD FLOW OF THE MIND ONE HAS TO MAKE A CONSTANT EFFORT AGAINST PAST ANIMAL HABITS. PLEASE EXPLAIN WHAT THE DIFFERENCE IS BETWEEN EFFORT AGAINST HABITS, AND SUPPRESSION.
TRANSFORMATION of the mind is a positive effort. Suppression of the mind is negative.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 What can Man Offer?</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_1/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_1/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
What can Man Offer?
23 February 1972 pm in Bombay, India
SADAAMANSKAM ARGHYAM
MIND CONSTANTLY ARROWED TOWARDS THAT IS ARGHYAM – THE OFFERING.
WHAT CAN man offer? What can the offering be7 We can offer only that which belongs to us. That which does not belong cannot become an offering, and man has always offered that which does not belong to him at all.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
