<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>God Is Not For Sale on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/god_is_not_for_sale/</link>
    <description>Recent content in God Is Not For Sale on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/god_is_not_for_sale/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/god_is_not_for_sale/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/god_is_not_for_sale/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
12 October 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, and tyagi means renunciation. Tyagi means one who has renounced – love and renunciation. I make a special condition for renunciation – and that is love. A man can renounce out of anger, a man can renounce out of hatred, a man can renounce out of frustration... but then it is meaningless.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/god_is_not_for_sale/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/god_is_not_for_sale/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
21 October 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss and shunyam means emptiness, nothingness, nobodyness. And that’s what bliss is. When you are empty, only then are you full – never before it. When you are not, only then you are – never before it. Your very absence is the door to the presence of God One has to annihilate oneself utterly; nothing less can help.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/god_is_not_for_sale/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/god_is_not_for_sale/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
22 October 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says he has always had trouble with relationships, including the present one with his girlfriend.]
Mm, mm. A relationship is always a problem because the other becomes the mirror and the presence of the other help you to see your own face in many ways. And the same happens to the other – you become the mirror.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/god_is_not_for_sale/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/god_is_not_for_sale/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
23 October 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin with a small child says that her husband has sent her away. He loves her but cannot live with her any more: He wants his silence, and the child and I are too much of a disturbance, I think.]
No, no, those are simply excuses. If you love, you accept everything that comes out of it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/god_is_not_for_sale/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/god_is_not_for_sale/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
24 October 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A newly arrived sannyasin says: I have been able to start witnessing myself. I don’t know if it’s really witnessing but it feels as if it’s something like that.]
Very good! That’s the only barrier – the subtle ego. It comes everywhere and it is so subtle that unless you are very very aware of it, it will go on deceiving you.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/god_is_not_for_sale/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/god_is_not_for_sale/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
25 October 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva Nisarga.… Nisarga means to be natural, to be spontaneous, to be simple and poor. And blessed are the poor – only they shall inherit the kingdom of God. Only the poor are rich. This inner poverty is really an inner richness. When you simply move with nature, by and by you disappear. You are so poor that even you are not there – the poverty is total.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/god_is_not_for_sale/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/god_is_not_for_sale/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
26 October 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine and batohi means the wanderer. And life is a divine wandering. There is no goal to it. One is not going somewhere – that’s why it is endless. It is not a journey – it is a wandering. A journey has a direction, and a journey has a destination in it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/god_is_not_for_sale/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/god_is_not_for_sale/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
27 October 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says he feels divided between following his feelings and making more effort.]
You simply follow your feelings. And who has said to you that it is easy to follow the feelings? It is the most difficult thing in the world, otherwise so many people would have been following their feelings; nobody follows.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/god_is_not_for_sale/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/god_is_not_for_sale/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
28 October 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin had previously written to Osho about a fever which she gets in the late afternoon and in the night. Osho checks her energy.]
Good. Come back! Do two things: one, tomorrow when you feel this heat coming to you, just go to the bathroom, rub your whole body with a dry towel.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/god_is_not_for_sale/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/god_is_not_for_sale/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
29 October 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prabhu means divine, and vairag means renunciation – divine renunciation. And renunciation can either be human Qr it can be divine. When it is human it is futile. When it is your doing it is not of much worth. But when it is God’s doing it has tremendous value. So I don’t teach that you have to practise renunciation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/god_is_not_for_sale/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/god_is_not_for_sale/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
30 October 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss and shantam means silence. So you have to be blissful and very silent. Happiness has a fever in it; it is never silent That’s the difference between happiness and bliss. Happiness is tense. One really gets tired of everything – even happiness. One cannot remain happy for a long time; you will get fed up with it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/god_is_not_for_sale/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/god_is_not_for_sale/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
13 October 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love and pradeepam means flame – a flame of love, a light of love or lamp of love. And sannyas is nothing but coming closer to me so that your unlit flame can be lit. Just coming closer to a flame is enough. In a certain moment the flame jumps from one flame to another.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/god_is_not_for_sale/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/god_is_not_for_sale/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
31 October 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
This will be your name... and to explain this a few things have to be understood. There has been a perennial debate down the centuries about man’s being – whether man comes into the world with an essence or just comes without any essence and accumulates essence through actions, through lifestyles, through experience... whether man comes like a seed or comes empty.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/god_is_not_for_sale/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/god_is_not_for_sale/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
1 October 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says: I feel if I don’t ask you whatever comes up – every week almost something new comes up – I’ll go off the track; I’ll go off on some incredible ego trip.]
Mm, mm. Even the fear of going in a wrong direction is an ego trip. Why are you so afraid of being in a wrong situation?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/god_is_not_for_sale/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/god_is_not_for_sale/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
2 October 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[The mother of a sannyasin said that Osho’s discourses had helped her to understand Jesus teachings: But when I go back, catholic students will ask me the difference between Osho Christ’s teaching and Jesus Christ’s teachings. And there is one point, if I may ask, I would like enlightenment on.
We are taught that the kingdom of heaven flowers in a love which shows itself in good works, in caring for the poor and the sick.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/god_is_not_for_sale/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/god_is_not_for_sale/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
3 October 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine and arpita means offered – offered to the divine, an offering to God. And that’s how life has to be. If it is not an offering one remains miserable. If it is not an offering one can never feel any meaning. Meaning comes only when you are joined together with something bigger than yourself; then suddenly there is meaning.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/god_is_not_for_sale/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/god_is_not_for_sale/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 24
5 October 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, natya means drama – a divine drama. And that’s what life is. It should not be taken seriously. The moment you take it seriously, you miss. It is a drama. Taken as a drama it is tremendously beautiful. One has nothing to lose in it and nothing to gain; it is simply fun.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/god_is_not_for_sale/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/god_is_not_for_sale/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 25
6 October 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[To a sannyasin leaving for the West.]
Continue to meditate. There are many temptations for dropping meditation, and they are not all from the outside; many are from the inside. The mind tends to be lethargic and it can always find good reasons, so don’t listen to the mind. Even if the reason seems to be perfectly right, be irrational but continue to meditate, because only those moments which have been used for meditation are the saved moments – all else is lost.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/god_is_not_for_sale/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/god_is_not_for_sale/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 26
7 October 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[To a sannyasin, recently-arrived from the West:]
These groups are just processes to unburden you a little, because God is not very far away; you just need a weightlessness. All that is needed is wings. He is very close, but everybody is so burdened – rocks upon rocks, and we cherish those rocks as if they are treasures.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/god_is_not_for_sale/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/god_is_not_for_sale/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
14 October 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine and dheeraj means patience – divine patience. And that is very significant to remember. On the path nothing more is needed than patience. Man can do everything that he is capable of, but still there is no necessity that the ultimate happens; it may happen, it may not. We can grope in the dark; the door may open, it may not So if one has not infinite patience, one starts getting tired of the search.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/god_is_not_for_sale/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/god_is_not_for_sale/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
15 October 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A visitor says: : I feel very close to you. I’ve been on the spiritual path for about twenty years... I’ve had many masters. When I first read the first few words of ‘My Way: The Way of the White Clouds’ I knew it was for me!]
(a chuckle) Good, very good. One has to learn from many sources, and one should never be closed to any possibility.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/god_is_not_for_sale/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/god_is_not_for_sale/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
16 October 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A visitor says: I’ve been here for five days and have been running the gammit of feelings from thinking you’re a phoney, to laughing at you. Now I’m at the point where all I have to say is – good, lord!
Osho had recounted a joke at the morning discourse that went like this:]</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/god_is_not_for_sale/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/god_is_not_for_sale/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
17 October 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Jaina is one of the most important concepts in the East. It means the conqueror of one’s own being. Literally it means the conqueror. And deva means divine – one who has become a god, or divine, by conquering himself. And there are only two possibilities to conquer: either you conquer others or you conquer yourself.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/god_is_not_for_sale/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/god_is_not_for_sale/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
18 October 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss and dhara means river – river of bliss. And become more and more river-like. Never allow anything to become stagnant Never allow anything to become frozen. The moment you see that something has become frozen, do something and get out of it.Because that frozen thing
is nothing but a dead part which has no more any life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/god_is_not_for_sale/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/god_is_not_for_sale/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
19 October 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss and subhan means well-aware – awareness of bliss. That you have to develop. Ordinarily we are more aware of misery. We are more aware of pain, more aware if something goes wrong, more aware of illness, disease, less aware of health, well-being. That creates much trouble, because if you are too much aware of pain you help pain to be there, you feed it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/god_is_not_for_sale/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/god_is_not_for_sale/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
20 October 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A therapist, recently arrived back from the States, was at darshan tonight Osho suggested he begin to plan a new group, commencing with just a vague idea of what he wanted... ]
.… There is no need to have a very fixed notion about it; just a hypothetical idea... just the direction, the line – like a vision – and then start working.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
