<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Only Losers Can Win in This Game on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Only Losers Can Win in This Game on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 Be Yes</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
Be Yes
1 October 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho tells a new sannyasin that the possibility is great and not to miss the opportunity... one can miss it very easily]
The door opens once in a while, so don’t hesitate. Right now the door is open for you. If you can gather courage to go into it, nothing is impossible in this moment.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Make womb for god</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
Make womb for god
10 October 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means blissful, yoganidra means a certain kind of sleep that only is possible in deep yoga.
The ordinary sleep has dreams; yoganidra has no dreams. In the ordinary sleep you become unconscious. In yoganidra you still retain your consciousness, you still remain alert. You know that you are fast asleep, but that knowing remains.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 Mystical marionettes</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
Mystical marionettes
11 October 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, barkha means rain: love rain. And that is the actual case: love is raining all over, because love is the stuff the universe is made of. When you pass by the side of a tree, the tree showers love. When you are standing open, under the open sky, the whole cosmos showers it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Jollity\&#39;s the only morality</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
Jollity’s the only morality
12 October 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, and vikrant means power: divine power. And trust not in your won power but in god’s. Man is impotent; only god is potent. If sometimes we feel powerful it is a borrowed power and you should not claim that it is yours; nothing is yours.
To understand this is to become a sannyasin, so from this moment all power is god’s.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 Love is a gift, not a guarantee</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
Love is a gift, not a guarantee
13 October 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva bhagya: divine benediction.And that has to become your climate: you have to start living in
that milieu. Take everything as a blessing – it is! Small joys of life, if looked into deeply and rightly, turn into great ecstasies. And even great ecstasies, if not looked at rightly and welcomed, turn into trivia.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 Meditation is manure for man</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
Meditation is manure for man
14 October 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva dwara: door to the divine. And become one! Everybody has the potential to become one. The potential just has to be transformed into an actuality; the seed has to become the tree.
And nothing much has to be done because we don’t make a seed a tree. We simply find the right soil, put the seed in the soil and it grows.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 Flying soul-o</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
Flying soul-o
15 October 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, ramraj means the kingdom of god: bliss, the kingdom of god. It is within you. The sky that I was talking about just now is within you. And the eagle I was telling you to become is your very soul. The soul is really confined, very much confined because the body is very earthbound.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 No \&#39;I\&#39; can see god</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
No ‘I’ can see god
16 October 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Visarjan means dissolution, dissolution into the divine, immersion in the divine, the state of being lost.…
One has to learn how to disperse oneself, how to come to a point where one is not. Only then god is. You and god cannot exist together; that’s not possible. That’s why so many people go on missing god – because they are asking for the impossible: they want to remain themselves and they want to see god.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 Don\&#39;t adore him, absorb him</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
Don’t adore him, absorb him
17 October 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho initiates someone who belonged to the Subud movement for ten years. She says her experience with them was sad.]
I will make it blissful!...
It happens many times. When you start going inwards the first layers are of sadness, because that’s what we have been repressing our whole lives or for many lives even.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 Love\&#39;s the cosmic cosmetic</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
Love’s the cosmic cosmetic
18 October 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, madhura means wine: bliss wine. And I sell it!... Now you are lost somewhere deep. It is good; there is no need to understand.You are intoxicated with me, you are drunk, so
how can you understand? But later on you will understand, mm? – there is no hurry.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19 Dropping burdens for birdswings</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
Dropping burdens for birdswings
19 October 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[To a new sannyasin Osho says:]
Raise your hands and close your eyes. Feel like a bird flying into the sky; these are your wings. If you start feeling like moving upwards, allow the body. If the hands start moving upwards, allow them; if the body starts swaying, go into that.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Play, Don\&#39;t Proselytise</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
Play, Don’t Proselytise
2 October 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A new sannyasin asks if Osho can help his father understand his taking sannyas because he is suffering over it.]
You can help him but his understanding cannot be guaranteed. If somebody wants to suffer then there is no way to help. If he is really that much closed – that he thinks only the thing he thinks is sane and everything else is insane – then he deserves suffering; he is earning it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 Sleep makes sheep of man</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
Sleep makes sheep of man
20 October 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine and gopala means shepherd. And everybody is a shepherd. It is not only that Christ is or Krishna is or Buddha is the shepherd: everybody is a shepherd. When you are not alert you are a sheep and when you alc alert you become the shepherd.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 To categorise is to devitalise</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
To categorise is to devitalise
21 October 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho gives someone sannyas, saying:]
Mm, close your eyes, and go in. Feel you are going in. You are not the body; keep that in your consciousness. The body is far away... surrounding you but you are not it. And neither are you the mind. That too is surrounding you – thoughts and thoughts surrounding you – but you are beyond it, you are the witness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22 The way is round the bend</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
The way is round the bend
22 October 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin brings her five-year-old son to take sannyas. She says she has problems with him: arguing... and he wants to fight with her in an angry way physically.]
I have given him the right name: courageous! Don’t try to force anything on him; let him have his way.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23 Mind is maddening</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
Mind is maddening
23 October 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says that she became exhausted assisting the Primal group, and has a fear that because she has burnt up so much energy in her past she will not live long.]
Just a mind idea! And you cannot spend your energy forever. Energy is continuously being produced. It is not like a reservoir: it has no fixed quantity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 Reflect, don\&#39;t project</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 24
Reflect, don’t project
27 October 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, mukul means mirror: a love mirror. And the message is that if one reflects rightly, if one becomes a mirror, one will not find anything else other than love. It is because of our distorting mind that we cannot see love, otherwise love is all around. From the trees and from the stars and from the sands and the sea and the pebbles, love is vibrating from everywhere.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25 Truth\&#39;s not a theory but a flower</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 25
Truth’s not a theory but a flower
28 October 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, blissful, and sanjaya means right victory – blissful right victory. Victory becomes wrong when it is enforced, when it is through violence, through aggression. When the other has to be defeated then the victory is wrong; it is ugly. When you don’t enforce it and the other simply surrenders to you it is right victory.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26 Self-erasing, truth-embracing</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 26
Self-erasing, truth-embracing
29 October 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, adima means primal. The cultured love is no more love; only the wild is true. The sophisticated is already dead; it breathes not. The civilised is so repressed, so managed, so formal, that it can’t be alive. Love is alive when it is primal. And if love is not alive, you are not alive.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27 Dying to live</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 27
Dying to live
30 October 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho initiates someone, telling her to imagine she is a waterfall. He then tells her that it is very difficult for her to imagine, so imagination cannot be of any help to her]
Imagination, if available, is great energy; it can transform you. But if you are not available then there is no need to go in that direction.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28 God has no fixed address</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/part28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/part28/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 28
God has no fixed address
31 October 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, lolita means moved by, swayed by, possessed by, swinging, rocking: rocking and swinging in love. And let that become your very life-style. Remain in movement, remain in a kind of dance, and be swayed by the small things of life. They are not small! If we can be swayed by them, they are all extraordinary.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Madness keeps you sane</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
Madness keeps you sane
3 October 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A mother brings her child to take sannyas. The child sits very still with closed eyes, and Osho tells her mother to help her meditate.]
She has very meditative energy... can easily go into meditation. So help her; whenever you go to the meditation take her with you. She can just be there and by and by she will start moving.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Hollow man or hollow bamboo</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
Hollow man or hollow bamboo
4 October 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means blissful, bhagat means a devotee a follower on the path of love.
There are three paths; one is of knowledge, of meditation, of purifying the intelligence. The second is of action, of service. And the third is of devotion, of love, of the heart. The path of action is body-oriented, the path of knowledge is mind-oriented, and the path of devotion is heart-oriented</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Better madly happy than sadly sane</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
Better madly happy than sadly sane
5 October 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin, who is leaving, says she wants to return with her children and husband.]
Mm mm, good! Something has happened and it will go on growing. It is not like a thing that happens; it is a process.
It will go on happening. Just cooperate with it; don’t stop it!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Divine Dictator</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
Divine Dictator
6 October 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine and suraj means order: divine order. To be in that state one has to be possessed by god. One has to lose oneself more and more, one’s ideas, one’s mind, one’s manipulations, one’s control.
There can be two orders in a human being. Either man orders himself – he is his own government – or god becomes his government and he simply follows.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Be a honey bee</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
Be a honey bee
7 October 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, madhukar means honey bee. And it is a very very pregnant symbol in the East – the honey bee. It represents freedom. It never becomes attached to any flower; it simply goes from one flower to another, collecting honey. But it is never attached, it remains unattached.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 Man is a mission impossible</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
Man is a mission impossible
8 October 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Veet vishada – beyond despair.…
And despair is the ordinary condition of humanity. People may know, may not know, but they are in despair. People are constantly in a turmoil, in an anxious state. That is natural because they don’t know who they are. They don’t know where they are going; they don’t know why they are existing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 Re-gem-ber yourself</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/only_losers_can_win_in_this_game/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
Re-gem-ber yourself
9 October 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, heera means diamond. And the diamond is there; we just have to search for it. Everybody brings it with their birth. God never sends anybody poor; he provides for the whole journey. But he keeps the diamond in such a hidden place in you that sometimes it takes many lives to discover it.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
