<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Don\&#39;t Just Do Something, Sit There on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Don\&#39;t Just Do Something, Sit There on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
1 September 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love and patanga is a special moth that is very much attracted to fire, flame, and whenever there is flame the moth will come and jump into it. Its only love is fire. And hence the name ‘patanga’ has become a metaphor in the east – a metaphor for the lover. A lover has to be like the moth – ready to jump into fire, ready to die, ready to disappear.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
10 September 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin couple and their baby are present. The man says he expected to come here and feel better, more loving. Instead, he says, in some ways he feels more sad, tense, angry.]
Expectation always creates misery. If you expect something, that very expectation will become the barrier. So live a life without any expectations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
11 September 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A new sannyasin asks if she can train in tantra yoga, as she is a therapist and can use it in her work.]
You can train. You can be of immense help to people.…
Yes, you can. So you do the tantra group here. You can bring very good energy into helping people. And people’s problems are basically concerned with sex energy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
12 September 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, vasant means spring – bliss spring. And when bliss comes it comes like a spring. It was not there and suddenly it is there; suddenly the whole climate is different. It takes you unawares. It comes very unexpectedly, and one never knows from where it will start and begin. which tree will bloom first, will have the first taste of spring, nobody knows.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
14 September 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, prasava means birth – birth of love. And let sannyas be a birth of love... a birth in love. Live love as intensely as possible; let that be your doing. Everything else in life is a means; the end is always love. And if the means fulfill love then the person is sane; if the means don’t fulfill love then the person is insane.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
15 September 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, samoda means delight – divine delight. And let that be your climate – live in it, breathe in it. It is only a question of remembering, and it comes. And you can do it very easily. You can easily become miserable, you can easily become blissful; it is one’s own creation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
16 September 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin, who is leaving, says she has a lot of fear, and perhaps she is running away.]
No, it is not escaping. It is not running away; it is part of the process. If you want to come close to me, sometimes you have to go away. Then next time you will come even closer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
17 September 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin who is leaving for Goa says: Thank you.]
Meditate in Goa, mm? Goa is very related to me! Either the sannyasin has first to go to Goa then come to me or has to come to me and then go to Goa! This way or that but Goa is related. It is a beautiful place, so be on the beach in the sun and meditate, mm?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
18 September 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho talks to a new sannyasin about being a therapist. He says, do you know the word ‘therapist’ comes from an ancient parsi word from Buddha’s time meaning elder brother?]
Anand means blissful, and Rinzai was a great zen mystic – a Chinese – founder of the Rinzai sect of zen.
Literally the word means: one who helps people to cross the river, the boatman.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
19 September 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A visitor says he is not sure about becoming a sannyasin.]
Nobody knows unless they become! How can one know without becoming? It is something to be experienced; it is something existential, experiential. It is not something that can be explained in any way. It is like love or like death: you know only when you have gone through it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
20 September 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho gives sannyasin to someone saying, just feel lost; lose control; don’t hold yourself together; just fall into pieces, and if the body starts falling on to the floor, allow it. Don’t be worried.]
The easiest is the most difficult; the difficult is not so difficult. The ego is always ready to do the difficult because doing the difficult the ego is enhanced; it feels good.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
2 September 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, nispati means conclusion. And there are two types of conclusion: one is logical, intellectual, another is of the heart. The logical conclusion is superficial; only the conclusion that arises in life through love is decisive. You can go on arguing and thinking round and round; thinking moves in a circle. It always feels as if something is happening, as if one is arriving, but one never arrives, and each conclusion simply begins to be another question.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
22 September 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says that he has been thinking on, and getting depressed about, the past. Osho says that to keep looking back to the past is an effective way of making misery for oneself. Good or bad, the past is finished. It has no more any validity, no more any relevance. Look forwards, never look backwards.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
23 September 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin asks how to make his hobby of painting a meditation.]
Art is meditation. Any activity becomes meditation if you are lost in it. So don’t just remain a technician. If you are just a technician then painting will never become meditation. You have to be crazily into it, madly into it, completely lost, not knowing where you are going, not knowing what you are doing, not knowing who you are.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
24 September 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin newly returned says: I’m pretty shaky but I feel good.]
One is shaky if one is feeling good! People don’t feel so shaky when they are not feeling good. People are acquainted with that state of not feeling good. They are perfectly familiar with it; they are not shaky. When you really feel good you feel shaky.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
25 September 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin has brought her son because she is worried about the way he doesn’t eat, which may be causing bronchitis, and how he relates with other children.]
What is the way? I think the problem is more with you than with him!
He seems to be perfectly okay! You seem to be too worried about him.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 24
26 September 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho tells an initiate to close her eyes and to feel a sound arising from her heart. Let yourself be possessed by the sound. If it starts coming – any sound – allow it. If you start saying it loudly, go with it; go into it.
Osho then explains the meaning of prem bhajan – worship through sound.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 25
27 September 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand vipal – bliss moment.
And remember that the moment is the penetration of eternity into time. The moment is not part of time; the moment is something that comes beyond time. In fact, the real moment is between two moments of time. It is just as these two fingers are there and there is a gap.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 26
28 September 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin who is leaving has difficulty surrendering to the commune. He asks Osho to decide whether he leaves or not... ]
Then I can just direct you what to do. Then there is no problem.The problem arises only when
you start doing your own thing, and then you fall out of tune with the things here.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 27
29 September 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, madhumaya means sweet as honey.
And love is the only sweetness; everything else is bitter. We can even tolerate bitter things if there is a little mixture of love in them; otherwise life becomes unbearable. Life is unbearable; it is only love that makes it bearable. Life in itself is meaningless – it is love that brings meaning to it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/part28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/part28/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 28
30 September 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says his wife, a non-sannyasin, wants to study psychology.] Where can she study psychology better than here? Just tell her!...
Anywhere else you can study psychology as a dead subject – here it is alive. Here people are opening up, growing, and that’s what psychology basically is: the science of the soul.
The western psychology is yet not worthy enough of being called psychology.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
3 September 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho explains the meaning of prem nutan: new, fresh love. Love is synonymous with life. If you can be true to love then there is no need for any other religion. Love is the highest religion possible and it takes you tot the ultimate goal. When there is flow, life has a glow. When there is no flow, life is just so-so.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
4 September 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Osho explains the meaning of veet nisadha: beyond no, beyond negation.… Drop no-saying; become more and more of a yea-sayer.]
Yes, say yes to life. And if one is aware, then one will be surprised that many times we unnecessarily say no... and we harm nobody except ourselves by saying that. No is fear-oriented; yes is love.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
5 September 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Ananda means bliss, svatma means the innermost self, the innermost core, the being. Bliss being – that will be the meaning of the name... and there is a message in it for you. I give names as messages. You will have to unfold it, live it, and by and by the name will become a reality.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
6 September 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho checks someone’s energy saying: Create a space of fear in and around yourself. Osho tells him that he is sitting on a deep layer of fear. Fear and anger are two sides of one coin. Fear is a good policy but very bad for growth. Anger is not a very good policy but is very good for growth.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
7 September 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho gives sannyas to a baby who throws the mala off. Then he tells the mother: And always treat him with great respect. Each child brings divine fragrance into the world and each child should be treated as a god or a goddess.
The following morning Osho spoke about him in discourse.]
Just last night, a sannyasin came with her small boy for sannyas.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
8 September 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho explains the meaning of prem akal – timeless love. And love is the only phenomenon that exists in time and yet is beyond time]
Once a gardener brought to me a summer flower – a small plant. After three, four weeks it bloomed. It was really a beautiful flower but within three, four weeks the flower was gone and the stem also died.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dont_just_do_something_sit_there/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
9 September 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means blissful, shravan means listening – blissful listening. And there is a difference between hearing and listening. If one is not deaf, one hears; it is the physical part of listening, the gross part. But if you are not listening attentively, if you are not hearing totally, if you are not there in it participating, then it remains hearing; it is not listening.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
