<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Dimensions Beyond the Known on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dimensions_beyond_the_known/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dimensions Beyond the Known on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/dimensions_beyond_the_known/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dimensions_beyond_the_known/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dimensions_beyond_the_known/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
28 February 1970 pm
Question 1
OSHO, I HAVE READ YOUR LITERATURE; I HAVE HEARD YOU. YOUR LANGUAGE HAS HYPNOTIC CHARM AND IS VERY CLEAR. SOMETIMES YOU SPEAK ON MAHAVIRA, SOMETIMES ON KRISHNA OR BUDDHA AND SOMETIMES YOU TELL ABOUT JESUS AND MOHAMMED AS WELL. YOU DIVULGE THE SECRETS OF THE GITA IN A MOST INSPIRING MANNER, YOU GIVE DISCOURSES ON THE UPANISHADS AND THE VEDAS, AND YOU WOULD NOT HESITATE TO GO TO TEMPLES OR CHURCHES TO GIVE DISCOURSES.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dimensions_beyond_the_known/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dimensions_beyond_the_known/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
7 March 1971 pm
Question 1
YOU SAID THAT IF ONE WERE TALKING ABOUT THE BODY YOU WOULD SAY THAT THE BODY WAS DEATH-ORIENTED AND IF ONE WERE TALKING ABOUT THE SOUL YOU WOULD SAY, “YOU WERE NEVER BORN AT ALL.” BUDDHA HAS SAID OF THE SOUL, “IT WAS JUST A BUBBLE WHICH IS NOW NO MORE. I MYSELF AM NOT THERE, SO WHERE WILL I GO?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dimensions_beyond_the_known/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dimensions_beyond_the_known/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
10 March 1971 pm
Question 1
OSHO, DOES THE RITUAL OF TWENTY-ONE DAYS WHICH YOU INDICATED YOU WERE DOING IN YOUR PREVIOUS BIRTH BELONG TO ANY PARTICULAR TRADITION OF MEDITATION AND SELF-EXPERIENCE? BECAUSE FROM YOUR SPEECHES, IT APPEARS THAT YOU ARE DEFINITELY REPRESENTING THE METHODS OF SOME GREAT TEACHER OR TEERTHANKER. IN VIEW OF THIS, MAY I ALSO DARE TO ASK WHETHER YOU WISH TO CONNECT A SPIRITUAL LINK TO SOME TRADITIONAL CHAIN, OR LIKE BUDDHA ARE YOU ATTEMPTING TO CUT A NEW PATH ON SOME MOUNTAIN?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dimensions_beyond_the_known/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dimensions_beyond_the_known/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
12 March 1971 pm
Question 1
OSHO, YOU HAVE TOLD US WHAT HAPPENS TO THE SOUL DURING THAT TIMELESS INTERVAL BETWEEN TWO BIRTHS. BUT SOME POINTS REMAIN UNRESOLVED, REGARDING THE BODILESS SOUL: IN THAT BODILESS STATE, DOES THE SOUL REMAIN STATIONARY OR CAN IT MOVE ABOUT? AND HOW DOES IT RECOGNIZE OTHER SOULS? IN THAT STATE, IS THERE ANY POSSIBILITY OF A DIALOGUE BETWEEN SOULS?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 From childhood to enlightenment, the birth of a new man</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dimensions_beyond_the_known/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dimensions_beyond_the_known/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
From childhood to enlightenment, the birth of a new man
Date unkown
Question 1
WHAT WAS THAT EVENT THAT MADE YOU TURN TOWARD THE SPIRITUAL? WHAT WAS THAT MIRACLE?
There has been no such event. It happens many times that some event occurs and a person takes a turn in life. It also happens that as a result of the collective effect of many events, a person’s life is changed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dimensions_beyond_the_known/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dimensions_beyond_the_known/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 6
Date unkown
Question 1
YOU HAVE EXPLAINED TO US ABOUT THE THREE GUNAS, THE THREE BASIC FORCES OF LIFE, OF TAMAS, THE CAUSE OF INACTIVITY, INERTIA AND INDOLENCE, RAJAS, THE CAUSE OF ACTIVITY OR PASSION, AND SATTWA, THE CAUSE OF SERENITY, CALMNESS AND KNOWLEDGE. YOU HAVE ALSO EXPLAINED TO US THAT THEY EXISTED IN EQUAL MEASURE IN THE PERSONALITIES OF LAO TZU, JESUS, MAHAVIRA AND KRISHNA.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
