<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Buddha Disease on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Buddha Disease on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 If you meet the Buddha on the Way\...</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
If you meet the Buddha on the Way...
1 January 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Buddha means one who is enlightened, and prem means love – love for the enlightened one, or love for enlightenment.
Buddha is not a person – mm? it is a state of ultimate being. There have been many buddhas, and everybody is potentially a buddha. The word itself means tremendously awakened, absolutely alert.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Man is made of the stuff called love</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
Man is made of the stuff called love
10 January 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love and swarupam means your innermost core – love is your innermost core. It is everybody’s innermost core – that1s why there is so much desire to be loved and to love. And unless that desire to love and to be loved is fulfilled, one remains very desperate.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 Love is the essential religion</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
Love is the essential religion
11 January 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, shantam means silent – divine silence. And let this be your basic key – silence. Whenever you can find time, wherever, fall into silence. And there is no need to find a separate place for it. Walking on the road you can remember and fall into silence, and you will enjoy the walk more, because when you are silent you are more alive, more pulsating.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 My whole work is to help you to die</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
My whole work is to help you to die
12 January 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, neelamber means blue sky – blue sky of bliss. And there is a particular meaning of blue sky in the eastern symbology. Sometimes you may see a small white cloud floating in the sky and then receding back far away, far away, disappearing, and suddenly it is gone.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 Meditation is the door to timelessness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
Meditation is the door to timelessness
13 January 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love and bindu means a drop; a drop of love. And a drop of love is big enough – it can become an ocean. It contains the ocean in it – it is not a mere drop. No drop is a mere drop – not at least the drop of love, because the very energy of love is expanding, opening, flowering.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 Go to God through laughter, through dancing</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
Go to God through laughter, through dancing
14 January 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, and achinta means no anxiety. And remember that only love brings a state of no anxiety – and only love. Everything else creates a new anxiety.
You can go on changing your anxieties – somebody is seeking money, somebody is seeking power, then somebody starts seeking god – but all things will bring anxiety.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 Our home is beyond the stars</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
Our home is beyond the stars
15 January 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin who is leaving for the west asks Osho to give her confirmation why she needs to wear orange and mala. She is afraid of her friends’ reactions. But also she is afraid if she doesn’t wear orange and mala, that Osho will not be with her.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 Dance is the basic language of religion</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
Dance is the basic language of religion
16 January 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love and gayan means singing; love singing. Two things to be remembered about it: one, that love is always in sharing, in singing, in expression. You cannot hoard it. Hoard it and it is gone. Hold it, hoard it, and you kill it. Love is only when it is flowing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 In the hands of love even a rock starts throbbing</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
In the hands of love even a rock starts throbbing
18 January 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem sandesh means message of love... and when you are really in the right space, you become the message of love. Your whole being flowers like love. Your whole life is nothing but love energy then, and whatsoever you touch becomes gold.
With hate, whatsoever you touch becomes poison – hate is a poisoning element.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19 The master is to shock you out of your sleep</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
The master is to shock you out of your sleep
19 January 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
.… Meditation is nothing but a remembrance of the kingdom that is yours, the kingdom that is within... of the kingship that everybody brings with himself into the world. A reminder is needed. Somebody has to shock you out of your sleep. That is the function of a master.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 I declare you a god, a goddess</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
I declare you a god, a goddess
2 January 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[To a new initiate Osho gives the name Ma Prem Kalpa]
Prem means love and kalpa means imagination – love imagination. And you have to work on it. Imagination is going to be your path. You have the capacity to visualise, to imagine – you have a poet’s heart – and images will come very easily to you.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 Just get more and more drunk with me</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
Just get more and more drunk with me
20 January 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[To Toshen who had taken sannyas in the West:
.… And do you know the meaning of your name?
That should not remain just the meaning of your name – it should become the meaning of your life too! It means bliss, contentment... and both are aspects of one phenomenon.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 Celebrate as if you are already a buddha</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
Celebrate as if you are already a buddha
21 January 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, anshujal means a net of rays, light rays. the whole name will mean a net of love and light rays, a synthesis of love and light. And in fact, that’s how reality is.
If you go through the scientific approach you will find nothing but light, a network of light and rays.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22 When the dance is total, the ego is nullified</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
When the dance is total, the ego is nullified
22 January 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, godly, and shalabha means a moth. And in indian mythology and in indian poetry too, the moth is a metaphor. Just as the moth is attracted towards light, knowing well that coming closer to the flame is going to be his death.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23 You are just part of a big orange ocean</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
You are just part of a big orange ocean
23 January 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, and vasundhara means the earth; divine earth. And I give you this name for many reasons: one, the earth represents the feminine mind – the sky represents the male mind. The feminine mind is very earthly, and every woman has to understand the meaning of the earth because that is her innermost core of being.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 To become aware is to become desireless</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 24
To become aware is to become desireless
24 January 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, and mahashunya means the great emptiness. Anand is the natural state of resting in oneself. It is not happiness – because it is not unhappiness. It is not part of the duality, the dual world – happy and unhappy, sound/silence, day/night, life/death. It is not part of duality; it is the non-dual state.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25 Life is a risk, that\&#39;s why it is so beautiful</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 25
Life is a risk, that’s why it is so beautiful
25 January 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, atideva means the great god; love, the great god. And love is the great god. All gods are lower than love – there is no value higher than love. Every value is a value because it partakes of love, but love is the supreme value.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26 OUr destiny is to have wings, to fly</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 26
OUr destiny is to have wings, to fly
26 January 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means blissful, and sadhu means simplicity; blissful simplicity. And these two things are to be remembered – be blissful and be simple. Only a complicated mind is lost – a simple mind is never lost. A simple mind is always at home – and you have that simple mind.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27 To be blissful is the greatest courage</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 27
To be blissful is the greatest courage
27 January 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means the ultimate state of bliss, mahavira means greatly courageous. And that’s what is needed!
Nothing else but courage is needed, and everything will happen on its own accord. We go on missing many things in life just because we lack courage. In fact, no effort is needed to achieve – just courage – and things start coming to you rather than you going to them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28 My whole work is to push you into emptiness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part28/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 28
My whole work is to push you into emptiness
28 January 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho gives sannyas to a seeker.]
This will be your name... and not only a name but a radical change – a one-hundred-and-eighty- degree turn. Less than that won’t do... Less than that never does anything. You can go on boiling water at ninety-nine degrees.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>29 Thorns are as significant as roses</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part29/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 29
Thorns are as significant as roses
29 January 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, and rajhansa means a royal swan.
It is a mythological metaphor. The ordinary swan can stay in any lake but the royal swan only stays at the purest lake in the himalayas; the lake is called mansorovhar. In the hindu mythology it is the purest lake in the world and it is the most beautiful.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 This feeling of belonging \-- that you are together with these trees and the stars and the moon and the sun \-- is what I call trust</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
This feeling of belonging – that you are together with these trees and the stars and the moon and the sun – is what I call trust
3 January 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Veet means beyond, sandhaya means doubt – beyond doubt. And that’s how one approaches truth. Doubt never leads towards truth – only trust. Trust is the key.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>30 If you know one secret \-- to be happy right now \-- you have learned it all</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part30/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 30
If you know one secret – to be happy right now – you have learned it
all
30 January 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, and sangeetam means music: bliss music. They have something in common. Bliss is a music – can be expressed only by music – and music has a blissfulness in it. Hence whenever somebody is lost in music, a glimpse of bliss, like a whip, comes into one’s being.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>31 Theology becomes alive only when a person is alive who knows God by existential experience</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part31/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 31
Theology becomes alive only when a person is alive who knows God
by existential experience
31 January 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Dharma means the ultimate law, tao, or what Christians and Jews call god. But in the East the word’god’ is not thought to be so supreme, because it becomes personalised; it becomes more anthropomorphic. So in the east we conceive of the ultimate reality more as an impersonal law than a person.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 In life, surrender is the key</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
In life, surrender is the key
4 January 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, and dhurva means fresh grass, just sprouting... very green, delicate – divine grass. And there is a particular meaning in it.
A man can exist in two ways: either like a very strong tree – resistant, fighting, stubborn – or like small grass – non-resistant, non-fighting, ready to yield.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Take life in the spirit of a picnic</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
Take life in the spirit of a picnic
5 January 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, abhiyana means adventure divine adventure. And remember it always – that life is never a static thing. And the moment you make it static, it has already slipped out of your hand. Life is only in the process. It is in adventure, pilgrimage.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Everything is within the reach of an empty hand</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
Everything is within the reach of an empty hand
6 January 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Dharma is a very special sanskrit word. It means exactly what in chinese they mean by tao, or what in greek they mean by logos – the ultimate law. Not any law in particularThe law of gravitation
is a particular law. And then there are many laws – chemical, biological, physical, but they are all particular laws.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Meditation is the art of creating inner beauty</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
Meditation is the art of creating inner beauty
7 January 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Jaya means inner victory, conquering oneself, and ananda means bliss – bliss that comes out of conquering oneself. And that is the only bliss there is. You can conquer the whole world and you will remain miserable; of course your misery will become a thousand-fold – the misery of an alexander is bound to be tremendous.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 Meditation is learning to wait</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
Meditation is learning to wait
8 January 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, and sarjan means creativity; divine creativity. And my attitude towards god is that he is not a creator but just pure creativity... just the energy, not a person. Personality is a human imposition on god – good for us because it is difficult for us to comprehend god as just pure energy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 Only dare-devils reach that which is called god</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_buddha_disease/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
Only dare-devils reach that which is called god
9 January 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Indradanu means rainbow – but better than rainbow. Indra is the god of rains. In the east everything is thought to be divine and everything is thought to be full of the divine. The god of rains is indra, and danu means the bow. So it is god indra’s bow.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
