<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Come Follow To You - Vol 3 on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/come_follow_to_you__vol_3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Come Follow To You - Vol 3 on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/come_follow_to_you__vol_3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chapter #1</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/come_follow_to_you__vol_3/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/come_follow_to_you__vol_3/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter #1‌ Chapter title: Jesus is like a wilderness: raw, but alive, 11 December 1975 am in Buddha Hall MATTHEW 13
54 AND WHEN HE WAS COME INTO HIS OWN COUNTRY, HE TAUGHT THEM IN THEIR SYNAGOGUE, INSOMUCH THAT THEY WERE
ASTONISHED, AND SAID, WHENCE HATH THIS MAN THIS WISDOM, AND
THESE MIGHTY WORKS?
55 IS NOT THIS THE CARPENTER&#39;S SON? IS NOT HIS MOTHER CALLED</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter #10</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/come_follow_to_you__vol_3/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/come_follow_to_you__vol_3/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌Chapter #10‌ Chapter title: Love is fragile like a flower. Hatred is powerful like a sword. 20 December 1975 am in Buddha Hall Question 1
WILL YOU PLEASE EXPLAIN TO ME THE LORD&#39;S PRAYER, AS GIVEN BY
JESUS?
MEDITATION CAN BE EXPLAINED, prayer never. It can be understood, but it cannot be explained. Prayer is something of the heart, very elusive, very indefinable. You can feel it, but you cannot think it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter #2</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/come_follow_to_you__vol_3/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/come_follow_to_you__vol_3/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter #2‌ Chapter title: Accept yourself as you are, and accept 12 December 1975 am in Buddha Hall Question 1
MANY TIMES I FEEL GUILTY BECAUSE I CANNOT RECEIVE YOU.
The word &#34;GUILT&#34; should never be used. The very word has wrong associations; and once you use it you are caught in it. Guilt is not a natural phenomenon: it is created by the priests.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter #3</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/come_follow_to_you__vol_3/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/come_follow_to_you__vol_3/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter #3‌ Chapter title: There is no Future God; there is no past 13 December 1975 am in Buddha Hall MATTHEW I6
13 WHEN JESUS CAME INTO THE COASTS OF CAESAREA PHILLIPI, HE
ASKED HIS DISCIPLES, SAYING, WHOM DO MEN SAY THAT I, THE SON OF
MAN, AM?
14 AND THEY SAID, SOME SAY THAT THOU ART JOHN THE BAPTIST: SOME, ELIAS; AND OTHERS,JEREMIAS, OR ONE OF THE PROPHETS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter #4</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/come_follow_to_you__vol_3/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/come_follow_to_you__vol_3/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter #4‌ Chapter title: Surrender is the door to bliss, to beauty, 14 December 1975 am in Buddha Hall Question 1
HOW WOULD YOU DESCRIBE YOUR PARTICULAR PATH TO ENLIGHTENMENT IN RELATIONSHIP TO OTHER TRADITIONAL PATHS
SUCH AS THE VARIOUS KINDS OF YOGA, SUFISM, BUDDHISM, ZEN, CHRISTIANITY, ETCETERA?
I HAVE NO particular path. I don&#39;t belong to any path whatsoever, and therefore all paths belong to me.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter #5</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/come_follow_to_you__vol_3/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/come_follow_to_you__vol_3/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter #5‌ Chapter title: No man has ever found God. Whenever man is 15 December 1975 am in Buddha Hall MATTHEW 21
12 AND JESUS WENT INTO THE TEMPLE OF GOD, AND CAST OUT ALL THEM THAT SOLD AND BOUGHT IN THE TEMPLE, AND OVERTHREW THE TABLES OF THE MONEY-CHANGERS, AND THE SEATS OF THEM THAT SOLD DOVES,
13 AND SAID UNTO THEM, IT IS WRITTEN, MY HOUSE SHALL BE CALLED</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter #6</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/come_follow_to_you__vol_3/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/come_follow_to_you__vol_3/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter #6‌ Chapter title: A man who is enlightened has no masks, has 16 December 1975 am in Buddha Hall Question 1
I MYSELF AM A QUESTION. I KNOW NOT WHO I AM. WHAT TO DO? WHERE TO GO?
REMAIN WITH THE QUESTION. Don t do anything, and don t go anywhere; and don&#39;t start believing in any answer. Remain with the question. That is one of the most difficult things to do -- to remain with a question, and not to seek the answer; because the mind is very cunning, it can supply a false answer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter #7</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/come_follow_to_you__vol_3/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/come_follow_to_you__vol_3/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter #7‌ Chapter title: The more you love, the more fear disappears. 17 December 1975 am in Buddha Hall MATTHEW 22
35 THEN ONE OF THEM, WHICH WAS A LAWYER, ASKED HIM A QUESTION, TEMPTING HIM, AND SAYING,
36 MASTER, WHICH IS THE GREAT COMMANDMENT IN THE LAW
37 JESUS SAID UNTO HIM, THOU SHALT LOVE THE LORD THY GOD WITH
ALL THY HEART, AND WITH ALL THY SOUL, AND WITH ALL THY MIND.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter #8</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/come_follow_to_you__vol_3/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/come_follow_to_you__vol_3/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter #8‌ Chapter title: I bring the greatest synthesis that is 18 December 1975 am in Buddha Hall Question 1
I OFTEN DESIRE TO HAVE AN ISOLATED, SECURE PLACE TO ALLOW SURRENDER. MEDITATIONS SEVERAL HOURS A DAY GOING DEEPER
AND DEEPER WITHOUT DISTRACTION. AS I UNDERSTAND, MOST YOGA MASTERS TEACH THAT WITHDRAWAL FROM THE WORLD IS
NECESSARY FOR A PERIOD OF TIME, ONCE KUNDALINI STARTS RISING, UNTIL ONE IS FINALLY ESTABLISHED IN SAMADHI; AT WHICH TIME</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter #9</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/come_follow_to_you__vol_3/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/come_follow_to_you__vol_3/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter #9‌ Chapter title: Jesus is water of eternity, a divine well. 19 December 1975 am in Buddha Hall JOHN 7
25 THEN SAID SOME OF THEM OF JERUSALEM...
27 HOWBEIT WE KNOW THIS MAN WHENCE HE IS: BUT WHEN CHRIST
COMETH, NO MAN KNOWETH WHENCE HE IS.
28 THEN CRIED JESUS IN THE TEMPLE AS HE TAUGHT, SAYING, YE BOTH
KNOW ME, AND YE KNOW WHENCE I AM: AND I AM NOT COME OF MYSELF, BUT HE THAT SENT ME IS TRUE, WHOM YE KNOW NOT.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
