<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Rainbow Bridge on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Rainbow Bridge on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
1 July 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Michael means one who is godlike, and anando means blissful. One is basically divine because all is divine. To exist is to be divine, to be alive is to be divine, to breathe is to be divine. Hence trees are divine and the rocks and the birds and the people – whatsoever is. Divinity is another name of isness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
10 July 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand Kaela. Anand means blissfulness; and if kaela has no meaning, then your name will mean a blissful meaninglessness. And that’s exactly what life is: it is utterly blissful but it has no meaning. It is blissful because it has no meaning.
To have meaning means to become a commodity, to have meaning means to become a thing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
12 July 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand Ciska. Anand means bliss; ciska means freedom. Bliss is freedom and vice versa: freedom is bliss. In fact they are two sides of the same coin. Misery arises out of limitation. Bliss is to know that we are infinite, that even the sky is not our limit, that we are one with the whole.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
13 July 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin, leaving, asks: How do I find when I am the witness?]
It is something self-evident: when you are, you know it; no extemal proof is needed. If the question arises that means that you are not, otherwise the question does not arise at all. It is like having a headache: nobody asks, “How am I to know whether I have a headache or not?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
14 July 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand Saoirse. Anand means bliss; saoirse means freedom. Bliss is possible only in freedom; freedom is the right space in which bliss grows, the right soil. Without freedom there is no possibility of bliss growing. One cannot be happy without freedom, one can at the most pretend to be happy.
As the society is, everybody exists as a slave.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
15 July 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem Francesco. Prem means love; francesco means freedom. Love is the ultimate form of freedom; if love cannot bring freedom then nothing else can. If even love becomes a bondage then everything else is going to become a bondage. Love is the only hope of salvation.
It is through love that we become able to see something of the beyond.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
16 July 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand Elles. Anand means bliss; elles comes from the Hebrew root el; el means God. Bliss is God.
God is indefinable, but if any definition is possible at all, then bliss is his definition. The definition that comes closest to define God is bliss. Even that falls short but it is the most approximate.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
17 July 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva Yoshiro. Deva means God; yoshiro means favorite – God’s favorite. Everyone is, but very few people become aware of it. Those who become aware become full of gratitude. And to be grateful, to feel grateful for all that is, is to be religious. And it is really a tremendously beautiful existence; it cannot be improved upon, it is perfect as it is.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
18 July 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva Constantinos. Deva means God; constantinos means constant. Only God is a constant factor in existence; everything else is always changing, moving. Everything else is a process; only God is a being. God is the very center of all this movement, and the center cannot move, only the wheel moves. The world is a wheel and God is the center of it – the center of the cyclone.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
19 July 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem Matthew. Prem means love; matthew means a gift of God. There are things which we can attain to, which can become our achievements – money, power, prestige – and there are things which we can never attain, which can never become our achievements: life, meditation, love. The things that we can attain are ordinary.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
20 July 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem Naoko. Prem means love; naoko means straight. Love is simple and straight. Because it is not cunning, it does not go roundabout, it does not move in circles; it goes like a straight arrow. It is innocent, hence it is straight.
And only love can reach to the ultimate source of life, because the ultimate source has to be penetrated like an arrow.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
2 July 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand Erik. Anand means bliss; erik means brave, courageous.
The root cause of misery is fear: we are too afraid of the unknown. We remain confined in the known, and because we remain confined in the known, life becomes a repetition, a circle; one goes on moving in the same circle again and again and again.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
21 July 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand Patrice. Anand means bliss; patrice means noble. Bliss makes a person noble, not birth, not education, not morality: only an overflowing bliss brings grace, and grace is noble.
The miserable person is bound to be mean. He cannot afford to be noble. It is impossible for him. He cannot give that which he has not got himself in the first place.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
22 July 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Veet Cyrena. Veet means beyond, cyrena means one who can take control. My teaching is that one has to go beyond all control, one has to learn to be free, one has to exist as freedom, not as control.
Control is not beautiful; it is ugly, it is repressive. You have to force things on yourself.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
23 July 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem Patrizia. Prem means love; patrizia means of noble birth.
Love comes from God; it is not only noble, it is divine too. Love is not something human, it is not something of the earth; it comes from the beyond. Hence the uplifting force of it: the moment it starts touching your heart it gives you wings.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
24 July 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem Joke. Prem means love; joke means God’s gift.
Love cannot be manufactured; there is no way to create it; either it is or it is not. Man is utterly impotent as far as love is concerned; it is beyond human creativity. We can only receive it from the above. There is no way to invent it, no way to make it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 24
25 July 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand Ursula. Anand means the state of ultimate bliss, a state from which one cannot fall – it is impossible. Once gained it is not ever lost, once gained it is forever. It is not a momentary phenomenon, it is not a changing phenomenon; it is the only constant factor in existence. Everything else changes, but not bliss.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 25
26 July 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand Dorian. Anand means bliss; dorian means bountiful, overflowing, abundant. The full name will mean bliss overflowing, bliss in a flood.
Bliss always comes in a flood. Bliss is not miserly. God is not miserly; only man with his cunning mind is a miser. God gives, and goes on giving for no motive at all; he does not desire anything in return.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 26
27 July 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand, Ria Anand means bliss. Bliss does not mean only happiness or joy; it is something more than that Happiness is a state of excitement; that excitement is missing in bliss. The ecstasy is there, but the excitement is not there. Happiness has something feverish in it; that fever is completely absent in bliss.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 27
28 July 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva Genevieve. Deva means divine; genevieve means a white wave.
The wave can exist in two waysOne: thinking of itself as separate from the ocean; the other: just
as an organic part of the whole. The first is the way of the ego and the second is the way of the sannyasin.
The sannyasin has to imbibe the spirit of being one with the whole, just a wave of the ocean.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part28/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 28
29 July 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand Brigitta. Anand means bliss; brigitta means bridge.
Bliss is the bridge to God. To be blissful is to be prayerful. To be blissful is to be religious, although just the contrary is the prevalent idea: religious people look very sad, they go on carrying long faces, they are haughty, egoistic. You can look in their eyes and you can see the holier-than-thou look.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>29</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part29/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 29
30 July 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem Marjorie. Prem means love; marjorie means a child of light. The full name will mean a child of love and light
Light is the physical expression of the energy love; love is unmanifest light. The physicists say the world consists only of light and the mystics say the world consists only of love... and both are not denying each other; they are simply using different expressions, different languages.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
3 July 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand Inger. Anand means bliss; inger, in Norse mythology, is the god of peace. Your full name will mean god of bliss and peace, or goddess of bliss and peace.
Bliss and peace have to happen together, only then does one realize the totality of life’s significance. Bliss can happen separately from peace; that’s what we know as pleasure, happiness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
4 July 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand Paul. Anand means bliss; paul means small. The way to be great is to be small; the way to be superior is to be a nobody. The superior man is not aware that he is. He is humble, not even conscious of his humbleness. Then bliss is natural.
Be a nobody, and you will be fulfilled.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
5 July 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Veet Roberta. Veet means going beyond; roberta means bright fame. The full name will mean going beyond all fame.
The ego longs to be famous, to be well-known. The ego is afraid of being nobody, is scared of being anonymous, because if you are not known you don’t know who you are; if you are not known by others you don’t know who you are.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
6 July 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem Kane. Prem means love, kane means beautiful. Beauty is not an objective quality; it does not belong to things. It is the loving eye that imparts it, that creates it. Beauty is a creation of love.
Ordinarily people think they have fallen in love because the other person is so beautiful. The reality is just the opposite: the other person looks so beautiful because they have fallen in love; love is fundamental.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
7 July 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Lalirra means waterhole in Australian Aboriginal.] Deva Lalirra – a divine source of water.
In all the primitive tribes water symbolizes life. Life is based on water: the human body is eighty-five percent water. And life depends – the life of animals and the trees and man and birds – all life depends on water.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
8 July 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem Maryan. Prem means love; maryan is made of two words, mary and hannah. Mary means rebellion, hannah means prayer. Your full name will mean love, rebellion, prayer. That’s exactly my definition of the sannyasin: he has to be love, he has to be a rebel, and he has to be prayerful.
Love alone, without rebelliousness, is impotent.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_rainbow_bridge/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
9 July 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva Miep. Deva means divine; miep means revolution, rebellion.
Religion is divine rebellion. It is the greatest revolution there is – the greatest because it does not rebel against the formal, it rebels against the essential. It does not change the form, it changes the very content. It is not concerned with the outward, it changes the core, the very being.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
