<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Shadow of the Bamboo on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Shadow of the Bamboo on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
1 April 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, elli is Hebrew; it means goddess – goddess of love. In fact God and love are synonymous. To be in love is to be in God. To know love is to know God. There is no other proof for God except love, and there is no other worship either. All other temples and churches are false, pseudo, except for the temple of love.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
10 April 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand Joseph. Anand means bliss, joseph is a blessing; it means may God increase. Your full name will mean may God increase your bliss. It is always a possibility, a hope, a dream. The dream can be fulfilled, the hope can become reality, the possible can be actual; but between the two there is a great gap.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
11 April 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Sybrand: It means burning iron or flaming sword. It’s actually the sword of the guards who protect paradise.]
Prem Sybrand. Prem means love – the fire of love, a burning love, a flame of love, or love aflame.
Man is alive only when love is aflame, when the heart is hot, otherwise man lives in a kind of ice- coldness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
12 April 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand Christopher. Anand means bliss, christopher means Christ-bearer. Each human being is a christopher, because each human being is a bearer of Christ-consciousness. Everybody is carrying the Christ within his soul; it has only to be uncovered. It is a hidden treasure: a little digging in the interiority of one’s being is needed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
13 April 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Veet Gunther. Veet means going beyond, surpassing, transcending, and gunther means war. Man has been in war continuously. The war has been of two kinds: on the outside with others and on the inside with oneself. The people who have been fighting with others are known as soldiers, and the people who have been fighting with themselves are known as monks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
14 April 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem Lennart. Prem means love, lennart means brave as the lion. Love needs the heart of a lion – the courage. The greatest courage in life is to dissolve yourself in love; there is no other bravery greater than that.
Everybody is a coward as far as the death of the ego is concerned because the death of the ego seems to be, appears to be, our death.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
15 April 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva Allene. Deva means divine, allene means harmony – divine harmony. The only secret worth learning in life is the secret of being in harmony with oneself, with others, and with the existence itself. Ordinarily people are constantly in conflict; they are in conflict with existence, with others, and with themselves. This triple conflict is their whole life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
16 April 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand Bram. Anand means bliss, bram is a form of abraham. Abraham was the first prophet, the father of religion, hence abraham became synonymous with the father.
Your full name will mean: become a father of bliss. Father bliss, give birth to bliss. It is a potential. God gives us the potential; that is his gift.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
17 April 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva Curtis. Deva means divine, curtis literally means court-bred, brought up in a king’s court; but that is only a literal meaning. Essentially it means graceful, gracious. Your full name will mean divine gracefulness.
Man can live in a violent way. That’s how many people live: aggressive – aggressive with others, aggressive with themselves.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
18 April 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand Tallis. Anand means bliss, tallis is the name of a poet. Your full name will mean a poet of bliss. And that you have to become.
Be as happy as possible. This is the right age – one can learn how to be happy or one can learn how to be unhappy, and then those patterns persist for the whole of life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
19 April 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand Karin. Anand means bliss, karin means pure – pure bliss. Bliss can exist in many forms. When it is physical we call it pleasure; when it is psychological we call it happiness; when it is spiritual we call it joy. But when it transcends all these three, then it attains to perfect purity; then it is pure bliss.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
2 April 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem Nozomi. Prem means love, nozomi means hope. Love is the only hope because only love can become a bridge between man and God, because only love can be the boat between this shore and that. Except for love there is no hope. A man without love lives in hopelessness. With love enters the ray of hope.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
20 April 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand Kees. Anand means bliss, kees means tree – a tree of bliss. Man is also a tree; man also has roots. They are invisible but man is not without roots. Man is constantly being nourished by existence. Each of the senses is a root into the universe. From the eyes we are nourished, from the ears we are nourished; from each pore of the body we are nourished.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
21 April 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva Debbie. Deva means divine, debbie means bee – a divine bee.
The bee is always searching for the lotus, hence it is a symbol of the seeker of truth. The lotus is the ultimate symbol of one’s flowering, hence in the East the ultimate state of samadhi is called the one-thousand-petaled lotus. Once the bee has entered into the lotus it never comes back.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
22 April 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva Julia. Deva means divine, julia means youthful. God is always young. The idea of an old God is just rubbish, because existence is always young. To be in God means to remain fresh and young, and the way towards God is being more and more youthful. The body will become old – that’s the nature of matter; matter is always old because matter is dead.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
23 April 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand Chris. Anand means bliss, blissful, chris means a follower of Christ. Christ is not a personal name; it has nothing to do with Jesus as such. Jesus is a Christ but not the Christ. Buddha is also a Christ, so is Zarathustra. There have been many, there will be many. Nobody is the Christ, and everybody can become a Christ.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 24
24 April 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Hock Hoe. Hock means prosperity, hoe means peace. Peace should be the center of life, then prosperity becomes the circumference automatically. If one is really peaceful, one prospers, one succeeds. Then whatsoever one does is bound to bring fulfillment. Then the man of peace has such an alchemical touch that whatsoever is touched by him turns into gold.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 25
25 April 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem Andre. Prem means love, andre means courage. Courage without love is dangerous, because courage without love is bound to turn towards destruction. Courage with love is creative, is a blessing. So love should be the very foundation of one’s courageousness. Courage only creates a warrior. With love, courage creates a sannyasin, a seeker of God, a lover of God.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 26
26 April 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand Annette. Anand means bliss, annette means mercy, compassion. It comes from the Hebrew, hannah; from hannah it became anna and from anna, annette.
Compassion comes as a shadow of bliss. It is a by-product; one cannot cultivate it. There is no way to go to it directly; it comes via blissfulness. If one is blissful, one is compassionate.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 27
27 April 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem Sylvia. Prem means love, sylvia means goddess of the forest. Your full name will mean love goddess of the forest. Love has something to do with nature. Love can never be artificial, it can never be synthetic. If it is artificial it is not love; it is just politeness, a formality, an empty gesture with no meaning, with no significance.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part28/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 28
28 April 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
John Satyam. John means a gift of God and satyam means the ultimate truth. To know the truth is to attain the ultimate fulfillment. That is the greatest possible gift. God makes it available to everybody but very few people receive it. God is not at fault. People are very miserly in opening up, in opening their heart lotuses.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
3 April 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem Akiko. Prem means love, akiko is the name of a famous poem. Your full name will mean: love, the poem. Life can either be prose or poetry: these are the two possibilities. If someone lives through the mind, life becomes prose, and if someone lives through the heart, life becomes poetry. When life is poetry, life is religious.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>30</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part30/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 30
30 April 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand Ineke. Anand means bliss, ineke means meek. Blessed are the meek, for theirs is the kingdom of God. To be humble, to be meek, is to be ready to receive God. God cannot be attacked and conquered. One cannot be aggressive about God: one can only be feminine. And that’s what meekness basically is – the fundamental quality of the feminine mind: to be ready to yield, just like the grass.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
4 April 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva Helen. Deva means divine, helen means light – divine light. Light represents the manifest part of God; darkness represents the unmanifest part. Both are divine, but darkness is the seed and light is the flower; darkness is the womb, light is the child.
Meditate on light, and the more you meditate on light, the more you will be surprised that something inside starts opening, as if a bud is opening and becoming a flower.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
5 April 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says he would like to spread Osho’s message in Japan. He may not have an opportunity to come here again.]
Don’t be worried, I will follow you! Just continue to meditate, help my people, help the center there; and many things are going to happen.
It will not be long before you are back.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
6 April 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, nirup means formless. Bliss is not an object, so it can’t have a form. Bliss is an experience, hence it is invisible, intangible. You cannot hold it in your hand; you cannot give it to anybody. Nobody can take it away from you. It cannot be stolen, it cannot be robbed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
7 April 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand Ralph. Anand means bliss, ralph means wolf. The wolf is an ancient symbol for courage; and bliss needs courage. Misery needs no courage, any coward can be miserable. In fact to be miserable simply means that you are a coward and nothing else. Misery is nothing but an aspect of inner cowardliness, and bliss is the flavor that comes with courage.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
8 April 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Uli Narayano. Uli means ruler of all, narayano is a name of God – God, the ruler of all. Only God can be the ruler of all; man tries but fails, is bound to fail. The very desire to become ruler of all is ugly. The desire to dominate is irreligious. The desire to be higher than others is the root cause of human misery.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_shadow_of_the_bamboo/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
9 April 1979 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand Manuel. Anand means bliss, manuel comes from the Hebrew, emmanuel. Emmanuel means “God, be with us.” It is the essence of prayer; and blissfulness arises only when this prayer is fulfilled. When God is with us then there is bliss. To be without God is to be in misery; to be with him is to be in a rejoicing.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
