<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Way of Tao, Volume 2 on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Way of Tao, Volume 2 on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 The dangers of success, the agony of the ego, and the gate of heaven</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_2/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_2/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
The dangers of success, the agony of the ego, and the gate of
heaven
29 January 1972 pm in Immortal Study Circle
IT IS BETTER TO LEAVE A VESSEL UNFILLED, THAN TO ATTEMPT TO CARRY IT WHEN IT IS FULL.
IF YOU KEEP FEELING A POINT THAT HAS BEEN SHARPENED, THE POINT CANNOT LONG PRESERVE ITS SHARPNESS.
WHEN GOLD AND JADE FILL THE HALL, THEIR POSSESSOR CANNOT KEEP THEM SAFE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 The invisible, inaudible and intangible Tao</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_2/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_2/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
The invisible, inaudible and intangible Tao
15 April 1972 pm in Immortal Study Circle
LOOKED AT, BUT CANNOT BE SEEN – THAT IS CALLED THE INVISIBLE (YI). LISTENED TO, BUT CANNOT BE HEARD – THAT IS CALLED THE INAUDIBLE (HSI). GRASPED AT, BUT CANNOT BE TOUCHED – THAT IS CALLED THE INTANGIBLE (WEI). THESE THREE ELUDE ALL OUR INQUIRIES AND HENCE BLEND AND BECOME ONE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 The image of the eternal and the formless, the ancient and the void</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_2/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_2/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
The image of the eternal and the formless, the ancient and the void
16 April 1972 pm in Immortal Study Circle NEITHER BY ITS RISING IS THERE LIGHT, NOR BY ITS SINKING IS THERE DARKNESS. UNCEASING, CONTINUOUS,
IT CANNOT BE DEFINED.
IT REVERTS AGAIN TO THE REALM OF NOTHINGNESS. THAT IS WHY IT IS CALLED THE FORM OF THE FORMLESS; THE IMAGE OF NOTHINGNESS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 The signs of a saint: he is alert and irresolute, egoless and playful</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_2/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_2/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
The signs of a saint: he is alert and irresolute, egoless and playful
17 April 1972 pm in Immortal Study Circle
THE SKILFUL MASTERS (OF THE TAO) IN OLD TIMES, WITH A SUBTLE AND EXQUISITE PENETRATION, COMPREHENDED ITS MYSTERIES, WHICH WERE SO DEEP THAT THEY ELUDED MAN’S KNOWLEDGE. AS THEY WERE THUS BEYOND MAN’S KNOWLEDGE, I WILL MAKE AN EFFORT TO DESCRIBE OF WHAT THEY APPEARED TO BE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 From repose to equality. to attain liberation through the golden mean</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_2/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_2/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
From repose to equality. to attain liberation through the golden mean
18 April 1972 pm in Immortal Study Circle
WHO CAN REPOSE IN A MUDDY WORLD? BY LYING STILL IT BECOMES CLEAR.
WHO CAN MAINTAIN HIS CALM FOR LONG? BY ACTIVITY, REST COMES BACK TO LIFE. HE WHO EMBRACES THIS TAO
GUARDS AGAINST BEING OVERFULL.
BECAUSE HE GUARDS AGAINST BEING OVERFULL, HE IS BEYOND WEARING OUT AND RENEWAL.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 The impartial awaiting, the death of pride and the one in the many</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_2/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_2/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
The impartial awaiting, the death of pride and the one in the many
19 April 1972 pm in Immortal Study Circle
Question 1
FOR THE LAST TWELVE YEARS I HAVE BEEN WAITING FOR THE WATERS OF MY MIND TO CLEAR, BUT THE CARTS OF SITUATIONS AND SURROUNDINGS KEEP PASSING THROUGH THEM CONSTANTLY. THIS WILL GO ON THROUGHOUT LIFE. SHOULD I STILL KEEP WAITING?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 Inaction, destiny and going back to the eternal law</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_2/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_2/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
Inaction, destiny and going back to the eternal law
15 June 1972 pm in Immortal Study Circle
ATTAIN THE UTMOST IN PASSIVITY.
HOLD FIRM TO THE BASIS OF QUIETUDE.
MYRIAD THINGS TAKE SHAPE AND RISE TO ACTIVITY, BUT I WATCH THEM FALL BACK TO THEIR REPOSE LIKE VEGETATION THAT LUXURIOUSLY GROWS BUT RETURNS TO THE ROOT (SOIL) FROM WHICH IT SPRINGS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 The door of Tao \-- forbearance and non-prejudice</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_2/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_2/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
The door of Tao – forbearance and non-prejudice
16 June 1972 pm in Immortal Study Circle
HE WHO KNOWS THE ETERNAL LAW IS TOLERANT. BEING TOLERANT, HE IS IMPARTIAL.
BEING IMPARTIAL, HE IS KINGLY.
BEING KINGLY, HE IS IN ACCORD WITH NATURE.
BEING IN ACCORD WITH NATURE, HE IS IN ACCORD WITH TAO.
BEING IN ACCORD WITH TAO, HE IS ETERNAL AND HIS WHOLE LIFE IS PRESERVED FROM HARM.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 Who is the best ruler? \-- he who is like god</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_2/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_2/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
Who is the best ruler? – he who is like god
17 June 1972 pm in Immortal Study Circle
OF THE BEST RULERS
THE PEOPLE DO NOT KNOW THAT THEY EXIST. THE NEXT BEST THEY LOVE AND PRAISE.
THE NEXT THEY FEAR.
AND THE NEXT THEY REVILE.
WHEN THEY DO NOT COMMAND THE PEOPLE’S FAITH, SOME WILL LOSE FAITH IN THEM,</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 The birth of doctrines from the decline of Tao</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_2/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_2/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
The birth of doctrines from the decline of Tao
18 June 1972 pm in Immortal Study Circle
ON THE DECLINE OF THE GREAT TAO,
THE DOCTRINES OF HUMANITY AND JUSTICE AROSE. WHEN KNOWLEDGE AND CLEVERNESS APPEARED, GREAT HYPOCRISY FOLLOWED IN ITS WAKE.
WHEN THE SIX RELATIONSHIPS NO LONGER LIVED AT PEACE, THERE WAS (PRAISE OF) ‘KIND PARENTS’ AND ‘FILIAL SONS’. WHEN A COUNTRY FELL INTO CHAOS AND MISRULE,</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19 To live in artless spontaneity and not in doctrines and decorum</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_2/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_2/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
To live in artless spontaneity and not in doctrines and decorum
19 June 1972 pm in Immortal Study Circle
BANISH WISDOM, DISCARD KNOWLEDGE,
AND THE PEOPLE SHALL PROFIT A HUNDRED FOLD; BANISH ‘HUMANITY’, DISCARD ‘JUSTICE’,
AND THE PEOPLE SHALL RECOVER LOVE OF THEIR KIN; BANISH CUNNING, DISCARD ‘UTILITY’,
AND THE THIEVES AND BRIGANDS SHALL DISAPPEAR.
The greatest difficulty in understanding Lao Tzu is our level of thinking.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 The oneness of the body and the soul, the eternal state of Tao, and the sadhana of the vital breath</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_2/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_2/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
The oneness of the body and the soul, the eternal state of Tao, and
the sadhana of the vital breath
30 January 1972 pm in Immortal Study Circle
WHEN THE INTELLIGENT SOUL AND THE ANIMAL SOUL ARE HELD TOGETHER IN ONE EMBRACE, THEY CAN BE KEPT FROM SEPARATING.
WHEN ONE GIVES UNDIVIDED ATTENTION TO THE (VITAL) BREATH AND BRINGS IT TO THE UTMOST DEGREE OF FLEXIBILITY, HE CAN BECOME LIKE A (TENDER) BABE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 The renunciation of spiritual desires the revelation of the simple self</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_2/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_2/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
The renunciation of spiritual desires the revelation of the simple self
20 June 1972 pm in Immortal Study Circle
AS THESE TOUCH THE EXTERNALS AND ARE INADEQUATE, THE PEOPLE HAVE NEED OF WHAT THEY CAN DEPEND UPON.
REVEAL THY SIMPLE SELF, EMBRACE THY ORIGINAL NATURE, CHECK THY SELFISHNESS, CURTAIL THY DESIRES.
To discard wisdom and knowledge, humanity and justice, cunning and utility, is the negation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 Religion is to be your own self</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_2/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_2/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 21
Religion is to be your own self
21 June 1972 pm in Immortal Study Circle
Question 1
ONE FRIEND HAS ASKED: IS IT NOT NECESSARY TO RUN IN ORDER TO STOP?
It is necessary. But you are running already. You have run enough. There is a long history of previous births behind you where you have been running. You are the result of this. Now it is no longer necessary to run; now it is necessary to stop.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 An aimless life, an inviting attitude and a pliable understanding</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_2/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_2/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
An aimless life, an inviting attitude and a pliable understanding
31 January 1972 pm in Immortal Study Circle
IN LOVING THE PEOPLE AND RULING THE STATE, CANNOT HE PROCEED WITHOUT ANY (PURPOSE) OF ACTION?
IN OPENING AND SHUTTING HIS GATES OF HEAVEN, CANNOT HE DO SO LIKE A FEMALE BIRD?
WHILE HIS INTELLIGENCE REACHES IN EVERY DIRECTION, CANNOT HE (APPEAR TO) BE WITHOUT KNOWLEDGE?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Tao\&#39;s unpresent presence</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_2/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_2/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
Tao’s unpresent presence
1 February 1972 pm in Immortal Study Circle
THE TAO PRODUCES ALL THINGS AND NOURISHES THEM;
IT PRODUCES THEM AND DOES NOT CLAIM THEM AS ITS OWN. IT DOES ALL, AND YET DOES NOT BOAST OF IT.
IT PRESIDES OVER ALL, AND YET DOES NOT CONTROL THEM. THIS IS WHAT IS CALLED THE MYSTERIOUS QUALITY OF THE TAO.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Non-existence and emptiness is the support of everything</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_2/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_2/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
Non-existence and emptiness is the support of everything
2 February 1972 pm in Immortal Study Circle
THE THIRTY SPOKES UNITE THE ONE NAME; BUT IT IS ON THE AXLE THAT THE USE OF THE WHEEL DEPENDS.
CLAY IS FASHIONED INTO VESSELS; BUT IT IS ON THEIR EMPTY HOLLOWNESS THAT THEIR USE DEPENDS.
THE DOORS AND WINDOWS ARE CUT OUT FROM THE WALLS TO FORM AN APARTMENT; BUT IT IS ON THE EMPTY SPACE WITHIN, THAT ITS USE DEPENDS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Not the hunger of the senses be concerned with the hunger of the spirit</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_2/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_2/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
Not the hunger of the senses be concerned with the hunger of the
spirit
3 February 1972 pm in Immortal Study Circle
COLOUR’S FIVE HUES, FROM THE EYES THEIR SIGHT WILL TAKE MUSIC’S FIVE NOTES, THE EARS AS DEAF CAN MAKE.
THE FIVE FLAVOURS DEPRIVE THE MOUTH OF TASTE. THE CHARIOT COURSE, AND THE WILD HUNTING WASTE
MAKE MAD THE MIND; AND OBJECTS RARE AND STRANGE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 The sadhana of Tao \-- in the context of yoga</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_2/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_2/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
The sadhana of Tao – in the context of yoga
4 February 1972 pm in Immortal Study Circle
Question 1
ONE FRIEND HAS ASKED: “YOGA IS A PATH OF ELEVATION, OF RAISING THE LIFE-ENERGY UPWARDS, WHEREAS LAO TZU’S METHOD IS EXACTLY THE OPPOSITE: OF BRINGING DOWN THE ENERGY TO THE NAVEL CENTRE. SO THE QUESTION INVARIABLY RISES: WHICH IS THE RIGHT METHOD?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 Two sides of the same coin: honour and dishonour, greed and fear</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_2/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_2/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
Two sides of the same coin: honour and dishonour, greed and fear
13 April 1972 pm in Immortal Study Circle
“FAVOUR AND DISGRACE CAUSE ONE DISMAY,
WHAT WE VALUE AND WHAT WE FEAR ARE AS IF WITHIN THE SELF.” WHAT IS MEANT BY SPEAKING THUS OF FAVOUR AND DISGRACE?
DISGRACE IS BEING IN A LOW POSITION (AFTER THE ENJOYMENT OF FAVOUR).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 Only he is fit to be the master whose ego is naught</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_2/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_way_of_tao_volume_2/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
Only he is fit to be the master whose ego is naught
14 April 1972 pm in Immortal Study Circle
WHAT DOES IT MEAN TO SAY THAT
WHAT WE VALUE AND WHAT WE FEAR ARE WITHIN THE SELF? WE HAVE FEAR BECAUSE WE HAVE A SELF.
WHEN WE DO NOT REGARD THAT SELF AS THE SELF, WHAT HAVE WE TO FEAR?</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
