<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>In Search of the Miraculous Vol 2 on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/in_search_of_the_miraculous_vol_2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in In Search of the Miraculous Vol 2 on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/in_search_of_the_miraculous_vol_2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 Outer help in the growth of kundalini energy</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/in_search_of_the_miraculous_vol_2/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/in_search_of_the_miraculous_vol_2/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
Outer help in the growth of kundalini energy
4 July 1970 pm in
Question 1
YOU SAID AT THE NARGOL MEDITATION CAMP THAT THE MEANING OF SHAKTIPAT – TRANSMISSION OF THE DIVINE ENERGY – IS THAT THE ENERGY OF THE DIVINE DESCENDS INTO THE MEDITATOR. LATER ON YOU SAID THAT THERE IS A DIFFERENCE BETWEEN SHAKTIPAT AND GRACE. THESE TWO STATEMENTS SEEM CONTRADICTORY.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Ripening of the meditator on the path</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/in_search_of_the_miraculous_vol_2/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/in_search_of_the_miraculous_vol_2/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
Ripening of the meditator on the path
5 July 1970 pm in
Question 1
IN ONE OF YOUR PREVIOUS DISCOURSES YOU SAID THAT A SUDDEN AND DIRECT DESCENT OF GRACE CAN BECOME A DISASTER SOMETIMES. THE PERSON MIGHT BE HARMED OR BECOME MAD OR HE MAY EVEN DIE. A QUESTION NATURALLY ARISES: IS GRACE NOT ALWAYS BENEFICIAL? DOES GRACE NOT KEEP ITS OWN EQUILIBRIUM?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 The path of kundalini: authenticity and freedom</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/in_search_of_the_miraculous_vol_2/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/in_search_of_the_miraculous_vol_2/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
The path of kundalini: authenticity and freedom
6 July 1970 pm in
Question 1
IN YESTERDAY’S TALK, YOU SAID THAT FALSE EXPERIENCES OF KUNDALINI CAN BE PROJECTED WHICH YOU CONSIDER TO BE NOT SPIRITUAL BUT PSYCHIC. IN YOUR INITIAL TALK, HOWEVER, YOU HAD SAID THAT KUNDALINI IS ONLY PSYCHIC. THIS MEANS, ACCORDING TO YOU, THAT THERE ARE TWO STATES OF THE KUNDALINI – PSYCHIC AND SPIRITUAL.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 The mysteries of the seven bodies</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/in_search_of_the_miraculous_vol_2/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/in_search_of_the_miraculous_vol_2/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
The mysteries of the seven bodies
7 July 1970 pm in
Question 1
IN YESTERDAY’S TALK YOU SAID THAT THE SEEKER SHOULD FIRST WORRY ABOUT HIS OWN RECEPTIVITY AND SHOULD NOT GO BEGGING FROM DOOR TO DOOR. BUT THE VERY MEANING OF A SADHAK IS THAT THERE ARE OBSTACLES ON HIS PATH OF SPIRITUAL GROWTH. HE DOES NOT KNOW HOW TO BE RECEPTIVE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 The occult mysteries of religion</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/in_search_of_the_miraculous_vol_2/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/in_search_of_the_miraculous_vol_2/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
The occult mysteries of religion
8 July 1970 pm in
Question 1
IN YESTERDAY’S TALK YOU SAID THAT IT IS POSSIBLE FOR SCIENCE TO ENTER THE FIFTH OR SPIRITUAL BODY. THEN YOU TALKED OF THE POSSIBILITIES OF SCIENCE IN THE FOURTH BODY. KINDLY TELL US ABOUT THE POSSIBILITIES OF SCIENCE IN THE FIFTH BODY.
What we call the physical body and what we call the soul are not two things that are different and apart.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Shaktipat: the mysteries of body-electricity</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/in_search_of_the_miraculous_vol_2/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/in_search_of_the_miraculous_vol_2/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
Shaktipat: the mysteries of body-electricity
9 July 1970 pm in
Question 1
IN THE CONTEXT OF THE SEVENTH BODY, YOU TALKED ABOUT AUM YESTERDAY. THERE IS STILL A SMALL QUESTION ON THE SAME SUBJECT. WHICH CHAKRAS DO A, U AND M INFLUENCE, AND HOW IS THIS HELPFUL TO THE MEDITATOR?
Yesterday I told you a few things about aum. There are a few more things worth knowing in the same context.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Kundalini: The discipline of transcendence</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/in_search_of_the_miraculous_vol_2/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/in_search_of_the_miraculous_vol_2/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
Kundalini: The discipline of transcendence
10 July 1970 pm in
Question 1
YESTERDAY YOU TALKED TO US ABOUT THE EFFECT OF SHAKTIPAT AND KUNDALINI AWAKENING ON PERSONS WHOSE FIRST THREE BODIES ARE NOT PREPARED FOR IT. PLEASE EXPLAIN FURTHER WHAT KIND OF EFFECT WILL TAKE PLACE IF THE SECOND AND THIRD BODIES ARE NOT PREPARED. ALSO, HOW SHOULD A MEDITATOR PREPARE HIS PHYSICAL, ETHERIC AND ASTRAL BODIES FOR THE EVENT?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 The esoteric dimensions of tantra</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/in_search_of_the_miraculous_vol_2/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/in_search_of_the_miraculous_vol_2/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
The esoteric dimensions of tantra
11 July 1970 pm in
Question 1
YOU HAVE SAID THAT THE DIFFERENCE OF MALE AND FEMALE ENDS WITH THE FIFTH BODY. HOW DO THE POSITIVE AND NEGATIVE POLES OF ELECTRICITY OF THE FIRST FOUR BODIES BECOME ADJUSTED TO BRING ABOUT THIS HAPPENING? PLEASE EXPLAIN THIS IN DETAIL.
In the context of the male and female bodies you have been told that the first body of the female is a female body while the second is male, and the exact opposite is the case with the male.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 Occult depths of kundalini and spirituality</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/in_search_of_the_miraculous_vol_2/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/in_search_of_the_miraculous_vol_2/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 9
Occult depths of kundalini and spirituality
12 July 1970 pm in
Question 1
IN THE NARGOL MEDITATION CAMP YOU SAID THAT THE PRACTICES OF YOGA – ASANAS, PRANAYAMAS, MUDRAS AND BANDHAS – WERE DISCOVERED IN THE STATE OF MEDITATION. IN DIFFERENT STATES OF MEDITATION, DIFFERENT POSTURES ARE FORMED BY THE BODY FROM WHICH THE DEPTH OF MEDITATION OF THE MEDITATOR COULD BE TOLD. CONVERSELY, CAN THE SAME INNER STATE BE BROUGHT ABOUT BY FORMING THE NECESSARY POSTURES?</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
