<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Open Secret on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Open Secret on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chapter title: None</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter title: None‌ 1 November 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium Archive code: 7711015 ShortTitle: OPENSE01 Audio:
No Video:
No
Anand means bliss, and avid means one who knows -- one who knows blissfully, one who knows through bliss, a knowing blissfulness. And God can only be known that way; God cannot be known through suffering. Everybody tends to remember God when they suffer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter title: None</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter title: None‌ 10 November 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium Archive code: 7711105 ShortTitle: OPENSE10 Audio:
No Video:
No
[A sannyasin woman has her arm in a sling after being knocked down in the street by some hostile Indians. She says she is tired of violence around her and how to get rid of it. She doesn&#39;t want to die right now. Should she go back to the West.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter title: None</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter title: None‌ 11 November 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium Archive code: 7711115 ShortTitle: OPENSE11 Audio:
No Video:
No
Prem means love, abhinaya means fire -- love fire.
Life is fire, love is fire, light is fire. Fire is the very substratum of all, hence fire worship is the ancient-most religion in the world. The first god was conceived of as fire and modern science also conceives of fire -- or electricity -- as being the basic element.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter title: None</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter title: None‌ 12 November 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium Archive code: 7711125 ShortTitle: OPENSE12 Audio:
No Video:
No
[Veet means beyond, manu means mind, Osho is saying. And all that is true, good, beautiful, is beyond the mind. He valiantly continues ]
The mind is only utilitarian. It is useful in the world but its reach is very limited. And all that can become a contentment is beyond its reach.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter title: None</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter title: None‌ 13 November 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium Archive code: 7711135 ShortTitle: OPENSE13 Audio:
No Video:
No
Deva means divine, amarga means pathlessness -- divine pathlessness. There is no path to God; all paths are false. In the very nature of things there can be no path to God because God is all and everywhere. A path leads somewhere. God is not somewhere: God is everywhere.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter title: None</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter title: None‌ 14 November 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium Archive code: 7711145 ShortTitle: OPENSE14 Audio:
No Video:
No
Deva means God, agata means arrival -- arrival of God. And God is just knocking on your door. God is always close by. The idea that God is far away in the heavens is just stupidity. He is in your very breath... he is your breath!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter title: None</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter title: None‌ 15 November 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium Archive code: 7711155 ShortTitle: OPENSE15 1/08/07
Copyright Osho International Foundation 1994
Osho&#39;s books on CD-ROM, published and unpublished Query:- Audio:
No Video:
No
[Veet Vidhan. It means beyond discipline, Osho explains, and truth is beyond discipline because it cannot be manufactured by man. It is not a doing; man cannot do it. Man can only be it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter title: None</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter title: None‌ 16 November 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium Archive code: 7711165 ShortTitle: OPENSE16 Audio:
No Video:
No
Deva means divine, parivartan means change -- a divine change. I am giving you this name for a specific purpose: from this moment start accepting change. And the more you accept change, the less will be your misery, the less will be the pain.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter title: None</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter title: None‌ 17 November 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium Archive code: 7711175 ShortTitle: OPENSE17 Audio:
No Video:
No
[A sannyasin had been practicing Vipassana every day in the West and began to have sensations of dissolving in the top of his head. He became scared of going crazy. Osho checks his energy.]
It is not anything like craziness but it will appear like craziness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter title: None</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter title: None‌ 18 November 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium Archive code: 7711185 ShortTitle: OPENSE18 Audio:
No Video:
No
[A new sannyasin says that he felt he needed to take a new step which he could not do in his home environment, so he came to Osho in the hope he can do it here.]
Yes, it is going to happen. You cannot do it; it can only happen.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter title: None</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter title: None‌ 19 November 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium Archive code: 7711195 ShortTitle: OPENSE19 Audio:
No Video:
No
[A sannyasin, who is leaving, says he feels afraid to leave and more afraid to stay... he feels far away.
Osho checks his energy.]
Just come close to me. Let me see how far away you are!
It is strange but it is beautiful.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter title: None</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter title: None‌ 2 November 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium Archive code: 7711025 ShortTitle: OPENSE02 Audio:
No Video:
No
Prem Sushila. It means love virtue... and love is the only virtue. Other virtues are needed only when love is missing. They are substitutes and very poor substitutes at that. Love is the only commandment. If love is missing then the ten commandments are needed, and even those ten cannot fulfill the need because all will be formal, imposed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter title: None</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter title: None‌ 20 November 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium Archive code: 7711205 ShortTitle: OPENSE20 Audio:
No Video:
No
Prem means love, sukavi means a poet - a poet of love. And everybody is born with the intrinsic quality of being a poet of love. Not everybody is a poet but everybody is destined to become a love poet. By a love poet I don&#39;t mean that you have to compose poetry or you have to write poetry.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter title: None</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter title: None‌ 21 November 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium Archive code: 7711215 ShortTitle: OPENSE21 Audio:
No Video:
No 1/08/07
Copyright Osho International Foundation 1994
Osho&#39;s books on CD-ROM, published and unpublished Query:-
Deva means divine, darshan means vision -- divine vision, divine insight, or divine eyes, that capacity which can make it possible for you to see God. That capacity is darshan.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter title: None</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter title: None‌ 22 November 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium Archive code: 7711225 ShortTitle: OPENSE22 Audio:
No Video:
No
[A sannyasin, recently arrived, wishes to say something but has not words.]
Then just raise your hands and close your eyes. Feel the energy, and if it starts shaking you, makes you quake, go with it. If it starts swaying you, sway with it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter title: None</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter title: None‌ 23 November 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium Archive code: 7711235 ShortTitle: OPENSE23 Audio:
No Video:
No
[Osho explains the meaning of Prem (love) Chintan (meditation). Contemplate on love and you will become love. Don&#39;t think of love as a relationship but as a quality of your inner being. Love has to become like breathing. What breathing is to the body, love is to the soul.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter title: None</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter title: None‌ 25 November 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium Archive code: 7711255 ShortTitle: OPENSE24 1/08/07
Copyright Osho International Foundation 1994
Osho&#39;s books on CD-ROM, published and unpublished Query:- Audio:
No Video:
No
Gypsy means a vagabond. Do you know that Gypsies originally belonged to India? They are Indians but they reached Europe through Egypt, hence the name Gypsy, from &#39;Egypt&#39;. They were coming from Egypt so they started being called &#39;Gypsy&#39; but their original land is India.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter title: None</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter title: None‌ 26 November 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium Archive code: 7711265 ShortTitle: OPENSE25 Audio:
No Video:
No
Learn something from Francis. He is one of the most important saints in Christianity, in fact the next after Jesus. He brings something new to the world. Imbibe that spirit. He brings this spirit, that he is deeply in love with nature, to the world.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter title: None</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter title: None‌ 27 November 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium Archive code: 7711275 ShortTitle: OPENSE26 Audio:
No Video:
No
[Osho explains the meaning of deva vasant. Deva means divine, vasant means spring -- divine spring. If one knows how to live rightly, Osho continues, one constantly lives in the spring. In the inner world it is always spring, things are always blooming; it is never otherwise.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter title: None</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter title: None‌ 28 November 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium Archive code: 7711285 ShortTitle: OPENSE27 Audio:
No Video:
No
Anand means bliss, chandan means sandalwood. Sandalwood is very symbolic in the East because when one reaches one&#39;s innermost core a certain fragrance arises in one&#39;s own being which is very similar to sandalwood, not exactly the same but almost. So sandalwood became sacred.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter title: None</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part28/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter title: None‌ 29 November 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium Archive code: 7711295 ShortTitle: OPENSE28 Audio:
No Video:
No
[A new sannyasin asks for a mantra. He was initiated by Ananda Marga with the mantra &#39;baba&#39;. Osho checks his energy, telling him to chant this mantra.]
Continue it; that&#39;s no problem. It will suit you. And it has nothing to do with Ananda Marga, mm?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter title: None</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part29/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌Chapter title: None‌ 30 November 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium Archive code: 7711305 ShortTitle: OPENSE29 Audio:
No Video:
No
[A sannyasin says all his money has gone to his wife, from whom he has separated, so now he is unable to stay in Poona, and does not know what to do.… he feels very happy here and would like to stay... but doesn&#39;t really care.]</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter title: None</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter title: None‌ 3 November 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium Archive code: 7711035 ShortTitle: OPENSE03 Audio:
No Video:
No
[A sannyasin asks: I was taught as a child to pray and the prayer was of thanksgiving. Now I don&#39;t know who I&#39;m praying to any more. Am I praying to Osho? I&#39;ve heard you say that God is just a name for one&#39;s innermost core.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter title: None</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter title: None‌ 4 November 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium Archive code: 7711045 ShortTitle: OPENSE04 Audio:
No Video:
No
[A seeker who is taking sannyas says that he has spent nine years serving other indian gurus, which has brought him to Osho. He has been critically ill for the last two years with disorders arising from a congenital problem.]
Deva means divine, narendra means a king -- divine king.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter title: None</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter title: None‌ 5 November 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium Archive code: 7711055 ShortTitle: OPENSE05 Audio:
No Video:
No
[A sannyasin is leaving and says he has a restaurant called &#39;The Traveller&#39;. So make a little corner in it for me! says Osho.… So I will give you a new name for it. It will be helpful for you to talk about me.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter title: None</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter title: None‌ 6 November 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium Archive code: 7711065 ShortTitle: OPENSE06 Audio:
No Video:
No
Deva means divine, and vihan means morning. And let this be your divine morning. Forget the night that you have been in and forget all those nightmares. Once we are able to forget them they disappear. By remembering them again and again we go on watching; that is a kind of nourishment for them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter title: None</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter title: None‌ 7 November 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium Archive code: 7711075 ShortTitle: OPENSE07 Audio:
No Video:
No
Deva means divine, arjava means straightforwardness, simplicity, authenticity, sincerity... all those things. The fundamental thing is authenticity. One should not allow any kind of imposition... not by others, not by oneself either. One should not wear masks. One should live one&#39;s original face whatsoever the cost.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter title: None</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter title: None‌ 8 November 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium Archive code: 7711085 ShortTitle: OPENSE08 Audio:
No Video:
No
[A sannyasin has brought her two children from the West. The older son is negative and wishes to return to the West. The mother says she doesn&#39;t want to force him to stay.]
Mm mm. So, let him go, and whenever he wants to go.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter title: None</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_open_secret/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Chapter title: None‌ 9 November 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium Archive code: 7711095 ShortTitle: OPENSE09 Audio:
No Video:
No
[Osho gives someone sannyas.]
Start feeling that a sound is arising upwards from your throat -- a moaning, groaning or a humming sound; feel ripples of sound arising. If you start feeling like humming or moaning, go into it; don&#39;t be shy and don&#39;t hold it.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
