<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>In Search of the Miraculous Vol 1 on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/in_search_of_the_miraculous_vol_1/</link>
    <description>Recent content in In Search of the Miraculous Vol 1 on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/in_search_of_the_miraculous_vol_1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 Kundalini \-- The Sleeping Serpent</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/in_search_of_the_miraculous_vol_1/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/in_search_of_the_miraculous_vol_1/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
Kundalini – The Sleeping Serpent
2 May 1970 am in
I do not know why you have come here. Perhaps you too, do not know. Most of us live in such a way that we are not aware why we are living, where we are going and why. We do not ask of ourselves, “Why?” When our whole life is spent without asking these basic questions it is no wonder if you all have come without knowing the purpose of your coming.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Meditation not Prayer has Great Future</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/in_search_of_the_miraculous_vol_1/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/in_search_of_the_miraculous_vol_1/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
Meditation not Prayer has Great Future
1 July 1970 am in
Question 1
QUESTIONER: YOU SAID AT THE NARGOL MEDITATION CAMP HELD RECENTLY, THAT THE SADHANA OR DISCIPLINE OF KUNDALINI IS A WAY OF PREPARING THE BODY. WILL YOU PLEASE EXPLAIN IT?
Firstly, the body and the soul in their very depth are not separate; the difference between them is very superficial.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 The Alchemy of Chaotic Breathing</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/in_search_of_the_miraculous_vol_1/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/in_search_of_the_miraculous_vol_1/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
The Alchemy of Chaotic Breathing
2 July 1970 am in
Question 1
QUESTIONER: A GREAT MYSTIC OF RUSSIA, GEORGE GURDJIEFF HAS WRITTEN A
MEMOIR OF HIS SPIRIT UAL ADVENTURES KNOWN AS Meetings with Remarkable Men. IN THE BOOK HE SAYS THAT HE WAS MUCH IMPRESSED BY A DISCUSSION WITH A SUFI DERVISH ON YOGIC PRANAYAM AND ASANAS. THE DERVISH HAD WARNED HIM AGAINST ALL KINDS OF BREATHING EXERCISES, BECAUSE ANY CHANGE IN THE NATURAL BREATHING SYSTEM BRINGS ABOUT DISORDER IN LIFE WITH DISASTROUS RESULTS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Kundalini Will Transform You</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/in_search_of_the_miraculous_vol_1/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/in_search_of_the_miraculous_vol_1/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 12
Kundalini Will Transform You
2 July 1970 pm in
Question 1
QUESTIONER: YOU SAID YESTERDAY THAT OUR KUNDAS OR POOLS OF ENERGY ARE NOT SEPARATE AND DIFFERENT FROM EACH OTHER; THEY ARE REALLY ONE COSMIC KUNDA. BUT SO FAR AS A SEEKER IS CONCERNED HIS ENERGY WILL RISE FROM HIS OWN KUNDA AND NOT FROM OTHERS. SO IS THE KUNDA REALLY ONE? PLEASE EXPLAIN.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Matter and God are One</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/in_search_of_the_miraculous_vol_1/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/in_search_of_the_miraculous_vol_1/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
Matter and God are One
3 May 1970 am in
The universe is an expansion of energy, and life is the crystallization of it. What we see as matter, what we see as stone, is also energy. What is seen as life, what is experienced as thought, what is felt like consciousness is also a trans formation of energy. The whole cosmos – whether it is the waves of the sea or the pine trees of the forest or the grains of sand or the stars in the skies or that which is within us – all are manifestations of the same energy in infinite forms and ways.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Osho Leads Dynamic</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/in_search_of_the_miraculous_vol_1/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/in_search_of_the_miraculous_vol_1/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
Osho Leads Dynamic
3 May 1970 om in
Please sit or stand apart. Keep a little distance from one an other so that those of you who want to lie down may do so comfortably. No one will talk, there will be no chit chatting at all.
You will sit quietly and no one will sit close to another. There is plenty of space here, so don’t be miserly.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Meditation is Death and Resurrection</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/in_search_of_the_miraculous_vol_1/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/in_search_of_the_miraculous_vol_1/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
Meditation is Death and Resurrection
3 May 1970 pm in
Question 1
A FRIEND HAS ASKED IF THERE IS A DANGER IN AWAKENING THE KUNDALINI. IF SO, WHAT IS THE DANGER? AND WHY SHOULD THE KUNDALINI BE AWAKENED IF IT IS DANGEROUS TO DO SO?
There is a good deal of danger involved. Really, there is a danger of losing all that we take to be our life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Osho Leads Dynamic</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/in_search_of_the_miraculous_vol_1/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/in_search_of_the_miraculous_vol_1/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
Osho Leads Dynamic
3 May 1970 xm in
Let us now sit for meditation. There is going to be some change in the schedule for meditation from tomorrow.
From tomorrow, mornings will be devoted to meditation alone and evenings to discourses exclusively. But this day we will follow the day’s schedule.
Take your seats apart, keeping a distance from one another. But do not go far, because this morning I noticed that friends who had moved far were deprived of the benefits of the psychic atmosphere that is being created here.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 God\&#39;s Grace and Our Efforts</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/in_search_of_the_miraculous_vol_1/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/in_search_of_the_miraculous_vol_1/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
God’s Grace and Our Efforts
4 May 1970 pm in
Question 1
FRIEND ASKS: DOES ONE ATTAIN TO MEDITATION THROUGH GOD’S GRACE?
It will be useful to understand this thing, because it has led to lots of misunderstandings and mistakes. A good number of people have thought that if meditation is attained through God’s grace then there is no need to do anything, and they did not do a thing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Osho Leads Dynamic</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/in_search_of_the_miraculous_vol_1/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/in_search_of_the_miraculous_vol_1/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
Osho Leads Dynamic
5 May 1970 am in
Please go for today’s meditation filled with a tremendous amount of hope and will, and know that you are going to make it. Know that as the sun has risen and flooded the earth with light, so your own light will flood you inside. As flowers have bloomed this morning, so will the flowers of bliss bloom within you.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 The Decisive Moment is at Hand</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/in_search_of_the_miraculous_vol_1/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/in_search_of_the_miraculous_vol_1/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
The Decisive Moment is at Hand
5 May 1970 pm in
As a large number of questions have been received in the last three days I would like today to answer briefly as many of them as possible.
A friend has said that when Vivekananda asked Ramakrishna, “Have you seen God?” Ramakrishna said in answer, “Yes, I have seen God as I see you right now.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 Kundalini, Shaktipat and Grace</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/in_search_of_the_miraculous_vol_1/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/in_search_of_the_miraculous_vol_1/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
Kundalini, Shaktipat and Grace
15 June 1970 am in
Question 1
QUESTIONER: HOW IS INTENSE BREATHING AND THE ASKING OF THE QUESTION “WHO AM I?” RELATED WITH THE PROCESS OF THE AWAKENING OF THE KUNDALINI AND ITS PENETRATION INTO THE VARIOUS CENTERS OR CHAKRAS OF THE BODY?
There is a relationship, and a deep relationship at that, between the two processes. In fact, it is the breath that connects the soul with the body; breath forms the bridge between the two.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
