<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Ultimate Alchemy Volume 2 on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Ultimate Alchemy Volume 2 on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 Awareness: The Gateway Toward Eden</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_2/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_2/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
Awareness: The Gateway Toward Eden
1 July 1972 pm in
CHIDAGNI SWAROOPAM DHOOPAH
“TO CREATE THE FIRE OF AWARENESS IN ONESELF IS DHOOP, THE INCENSE.”
FOR PHILOSOPHY, many are the problems – infinite. But for religion there is only one problem, and that problem is man himself. It is not that man has problems, but man is the problem. And why is man the problem?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 I am \&#34;That\&#34;</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_2/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_2/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
I am “That”
1 August 1972 pm in
SOHAM BHAVO NAMASKARAH
“THE FEELING OF I AM THAT – SO-AHAM – IS THE SALUTATION.”
EXISTENCE is one, or rather, Existence is oneness. Al-Hillaj Mansoor was flayed alive because he said, “I am the Beloved; I am the Divine; I am That which created the world.” Islam was totally unacquainted with this type of language.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 Questions and Answers</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_2/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_2/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
Questions and Answers
2 August 1972 pm in
Question 1
OSHO, “SO-AHAM – I AM THAT,” OR “AHAM BRAHMASMI – I AM THE BRAHMAN,” OR “ANAL- HAK”: ALL THESE STATEMENTS SEEM TO BE THAT OF A GYANI (ONE WHO IS ON THE PATH OF KNOWLEDGE). LAST NIGHT’S SUTRA SAYS: “I AM THAT – SO-AHAM – IS THE SALUTATION.” THE SECOND PART SEEMS TO BE THAT OF A BHAKTA (ONE WHO IS ON THE PATH OF DEVOTION), WHEREAS THE FIRST PART SEEMS TO BE THAT OF A GYANI.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Breaking the Inner Monologue</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_2/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_2/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
Breaking the Inner Monologue
3 August 1972 pm in MOUNAM STUTIHI “SILENCE IS THE PRAYER.”
“SILENCE is the prayer.” By prayer we always mean a communication, something said to the Divine,
but the Upanishads say that whatsoever you may say will not be prayer. Prayer is not something to be done. You cannot do it. It is not an act; it is not your doing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 Questions and Answers</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_2/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_2/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
Questions and Answers
4 August 1972 pm in
Question 1
OSHO, LAST NIGHT YOU SAID THAT ONE CAN GROW THROUGH TOTAL ACCEPTANCE. BUT THE EAST HAS REMAINED UNDEVELOPED DUE TO THIS PRINCIPLE OF ACCEPTANCE AND CONTENTMENT, WHEREAS THE WEST HAS BECOME MORE DEVELOPED ONLY BECAUSE OF NON-ACCEPTANCE AND DISCONTENTMENT.
THEREFORE, ISN’T IT OBVIOUS THAT DISCONTENTMENT AND NON-ACCEPTANCE IS THE PRINCIPLE FOR EVOLUTION AND GROWTH AND NOT TOTAL ACCEPTANCE?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 Contentment: The Dispersion of Desires</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_2/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_2/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
Contentment: The Dispersion of Desires
5 August 1972 pm in
SARVA SANTOSHO VISARJANAMITI YA AEVAM VEDA
“TOTAL CONTENTMENT IS VISARJAN, THE DISPERSION OF THE WORSHIP RITUAL. ONE WHO UNDERSTANDS SO IS AN ENLIGHTENED ONE.”
TOTAL contentment is wisdom. Three things have to be understood. First, what total contentment is; second, what wisdom is, what it means to be wise, to be Enlightened, and third, why contentment is wisdom.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 Questions and Answers</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_2/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_2/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
Questions and Answers
6 August 1972 pm in
Question 1
OSHO, YOU TOLD LAST NIGHT ABOUT THE HINDU SYSTEM OF CREATING A MUD IDOL FOR WORSHIP, AND AFTER THE WORSHIP, ABOUT ITS VISARJAN DISPERSION – INTO THE SEA OR A RIVER. THIS HAPPENS ON THE OUTER PHYSICAL PLANE. WHAT IS THE PSYCHOLOGICAL AND INNER MEANING OF THIS OUTER RITUAL? WHAT IS IT THAT MUST BE CREATED INWARDLY?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 Experiencing: The Essence of the Hindu Mind</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_2/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_2/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
Experiencing: The Essence of the Hindu Mind
7 August 1972 pm in
SARVA NIRAMAYA PARIPOORNOHAMASMITI MUMUKSHUNAM MOKSHAIK SIDDHIRBHAWATI
“I AM THAT ABSOLUTELY PURE BRAHMAN: TO REALIZE THIS IS THE ATTAINMENT OF LIBERATION.”
EXISTENCE is divided into two. Existence, as we see it, is a duality. Biologically, man is divided into two: man and woman, ontologically, Existence is divided into mind and matter.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 Questions and Answers</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_2/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_2/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
Questions and Answers
8 August 1972 pm in
Question 1
OSHO, WHY HAVE WE NOT BEEN ABLE TO CREATE A SOCIETY WHICH COMBINES BOTH POLARITIES – PHILOSOPHY AND POETRY, SCIENCE AND RELIGION?
IS THERE A POSSIBILITY OF THE TOTAL MEETING OF THESE POLARITIES? WHICH LAND IS MORE FERTILE FOR THIS MEETING – EAST OR WEST?
IS THIS MEETING POSSIBLE ONLY IN AN INDIVIDUAL, OR CAN IT EXIST SIMULTANEOUSLY IN THE SOCIETY ALSO?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 Questions and Answers</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_2/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_2/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 18
Questions and Answers
9 August 1972 pm in
OSHO, IT IS GENERALLY BELIEVED THAT RELIGION IS A SEARCH FOR TRUTH. BUT ONE NIGHT YOU SAID THAT WHILE THE GREEK MIND, THE SCIENTIFICALLY INCLINED MIND, SOUGHT TRUTH, THE EASTERN MIND, THE RELIGIOUS MIND, HAS Moksha, OR FREEDOM, AS ITS OBJECT OF SEARCH. BUT YOU HAVE ALSO SAID IN THE PAST THAT IT IS TRUTH ALONE THAT LIBERATES.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Questions and Answers</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_2/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_2/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
Questions and Answers
2 July 1972 pm in
Question 1
OSHO, AFTER EATING THE FRUIT OF THE TREE OF KNOWLEDGE, ADAM AND EVE, FOR THE FIRST TIME, BECAME AWARE OF THEIR NAKEDNESS AND FELT ASHAMED. WHAT IS THE DEEPER MEANING BEHIND THIS FEELING?
AND, SECONDLY, IT HAS BEEN SAID THAT THE FORBIDDEN FRUIT OF THE TREE OF KNOWLEDGE IS KNOWLEDGE OF SEX.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 The Lamp of Awareness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_2/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_2/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
The Lamp of Awareness
3 July 1972 pm in
CHIDADITYA SWAROOPAM DEEPAH
“TO BE ESTABLISHED IN THE SUN OF AWARENESS IS THE ONLY LAMP.”
ONE DAY a lady came to Mulla Nasrudin’s school with her small child, her son. The lady asked Mulla to frighten the boy. He had become unruly and he would not listen to anyone. He needed to be frightened by some big authority.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Questions and Answers</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_2/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_2/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
Questions and Answers
4 July 1972 pm in
Question 1
OSHO, MAN’S PARTIAL CONSCIOUSNESS IS A STAGE IN THE GRAND EVOLUTION OF LIFE. WHAT COULD BE THE SIGNIFICANCE OF HIS VOLITIONAL EFFORTS IN ITS GROWTH?
PLEASE ALSO EXPLAIN THE ROLE THAT THE BUDDHAS, THE ENLIGHTENED ONES, PLAY IN THE EXPANSION OF HUMAN CONSCIOUSNESS.
Evolution is unconscious. No volition is needed, no conscious effort: it is just natural.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 The Ultimate Alchemy</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_2/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_2/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
The Ultimate Alchemy
5 July 1972 pm in
PARIPOORN CHANDRA AMRIT RASAIKI KARANAM NAIVEDYAM
“ACCUMULATION OF THE NECTAR OF THE INNER FULL MOON IS NAIVEDYA, THE FOOD OFFERING.”
YOU MUST have heard about the Taoist concept of yin and yang – the concept of polar opposites into one reality. Reality exists through polar opposites – through the positive and the negative, through the male and the female, through yin and yang.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Questions and Answers</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_2/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_2/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
Questions and Answers
6 July 1972 pm in
Question 1
OSHO, WHAT ARE THE REASONS THAT VERY FEW PERSONS IN THE WORLD ARE INTERESTED IN TRANSFORMING THEIR INNER HEAT INTO SPIRITUAL LIGHT? DO YOU FEEL THAT THE PRESENT GENERATION IS CAPABLE OF CREATING ENLIGHTENED ONES LIKE KRISHNA, LAO TZU AND CHRIST?
MAN IS FREEDOM, absolute freedom, so spirituality is a choice. There is no force compelling you to be spiritual; there is no cause forcing you to transform.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Toward the Silence of the Innermost Center</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_2/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_2/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
Toward the Silence of the Innermost Center
7 July 1972 pm in
NISCHALATWAM PRADAKSHINAM
“STILLNESS IS PRADAKSHINA, THE MOVEMENT AROUND THAT FOR WORSHIP.”
SILENCE is meditation and silence is basic for any religious experience. What is silence? You can create it, you can cultivate it, you can force it, but then it is just superficial, false, pseudo. You carl practise it, and you will begin to feel and experience it – but your practice makes it auto-hypnotic.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 Questions and Answers</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_2/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_2/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
Questions and Answers
8 July 1972 pm in
Question 1
OSHO, LAST NIGHT YOU EXPLAINED INNER STILLNESS THROUGH THE DIMENSION OF INNER SILENCE. PLEASE EXPLAIN INNER STILLNESS FROM SOME OTHER DIMENSION.
STILLNESS has many dimensions. One is silence: it is the polar opposite of sound; it is soundlessness. The second dimension is no-movement: it is the polar opposite of movement. Mind is movement just as mind is sound.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 Questions and Answers</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_2/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_ultimate_alchemy_volume_2/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
Questions and Answers
9 July 1972 pm in
Question 1
OSHO, YOU SAID ONE NIGHT THAT AWARENESS BRINGS KNOWLEDGE AND KNOWLEDGE MAKES MAN AWARE OF MANY PROBLEMS AND SUFFERINGS WITHIN HIMSELF. BUT ISN’T IT TRUE THAT AWARENESS AND KNOWLEDGE GIVE MORE RICHNESS, GROWTH AND DEPTH TO MAN’S LIFE?
PLEASE EXPLAIN ABOUT THIS DIALECTICAL SITUATION IN MAN AND THE WAY TO TRANSCEND THE KNOWLEDGE AS WELL.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
