<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Heart Sutra on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heart_sutra/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Heart Sutra on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/the_heart_sutra/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 The Buddha Within</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heart_sutra/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heart_sutra/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Osho
The Heart Sutra
Talks on Prajnaparamita Hridayam Sutra of Gautama the Buddha Talks given from 11/10/77 am to 20/10/77 am
English Discourse series 10 Chapters
Year published: 1978
1 The Buddha Within 2
2 Surrender is Understanding 19
3 Negation of Knowledge 34
4 Understanding: The Only Law 50
5 The Fragrance of Nothingness 65
6 Don&#39;t Be Too Sane 85
7 Full Emptiness 102</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Sannyas: Entering the Stream</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heart_sutra/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heart_sutra/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌A guru is one who makes you free. A guru is one who delivers you freedom. A guru is one who liberates you. Buddha is one of the mahagurus. His message is the greatest that has ever been delivered to man. And this sutra is one of the greatest expressions of Buddha. He has talked for forty-two years, and he has said many things, but nothing compared to this.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Surrender is Understanding</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heart_sutra/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heart_sutra/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌The novice went away sadly, for he had labored hard to reach the essence. But after ten years he came back, and bowing low before the master offered him just five pages and said, &#34;This is the kernel of my faith, the core of my life, and I ask your blessings for having brought me to it.&#34;
The master read it slowly and carefully: &#34;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Negation of Knowledge</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heart_sutra/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heart_sutra/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌The second thing: if he does not understand your sannyas, it is his problem. You have to live your life. Never compromise, otherwise you will miss much. Never compromise! If you feel like becoming a sannyasin, become a sannyasin. Take the risk. If he loves you there is no problem, he will understand -- because love gives freedom. If he does not love you then there will be difficulty for him, because he will feel you are getting out of his possession, you are becoming independent, you are trying to be yourself.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Understanding: The Only Law</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heart_sutra/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heart_sutra/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌THERE IS NEITHER SELF NOR OTHER THAN SELF. WHEN DIRECT IDENTIFICATION IS SOUGHT,
WE CAN ONLY SAY &#39;NOT TWO&#39;. ONE IN ALL, ALL IN ONE:
IF THIS IS REALIZED,
NO MORE WORRY ABOUT YOUR NOT BEING PERFECT.
ONE IN ALL, ALL IN ONE -- IF THIS IS REALIZED, NO MORE WORRY ABOUT
YOUR NOT BEING PERFECT. There is no perfection, no imperfection. See it, and see it right now!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 The Fragrance of Nothingness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heart_sutra/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heart_sutra/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌you are afraid that tomorrow you may not be able to possess, she may go to somebody else. She is still alive, she can go. Only dead women won&#39;t go; she is still alive. You can possess only a corpse -- then there is no fear, the corpse will be there. You can possess furniture, then there is no fear. But when you try to possess a human being fear comes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Don\&#39;t Be Too Sane</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heart_sutra/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heart_sutra/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌So the sage gives you a well-formulated eightfold path. He says, &#34;This is the way.&#34; One day, when you will really be awake... And remember, these things help you to awake. Now even if you stand on your head in a dream there is a possibility your dream will be broken. Try! Try tonight! When you are in a dream, just stand on your head in the dream, and suddenly you will see that you are awake.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Full Emptiness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heart_sutra/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heart_sutra/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌important questions of life. Don&#39;t start hankering and longing for some future ideal, idea, perfection. Drop all ideals and live here-now.
My commune is not going to be an ideal society. My commune is going to be a herenow commune.
Enough for today.
7
Full Emptiness
17 October 1977 am in Buddha Hall
THEREFORE, O SARIPUTRA,
IT IS BECAUSE OF HIS NON-ATTAINMENTNESS THAT A BODHISATTVA, THROUGH HAVING RELIED ON THE PERFECTION OF WISDOM, DWELLS WITHOUT THOUGHT-COVERINGS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 The Path of Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heart_sutra/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heart_sutra/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌IN THE THREE PERIODS OF TIME
FULLY AWAKE TO THE UTMOST, RIGHT AND PERFECT ENLIGHTENMENT BECAUSE THEY HAVE RELIED ON THE PERFECTION OF WISDOM.
The only refuge is the perfection of wisdom, the perfection of meditation. In the past it has been so, in the present it is so, in the future it will be so. Anybody who becomes a Buddha becomes one through meditation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 Gone, Gone, Gone Beyond!</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heart_sutra/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_heart_sutra/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Saint Peter: &#34;And you?&#34;
Salesman: &#34;While pushing a fridge through a window I died of a heart attack.&#34; Saint Peter to the third man: &#34;What did you die of?&#34;
Third man: &#34;Well, I was sitting in this fridge, minding my own business, and...&#34;
Life is very accidental. One never knows from where the fridge will come. Somebody may be sitting in it, minding his own business.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
