<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Madman\&#39;s Guide to Enlightenment on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Madman\&#39;s Guide to Enlightenment on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
1 June 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Remember only one thing: the past is a hindrance, the greatest hindrance. It has to be completely dropped, utterly dropped. To be with me is to be in the now – no past, no future. This moment is all there is and just this moment is god. Everything else is just the mind dreaming, desiring, imagining.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
10 June 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, prasthano means beginning – a divine beginning. Sannyas is a beginning, not the end – the first step but the most vital, the most radical. Even the last step will not be so radical, because the last comes of its own accord – the first has to be taken. It needs your decision, your commitment, your involvement.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
11 June 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine or godly, and kalyani means one who brings blessings. The full name will mean: one who brings divine blessings... and each of us has the power to become a blessing to the world. The same energy can become destructive and a curse. The energy is the same; whether it becomes destruction or creation depends on one’s choice.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
12 June 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A ten-year-old sannyasin says: I always feel that this is a dream, life is a dream.]
It is a dream, and your feeling is perfectly right. Don’t forget it! It is a dream, and every child knows it in the beginning. Slowly slowly one forgets it and starts thinking it is very real...</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
13 June 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, samapatti means richness, wealth, treasure – divine treasure. It is there – and you have not claimed it yet – and it is yours, just for the asking. You need not spread your hands anywhere before anybody. The treasure is hidden within your own heart. And people go on searching everywhere else except in the heart.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
14 June 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says: I haven’t really got any problems or anything but I feel that I’d like some advice.]
There is no need. It is good to be without any problem. And if one can live without any problem, one knows how to live. All problems are unnecessary. We create them because we cannot live without problems, because we cannot allow ourselves to be without problems – we cannot allow that much freedom and that much joy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
15 June 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, veenu is a musical instrument – a musical instrument of love. And man is a musical instrument. If we allow god, he can create much music in us. But we don’t allow it; we resist, we fight. Hence our life remains musicless, and that is the misery. Unless great music is born in the heart one cannot feel any significance, any splendour in life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
16 June 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, neelambar means blue light – divine blue light. And the blue light represents infinity; it is the colour of the infinite, the colour of the sky. It is not really a colour. The sky has no colour; it appears blue because of its infinity. The sheer vastness, the depth makes it appear blue.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
17 June 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, vatayana means now, the present moment – love now. And my whole emphasis is on this moment, because this moment contains all. Now is the only reality – all else is either memory or imagination. And even for the past to exist as memory, now is needed. It doesn’t exist as the past; it exists as a thought in the present.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
18 June 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means god, bhumika means introduction – introduction to god. And life is an introduction to god. It is not against god, as the old religions have been teaching again and again. It is not antagonistic to god – it can’t be. It is god’s extension, it is his manifestation, it is his song.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
19 June 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, sahajia means one who believes in spontaneity. The full name will mean: one who trusts in spontaneity and bliss. And they always go together; they are two aspects of the same coin. Bliss is always spontaneous – it is never manufactured, there is no way to put it on the assembly line.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
2 June 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, sarla means innocence divine innocence. That is the way to know god. Knowledge is not the way, but innocence, a quality of childlikeness. We cannot approach reality through our calculating mind, because it is not a problem to be solved, it is not a problem at all. So mathematics, logic, can’t help.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
20 June 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, sarlo means simplicity divine simplicity. And simplicity is one of those things which cannot be cultivated. If cultivated then it is simplicity no more; it is already complex. If cultivated, it is already calculated. If cultivated, it is projection of the mind. Simplicity is something that cannot be manufactured by the mind.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
21 June 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, vismayo means wonder – divine wonder. And there is nothing more divine in life than wonder. Just as knowledge prevents one getting in tune with god, wonder bridges one. Wonder is the polar opposite of knowledge. Knowledge kills wonder. The more a man becomes knowledgeable, his capacity to wonder becomes less and less.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
22 June 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, nirakar means formless. Misery has a form, bliss has no form. Misery is definable, bliss is not. You can pinpoint where misery is; you cannot do the same with bliss. Misery is small; bliss is vast. Misery is smaller than you; bliss is infinite. Misery is always in you; bliss never in you.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
23 June 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Prem Niradha – a cloud of love]
And the cloud represents freedom. It has no roots anywhere. It is utter freedom. It has no direction either, no destiny, because any kind of destiny is bound to become a slavery. Then it is fate, not freedom. If there is a direction, then the freedom is narrowed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 24
24 June 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, Hamido is a name of god, so it will mean god of love.
Only love gives the quality of being divine. All else is mundane, all else is just trivial. Only love is something of the beyond, non-material. In the world, except for love, there is no proof for god. So the man who does not know what love is will be incapable of knowing god – not only incapable of knowing but incapable of trusting, not only incapable of trusting but even incapable of comprehending the fact of god.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 25
25 June 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, hasid means a disciple a divine disciple, a disciple of god. Disciplehood is always of god; the master is only a link. One does not become a disciple of a master; one becomes a disciple through the master. The master is a door, a bridge, but the disciplehood is always of god.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 26
26 June 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
It means ‘only consciousness’. Nothing else exists but consciousness, and all else that appears to exist is only appearance.
Just one hundred years ago Friedrich Nietzsche declared ‘God is dead.’ Those were the days of great enthusiasm for materialists. Science was evolving, exploding, and man was full of great hope that now he had come to the solution of all problems, god was no more needed, man had come of age.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 27
27 June 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Soma means the moon, and deva means god – moon god. It is one of the most pregnant symbols. The moon represents the feminine energy, just as the sun represents the masculine energy. Masculine energy is out-going; feminine energy is in-going. It is like inhalation; masculine is like exhalation. Inhalation is life, exhalation is death.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part28/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 28
28 June 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Chid means consciousness, akash means sky. One sky is outside us, but another and a far more significant one is inside us. Our body is just dividing two skies. The moment we forget our body, those two skies become one and that meeting of those two skies is samadhi; the meeting of the inner with the outer is enlightenment.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>29</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part29/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 29
29 June 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, nirvana means liberation. Man cannot liberate himself – that is impossible, because man himself is the cause of bondage. The very idea ‘I am’ is the root cause of bondage, so there is no way to go beyond the ‘I’, through the ‘I’; it won’t allow. It will go on surrounding you in new ways, in new forms.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
3 June 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho gives a fourteen-year-old boy the name Swami Prem Ajita – unconquerable love]
And love is the only power that cannot be conquered. There is no way to conquer it. The only way to approach it is to surrender – not through conflict, not through conquering. The only way to attain to love is to bow down to it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>30</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part30/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 30
30 June 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[true religion – Satdharma.]
The religion one is born into is never true; it cannot be true, because one has never chosen it. To be true a religion has to be consciously chosen, otherwise it remains just a conditioning. One is born into Hinduism; he is a Hindu. Another is born into Christianity and he is a Christian, but this is only upbringing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
4 June 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho gives a couple an ‘energy darshan’]
Good. Come back. This is the best way to say something of the heart. And there is much the heart wants to say but the mind is incapable of saying it. It can be said only through the energy. Words are inadequate; only vitality can be adequate for it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
5 June 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho gives a meditation to a sannyasin.]
You start one meditation, and that is just sitting silently and allowing your fingers to have their own movement. Feel the movement from the inside. Don’t try to see it from the outside. So keep your eyes closed and just feel the movements from inside. let the energy flow more and more into the hands.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
6 June 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says: Sometimes I wonder whether you’re real or not.]
Everything is unreal – I am too – because reality is not a thing. All things are unreal. Reality is a nothing, no-thing. Things are only appearances, forms of something which is formless. That formlessness is real but that cannot be seen by the eyes and cannot be touched and felt is unreal; it is all dream stuff – and I am included in it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
7 June 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin asks about earning money in the West and finding time for sannyas activities.]
Do at least one meditation every day. Choose any meditation, but persist with one method; don’t go on changing. Whether results come or not, go on persisting in it. Results certainly come; all that is needed is patience. Methods don’t work.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
8 June 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, padmaja means the lotus-born lotus-born love. And the lotus is one of the greatest symbols in the East: it is a representative of the beyond. It exists on the earth but it is not of the earth. The beauty of it, the grace of it is so tremendous, so incredible, that it cannot be of this world – it must be of the other.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_madmans_guide_to_enlightenment/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
9 June 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says: I felt lots of times to write. Once I nearly came and spoke to you but I didn’t, and things have worked out fine. It’s just: am I using you enough? – that’s what I’m not sure of.]
You are... and it is good. Writing is not of much use. If sometimes it becomes impossible and you cannot help it, write.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
