<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Beginning of the Beginning on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_beginning_of_the_beginning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Beginning of the Beginning on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/the_beginning_of_the_beginning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 From Dependence Towards Truth</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_beginning_of_the_beginning/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_beginning_of_the_beginning/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
From Dependence Towards Truth
25 February 1969 pm in
Enchanted by the song of a bird singing happily on the branch of a tree, a king had it caught and kept in a cage. Even singing is wrong in the presence of wrong people. The poor bird could not have imagined that his song would get him behind bars! The bird that flew in abandon in the free skies and flitted from one branch to another as he wished, now found himself in a golden cage, inlaid with precious stones to one who has tasted the freedom of the skies?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 From Delusion Towards Truth</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_beginning_of_the_beginning/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_beginning_of_the_beginning/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
From Delusion Towards Truth
26 February 1969 am in
One expansion is external. The eyes look out; the hands feel the touch of external objects; the ears hear the outside sounds. But there is an expansion within also, which the eyes cannot see the ears cannot hear, and bands cannot touch. That is why, perhaps, what is within remains unknown and unfamiliar.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 From Belief Towards Truth</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_beginning_of_the_beginning/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_beginning_of_the_beginning/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
From Belief Towards Truth
26 February 1969 pm in
Friends have asked many questions. One friend asks: “You say that Truth is not obtained from words, much less from scriptures and from gurus, then what is the purport of your talk?”
Truth will not be obtained from my talk – please understand this well. Nobody’s words can convey Truth. If a thorn gets embedded in your foot, you can use a second thorn to remove it; but once the thorn is out both become equally redundant.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 From Dreams Towards Truth</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_beginning_of_the_beginning/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_beginning_of_the_beginning/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
From Dreams Towards Truth
27 February 1969 am in
I have just been to the Girnar mountains, where the temples glisten in the morning sun. Seeing these temples, it occurred to me: The soul too has such high peaks where temples shine even brighter; for the Lord’s light is more keen and intense than the Sun’s light. But we are such; we lose ourselves in the temples outside and get no hint of the temples within.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 From Emptiness Towards Truth</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_beginning_of_the_beginning/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_beginning_of_the_beginning/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 5
From Emptiness Towards Truth
27 February 1969 pm in
Many questions are before me. One friend has asked: “If the soul cannot be seen, then why is so much importance given to something invisible? Why do you also talk about this same unseen atman?”
The trees are visible, not so the roots that lie hidden in the ground beneath. That does not mean that they are of less significance.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
