<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>For Madmen Only (Price of Admission. Your Mind) on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/</link>
    <description>Recent content in For Madmen Only (Price of Admission. Your Mind) on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
1 April 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem kutera. It means a small shrine of love, a small hut of love, a small space for love. Prem means love and kutera means a small place. And that’s all that a man needs to be fulfilled: if one can become a small shrine, nothing is lacking.
The very phenomenon of love integrates you, and when love is missing, you start falling apart – it is the glue that keeps you together.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
10 April 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, ketan means house – a house of love or a temple of love, a shrine.
Man can function from three centres: one is the head, another is the heart and the third one is the navel. If you function from the head you will go on spinning thoughts and thoughts and thoughts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
11 April 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A new sannyasin asks: What is de-materialisation? Is it possible?]
Everything is possible, possibilities are infinite. Materialisation is possible and de-materialisation is possible. In fact it is happening all the time.
There was a time when the earth was not there, then it materialised. And there are stars which are disappearing, de-materialising. Now physicists say that when a star de-materialises it leaves an empty hole in its place, a black hole – just emptiness is left and the whole of the matter simply disappears.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
12 April 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says: I have a very beautiful relationship... I don’t know what to say!]
That’s very good! Don’t destroy it, that’s all, because beautiful things are destroyed so easily. The more beautiful, the more dangerous, because they can be destroyed more easily. The more beautiful, the more delicate – so handle with care!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
13 April 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, varsha means rain – and you have to keep that continuously in your awareness, that god is raining on you. And it is not imagination, it is the truth: god is raining every moment. We live only because he goes on raining; the moment the rain stops, we disappear. It is a subtle energy rain – it is invisible, but life is continuously being given to you.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
14 April 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A visitor says: I have come here with an open heart... and I wish to know.]
Good – the heart is ready for many things and very very hungry for something to happen. Not only open, but waiting too – and nothing has happened for the whole life.
You have come into this life with a great thirst for something to happen.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
15 April 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divinity, divineness, and siddhen means one who has arrived. And that’s my basic teaching and basic message, that we are not to go anywhere, we are already in the state, we are already there, we have already arrived. There is nowhere to go; we just have to see where we are. The difference is only of being aware or unaware.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
16 April 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem madhi. It means love mind. The mind has two aspects: one aspect which thinks, another aspect which feels. And the reality is known not by the thinking aspect but by the feeling aspect.
The joy of life is also attained through the feeling aspect. If a person becomes addicted too much to the thinking aspect he becomes dry.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
17 April 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin with her baby, who has a spinal defect, says: She hasn’t been well. I think she hasn’t decided whether she wants to stay her or not in this world.]
Let her decide – give her freedom.
[She asks: How can I watch all these problems? How can I be aware? It’s hard.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
18 April 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine and shravaka means ‘who has heard’ – one who has heard the call of the divine.
And always remember that we start looking for god only when he has called us. It is not otherwise, that we start looking first. It is always he who takes the initiative. We may not be even aware of it, but unless he calls, nobody moves towards him.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
19 April 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Bodhi means consciousness, awareness, and dhara means a river: a river of awareness. And awareness is a river – it is a stream, it is a flow. It lives only when it flows; when it is not flowing it is dead.
So whenever the consciousness is not flowing, a person lives a dead life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
2 April 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love and aja means unborn. And that’s how we exist: we are born like seeds – something has yet to flower. The love has yet to happen, it is not yet born; it is there, hankering to be born, it is still in the womb.
Every man is love unborn, hence the misery, the anguish.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
20 April 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, jayana means victory. And there is only one victory in life, and that is with god, with the divine. Alone we are defeated, with him we are winners.
Man alone cannot win, there is no possibility. Man alone is doomed, man alone is simply helpless. To be with god is to be victorious, because the total wins finally, not the part – and god means the total or the whole.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
21 April 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says: I feel very lost and I cannot get out of it. I am in a trap. Sometimes I think it is just mind. I see that everything that happens is my responsibility although I think all doors are closed.
Osho checks his energy.]
Everything is going so beautifully well – you unnecessarily become worried.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
22 April 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem Saraha. I’m talking about saraha these days (in the morning discourses). Prem means love and saraha means one who has attained the target – one who has attained the target of love. It is still a possibility, but it can become actual; I give the name with a great hope. It is not yet actual but it can become actual, with just a little effort and a little awareness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
23 April 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine and yashodara means the glorious one. Yashodara is the name of the wife of Buddha, too. And that is the true reality of everyone: the glorious one is sitting inside you, waiting for your knock. It is not far away, it is very close by – just a slight turn and the meeting happens.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 24
24 April 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, mantra means chanting. And if we look into life it is a constant singing. Basically it is sound – the existence consists of sound, eternal sound. And whenever we are close to that sound we are happy, whenever we fall in tune with that song we are happy and blissful. Whenever we are out of step we are unhappy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 25
25 April 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho gives a name for a centre in the West.]
This will be the name: shraddhan meditation centre. Shraddhan means trust. And that is the most significant quality for a seeker, to be able to trust – because the whole movement is into the unknown. Unless you trust you cannot go into it. It needs tremendous courage to trust.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 26
26 April 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A new sannyasin tells Osho she is unsure as to whether she should complete the last two years of her psychology degree]
My feeling is, if you can complete it, it will be good. It may not be very beautiful to study, you may not enjoy it very much, but the ultimate result will be good.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 27
27 April 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin asks: In the lectures, I don’t know, but it seems that you have looked at me very furiously, angry – was this real? Was this just me? I don’t know.]
It must have been you. You must have some resistance, you must be afraid of me, so you projected it. Otherwise why should I be angry with you?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part28/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 28
28 April 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, mani means diamond – bliss diamond. And everybody is carrying that diamond within his soul. If we are feeling like beggars, it is just because we have not looked into our being, otherwise everybody is born an emperor. God never creates any beggar, that is an impossibility – god cannot do that.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>29</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part29/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 29
29 April 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means god or divine and pashianti means clarity, vision. capacity to see. Capacity to clearly see god – that will be the meaning of the whole name.
Everybody is born capable; somewhere on the way we lose the capacity. Every child comes with a very clear vision of god, but by and by we force him to forget; we force him to remember the world and forget god.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
3 April 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin who is returning to the West says: I feel vulnerable and somehow strong... I just hope you’ll be with me... through all of this turbulence.]
Yes, I will be with you. And this is really important, to be vulnerable and strong. There are people who feel strong only when they are not vulnerable; that strength is bogus.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>30</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part30/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 30
30 April 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin, who is leaving, says: Would you say something about dying? I’m very much engaged with that. I awoke last night and suddenly I saw how absolute it was. I’ve never seen it before like that – I could hardly get any air.
In response to Osho’s query she says she likes Kundalini meditation best.]</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
4 April 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin returning to the West says he will stay with his brother: My brother is a carpenter on the river – he works with boats.]
Very good. Just be there, mm? by the river. It is good to be with a carpenter; people who work with their hands are beautiful people. It is not just accidental that Christ was born to a carpenter.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
5 April 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin, who is leaving, says: It’s bothered me for a long time that I feel I never meditated... I opened a lot but I never go inside at all.
Osho checks her energy.]
Mm mm, just come closer. Raise your hands, close your eyes, and if something starts happening in the body energy, allow it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
6 April 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
... Dweepam – and this is a special word in the buddhist tradition.
Buddha says to his disciples again and again ‘Become an island’ – and by that he means to remain in your aloneness totally. Just like an island unconnected to anything, just you yourself in your absolute aloneness – then you become an island.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
7 April 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[The Primal therapy group is present. Osho asks the leader for comments. The leader says it was a very soft group, influenced by a new co-leader. He then asks about a personal problem.]
Mm! First you talk about the group, mm? and when you want to talk about yourself, come separately – always remember this!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
8 April 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says: It’s been a strange time here for me. I’ve been feeling the West a lot and so have decided to go back. I also feel sad about it sometimes.]
No, there is no need to be sad – go to the West. One day the west will disappear from the mind, but it will take time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/for_madmen_only_price_of_admission_your_mind/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
9 April 1977 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho asks a sannyasin couple who is leaving when they will be coming back. The man answers: God knows... maybe fall.]
In the fall? Have you heard the famous Mulla Nasrudin story?
Mulla had saved up to buy a new shirt. He went to a tailor’s shop, full of excitement. The tailor measured him and said, ‘Come back in a week, and – if Allah wills – your shirt will be ready.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
