<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Tongue-Tip Taste of Tao on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Tongue-Tip Taste of Tao on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
1 October 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Tao Devam. Tao means the way – not the way to any goal, but the way things are. Tao has nothing to do with goals; it has no future-orientation. It is the present moment and the things that are in the herenow. It is the totality of existence in the present and the law that holds it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
10 October 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, wajid is a Sufi word. It means intense yearning for god, a total longing for god, a passionate longing for god – not just a desire. A desire becomes a longing when you are ready to risk all for it. Even life seems to be less valuable than it.
Desires serve life; a life serves a longing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
11 October 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, wajida is a Sufi word; it means ‘one who yearns for god.’ Your full name will mean: love that yearns for god, love that longs for god, love that cannot be satisfied by anything else other than god. And that is one of the most significant facts to recognise, to remember: man cannot be content through anything else than god.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
12 October 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Veet means beyond, gyan means knowledge – beyond knowledge. God is beyond knowledge, it is intrinsically unknowable. The very effort to know it is a barrier in knowing it, because we can know something only if we are separate from it. Knowledge requires a division, the division between the object and the subject. Knowledge requires a kind of distance between the knower and the known, and that is not possible with god.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
13 October 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, mahabodh means great awakening – a great awakening of love. Only love is great – all else is very small. Even the greatest thought of the mind is very small. The mind cannot be great; the mind is basically mean. It is not spacious. The heart is spacious, expansive. The heart can grow so big that it can contain the whole universe.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
14 October 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Dhyan means meditation, samma means right – right meditation. Meditation is wrong when it is a ritual, when it is not of the heart. Meditation is right when it arises out of your heart and is not imposed by the mind, when it is not a ritual. The mind can only do rituals; it is very clever in creating rituals.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
15 October 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, anamo means namelessness – divine namelessness. Man comes without any name – the name is given here. It is useful but not real. But the mind has the tendency to become attached to all kinds of unrealities. It becomes attached to the name too, and that becomes one of the greatest problems.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
16 October 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, giri means mountain – a divine mountain. It is a metaphor for absolute meditation. When one is utterly silent, still, and there is no movement in the mind, one starts feeling like a great peak of the mountain... snow-capped.
The mountain has always attracted meditators. There is something in the mountains – the silence, the stillness, the absolute unmoving.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
17 October 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Satyen means the truth. The real search is not for god and cannot be. To seek and search for god means that you have already accepted the idea that god is; you have already concluded. The search is no more true, no more authentic. Now your mind will try to prove whatsoever it has already accepted, believed – your enquiry is doomed from the very beginning.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
18 October 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, prakasho means light – divine light. And remember that darkness is accidental – light is our nature. We are surrounded by darkness but we are not it: we are its observers. And the moment one goes in one comes across great darkness. Every seeker into one’s self finds great darkness. But remember you are not it – you are the one who is seeing it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
19 October 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, tarshito means thirst for – thirst for god. God is possible only when it becomes a thirst for each cell of your being, when one is afire, when it is not only curiosity. Because if it is curiosity it remains only in the head – it never reaches to the heart; it is superficial.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
2 October 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[To a new sannyasin:]
You have come home! This was the search for your whole life – now the moment to fulfil it has come. And it is very rare, because many strive but very few reach. The desire to know, the desire to know the mystery of life is every heart’s desire, but very few fortunate people find a way to it, a door to it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
20 October 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Veet means beyond, shankaro means conditionings. Man is born unconditioned, man is born as freedom... just an open sky, with no clouds, with no boundaries, with no adjectives, no definitions – neither Hindu nor Christian nor Communist – just pure existence, an emptiness. But immediately the society starts closing in on you, starts making boundaries; those boundaries are conditionings.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
21 October 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, gandhraj is one of the most fragrant flowers. Literally it means ‘the king of all flowers.’ Bliss, the king of all flowers – that will be the meaning of your name. Bliss is a fragrance – like musk. The musk deer starts searching for the source from where this fragrance is coming and starts running hither and thither in the forest not knowing at all that the fragrance is coming from his own navel.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
22 October 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Anand Rupen – Bliss beauty]
Bliss is the ultimate state of consciousness. Bliss is not possible unless the mind is completely gone. It is the absence of the mind; it happens only in the absence of the mind. And the mind is the source of all ugliness, all negativities – hatred, anger, jealousy, possessiveness; all that comes from the mind.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
23 October 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Sansar means the world, atosha means discontent – discontent with the world... that is the beginning of the search. Those who are contented with the world are unfortunate, they are contented with the trivia; they are simply wasting their opportunity to grow. They are contented with toys. The world consists of all kinds of toys; that is the meaning of the word sansar.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 24
24 October 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, dwabha means twilight – divine twilight... and that is the situation where you are. The past is gone, and the future has not come yet. The old is disappearing and the new has not come yet. Hence there is a chaos inside, a great confusion.
You cannot go back to the old – the old mind is no more relevant – and you don’t know what the new mind is.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 25
25 October 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, nishkamo means desireless. Love with desire is lust. Love with a motive keeps one tethered to the body, to the mundane. Love without desire immediately frees you from the mundane and the door to the sacred is opened.
Love without desire is no more lust; it is prayer. That is the only difference between lust and prayer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 26
26 October 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, samagro means totality. Perfection is not the goal of life, although the whole past of humanity has been teaching people that perfection is the goal. And because of that teaching they have driven the whole of humanity neurotic; nobody can be perfect. Except for the total, the whole, there is no possibility of anybody being perfect.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 27
27 October 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine and halim should mean ‘no person’, not mild person. Even if you are a mild person, you remain arrogant in your mildness. It is hidden – it is not so overt, not so obvious, it has gone underground – but the mild person still carries the ego; maybe now the ego is that of mildness, humbleness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part28/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 28
28 October 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, lolita means moved by – moved by the divine, stirred by the divine. Just as wind comes and makes the tree a dancing girl, like that god comes and moves man’s heart. God is a breeze – invisible – but the heart can feel it and the heart can feel its movement.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>29</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part29/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 29
29 October 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, smito means smile – a divine smile. Laughter is a little rough. It has something of anger in it, something of violence too. Laughter is aggressive. A smile is feminine, non-aggressive, non-violent; a smile is passive. It does not make noise – it comes very silently and it disappears silently.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
3 October 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says: I always have so much to say to you, but I have nothing to say!]
That’s right. When there is so much to say, it is always difficult to say it. Only small things can be said, only trivia can be said, only the mundane can be said. Whenever you feel something overwhelming it is impossible to say it, because words are too narrow to contain anything essential.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>30</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part30/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 30
30 October 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, svado means taste. God is a taste... a taste on the tongue.
God is not a hypothesis to explain anything; it is something very existential. And the proof of god is not in any argument – it is exactly in tasting it. And the taste is such that even those who have tasted cannot express it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>31</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part31/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 31
31 October 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, astiko means one who trusts. Trust does not mean belief. Belief is of the intellect – trust is of the heart. Belief is always in a certain kind of doctrine. A person who believes in god really believes in the belief of god.
Trust is not in any philosophy – it is in something existential.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
4 October 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, sankirtan means holy singing, holy song. Life is sacred song; that’s what Jesus means when he says ‘Man cannot live by bread alone.’ The bread represents the business-side of life, it represents the calculative mind. And if life is only bread, then it is meaningless; the bread cannot give meaning to it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
5 October 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyas couple bring a new baby.]
This will be her name: Ma Prem Bindi. Prem means love, bindi means symbol – the symbol of love. The Indian women use a bindi on their forehead, just exactly on the third eye spot. It is also called bindi because it is only used by married women.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
6 October 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, jagran means awakening – the awakening of love. And that’s what god is. Once the heart has awakened in love, one has arrived home. Nothing else is missing – just the heart is fast asleep.
We have bypassed our hearts, we have entered into our heads directly without moving through the heart.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
7 October 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, idam means this-ness – the divinity of this-ness, the divinity of this moment. And it is the very essence of meditation: just this. To remain aware of just this is meditation – watching it, observing it, with no condemnation, with no evaluation, just remaining like a mirror. And slowly slowly the mind disappears, because the mind can live only in the past and through the past, or in the future and through the future.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
8 October 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, viryo means life, energy – divine life energy. The divine is the hidden part of reality... the inner part of reality. The outer is visible; the inner is invisible. The outer is available through the senses; the inner is available only through consciousness. So those who depend only on the outer senses see reality on the circumference.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_tonguetip_taste_of_tao/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
9 October 1978 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, shravano means listening – the art of divine listening. And that’s what meditation is. If one can learn how to listen rightly, one has learned the deepest secret of meditation. People hear but they don’t listen. Hearing is one thing – listening, altogether different; they are worlds apart. Hearing is a physical phenomenon; you hear because you have ears.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
