<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Meditation: The First and Last Freedom on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Meditation: The First and Last Freedom on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A meditation for the jet set</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part82/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part82/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
A meditation for the jet set ‌
You cannot find a better situation in which to meditate than while flying at a high altitude. The higher the altitude, the easier is the meditation. Hence, for centuries, meditators have been moving to the Himalayas to find a high altitude.
When gravitation is less and the earth is very far away, many pulls of the earth are far away.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Abdullah</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part65/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part65/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Abdullah ‌
One Sufi mystic who had remained happy his whole life—no one had ever seen him unhappy—he was always laughing. He was laughter, his whole being was a perfume of celebration. In his old age, when he was dying—he was on his deathbed, and still enjoying death, laughing hilariously—a disciple asked, “You puzzle us. Now you are dying. Why are you laughing?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Abiding joy for no reason at all</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Abiding joy for no reason at all ‌
For no reason at all you suddenly feel yourself joyous. In ordinary life, if there is some reason, you are joyful. You have met a beautiful woman and you are joyous, or you have got the money that you always wanted and you are joyous, or you have purchased the house with a beautiful garden and you are joyous, but these joys cannot last long.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About the Author</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part119/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part119/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
About the Author
The Osho teachings defy categorization, covering everything from the individual quest for meaning to the most urgent social and political issues facing society today. His books are not written but are transcribed from audio and video recordings of extemporaneous talks given to international audiences over a period of 35 years. Osho has been described by the Sunday Times in London as one of the “1000 Makers of the 20thCentury” and by American author Tom Robbins as “the most dangerous man since Jesus Christ.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>All paths merge on the mountain</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part113/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part113/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
All paths merge on the mountain‌
Is awareness a higher value than love?
The highest peak is the culmination of all values: truth, love, awareness, authenticity, totality. At the highest peak they are indivisible. They are separate only in the dark valleys of our unconsciousness. They are separate only when they are polluted, mixed with other things. The moment they become pure they become one; the more pure, the closer they come to each other.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aloneness: your self-nature</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Aloneness: your self-nature ‌
Aloneness is a flower, a lotus blooming in your heart. Aloneness is positive, aloneness is health. It is the joy of being yourself. It is the joy of having your own space.
Meditation means: bliss in being alone…. One is really alive when one has become capable of it, when there is no dependence any more on anybody, on any situation, on any condition.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Energy Phenomenon</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part46/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part46/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
An Energy Phenomenon ‌
Meditation is an energy phenomenon. One very basic thing has to be understood about all types of energies, and this is the basic law to be understood: energy moves in a dual polarity. That is the only way it moves; there is no other way for its movement. It moves in a dual polarity.
For any energy to become dynamic, the anti-pole is needed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anything Can Be a Meditation</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part52/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part52/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Anything Can Be a Meditation ‌
This is the secret: de-automatize. If we can de-automatize our activities, then the whole life becomes a meditation. Then any small thing, taking a shower, eating your food, talking to your friend, becomes meditation.
Meditation is a quality; it can be brought to anything. It is not a specific act. People think that way, they think meditation is a specific act—when you sit facing to the east, you repeat certain mantras, you burn some incense, you do this and that at a particular time in a particular way with a particular gesture.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Appreciate unawareness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part38/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part38/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Appreciate unawareness ‌
While aware enjoy awareness, and while unaware enjoy unawareness. Nothing is wrong, because unawareness is like a rest. Otherwise awareness would become a tension. If you are awake twenty-four hours, how many days do you think you can be alive? Without food a man can live for three months; without sleep, within three weeks he will go mad, and he will try to commit suicide.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atisha&#39;s Heart Meditation</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part63/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part63/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
Atisha’s Heart Meditation‌
Atisha said:
Train in joining, sending and taking together. Do this by riding the breath.
Atisha says: start being compassionate. And the method is, when you breathe in—listen carefully, it is one of the greatest methods—when you breathe in, think that you are breathing in all the miseries of all the people in the world. All the darkness, all the negativity, all the hell that exists anywhere, you are breathing it in.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aum</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part76/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part76/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Aum ‌
AUM is one of the basic sounds. A-U-M: these three sounds are combined in it. A-U-M are three basic sounds. All sounds are made of them or derived from them; all sounds are combinations of these three sounds. So these three are basic. They are as basic as the claim of physics that the electron, neutron and proton are basic. This has to be deeply understood.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Be comfortable</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part31/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Be comfortable ‌
A posture should be such that you can forget your body. What is comfort?
When you forget your body, you are comfortable. When you are reminded continuously of the body, you are uncomfortable. So whether you sit in a chair or you sit on the ground, that is not the point. Be comfortable, because if you are not comfortable in the body you cannot long for other blessings which belong to deeper layers: the first layer missed, all other layers closed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Be patient</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part36/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part36/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Be patient ‌
Don’t be in a hurry. So often, hurrying causes delay. As you thirst, wait patiently—the deeper the waiting, the sooner it comes.
You have sown the seed, now sit in the shade and watch what happens. The seed will break, it will blossom, but you cannot speed the process. Doesn’t everything need time? Work you must, but leave the results to God.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Be playful</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part35/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part35/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Be playful ‌
Millions of people miss meditation because meditation has taken on a wrong connotation. It looks very serious, looks gloomy, has something of the church in it; it looks as if it is only for people who are dead, or almost dead—those who are gloomy, serious, have long faces, who have lost festivity, fun, playfulness, celebration….
These are the qualities of meditation: a really meditative person is playful; life is fun for him, life is a leela, a play.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Begin with catharsis</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part32/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part32/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Begin with catharsis ‌
I never tell people to begin with just sitting. Begin from where beginning is easy. Otherwise, you will begin to feel many things unnecessarily—things that are not there.
If you begin with sitting, you will feel much disturbance inside. The more you try to just sit, the more disturbance will be felt. You will become aware only of your insane mind and nothing else.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Begin with effort</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Begin with effort ‌
Meditation techniques are doings, because you are advised to do something
—even to meditate is to do something; even to sit silently is to do something, even to not do anything is a sort of doing. So in a superficial way, all meditation techniques are doings. But in a deeper way they are not, because if you succeed in them, the doing disappears.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breath---a Bridge to Meditation</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part57/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part57/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Breath—a Bridge to Meditation ‌
If you can do something with the breath, you will suddenly turn to the present.
If you can do something with breath, you will attain to the source of life. If you can do something with breath, you can transcend time and space. If you can do something with breath, you will be in the world and also beyond it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Celebrating consciousness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part114/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part114/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
Celebrating consciousness‌
After working with the cathartic techniques for a few years, I feel that a deep inner harmony, balance and centering is happening to me. But you said that before entering into the final stage of samadhi, one passes through a great chaos. How do I know if I am finished with the chaotic stage?
First, for hundreds of lives you have lived in a chaos.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Center of the cyclone</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part67/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part67/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Center of the cyclone ‌
When desire grips you, you are disturbed. Of course, that is natural. Desire grips you, then your mind starts wavering and many ripples go on, on the surface. The desire pulls you somewhere into the future; the past pushes you somewhere into the future. You are disturbed: you are not at ease. Desire is, therefore, a ‘dis-ease.’</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Compassion</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Compassion ‌
Buddha has defined compassion as ‘love plus meditation.’ When your love is not just a desire for the other, when your love is not only a need, when your love is a sharing, when your love is not that of a beggar but that of an emperor, when your love is not asking for something in return but is ready only to give—to give for the sheer joy of giving—then add meditation to it and the pure fragrance is released, the imprisoned splendor is released.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Count the moments of awareness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part115/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part115/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
Count the moments of awareness‌
You tell us to be aware of everything—which means to be a witness to everything, every act. When I decide to be aware in work, I forget about awareness, and when I become aware that I was not aware, I feel guilty; I feel that I have made a mistake. Could you please explain?
It is one of the basic problems for anybody who is trying to be aware while at work—because work demands that you should forget yourself completely.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cover Page</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌[A PRACTICAL GUIDE TO OSHO MEDITATIONS]{.s1 style=” background-color: #034D97;“}
&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devavani</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part77/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part77/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Devavani ‌
Every night before you go to sleep, you can do a small technique that will help tremendously. Put the lights out, sit in your bed ready to sleep, but sit for fifteen minutes. Close your eyes and then start any monotonous nonsense sound, for example: la, la, la—and wait for the mind to supply new sounds. The only thing to be remembered is that those sounds or words should not be of any language that you know.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t be fooled by experiences</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part104/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part104/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
Don’t be fooled by experiences‌
All experiences are just tricks of the mind, all experiences are just escapes.
Meditation is not an experience, it is a realization. Meditation is not an experience; rather, it is a stopping of all experience. §
Experience is something outside you. The experiencer is your being. And this is the distinction between true spirituality and false: if you are after experiences, the spirituality is false; if you are after the experiencer, then it is true.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t look for results</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part37/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part37/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Don’t look for results ‌
The ego is result-oriented, the mind always hankers for results. The mind is never interested in the act itself, its interest is in the result. “What am I going to gain out of it?” If the mind can manage to gain without going through any action, then it will choose the short-cut.
That’s why educated people become very cunning, because they are able to find short-cuts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enough space</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part29/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Enough space ‌
When you are trying to meditate, put the phone off the hook, disengage yourself. Put a notice on the door that for one hour nobody should knock, that you are meditating. And when you move into the meditation room take your shoes off, because you are walking on sacred ground. Not only take your shoes off, but everything that you are preoccupied with.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enter the clear sky</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part80/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part80/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Enter the clear sky ‌
Meditate on the sky: a summer sky with no clouds, endlessly empty and clear, nothing moving in it, in its total virginity. Contemplate on it, meditate on it, and enter this clarity. Become this clarity, this space-like clarity.
To meditate on the sky is beautiful. Just lie down so you forget the earth; just lie down on your back on any lonely beach, on any ground, and just look at the sky.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>False methods</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part100/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part100/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
False methods ‌
Meditation is not concentrationMeditation is not introspection
&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finding the real source</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part66/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part66/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Finding the real source ‌
When you see a friend and suddenly feel a joy rising in your heart,
concentrate on this joy. Feel it and become it, and meet the friend while being aware and filled with your joy. Let the friend be just on the periphery, and you remain centered in your feeling of happiness.
This can be done in many other situations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finding the Space Within</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part79/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part79/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Finding the Space Within ‌
Emptiness is your innermost center. All activity is on the periphery: the innermost center is just a zero.
Enter the clear skyInclude EverythingA meditation for the jet set
&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finding the Witness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part86/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part86/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Finding the Witness ‌
This was the technique given to Pythagoras. Pythagoras went with this technique to Greece. And, really, he became the fountainhead, the source, of all mysticism in the West. He is the father of all mysticism in the West.
This technique is one of the very deep methods. Try to understand it.
Modern physiology, scientific research, says that between the two eyebrows is the gland which is the most mysterious part in the body.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First understand the technique</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
First understand the technique ‌
I have heard a story about an old doctor. One day his assistant phoned him because he was in very great difficulty: his patient was choking to death; a billiard ball was stuck in his throat, and the assistant was at a loss for what to do. So he asked the old doctor, “What am I supposed to do now?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Foreword</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Foreword ‌
Meditation is a science, not a superstition. Meditation says that if you experiment with your mind—it is too full of thoughts—thoughts can be dispersed. The clouds can be dispersed and you can attain to an empty sky of your inner being. And it needs just a little courage, a little effort, a little daring, a little persistence and perseverance. A little patience, yes, but no trust—you don’t believe in God?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From head to heart</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part61/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part61/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
From head to heart ‌
The first point: try to be headless. Visualize yourself as headless; move headlessly. It sounds absurd, but it is one of the most important exercises. Try it, and then you will know. Walk, and feel as if you have no head. In the beginning it will be only ’as if.’It will be very weird. When the feeling comes to you that you have no head, it will be very weird and strange.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gibberish Meditation</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part55/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part55/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Gibberish Meditation ‌
This is a cathartic technique, which encourages expressive body movements.
It should be distinguished from the gentle Devavani Meditation.
Instructions
First stage: 15 minutes
Either alone or in a group, close your eyes and begin to say nonsense sounds
—gibberish. Allow yourself to express whatever needs to be expressed within you.
Throw everything out. The mind always thinks in terms of words.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Golden Light meditation</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part71/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part71/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Golden Light meditation ‌
Do this at least twice a day—the best time is early in the morning, just before you get out of bed. The moment you feel you are alert, awake, do it for twenty minutes. Do it first thing in the morning!—don’t get out of bed. Do it there, then and there, immediately!—because when you are coming out of sleep you are very, very delicate, receptive.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Growing in sensitivity</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Growing in sensitivity ‌
Meditation will bring you sensitivity, a great sense of belonging to the world.
It is our world—the stars are ours, and we are not foreigners here. We belong intrinsically to existence. We are part of it, we are the heart of it.
You become so sensitive that even the smallest blade of grass takes on an immense importance for you.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guidelines to Freedom</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part33/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part33/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Guidelines to Freedom ‌
The three essentialsBe playfulBe patientDon’t look for resultsAppreciate unawarenessMachines help, but don’t create meditationYou are not your experiences
&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heart of light</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part72/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part72/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Heart of light ‌
While waking, moving, eating, working, remember yourself as light, as if in your heart a flame is burning, and your body is nothing but the aura around the flame. Imagine it: in your heart a flame is burning, and your body is nothing but a light aura around the flame; your body is just a light around the flame.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Include Everything</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part81/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part81/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Include Everything ‌
This technique is a little difficult, but if you can do it, then it is very wonderful, beautiful. Sitting, don’t divide. Sitting in meditation, be inclusive of all—your body, your mind, your breath, your thinking, your knowing, everything. Be inclusive of all. Don’t divide, don’t create any fragmentation.
Ordinarily we are fragmenting; we go on fragmenting. We say, “The body is not me.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inner Centering</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part64/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part64/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Inner Centering ‌
Nobody can exist without a center…. It has not to be created but only rediscovered. Essence is the center, that which is your nature, that which is God-given. Personality is the circumference, that which is cultivated by society; it is not God-given. It is by nurture, not by nature.
AbdullahFinding the real sourceCenter of the cycloneWho am I?OSHO WHIRLING MEDITATION</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inner darkness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part74/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part74/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
Inner darkness‌
How can you enter blackness? Three things.
Step 1:
Stare into blackness. Difficult. It is easy to stare at a flame, at any source of light, because it is there as an object, pointed; you can direct your attention to it. Darkness is not an object; it is everywhere, it is all around. You cannot see it as an object. Stare into the vacuum.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intelligence: the ability to respond</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Intelligence: the ability to respond ‌
Intelligence simply means ability to respond, because life is a flux. You have to be aware and to see what is demanded of you, what is the challenge of the situation. The intelligent person behaves according to the situation and the stupid behaves according to the ready-made answers. Whether they come from Buddha, Christ or Krishna, it does not matter.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Introduction ‌
Just as the science and technology that has transformed our outer lives has been largely a Western phenomenon, so the East has provided the main source of the science that can transform our inner lives. Today, just like the light bulb, meditation is a universal phenomenon—one helps illuminate our outer world, the other our inner world.
But in the process of becoming universal, many misconceptions about meditation have arisen: that it is “religious,” that it is about sitting in difficult postures, perhaps with your ankle round your neck and a holy look on your face to hide the discomfort; maybe even humming, or chanting some esoteric- sounding mantra.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Just a 180° turn</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part112/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part112/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
Just a 180° turn‌
Two Polacks were driving along in the front seat of their car. As they approached a corner, the one who was driving said to his friend, “Will you look out of the window and see if the indicator, the turn signal, is working?”
He promptly leaned out of the window and looked at the indicator light and shouted back at his friend, “Yes it is—no it’s not, yes it is—no it’s not, yes it is— no it’s not.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Just Sitting</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part88/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part88/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Just Sitting ‌
You are simply sitting there, doing nothing … and all is silence and all is peace and all is bliss. You have entered godliness, you have entered truth.
—Osho
Zazen
&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Laughing Meditation</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part54/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part54/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Laughing Meditation ‌
Laughter brings some energy from your inner source to your surface. Energy starts flowing, follows laughter like a shadow. Have you watched it? When you really laugh, for those few moments you are in a deep meditative state. Thinking stops. It is impossible to laugh and think together. They are diametrically opposite: either you can laugh or you can think.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Love, the fragrance of meditation</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Love, the fragrance of meditation ‌
If you meditate, sooner or later you will come upon love. If you meditate deeply, sooner or later you will start feeling a tremendous love arising in you that you have never known before—a new quality to your being, a new door opening. You have become a new flame and now you want to share.
If you love deeply, by and by you will become aware that your love is becoming more and more meditative.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machines help, but don&#39;t create meditation</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part39/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part39/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Machines help, but don’t create meditation ‌
So many machines are being developed around the world, pretending that they can give you meditation; you just have to put on earphones and relax, and within ten minutes you will reach the state of meditation.
This is utter stupidity, but there is a reason why such an idea has come to the minds of technical people.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Make things as simple as possible</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part116/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part116/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
Make things as simple as possible‌
How can I tell the difference between one part of the mind watching another part of the mind, and the watcher. Can the watcher watch itself? One time, I thought I had got it, and then that same day I heard you, “If you think you’ve got the watcher, you’ve missed.” Since then, I’ve tried watching feelings in the body, thoughts and emotions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MEDICAL DISCLAIMER</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
MEDICAL DISCLAIMER ‌
Advice or teachings given in this book are not intended to replace the services of a physician, therapist, or psychiatrist. Nor is the book meant to provide an alternative to professional medical treatment. This book offers no medical diagnosis of, or treatment for, any specific medical or psychological problems you may have. Some of the meditations include strenuous physical activity—if you have any reason to be concerned about the effects of such activity on your health, you should consult your physician before trying these meditations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meditation is a knack</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part41/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part41/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Meditation is a knack ‌
Meditation is such a mystery that it can be called a science, an art, a knack, without any contradiction.
From one point of view it is a science because there is a clear-cut technique that has to be done. There are no exceptions to it, it is almost like a scientific law.
But from a different point of view it can also be said to be an art.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meditation is not concentration</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part101/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part101/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
Meditation is not concentration‌
Meditations can be wrong. For example, any meditation that leads you deep into concentration is wrong. You will become more and more closed rather than becoming open. If you narrow down your consciousness, concentrate on something, and you exclude the whole of existence and become one-pointed, it will create more and more tension in you. Hence the word ‘attention.’ It means ‘at-tension.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meditation is not introspection</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part102/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part102/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
Meditation is not introspection‌
Introspection is thinking about yourself. Self-remembering is not thinking at all: it is becoming aware of yourself. The difference is subtle, but very great.
Western psychology insists on introspection, and Eastern psychology insists on self-remembering. When you introspect, what do you do? For example, you are angry: you start thinking about anger, how it is caused. You start analyzing why it is caused.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meditations in Sound</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part75/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part75/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Meditations in Sound ‌
The meditations concerned with ear energy are feminine meditations, passive—you have just to listen, not to do anything. Listening to the birds, the wind passing through the pine trees, or to some music, or to the noise of the traffic—just listening, doing nothing—great silence comes in, and great peace starts falling and showering on you. It is easier through the ear than through the eye.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meditations on Darkness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part73/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part73/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Meditations on Darkness ‌
Just like the seed that starts its life in the darkness of the soil, or the child that starts its life in the darkness of the womb, all beginnings are in the dark, because darkness is one of the most essential things for anything to begin.
The beginning is mysterious, hence darkness is needed. And the beginning is so delicate, that’s also why darkness is needed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meditations on Light</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part70/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part70/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Meditations on Light ‌
In your heart a flame is burning, and your body is just a light aura around the flame.
Golden Light meditationHeart of light
&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Methods and Meditations</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Methods and Meditations ‌
Techniques are helpful because they are scientific. You are saved from unnecessary wandering, unnecessary groping; if you don’t know any techniques, you will take a long time.
Techniques are helpfulBegin with effortThese methods are simpleFirst understand the techniqueThe right method will clickWhen to drop the method
&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mind can deceive you</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part106/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part106/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
Mind can deceive you‌
There are patterns the seeker gets entangled with.
The first thing is: most seekers get lost in an illusory feeling that they have arrived. It is like the kind of dream in which you feel you are awake. You are still dreaming—your feeling of being awake is part of the dream. The same kind of thing happens to the seeker.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mind can enter again</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part105/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part105/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
Mind can enter again‌
In meditation sometimes you feel a sort of emptiness that is not really emptiness. I call it just “a sort of emptiness.” When you are meditating, for certain moments, for a few seconds, you will feel as if the thought process has stopped. In the beginning these gaps will come. But because you are feeling as if the thought process has stopped, this is again a thought process, a very subtle thought process.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Only a witness can really dance</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part108/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part108/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
Only a witness can really dance‌
You continually encourage us to “be aware,” to “be a witness.” But can a witnessing consciousness really sing, dance and taste life? Isn’t a “witness” a mere spectator of life and never a participant?
Mind is bound to raise this question sooner or later, because mind is very much afraid of you becoming a witness. Why is the mind so much afraid of you becoming a witness?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Opening the Heart</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part60/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part60/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Opening the Heart ‌
The heart is the gateless gate to reality. Move from the head to the heart. We are all hung up in the head. That is our only problem, the only one problem. And there is only one solution: get down from the head into the heart and all problems disappear. They are created by the head. And suddenly everything is so clear and so transparent that one is surprised how one was continuously inventing problems.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OSHO BORN AGAIN</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part94/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part94/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
OSHO BORN AGAIN‌
Remember this: regain your childhood. Everyone longs for it, but no one is doing anything to regain it. Everyone longs for it! People go on saying that childhood was paradise and poets go on writing poems about the beauty of childhood. Who is preventing you? Regain it! I give you this opportunity to regain it.
Be playful. It will be difficult, because you are so much structured.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OSHO DYNAMIC MEDITATION: Catharsis and Celebration</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part47/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part47/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
OSHO DYNAMIC MEDITATION: Catharsis and Celebration‌
“When the sleep is broken the whole of nature becomes alive. The night has gone, the darkness is no more, the sun is coming up, and everything becomes conscious and alert. So this first meditation is a meditation in which you have to be continuously alert, conscious, aware, whatsoever you do.
“Remain a witness. Don’t get lost. It is easy to get lost.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OSHO GOURISHANKAR MEDITATION</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part84/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part84/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
OSHO GOURISHANKAR MEDITATION‌
This technique consists of four stages of 15 minutes each. The first two stages prepare the meditator for the spontaneous Latihan of the third stage. Osho has said that if the breathing is done correctly in the first stage, the carbon dioxide formed in the bloodstream will make you feel as high as Gourishankar (Mt. Everest). NOTE: Those with a history of neurological disorders such as epilepsy should never use a strobe or flashing light for this meditation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OSHO KUNDALINI MEDITATION</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part49/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part49/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
OSHO KUNDALINI MEDITATION‌
This is the much-loved sister meditation of the Osho Dynamic Meditation. It consists of four stages of 15 minutes each.
First stage: 15 minutes
Be loose and let your whole body shake, feeling the energies moving up from your feet. Let go everywhere and become the shaking. Your eyes may be opened or closed.
Second stage: 15 minutes
Dance … any way you feel, and let the whole body move as it wishes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OSHO MANDALA MEDITATION</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part85/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part85/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
OSHO MANDALA MEDITATION‌
This is another powerful, cathartic technique that creates a circle of energy that results in a natural centering. There are four stages of 15 minutes each.
First stage: 15 minutes
With open eyes run on the spot, starting slowly and gradually, getting faster and faster. Bring your knees up as high as possible. Breathing deeply and evenly will move the energy within.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OSHO MEDITATIVE THERAPIES</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part91/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part91/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
OSHO MEDITATIVE THERAPIES ‌
The ancient methods of meditation were all developed in the East. They never considered the Western man…. I am creating techniques which are not only for the Eastern man, but which are simply for every man— Eastern or Western.
—Osho
Osho has created a series of “meditative therapies”—The Mystic Rose, No- Mind, and Born Again. Uniquely simple and effective, they involve a minimum of interaction among the participants, but the energy of the group helps each individual go more deeply into his or her own process.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OSHO NADABRAHMA MEDITATION</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part51/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part51/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
OSHO NADABRAHMA MEDITATION‌
Nadabrahma is based on Tibetan techniques done in the early hours of the morning. It can be done at any time of the day, alone or with others, but have an empty stomach and remain inactive for at least 15 minutes afterwards. The meditation lasts an hour, and there are three stages.
First stage: 30 minutes
Sit in a relaxed position with eyes closed and lips together.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OSHO NATARAJ MEDITATION</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part50/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part50/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
OSHO NATARAJ MEDITATION‌
Disappear in the dance
Forget the dancer, the center of the ego; become the dance. That is the meditation. Dance so deeply that you forget completely that ‘you’ are dancing and begin to feel that you are the dance. The division must disappear; then it becomes a meditation. If the division is there, then it is an exercise: good, healthy, but it cannot be said to be spiritual.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OSHO REMINDING YOURSELF OF THE FORGOTTEN LANGUAGE OF TALKING TO YOUR BODYMIND</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part95/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part95/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
OSHO REMINDING YOURSELF OF THE FORGOTTEN LANGUAGE OF TALKING TO YOUR BODYMIND‌
Once you start communicating with your body, things become very easy. The body need not be forced, it can be persuaded. One need not fight with the body—that’s ugly, violent, aggressive, and any sort of conflict is going to create more and more tension. So you need not be in any conflict—let comfort be the rule.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OSHO WHIRLING MEDITATION</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part69/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part69/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
OSHO WHIRLING MEDITATION‌
Sufi Whirling is one of the most ancient techniques, one of the most forceful. It is so deep that even a single experience can make you totally different. Whirl with open eyes, just like small children go on twirling, as if your inner being has become a center and your whole body has become a wheel, moving, a potter’s wheel, moving.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Part 1: ABOUT MEDITATION</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Part 1: ABOUT MEDITATION ‌
What is meditation?Witnessing, the spirit of meditationThe flowering of meditationThe great silenceGrowing in sensitivityLove, the fragrance of meditationCompassionAbiding joy for no reason at allIntelligence: the ability to respondAloneness: your self-natureYour real self
&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Part 2: THE SCIENCE OF MEDITATION</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Part 2: THE SCIENCE OF MEDITATION ‌
Methods and MeditationsTechniques are helpfulBegin with effortThese methods are simpleFirst understand the techniqueThe right method will clickWhen to drop the methodSuggestions for beginnersEnough spaceThe right placeBe comfortableBegin with catharsisGuidelines to FreedomThe three essentialsBe playfulBe patientDon’t look for resultsAppreciate unawarenessMachines help, but don’t create meditationYou are not your experiencesMeditation is a knack
&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Part 3: THE MEDITATIONS</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part42/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part42/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Part 3: THE MEDITATIONS ‌
THE OSHO ACTIVE MEDITATIONSWhy active meditation?Powerful Methods for AwakeningAn Energy PhenomenonOSHO DYNAMIC MEDITATION: Catharsis and CelebrationRemember, remain a witnessOSHO KUNDALINI MEDITATIONOSHO NATARAJ MEDITATIONOSHO NADABRAHMA MEDITATIONAnything Can Be a MeditationRunning, Jogging and SwimmingLaughing MeditationGibberish MeditationSmoking MeditationBreath—a Bridge to MeditationVipassanaThrowing things outOpening the HeartFrom head to heartThe heart of peacefulnessAtisha’s Heart MeditationInner CenteringAbdullahFinding the real sourceCenter of the cycloneWho am I?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Part 4: OBSTACLES TO MEDITATION</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part96/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part96/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Part 4: OBSTACLES TO MEDITATION ‌
The two difficultiesThe egoThe chattering mindFalse methodsMeditation is not concentrationMeditation is not introspectionTricks of the mindDon’t be fooled by experiencesMind can enter againMind can deceive you
&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Part 5: RESPONSES TO QUESTIONS ABOUT MEDITATION</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part107/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part107/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Part 5: RESPONSES TO QUESTIONS ABOUT MEDITATION ‌
Only a witness can really danceThe goose has never been inThe watcher on the hillWhere did you leave your bicycle?Just a 180° turnAll paths merge on the mountainCelebrating consciousnessCount the moments of awarenessMake things as simple as possibleWitnessing is like sowing seedsWitnessing is enough
&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Powerful Methods for Awakening</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part45/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part45/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Powerful Methods for Awakening ‌
These are not really meditations. You are just getting in tune. If you have seen Indian classical musicians playing you will notice that for half an hour, or sometimes even more, they simply go on adjusting their instruments. They will move the knobs, they will make the strings tight or loose, and the drum player will go on checking his drum, whether it is perfect or not.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remember, remain a witness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part48/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part48/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
Remember, remain a witness‌
This is a meditation in which you have to be continuously alert, conscious, aware, whatsoever you do. The first step, breathing; the second step, catharsis; the third step, the mantra, the mahamantra ‘hoo’. Remain a witness. Don’t get lost.
It is easy to get lost. While you are breathing you can forget. You can become one with the breathing so much that you can forget the witness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Running, Jogging and Swimming</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part53/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part53/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Running, Jogging and Swimming ‌
It is natural and easy to keep alert while you are in movement. When you are just sitting silently, the natural thing is to just fall asleep. When you are lying on your bed it is very difficult to keep alert because the whole situation helps you to fall asleep. But in movement naturally you cannot fall asleep, you function in a more alert way.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Smoking Meditation</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part56/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part56/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Smoking Meditation ‌
A man came to me. He had been suffering from chain-smoking for thirty years; he was ill and the doctors said, “You will never be healthy if you don’t stop smoking.” But he was a chronic smoker; he could not help it. He had tried
—not that he had not tried—he had tried hard, and he had suffered much in trying, but only for one day or two days, and then again the urge would come so tremendously, it would simply take him away.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Suggestions for beginners</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part28/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Suggestions for beginners ‌
Enough spaceThe right placeBe comfortableBegin with catharsis
&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Table of Contents</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌TABLE OF CONTENTS‌
Title Page Copyright Foreword
MEDICAL DISCLAIMER
‌
Introduction ‌
Part 1: ABOUT MEDITATION ‌
What is meditation? Witnessing, the spirit of meditation
‌
The flowering of meditation The great silence Growing in sensitivity‌
Love, the fragrance of meditation Compassion‌
Abiding joy for no reason at all Intelligence: the ability to respond‌
‌
Aloneness: your self-nature Your real self
‌
Part 2: THE SCIENCE OF MEDITATION Methods and Meditations Techniques are helpful Begin with effort‌‌</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Techniques are helpful</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Techniques are helpful ‌
With a master, with scientific techniques, you can save much time, opportunity and energy. And sometimes within seconds you can grow so much that even within lives you would not have been able to grow that much. If a right technique is used, growth explodes. And these techniques have been used in thousands of years of experiments. They were not devised by one man; they were devised by many, many seekers, and only the essence is given here.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The center of sound</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part78/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part78/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
The center of sound ‌
This technique can be done in many ways. One way is to begin by just sitting anywhere. Sounds are always present. It may be in a market or it may be at a Himalayan retreat: sounds are there. Sit silently, and with sound there is something very special. Whenever there are sounds, you are the center. All the</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The chattering mind</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part99/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part99/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
The chattering mind‌
You cannot sit even for a single minute, the mind goes on chattering: relevant, irrelevant, meaningful, meaningless thoughts go on. It is a constant traffic and it is always rush hour. You see a flower and you verbalize it; you see a man crossing the street and you verbalize it. The mind can translate every existential thing into a word, everything is being transformed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The ego</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part98/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part98/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
The ego‌
The whole idea of modern psychology, modern education, is that unless a person has a very strong ego he will not be able to struggle in life where there is so much competition that, if you are a humble man, anybody will push you aside; you will always remain backward. You need a very steely, strong ego to fight in this competitive world; then only can you become a success.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The flowering of meditation</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
The flowering of meditation ‌
Meditation is not an Indian method; it is not simply a technique. You cannot learn it. It is a growth: a growth of your total living, out of your total living. Meditation is not something that can be added to you as you are. It cannot be added to you; it can only come to you through a basic transformation, a mutation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The goose has never been in</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part109/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part109/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
The goose has never been in‌
Sometimes, when dark sides of my mind come up, it really scares me. It is very difficult for me to accept that it is just the polar opposite of the bright ones, I feel dirty and guilty and unworthy. I want to face all facets of my mind and accept them because I hear you often say that acceptance is the condition to transcend the mind.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The great silence</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
The great silence ‌
Silence usually is understood to be something negative, something empty, an absence of sound, of noises. This misunderstanding is prevalent because very few people have ever experienced silence.
All that they have experienced in the name of silence is noiselessness. But silence is a totally different phenomenon. It is utterly positive. It is existential, it is not empty. It is overflowing with a music that you have never heard before, with a fragrance that is unfamiliar to you, with a light that can only be seen by the inner eyes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The heart of peacefulness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part62/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part62/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
The heart of peacefulness ‌
A very simple method but it works miraculously—try it. And anyone can try it, there is no danger. In an easy position: the first thing is to be in a relaxed position—easy, whatsoever is easy for you. So don’t try some particular position or asana. Buddha sits in a particular posture. It is easy for him. It can also become easy for you if you practice it for a time, but in the very beginning it will not be easy for you.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE OSHO ACTIVE MEDITATIONS</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part43/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part43/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
THE OSHO ACTIVE MEDITATIONS ‌
All OSHO Active Meditations involve a beginning stage of activity? sometimes intense and physical*—followed by a period of silence. All are accompanied by music that has been specially composed to guide the meditator through the different stages. Different meditations are recommended for different times of the day.
A complete list of available music CD’s for different OSHO ACTIVE MEDITATIONS can be found in the back of this book.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The OSHO MYSTIC ROSE MEDITATION</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part92/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part92/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
The OSHO MYSTIC ROSE MEDITATION‌
The symbol of the mystic rose is that if a man takes care of the seed he is born with, gives it the right soil, gives it the right atmosphere and the right vibrations, moves on a right path where the seed can start growing, then the ultimate growth is symbolized as the mystic rose—when your being blossoms and opens all its petals and releases its beautiful fragrance.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The OSHO NO-MIND MEDITATION</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part93/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part93/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
The OSHO NO-MIND MEDITATION‌
No-mind means intelligence. And when I am asking you to do gibberish, I am simply asking you to throw out the mind and all its activity so you remain behind—pure, clean, transparent, perceptive.
—Osho
I am introducing you to a new meditation. It is divided in three parts.
The first part is gibberish. The word ‘gibberish’ comes from a Sufi mystic, Jabbar.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The right method will click</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
The right method will click ‌
Really, when you try the right method it clicks immediately. So I will go on talking about methods here every day. You try them. Just play with them: go home and try. The right method, whenever you happen upon it, just clicks.
Something explodes in you, and you know that “This is the right method for me.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The right place</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part30/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
The right place ‌
You should find a place which enhances meditation. For example, sitting under a tree will help. Rather than going and sitting in front of a movie house or going to the railway station and sitting on the platform, go to nature, to the mountains, to the trees, to the rivers where tao is still flowing, vibrating, pulsating, streaming all around.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The three essentials</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part34/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part34/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
The three essentials ‌
Meditation has a few essential things in it, whatever the method, but those few essentials are necessary in every method. The first is a relaxed state: no fight with the mind, no control of the mind, no concentration. Second, just watch with a relaxed awareness whatever is going on, without any interference—just watching the mind, silently, without any judgment, evaluation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The two difficulties</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part97/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part97/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
The two difficulties ‌
There are only two difficulties on the path of meditation: one is the ego. You are continuously prepared by the society, by the family, by the school, by the church, by everybody around you, to be egoistic. Even modern psychology is based on strengthening the ego.
The egoThe chattering mind
&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The watcher on the hill</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part110/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part110/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
The watcher on the hill‌
I seem to be neither totally “in the world,” nor the “watcher on the hill.” How to be someplace? I feel like I am in between everything I do.
Then that is exactly the place you should be.
You go on creating problems. Wherever you are, be there. There is no need to be a watcher on the hills.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>These methods are simple</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
These methods are simple ‌
Each of these methods which we will be discussing has been told by someone who has achieved. Remember this. They will look too simple, and they
are. To our minds, things which are so simple cannot be appealing. Because if techniques are so simple and the abode is so near, if you are already in it, and the home is so near, you will look ridiculous to yourself—then why are you missing it?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Throwing things out</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part59/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part59/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Throwing things out ‌
Whenever you feel that the mind is not tranquil—tense, worried, chattering, anxious, constantly dreaming—do one thing: first exhale deeply. Always start by exhaling. Exhale deeply; as much as you can, throw the air out. Throwing out the air, the mood will be thrown out too, because breathing is everything. And then expel the breath as far as possible. Pull the belly in and retain for a few seconds; don’t inhale.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Title Page</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌Meditation‌ THE FIRST and LAST FREEDOM
A practical guide to OSHO meditations
OSHO
&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Touching as a Feather</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part87/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part87/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Touching as a Feather ‌
Use both your palms, put them on your closed eyes, and allow the palms to touch the eyeballs—but just like a feather, with no pressure. If you press you miss the point, you miss the whole technique. Don’t press; just touch like a feather. You will have to adjust, because in the beginning you will be pressing. Put less and less pressure until you are just touching with no pressure at all—just your palms touch the eyeballs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tricks of the mind</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part103/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part103/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Tricks of the mind ‌
Don’t be fooled by experiencesMind can enter againMind can deceive you
&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vipassana</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part58/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part58/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Vipassana ‌
Vipassana is the meditation that has made more people in the world enlightened than any other, because it is the very essence. All other meditations have the same essence, but in different forms; something non-essential is also joined with them. But vipassana is pure essence. You cannot drop anything out of it and you cannot add anything to improve it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Watching with the Third Eye</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part83/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part83/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Watching with the Third Eye ‌
It is one of the contributions of the East to the world: the understanding that between these two eyes, there is a third eye inside which normally remains dormant.
One has to work hard, bring his whole sexual energy upward, against gravitation, and when the energy reaches the third eye, it opens. Many methods have been tried to do that, because when it opens there is suddenly a flash of light, and things which have never been clear to you suddenly become clear.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is meditation?</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
What is meditation? ‌
Meditation is an adventure, adventure into the unknown, the greatest adventure the human mind can take.
Meditation is just to be, not doing anything—no action, no thought, no emotion. You just are and it is a sheer delight. From where does this delight come when you are not doing anything? It comes from nowhere, or it comes from everywhere.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When to drop the method</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
When to drop the method ‌
All the great masters say this, that one day you have to drop the method. And the sooner you drop it, the better. The moment you attain, the moment awareness is released in you, immediately drop the method.
Buddha used to tell a story again and again. Five idiots passed through a village. Seeing them, people were surprised, because they were carrying a boat on their heads.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where did you leave your bicycle?</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part111/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part111/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
Where did you leave your bicycle?‌
During the meditations, my mind still goes five hundred miles per hour. I never experience silence, and whatever witnessing happens is very short, like flashes. Am I wasting my time?
Your mind is mighty slow. Five hundred miles per hour, only?! And do you think this is speed? You are mighty slow. Mind goes so fast it knows no speed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who am I?</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part68/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part68/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Who am I? ‌
Gurdjieff tried from one angle. He said, just try to remember you are.
Ramana Maharshi tried from another angle. He made it a meditation to ask, to inquire, “Who am I?” And don’t believe in any answers that the mind can supply. The mind will say, “What nonsense are you asking? You are this, you are that, you are a man, you are a woman, you are educated or uneducated, rich or poor.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why active meditation?</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part44/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part44/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Why active meditation? ‌
If you can sit, there is no need for meditations. In Japan, for meditation they have the word “Zazen”. It means just sitting, doing nothing. If you can sit, not doing anything, this is the ultimate in meditations. There is no need for any other thing.
But can you sit? There is the crux of the whole problem. Can you sit?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Witnessing is enough</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part118/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part118/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
Witnessing is enough‌
I have always heard You say, “Stop doing. Watch.” Several times lately I’ve heard You say that the mind should be the servant instead of our master. It feels that there is nothing to do except watch. But the question still arises: Is there anything to do with this unruly servant but to watch?
There is nothing else to do with this unruly servant, but just to watch.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Witnessing is like sowing seeds</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part117/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part117/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
Witnessing is like sowing seeds‌
How does watching lead to no-mind?I am more and more able to watch my body, my thoughts and feelings and this feels beautiful. But moments of no thoughts are few and far between. When I hear you saying “Meditation is witnessing,” I feel I understand. But when you talk about ‘no-mind,’ it doesn’t sound easy at all. Would you please comment?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Witnessing, the spirit of meditation</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
Witnessing, the spirit of meditation‌
When you are not doing anything at all—bodily, mentally, on no level— when all activity has ceased and you simply are, just being, that’s what meditation is. You cannot do it, you cannot practice it: you have only to understand it.
Whenever you can find time for just being, drop all doing. Thinking is also doing, concentration is also doing, contemplation is also doing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You are not your experiences</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part40/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part40/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
You are not your experiences ‌
One of the most fundamental things to remember is that whatever you come across in your inner journey, you are not it. You are the one who is witnessing it. It may be nothingness, it may be blissfulness, it may be silence…ut one thing
has to be remembered—however beautiful and however enchanting an experience you come to, you are not it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Your real self</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Your real self ‌
Meditation is nothing but a device to make you aware of your real self— which is not created by you, which need not be created by you, which you
already are. You are born with it. You are it! It needs to be discovered. If this is not possible, or if the society does not allow it to happen…and no society allows it to happen, because the real self is dangerous: dangerous for the established church, dangerous for the state, dangerous for the crowd, dangerous for the tradition, because once a man knows his real self, he becomes an individual.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zazen</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part89/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/meditation__the_first_and_last_freedom/part89/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌
Zazen ‌
The Zen people say just sit, don’t do anything. The most difficult thing in the world is just to sit doing nothing. But once you have got the knack of it, if you go on sitting for a few months doing nothing for a few hours every day, slowly, slowly many things will happen. You will feel sleepy, you will dream.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
