<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Osho Upanishad on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Osho Upanishad on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 The mystery school: an encounter with the miraculous</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
The mystery school: an encounter with the miraculous
16 August 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
COULD YOU PLEASE EXPLAIN EXACTLY WHAT THE WORK OF THE MYSTERY SCHOOL IS?
My beloved ones...
You are blessed to be here today, because we are starting a new series of talks between the master and the disciple.
It is not only a birth of a new book, it is also a declaration of a new phase.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Mind is friction, understanding is transcendence</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
Mind is friction, understanding is transcendence
25 August 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
BROADLY SPEAKING, AS I UNDERSTAND IT, THERE ARE TWO SETS OF RULES: ONE FOR THE OUTER WORLD – WHICH IS THE MAN-MADE WORLD CONCERNED WITH EARNING MONEY, REARING CHILDREN, DRIVING ON A CERTAIN SIDE OF THE ROAD – AND A DIFFERENT SET OF RULES FOR THE INNER WORLD; FOR EXAMPLE, HYPNOSIS, TELEPATHY, MIND-READING AND SO ON, AND FOR ATTAINING INNER GROWTH OF CONSCIOUSNESS, LEADING FINALLY TO SAMADHI, ENLIGHTENMENT, NIRVANA.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 From somebody to nobody\... a journey from fiction to reality</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
From somebody to nobody... a journey from fiction to reality
26 August 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
LATELY I FIND THAT I AM DESPERATELY TRYING TO FIND OR DO OR LEARN SOMETHING IN ORDER TO GIVE MYSELF AN IDENTITY, KNOWING PERFECTLY WELL THAT THIS IS A TRAP OF THE MIND.
WHY IS IT SO PAINFUL AND SHOCKING TO NOT HAVE ANY IDENTITY, TO BE NOBODY?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 To be an individual is the greatest courage</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
To be an individual is the greatest courage
30 August 1986 pm in
Question 1
BELOVED OSHO, WHY HAS LIFE ALL ALONG BEEN A VERY SERIOUS AFFAIR FOR ME, AND NOT FUN TO LIVE AND ENJOY AND CELEBRATE AS YOU SAY IT SHOULD BE?
Maitreya, you have been in the wrong hands from the very beginning of your life.
It will be difficult for others to understand the answer if I don’t tell you the background of the questioner.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 The Master\&#39;s art: expressing the inexpressible</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
The Master’s art: expressing the inexpressible
31 August 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
PLEASE THROW LIGHT ON THE DIFFERENCE BETWEEN A MYSTIC AND A MASTER.
There is an ancient Tibetan parable. It says, “When one hundred people try to reach the goal only ten ever start the journey; and out of the ten only one reaches the goal.” And those few people who reach the goal are not capable of being masters.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 Beyond science is knowing</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
Beyond science is knowing
1 September 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
THERE IS A STATEMENT BY J. KRISHNAMURTI THAT “THE OBSERVER IS THE OBSERVED.” WILL YOU PLEASE KINDLY ELABORATE AND EXPLAIN WHAT IT MEANS?
The statement that “the observer is the observed” is one of the most significant things ever said by any man on the earth. The statement is as extraordinary as J.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 The art of remembering who you are</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
The art of remembering who you are
2 September 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I SEE THE BEGINNING WITH YOU, BUT NOT THE END. PLEASE COMMENT.
There is no end to this pilgrimage, there is only the beginning. It is a very profound question.
Gautam Buddha is reported to have said “The world never begins, but it ends. Enlightenment begins, but it never ends.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 The truth is always individual</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
The truth is always individual
3 September 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
AS THE WORLD IS PROGRESSING ALONG A RATIONAL PATH, IN LESS THAN A HUNDRED YEARS HENCE, PEOPLE WILL BEGIN TO WONDER WHY YOU WERE NOT BEING HEARD AND ACCEPTED NOW. HAVING SUCCESSFULLY LAID DOWN THE FOUNDATIONS OF THE RELIGION OF THE FUTURE, HOW DOES IT FEEL TO BE PERSECUTED IN YOUR OWN TIME?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 Saying thank you to an empty room</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
Saying thank you to an empty room
4 September 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
ONCE AGAIN, I WAS SITTING IN HOLLAND MINDING MY OWN BUSINESS WHEN I HEARD YOU HAD LANDED IN BOMBAY. IT TOOK ME THREE DAYS TO DECIDE I HAD TO COME AND SEE YOU, BE WITH YOU, HANG OUT IN YOUR PRESENCE. CATCHING UP WITH YOU HAS BEEN QUITE AN ADVENTURE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 Don\&#39;t come down go higher!</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
Don’t come down go higher!
5 September 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I HAVE JUST PASSED A TIME OF DEEP SPIRITUALITY, AND MY LIFE IS CHANGED. I UNDERSTAND YOUR WORK MORE AND MORE, AND WITH MY COMMUNE I WANT TO BE IN MORE COMMUNION WITH YOU. I WANT TO KNOW HOW THIS IS POSSIBLE.
The revolution that spirituality brings is in a way very simple, but in another way it is very complex too.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19 Responsibility: the very first step of freedom</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
Responsibility: the very first step of freedom
6 September 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
AS I SEE IT, THE SITUATION IS AS FOLLOWS: YOU ARE, AND WE ARE NOT, OR TO BE MORE PRECISE, YOU AREN’T, AND WE STILL ARE.
IT SEEMS THAT THE MASTER-DISCIPLE RELATIONSHIP IS REALLY A KINDNESS ON YOUR PART TO DESCRIBE, IN FLATTERING TERMS, WHAT IS ESSENTIALLY OUR FAILURE TO HEAR WHAT YOU HAVE SAID – MORE OFTEN, MORE CLEARLY, AND MORE LOVINGLY THAN ANY DISCIPLES IN HISTORY COULD HAVE POSSIBLY BEEN BLESSED WITH.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 The Master: making your life an orchestra</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
The Master: making your life an orchestra
17 August 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
YOU SEEM TO BE FULFILLING TWO ROLES: AN OUTER ONE IN WHICH YOU PROVOKE AND EXPOSE THE STRUCTURE OF OUR SOCIETY, AND A MORE INTIMATE ONE IN WHICH YOU ENCOURAGE YOUR DISCIPLES TOWARDS THE ULTIMATE.
COULD YOU PLEASE COMMENT.
Existence consists of both: the inner and the outer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 When the disciple is ready</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
When the disciple is ready
7 September 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
IS ENLIGHTENMENT THE ONLY WAY A DISCIPLE CAN TRULY EXPRESS HER GRATITUDE TO HER MASTER?
Maneesha, even enlightenment is not enough to express the gratitude the disciple has for the master. There is simply no way.
The gratitude of the disciple remains unexpressed. It is one of those mysteries which can be experienced but cannot be explained.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 Only the real can meet the real</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
Only the real can meet the real
8 September 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
BEING WITH YOU IN INDIA IS MUCH STRONGER THAN ANYWHERE ELSE IN THE WORLD. SITTING WITH YOU IN DISCOURSE FEELS LIKE BEING IN THE VERY HEART OF THE WORLD. SOMETIMES JUST SITTING IN THE HOTEL ROOM, CLOSING MY EYES, I FEEL THAT YOUR HEARTBEAT AND MINE ARE BEATING IN THE SAME RHYTHM.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22 A journey without end</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
A journey without end
9 September 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED MASTER,
I HAVE DONE NOTHING TO DESERVE YOUR INFINITE LOVE AND COMPASSION, AND THEREFORE NO ACT OF MINE CAN BE APPROPRIATE TO EXPRESS MY GRATITUDE TOWARDS YOU.
I PRAY TO YOU, MY LORD, PLEASE GIVE ME THE STRENGTH TO FIGHT THOSE UGLY AND INHUMAN PEOPLE WHO, WITH THE HELP OF THEIR BRUTAL POWER, ARE DREAMING OF DESTROYING YOU.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23 \`Nothing\&#39; is my sword</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
‘Nothing’ is my sword
10 September 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
BEFORE I MADE MY APPLICATION TO TAKE SANNYAS, I HAD A BIG PROBLEM, THINKING THAT TAKING SANNYAS WAS RECOGNIZING THAT ONE IS ILL. I WAS SO CONFUSED ABOUT IT, AND I DIDN’T TRUST TELLING ANY SANNYASIN. I READ THAT YOU SAID IN POONA THAT WE ARE ALL ILL UNTIL WE ARE ENLIGHTENED.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 Around me\... something happens</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 24
Around me... something happens
11 September 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHEN I TOOK SANNYAS AND I FIRST MET YOU, IT WAS LIKE MEETING AGAIN WITH AN ANCIENT BELOVED, AS IF I HAD KNOWN YOU FOR A LONG TIME.
IS IT SO, OR IS EVERY MEETING WITH AN ENLIGHTENED BEING SO MUCH A REMINDER OF ONE’S OWN INNER SELF THAT IT FEELS AS IF ONE HAS MET BEFORE?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25 Listening lets the heart decide</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 25
Listening lets the heart decide
12 September 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHY CAN’T I HEAR YOU? AM I DEAF?
You are not deaf. And you also hear me, but you are not listening. And you don’t know the distinction between hearing and listening.
Anybody who has ears can hear, but it is not necessary that he will be able to listen.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26 The Master \-- your death and your resurrection</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 26
The Master – your death and your resurrection
13 September 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
THE MORE YEARS I AM WITH YOU, THE LESS I KNOW WHO I AM. AM I MISSING YOU?
Turiya, this is the way of getting me, and this is the way of getting yourself too.
You are not missing anything, but the mind will again and again raise the question, because mind needs information – more information means you are getting it, you are becoming more knowledgeable.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27 You thimk this is a discourse. It is just adevice</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 27
You thimk this is a discourse. It is just adevice
14 September 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
IS IT TRUE THAT WHATSOEVER THE MASTER SAYS OR DOES IS SIMPLY A DEVICE TO TRANSFORM THE DISCIPLE?
Narendra, it is one of the most impossible things in the world to indicate, to explain the ultimate truth.
The experience is beyond words. And the difficulty is, we have nothing else to communicate with; words are our only means of communication.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28 If you swim, you miss</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part28/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 28
If you swim, you miss
15 September 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHAT CAN WE DO FROM OUR SIDE TO SURRENDER THE EGO, WHEN THIS WANTING TO SURRENDER IT IS, IN ITSELF, AN INTRINSIC PART?
Latifa, the ego is a puzzle. It is something like darkness – which you can see, which you can feel, which can obstruct your way but which does not exist.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>29 Mysticism, the forgotten language</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part29/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 29
Mysticism, the forgotten language
16 September 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
HOW DID YOU MANAGE TO FIND ME?
Existence is always a mystery.
People fall in love; they cannot answer why, how they have found each other. And when they fall in love there is an absolute feeling that they are made for each other – but how did they manage to find each other in such a big world?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Master and disciple, a journey hand in hand</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
Master and disciple, a journey hand in hand
18 August 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
MY FEELING IS THAT SINCE I HAVE KNOWN YOU, YOUR SANNYASINS HAVE PASSED THROUGH AN EVOLUTION, BUT YOU HAVE TOO. SO ARE WE MAKING THIS JOURNEY HAND IN HAND?
It is true, and it is not true.
The sannyasins have been certainly evolving, going through radical changes in their lifestyle, in their thinking, in their behavior, in their very vision of existence.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>30 The Taste of No-Mind</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part30/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 30
The Taste of No-Mind
18 September 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
EACH TIME I COME CLOSE TO YOU, IT LOOKS LIKE MY MIND DOESN’T WORK ANY MORE. I CANNOT HOLD ON TO ANY CONCRETE THOUGHT; EVERYTHING DISAPPEARS AS IF IN A WHITE, LIGHT CLOUD.
ON ONE SIDE IT IS LIKE COMING HOME AFTER ALL THIS INTENSE LONGING, AND ON THE OTHER SIDE THE FEAR OF BECOMING CRAZY COMES UP.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>31 The greatest reality in the world</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part31/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 31
The greatest reality in the world
19 September 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
AS ONE PAIR OF SPARKLING EYES AFTER ANOTHER ARRIVES TO BE WITH YOU HERE, IS IT PERHAPS THAT YOU ARE SURROUNDED FOR THE FIRST TIME BY DISCIPLES WHO LOVE YOU AS YOU ARE, OR HOWEVER YOU WANT TO BE – AND WHO ARE CERTAINLY NOT LOOKING FOR ANY GOODY-GOODY SAINT?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>32 The greatest gamble</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part32/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part32/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 32
The greatest gamble
20 September 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHEN THE COMMUNIST PARTY TELLS A LIE, WE KNOW IT IS A LIE. WHEN THE POPE TELLS A LIE, WE KNOW IT IS A LIE AND WE SAY THAT HE IS TELLING A LIE, BUT WHEN YOU TELL A LIE, WE ALWAYS SAY IT IS A “DEVICE.”
I WOULD LIKE TO KNOW WHY YOU TELL US SO MANY LIES-DEVICES.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>33 Meditation in the market place, not market place meditation</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part33/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part33/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 33
Meditation in the market place, not market place meditation
21 September 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WADUDA AND I ARE LEADING A GROUP CALLED “MEDITATION IN THE MARKETPLACE” WHICH INCLUDES TEACHING PEOPLE HOW THEIR MINDS CREATE THEIR REALITY. ONE OF THE EXERCISES IS SHOWING PEOPLE WAYS TO FULFILL THEIR DESIRES.
DOES SHOWING PEOPLE HOW TO FULFILL THEIR DESIRES BRING THEM TO A STATE OF MEDITATION, OR DOES IT LEAD THEM FURTHER AWAY FROM IT?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>34 Not to be, the greatest ecstasy</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part34/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part34/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 34
Not to be, the greatest ecstasy
22 September 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I HAVE SEEN YOU IN DISCOURSE FOR MANY YEARS, AND YOU APPEAR TO BE MORE FULL OF EMPTINESS AS TIME PASSES. I KNOW THIS DOES NOT MAKE SENSE, BUT IS IT POSSIBLE THAT YOU ARE MORE EMPTY?
Shunyo, it is exactly the meaning of your name.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>35 Bhagwan rajneesh, the buddha lord maitreya</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part35/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part35/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 35
Bhagwan rajneesh, the buddha lord maitreya
23 September 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
IS THIS A QUESTION, A REALIZATION, OR A DECLARATION?
SOMETHING BEYOND FORCES ME TO PUT THIS ON PAPER; THOUGH I AM WRITING THIS, THE WORDS ARE NOT MINE.
IT IS PAST MIDNIGHT, ABOUT FIVE O’CLOCK ON THE FULL MOONLIGHT NIGHT OF THE INDIAN MONTH KNOWN AS “BHADRA THE THURSDAY,” THE GURUVAR MASTER’S DAY IN INDIAN LANGUAGE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>36 You are here only for that miracle</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part36/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part36/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 36
You are here only for that miracle
24 September 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
THE OTHER DAY I HAD NARRATED AN EVENT, AND YESTERDAY YOU REPLIED IN YOUR OWN WAY. THE EVENT, THE QUESTION AND ANSWER, IS KNOWN TO YOU AND ME ONLY. NOW I CAN UNDERSTAND WHAT MUST HAVE TRANSPIRED BETWEEN BHAGWAN BUDDHA AND THE DISCIPLE MAHAKASHYAP.
BELOVED, BEAUTIFUL OSHO, IT’S NOT THE LANGUAGE BUT THE SILENCE THAT HAS AND HAD ASKED, THAT HAS ANSWERED AND HAD ANSWERED.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>37 Bowing down to the Master</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part37/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part37/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 37
Bowing down to the Master
25 September 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
NEVER BEFORE HAVE I FELT SO MUCH AT HOME WITH YOU. THIS PLACE HAS SUCH A BEAUTIFUL VIBRATION, AND I FEEL ALOT OF IT IS CREATED BY YOUR INDIAN DISCIPLES.
SOMETIMES, IT FEELS THAT THEIR GESTURES ARE IN SUCH A MELTING WITH YOUR GESTURES AND GRACE THAT I START ASKING MYSELF IF WE, YOUR WESTERN SANNYASINS, ARE MISSING OUT ON SOMETHING.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>38 The conspiracy against the individual</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part38/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part38/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 38
The conspiracy against the individual
26 September 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHY IS IT SO DIFFICULT FOR THE WORLD TO ACCEPT YOU AS YOU ARE?
There are many implications.
First, the world never accepts anybody as he is. That is something very fundamental about the world and the way it treats individuals.
The individual is small; the individual is born helpless, a child.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>39 Don\&#39;t say goodbye, say good morning</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part39/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part39/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 39
Don’t say goodbye, say good morning
27 September 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
BESIDE YOU NOW, I FEEL LIKE A HAPPY BUBBLE NEWLY CREATED AT THE BOTTOM OF A WATERFALL, LAUGHING AND DANCING ITS WAY DOWNSTREAM TO THE OCEAN. IF I SHOULD MAKE IT IN THIS LIFE TO REACH THE OCEAN, DOES IT REALLY MEAN THAT YOU AND I MUST SAY GOODBYE?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Misery is the prison, nothingness is the door</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
Misery is the prison, nothingness is the door
19 August 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHY DON’T WE DROP OUR MISERIES, OUR IGNORANCE AND UNHAPPINESS? HOW CAN A MAN BE HAPPY AND BLISSFUL?
It is one of the most fundamental questions that a man can ask.
It is also strange, because it should be easy to drop suffering, anguish, misery.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>40 My disciples are my garden</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part40/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part40/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 40
My disciples are my garden
28 September 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I HAVE NO WORDS TO EXPRESS YOUR LOVE AND COMPASSION SHOWERING ON ME. MY GRATITUDE AND THANKFULNESS CANNOT BE EXPRESSED IN ANY WORD OR ANY LANGUAGE.
PLEASE FORGIVE ME FOR MY SHORTCOMINGS.
ALSO, PLEASE FORGIVE ME, MY DEAREST LORD OSHO, THAT YOU HAD TO BEND DOWN TO TAKE MY HEAD INTO YOUR HANDS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>41 From information to transformation</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part41/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part41/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 41
From information to transformation
29 September 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I CANNOT UNDERSTAND WHAT AN ENLIGHTENMENT IS. OH, MY BEAUTIFUL MASTER, WILL YOU PLEASE SAY SOMETHING ABOUT THE TASTE OF ENLIGHTENMENT?
Chetna, there are things in life which cannot be understood. They can be experienced, but they cannot be explained. To explain them is to explain them away.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>42 Be a seeker, not a believer</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part42/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part42/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 42
Be a seeker, not a believer
30 September 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I UNDERSTAND PERFECTLY WELL WHY YOU ARE DRIVING US, SLOWLY SLOWLY, TO BE INDEPENDENT OF YOUR PHYSICAL PRESENCE, BUT I WONDER HOW.
THE OTHER DAY YOU SAID THAT YOU HAVE YOUR OWN METHODS. I TRUST YOU TOTALLY, AND I KNOW THAT YOU WILL NOT HURT THE DELICATE VEIL BETWEEN US AND YOU; AND IF YOU DO, IT IS BECAUSE SOMETHING IS MISSING IN OUR JOURNEY.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>43 The sunflower always faces the sun</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part43/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part43/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 43
The sunflower always faces the sun
1 October 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WITH WHAT LOVE AND COMPASSION YOU FOLD YOUR HANDS AND DO NAMASTE TO US – THANK YOU, THANK YOU, OSHO.
I HAVE NEVER ASKED – YET, ALL MY QUESTIONS HAVE BEEN ANSWERED.
OSHO, COULD YOU GUIDE US AS TO WHAT KIND OF QUESTION A DISCIPLE SHOULD ASK?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>44 Paradise is only for the courageous</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part44/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part44/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 44
Paradise is only for the courageous
2 October 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHY IS IT THAT WE ARE ALL SO AFRAID OF A HIT FROM THE MASTER? WHEN IT IS HAPPENING, IT IS PROOF THAT IT IS JUST WHAT WE NEEDED, YET THE FEAR REMAINS. IS COWARDICE AN ESSENTIAL PART OF THE EGO?
The ego is cowardice.
Cowardice is not an essential part of the ego, it is the whole of the ego.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Madness: the ultimate evolution of mind</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
Madness: the ultimate evolution of mind
20 August 1986 pm in
Question 3 BELOVED OSHO,
I HAVE NO IDEA ABOUT WHAT ‘RIGHT AWARENESS’ IS. HOW TO JUDGE THAT I AM GOING IN THE RIGHT DIRECTION?
There is no right awareness because there is no possibility of wrong awareness. Awareness is right. So first, drop the wrong question. Once you are asking a wrong question to yourself you cannot get the right answer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Mind thinks, meditation knows</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
Mind thinks, meditation knows
21 August 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHY CAN A MAN NOT BECOME MEDITATIVE? HOW CAN A MOVEMENT FOR MEDITATION BE CREATED?
Meditation is a danger, it is a risk.
It is a danger to all the vested interests, and it is a risk to the mind.
Mind and meditation cannot co-exist. There is no question of having both of them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Silence is a song without words</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
Silence is a song without words
22 August 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
LAST NIGHT I WAS READING “THE BOOK OF MIRDAD”. IT WAS SO BEAUTIFUL AND SO STRONG THAT I COULDN’T STOP READING FOR HOURS. THEN SUDDENLY I FELT THAT MY BREATH HAD CHANGED, AND I FOUND MYSELF ON THE EDGE OF CRYING, AND I DIDN’T KNOW WHETHER IT WAS SADNESS, DESPERATION, BLISS, OR ALL THREE AT THE SAME TIME.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 The conspiracy of the mystics</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
The conspiracy of the mystics
23 August 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
FOR THE LAST WEEK I HAVE KNOWN THAT I HAVE CANCER. FROM THAT TIME, EXCEPT FOR A FEW MOMENTS OF PANIC AND FEAR, I HAVE FELT A DEEP CALMNESS AND RELAXATION COMING INTO MY BEING.
HAVE I ALREADY GIVEN UP MY LIFE, OR IS THIS THE QUIETNESS OF ACCEPTANCE?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 The way of the Upanishads</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_osho_upanishad/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
The way of the Upanishads
24 August 1986 pm in
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHAT ARE THE ROOTS AND WHAT ARE THE WINGS OF A MEDITATOR?
Meditation is a way of settling in oneself, at the innermost core of your being. Once you have found the center of your existence, you will have found both the roots and the wings.
The roots are in existence, making you a more integrated human being, an individual.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
