<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Nothing to Lose But Your Head on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/nothing_to_lose_but_your_head/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nothing to Lose But Your Head on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/nothing_to_lose_but_your_head/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/nothing_to_lose_but_your_head/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/nothing_to_lose_but_your_head/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
13 February 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A visitor asked what the agreement of sannyas meant.]
That you are no more. It is a total surrender. No agreement – because in an agreement there are two parties. You simply surrender. Much courage is needed...
It is not an agreement because it is not a legal thing. It is just a love affair.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/nothing_to_lose_but_your_head/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/nothing_to_lose_but_your_head/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
23 February 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin said he found life easier in the West, and it was difficult for him to be totally here.
Osho said he should go and live out the fantasies he had been having, but that the moment he reached the States he would start thinking about Poona. He said it was good to go and be finished with those things he felt incomplete, and that he would find that there was a vast difference between reality and fantasy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/nothing_to_lose_but_your_head/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/nothing_to_lose_but_your_head/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
24 February 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Ramteerth was an indian mystic – one of the most beautiful of this century. So read something about him... you can find the books. Just go through them, that’s all – they will be helpful.
[A sannyasin says she is going up and down, and she feels that when she is down she should do something about it]</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/nothing_to_lose_but_your_head/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/nothing_to_lose_but_your_head/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
25 February 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin asked about watching ’a lot of shit going through his head]
It is natural, so don’t feel in any way depressed by it. If you do, it is impossible to get rid of it because you lose all energy in it. People who become interested in meditation, sooner or later start feeling hopeless, because the chatter of the mind seems non-ending; it goes on and on, and the more you try to finish with it, the more it bubbles up.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/nothing_to_lose_but_your_head/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/nothing_to_lose_but_your_head/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
26 February 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[An ashram yoga teacher wanted to teach a synthesis of what he had learnt from several teachers. He asked Osho if he should ‘do my own thing’.]
You do your own thing. Absorb whatsoever you can get from anywhere, and always create a synthesis out of your own experience. Otherwise what you teach is borrowed, and the borrowed cannot be taught – because it is an art, not a science.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/nothing_to_lose_but_your_head/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/nothing_to_lose_but_your_head/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
27 February 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin, who is a sculptor, says: I want it to flow here. And I want to give myself to you.]
You are accepted. And I looked at your album of sculpture. It is beautiful... but it seems to me that you are working with a very limited idea again and again.
[He replies: Now I have no idea.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/nothing_to_lose_but_your_head/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/nothing_to_lose_but_your_head/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
28 February 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[The Tao group is present. A group member says she feels like a child, and should she continue with this. Osho checks her energy.]
It is good, mm? It is very good to go back to your childhood, because that is the point at which your life bifurcated – at five years old. That is where you missed the real life and you started becoming phoney.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/nothing_to_lose_but_your_head/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/nothing_to_lose_but_your_head/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
29 February 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin asks about studying Tai Chi and acupunture. Osho said they were both very meditative.]
... both are joined together deep down. So if you learn both it will be good. If you know your own energy and its centring, it is very easy to feel another’s energy.
And in fact it is a knack – it is not a science.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/nothing_to_lose_but_your_head/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/nothing_to_lose_but_your_head/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
1 March 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Paravritti means turning in, moving towards oneself.
[The new sannyasin says she has been travelling through many countries and experiencing things.]
It is good. There is a time to experience many things. When one is young, one has to experience many things – both good and bad, the dark and the light.
But the real travelling starts when you start turning in.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/nothing_to_lose_but_your_head/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/nothing_to_lose_but_your_head/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌8 March 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
There was no darshan on March 8th.
Chapter 18 contains interviews with people about how they experienced groups.
&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/nothing_to_lose_but_your_head/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/nothing_to_lose_but_your_head/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌9 March 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, or blissful, and Subhuti is the name of one the chief disciples of Buddha. The literal meaning is, one who is well-known, world famous, mm?
[A sannyasin who is involved in a clothes design business in the West, said that she was afraid it would be a distraction now she was back in Poona.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/nothing_to_lose_but_your_head/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/nothing_to_lose_but_your_head/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
14 February 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A seeker said that he had an experience following Kundalini meditation that had given him a great sense of joy. He had gazed at a tree and had become so filled with its beauty, so full of joy, that he felt he could not contain his feelings, and he became afraid.
Osho said that one’s capacity is limited in the beginning, but it increases as the joy increases.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/nothing_to_lose_but_your_head/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/nothing_to_lose_but_your_head/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
10 March 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says that sometimes she feels fear, and when she sees Osho during the lectures, her body begins trembling.]
That’s very good, mm? Fear is natural – because you are moving somewhere you have never moved before... a territory completely unknown to you. Not only unknown, but unconnected with all that you have known.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/nothing_to_lose_but_your_head/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/nothing_to_lose_but_your_head/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
11 March 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin said that during after the meditations she was shaking very much, and she felt really shattered.]
You must be trying to control it – that is wrong.
Fever can come because you create a contradiction in your being. The energy is arising, and you start controlling it. You are doing two opposite things together.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/nothing_to_lose_but_your_head/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/nothing_to_lose_but_your_head/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 22
12 March 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Vipassana’s body died this afternoon. Most of this chapter contains a description of the death and sannyasin’s reactions to it. Then follows a description of the celebration and Osho’s discourse about her death.]
I would like to read you a few lines from Huub Oosterhuis...
The man who wants to live the life of a god on earth must go the way of every seed and die before he has rebirth.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/nothing_to_lose_but_your_head/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/nothing_to_lose_but_your_head/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
15 February 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss and praghosha means a declaration – a declaration of bliss.
Become a declaration of bliss. Don’t hide It – manifest it as much as you can. The more you manifest bliss, the more it will be coming to you. Remember a very basic law: that if bliss is expressed, shared, it grows.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/nothing_to_lose_but_your_head/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/nothing_to_lose_but_your_head/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
16 February 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says: Now I know I am not... and this comes to me all the time. Not only when I’m meditating, but when I’m alone in the hotel room, it takes over. Can I let go of it?]
Let go of it. Don’t resist it, don’t fight it. That is the whole effort we are making here – so that you disappear and something bigger than you takes possession.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/nothing_to_lose_but_your_head/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/nothing_to_lose_but_your_head/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
17 February 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love and sushma means harmony – harmony that comes through love.
In fact there is no other harmony – only love gives harmony. Through love you are no more a separate part. You become one with the main, the continent. You are no more an island. And everything that was not in harmony falls into harmony.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/nothing_to_lose_but_your_head/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/nothing_to_lose_but_your_head/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
18 February 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A visitor said that she had been practising Vipassana for some time, and had found it helpful. She said that she enjoyed the active meditations, enjoyed the dancing, but found that it did not go as deep for her as being silent.
Osho said that Vipassana was good, but that as one became more silent, one tended to become a little sad.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/nothing_to_lose_but_your_head/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/nothing_to_lose_but_your_head/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
19 February 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, and siddhanta means principle – principle of love. And that’s the principle of life also.
Love is life, and there is no life except love, mm? So become more and more loving, trusting – without any conditions. If one loses everything in love, nothing is lost. And if one can save everything and love is lost, then everything is lost.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/nothing_to_lose_but_your_head/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/nothing_to_lose_but_your_head/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
20 February 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Daya means compassion, and anand means bliss – compassion and bliss. Let compassion be your goal. Feel as compassionate as possible. Just have a feeling of compassion surrounding you all the time.
Look at the trees, but with compassion. Or look at a passing dog, but with compassion, mm? By and by you will get into the feeling.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/nothing_to_lose_but_your_head/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/nothing_to_lose_but_your_head/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
22 February 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin who has just returned from the West said that she felt that she wanted to open up as much as possible... ]
... if one wants to open, one opens – there is no barrier, nobody hindering you. If the wanting is really there, the opening is just a by-product of it – nothing else is needed.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
