<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Theologia Mystica on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/theologia_mystica/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Theologia Mystica on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/theologia_mystica/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/theologia_mystica/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/theologia_mystica/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
11 August 1980 am in Buddha Hall
THOU TRINITY BEYOND BEING, DIRECT US TO THE HEIGHT OF MYSTICAL REVELATION, SUBLIME BEYOND ALL THOUGHT AND LIGHT; WHEREIN THE SIMPLE, ABSOLUTE AND IMMUTABLE MYSTERIES OF DIVINE TRUTH ARE HIDDEN IN THE TRANSLUCENT DARKNESS OF THAT SILENCE WHICH REVEALETH IN SECRET. FOR THIS DARKNESS, THOUGH OF DEEPEST OBSCURITY, IS YET RADIANTLY CLEAR, AND, THOUGH BEYOND TOUCH AND SIGHT, IT OVERFILLS OUR UNSEEING MINDS WITH SPLENDORS OF TRANSCENDENT BEAUTY.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/theologia_mystica/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/theologia_mystica/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
20 August 1980 am in Buddha Hall
I THINK, TOO, THAT YOU HAVE UNDERSTOOD HOW THE DISCUSSION OF PARTICULARS IS MORE LENGTHY THAN OF UNIVERSALS.
FOR THE MORE WE ASPIRE TO HIGHER THINGS, THE MORE OUR DISCOURSE UPON THINGS OF THE INTELLECT IS CUT SHORT, EVEN AS, WHEN WE ENTER THAT DARKNESS WHICH PASSES UNDERSTANDING, WE SHALL FIND NOT BREVITY OF SPEECH BUT PERFECT SILENCE AND UNKNOWING.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 The Real Alcoholics</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/theologia_mystica/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/theologia_mystica/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
The Real Alcoholics
21 August 1980 am in Buddha Hall
OSHO, ACCORDING TO WHAT I HAVE BEEN HEARING YOU SAY, THE TITLE OF THIS SERIES, THEOLOGIA MYSTICA, SEEMS TO BE A CONTRADICTION IN TERMS.
Yoga Anurag,
IT is true, but the title was given by Dionysius himself, so at least I am not responsible for it. In a way, mysticism is bound to be a contradiction in terms, whether the word theologia is in it or not.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/theologia_mystica/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/theologia_mystica/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
22 August 1980 am in Buddha Hall
The first question Question 1 OSHO,
WHAT IS THE DIFFERENCE BETWEEN A MASTER AND THE PERFECT MASTER?
Tiko,
FIRST try to understand the difference between a teacher and a Master, then the difference between a teacher and a perfect teacher. Only then will you be able to understand the difference between a Master and a perfect Master.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 Neither This Nor That</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/theologia_mystica/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/theologia_mystica/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
Neither This Nor That
23 August 1980 am in Buddha Hall
GOING YET HIGHER, WE SAY THAT HE IS NEITHER A SOUL, NOR A MIND, HE IS NEITHER A SOUL NOR A MIND NOR AN OBJECT OF KNOWLEDGE; NEITHER HAS HE OPINION, NOR REASON, NOR INTELLECT; NEITHER IS HE REASON, NOR THOUGHT, NOR IS HE UTTRABLE OR KNOWABLE; NEITHER IS HE NUMBER, ORDER, GREATNESS, LITTLENESS, EQUALITY, INEQUALITY, LIKENESS OR UNLIKENESS; NEITHER DOES HE STAND NOR MOVE, NOR IS HE QUIESCENT; NEITHER HAS HE POWER, NOR IS POWER, NOR LIGHT; NEITHER DOES HE LIVE, NOR IS LIFE; NEITHER IS HE BEING, NOR ETERNITY, NOR TIME, NOR IS HIS TOUCH KNOWABLE; NEITHER IS HE KNOWLEDGE, NOR TRUTH, NOR KINGSHIP, NOR WISDOM, NOR ONE, NOR ONE-NESS, NOR GOODNESS; NEITHER IS HE SPIRIT, AS WE CAN UNDERSTAND IT, NOR SONSHIP, NOR FATHERHOOD, NOR ANY OTHER THING KNOWN TO US, OR TO ANY OTHER CREATURE; NEITHER IS HE OF THINGS WHICH ARE NOT, NOR OF THINGS WHICH ARE; NEITHER DO THE THINGS WHICH ARE UNDERSTAND HIM.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 Understanding is Enough</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/theologia_mystica/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/theologia_mystica/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
Understanding is Enough
24 August 1980 am in Buddha Hall
The first question Question 1 OSHO,
WHEN I WAS A CHILD ATTENDING SUNDAY SCHOOL THERE WAS A HEBREW PROVERB HANGING ON THE WALL. IT READ: “THE BEGINNING OF WISDOM IS THE FEAR OF THE LORD.” FOR MANY YEARS I WAS CONVINCED OF THE MEANING THAT GOD WAS FRIGHTENED OF MAN GAINING ANY WISDOM.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/theologia_mystica/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/theologia_mystica/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 15
25 August 1980 am in Buddha Hall
The first question Question 1 OSHO,
DO YOU REALLY LOVE SOMENDRA STILL?
Manu,
MY LOVE is not conditional. Love cannot be conditional – either it is or it is not. It is not caused by anything, hence nothing can disturb it. But you know something else in the name of love: you know only infatuation, attraction, lust. Your love is nothing but a subtle strategy to exploit the other, hence it is bound to disappear sooner or later – and you will find enough reasons why it disappears.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 God is a Ventriloquist</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/theologia_mystica/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/theologia_mystica/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
God is a Ventriloquist
12 August 1980 am in Buddha Hall
The first question Question 1
OSHO, THE OTHER NIGHT AFTER DARSHAN I DREAMT THAT YOU SANG “I’M A STRANGER IN PARADISE” TO ME. IT WAS INCREDIBLE, AND YOU WERE REALLY GOOD AT IT! DO YOU EVER SING AND DANCE, BEYOND THE METAPHORICAL USE OF THE WORDS? YOU ARE SO FULL OF GRACE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 True Life</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/theologia_mystica/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/theologia_mystica/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
True Life
13 August 1980 am in Buddha Hall
The first question Question 1
OSHO, CAN YOU PLEASE SING US A SONG ON THIS? LATELY I HAVE SEEN THAT I AM TOTALLY VICIOUS. SUDDENLY MY HEART THEN CARRIES ME INTO A VERY INSECURE BUT BEAUTIFUL PLACE. I LOVE THIS WHENEVER IT COMES, BUT WHY THE INSECURITY AND MUDDLEDNESS, YET SO MUCK GRACE?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Mystical Unknowing</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/theologia_mystica/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/theologia_mystica/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
Mystical Unknowing
14 August 1980 am in Buddha Hall
BUT TAKE HEED LEST THE PROFANE HEAR THOSE, I SAY, WHO CLING TO CREATURES, AND IMAGINE IN THEMSELVES THAT NOTHING IS BEYOND BEING, BEYOND EXISTENCES, BUT SUPPOSE THEMSELVES TO KNOW HIM “WHO MAKETH DARKNESS HIS HIDING PLACE.” IF, THEN, THE DIVINE MYSTERIES ARE BEYOND SUCH, WHAT SHALL BE SAID OF THOSE YET MORE PROFANE WHO CONCEIVE THAT THE UNDERLYING CAUSE OF ALL IN TERMS OF THE OUTWARD FORMS OF THINGS AND ASSERT THAT HE EXCEEDS NOT THESE IMPIOUS AND MANIFOLD CONCEITS OF THEIR OWN MAKING?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Man\&#39;s is Life\&#39;s Invention</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/theologia_mystica/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/theologia_mystica/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
Man’s is Life’s Invention
15 August 1980 am in Buddha Hall
The first question Question 1 OSHO,
TO WHAT EXTENT DOES LIFE HAVE RELEVANCE TO LOGIC?
Mavji Savla,
LOGIC is a very small thing, life is vast. Logic is utilitarian, it is an invention of man. Life is non-utilitarian, it is not an invention of man; on the contrary, man is life’s invention.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/theologia_mystica/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/theologia_mystica/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
16 August 1980 am in Buddha Hall
The first question Question 1 OSHO,
WHAT IS THE DIFFERENCE BETWEEN BEING AN INDIVIDUAL AND JUST BEING STUBBORN
Yoga Prem,
THE DIFFERENCE is immense – it is absolutely unbridgeable. Two things will have to be understood: one is personality and the second is individuality.
We ordinarily don’t have individuality at all. That’s what Gurdjieff means when he says it is very rare to find a person who has a soul.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Translucent Darkness</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/theologia_mystica/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/theologia_mystica/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
Translucent Darkness
17 August 1980 am in Buddha Hall
WE LONG EXCEEDINGLY TO DWELL IN THIS TRANSLUCENT DARKNESS, AND THROUGH NOT SEEING AND NOT KNOWING TO SEE AND TO KNOW HIM WHO IS BEYOND BOTH VISION AND KNOWLEDGE – BY THE VERY FACT OF NEITHER SEEING HIM NOR KNOWING HIM. FOR THIS IS TRULY TO SEE AND TO KNOW, AND, THROUGH THE ABANDONMENT OF ALL THINGS, TO PRAISE HIM WHO IS BEYOND ALL ABOVE ALL.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 The Real Magic</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/theologia_mystica/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/theologia_mystica/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
The Real Magic
18 August 1980 am in Buddha Hall
The first question Question 1 OSHO,
I UNDERSTAND YOU SAID THE OTHER DAY IN THE LECTURE THAT JESUS DID NOT WALK ON WATER AND THERE ARE NO MIRACLES AS SUCH. BUT BY PRACTICING THE SAMYAMA ON PATANJALI’S UDANA SUTRA, IS NOT MAN ABLE TO DO THIS?
PLEASE COMMENT.
Anand Guenter,
I SAY again that there are no miracles as such, because the whole existence is a miracle.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 I laughed</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/theologia_mystica/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/theologia_mystica/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
I laughed
19 August 1980 am in Buddha Hall
The first question Question 1 OSHO,
I AM DEEPLY CONVINCED THAT OUR WAY IS TO DROP THE EGO, TO COME BACK TO OUR POTENTIAL OF SENSUALITY AND EMOTIONAL SENSITIVITY, AND TO INCREASE IN TOTAL AWARENESS. I NEVERTHELESS HAVE DIFFICULTY IN COMPREHENDING THAT SPIRITUAL CREATIVITY SHOULD NOT BE AN ORIGINAL PART OF OURSELF. AGAINST THIS I REALIZE THAT THE CREATIVE SPIRIT IS HAPPENING HERE AND THAT NEW FORMS OF LIFE HAVE BEEN CREATED IN POONA.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
