<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Dance Your Way to God on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dance_your_way_to_god/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dance Your Way to God on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/dance_your_way_to_god/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dance_your_way_to_god/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dance_your_way_to_god/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
28 July 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin says: I’m not sure which direction to take – whether to go out more to people or to go inside myself more. I’m not sure which is best for my growth.
Osho checks his energy.]
Good, come back. The energy is really good.
You have to do both. Choosing won’t be good.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dance_your_way_to_god/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dance_your_way_to_god/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
6 August 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin reports back on a meditation Osho had given him to stare at a light. (see ‘a rose is a rose is a rose’, friday july 23rd). The sannyasin said he found it hard to sit still; he itched and wanted to scratch.]
Allow it – don’t be worried about it. Scratch and just scratch very consciously.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dance_your_way_to_god/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dance_your_way_to_god/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
7 August 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[To a visitor who is a primal therapist.]
And can you remember yourself as a small cell in the womb? [She answers: Yes.]
Just close your eyes and feel that you are becoming smaller and smaller, so I can feel where you are going and what more can be done. If something happens in the body, allow it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dance_your_way_to_god/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dance_your_way_to_god/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
8 August 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
This will be your name, so completely forget the old one as if it never belonged to you, not even a relationship with it. Just completely break away from it, slip out of it just as a snake slip out of the old skin. And don’t look back.
It is simple, but it does miracles.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dance_your_way_to_god/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dance_your_way_to_god/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
9 August 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin who bakes said that because of his work he was unable to do the meditations, and should he do anything else. Osho said that when he had time he could meditate alone... ]
... and baking is a good meditation. Put your love into it, your whole awareness into it. Just don’t do it for the money – do it for love also.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dance_your_way_to_god/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dance_your_way_to_god/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
10 August 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love, parimal means fragrance, love’s fragrance. And that is the only fragrance there is, so remember it. Remember it so constantly that it becomes a deep truth in your being. Constantly remember it. By remembering something constantly, it creates a milieu around you. And as I see it, if one can attain to love, one has attained.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dance_your_way_to_god/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dance_your_way_to_god/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
11 August 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin recently returned from japan, formerly had long flowing black hair. Tonight his hair was cropped very short.]
It was looking good – grow it again! Because long hairs are very symbolic, very significant. It is not just accidental that the new generation has moved towards long hair. It is indicative of a very deep change in the world mind.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dance_your_way_to_god/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dance_your_way_to_god/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
12 August 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss and karunesh means god of compassion. So the whole name will mean god of compassion and bliss. And compassion is going to be your path. Feel as much compassion as possible. Feel unconditionally compassionate. And give as much as you can give of your love. Share your life as much as you can share.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dance_your_way_to_god/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dance_your_way_to_god/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
13 August 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine and geetika means a poem, a song; a divine song. Will it be easy to pronounce, ‘geetika’?
And sing more – that’s all we can do. We can dance, we can sing. There is nothing else for man to do. Nothing else is possible. We can pray, we can be full of wonder.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dance_your_way_to_god/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dance_your_way_to_god/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
14 August 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine, samarpana means surrender; surrender to god, surrender to the divine. It means total surrender – and that is your way and your path. You are not supposed to do something about it. You are just supposed to allow god to do something to you.
We just have to be in tune with the whole.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dance_your_way_to_god/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dance_your_way_to_god/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
15 August 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine and ayama means dimension, the divine dimension. And that is the goal. One has to move into the divine dimension by and by. So become less and less interested in things. Become more interested in persons. Even while relating with things, relate to them as if you are relating with persons.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dance_your_way_to_god/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dance_your_way_to_god/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
29 July 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love and divya means divine, divine love. Remember it. It should not be just a name. It should become a remembrance – that love is divine and that only love is divine, and there is no other door to the divine than love. The more you love, the closer you are to god.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dance_your_way_to_god/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dance_your_way_to_god/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
16 August 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss or blissful, and sugatta is a name of buddha. Literally it means well gone, because in india we call those people well-gone who are not going to come back again, who are gone forever. They have gone so well that they will not be returning. It is a beautiful term, very significant.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dance_your_way_to_god/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dance_your_way_to_god/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
17 August 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Someone asks: I feel that different centres have opened in part, but I don’t know which one to go with, to live with. I don’t know which one is best to put more time and energy into.]
Think more about love, about the heart. We call that chakra ‘anahata’ in yoga psychology.
There are seven chakras, and the anahata is just in the middle; three below it, three above it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dance_your_way_to_god/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dance_your_way_to_god/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
18 August 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Deva means divine and madira means wine, divine wine. And become that! Be so ecstatic – because if one is not ecstatic, the same energy tends to become negative. If you don’t move into happiness, the same energy becomes unhappiness. It is the same energy. Either you change it into ecstasy or it becomes a depression, a load.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dance_your_way_to_god/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dance_your_way_to_god/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
19 August 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Anand means bliss, the ultimate state of consciousness when there is nothing to be blissful about... just pure bliss, uncaused. That is the difference between bliss and happiness. Happiness needs a cause for it to exist. Bliss needs no cause. And when happiness needs a cause, it can create unhappiness, because the cause is always beyond you; you cannot do anything about it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dance_your_way_to_god/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dance_your_way_to_god/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 24
20 August 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin who is an artist, was leaving for a few months to organise some exhibitions for his work. Osho said that his meditation was going well, but into his work he should also try to bring a meditative dimension.]
... just paint with the idea that if somebody looks at the painting, he feels awe, reverence, silence.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dance_your_way_to_god/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dance_your_way_to_god/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
30 July 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Through a translator, a visitor said he had come to Osho because he needed a friend.]
Good... but coming to me is dangerous because it means going away from the personality that you have been up to now. The only way to come closer to me is to die in a certain way. Only then is one reborn.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dance_your_way_to_god/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dance_your_way_to_god/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
31 July 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
Prem means love and bhagwatam means divine, godly. And love is always godly. Howsoever imperfect, it is always godly. You may understand it, you may not understand it, but it is godly. Love is the only proof of god – that he exists. And people who don’t know what love is can never know what god is.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dance_your_way_to_god/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dance_your_way_to_god/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
1 August 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin said he did not want to push himself as Osho had suggested: But I know I have to take risks, I know I have to try new things but... ]
If it comes – this urge to try new things, to venture into new styles of being, to go on a journey of the unknown – then follow it!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dance_your_way_to_god/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dance_your_way_to_god/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
2 August 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A visitor to the ashram, told Osho that she had been practising yoga for some time and had also worked at the jung institute.
Osho said that she was ready now to move into meditation.]
OSHO:.but you will have to find the right meditation for yourself, because there are a thousand
and one techniques.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dance_your_way_to_god/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dance_your_way_to_god/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
3 August 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A sannyasin said she had done much work on herself in the states, participating in arica, est, fischer-hoffman therapy, and a vipassana course. She felt that the arica course lacked heart.
Osho said that he could see some traces of a lingering hardness in her face, but that it was no cause for concern and could be dropped.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dance_your_way_to_god/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dance_your_way_to_god/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
4 August 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[Osho suggested that a visitor do the camp, because one cannot observe what meditation was from the outside; one needs to participate. He added that participation does not mean following or becoming a follower, but simply seeing for yourself what it is about. Osho recommended that simon do the encounter group, saying... ]</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/dance_your_way_to_god/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/dance_your_way_to_god/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
5 August 1976 pm in Chuang Tzu Auditorium
[A visitor says he is studying massage.]
No, it is good. It is a great art, so don’t just study it as a profession. No, learn it as an art.
The human body is the greatest mystery in existence, and massage is trying to get in tune with the energy of the human body.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
