<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Transmission of the Lamp on Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
    <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Transmission of the Lamp on Osho - The complete works of Osho</description>
    <image>
      <title>Osho - The complete works of Osho</title>
      <url>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://osho.lol/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 The animals must all be laughing</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 1
The animals must all be laughing
26 May 1986 pm in Punta Del Este, Uruguay.
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WITH MY FRIEND, MEDITATION, I CLEAN THE SKELETONS FROM THE CLOSET.
WITH MY FRIEND, TRUST, I ENTER THE DARK BASEMENT AND SWEEP IT CLEAN OF ANCIENT DUST.
WITH MY FRIEND, THE HEART, I OPEN ALL THE WINDOWS AND ALLOW THE FRESH BREEZES IN.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 When the heart is ready the guest comes</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 10
When the heart is ready the guest comes
31 May 1986 am in Punta Del Este, Uruguay.
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
TO ME ONE OF THE MOST TRAGIC FALLS OF MAN TODAY IS HIS VALUING ALL THE WRONG THINGS. SOMEWHERE IN THE COLLECTIVE UNCONSCIOUS THERE MUST BE SOME IDEA OF WANTING ALL THE MOST BEAUTIFUL THINGS OF LIFE FOR FREE – AND PAYING HUGELY FOR ALL THE UNESSENTIALS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 Footprints in the sky</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 11
Footprints in the sky
31 May 1986 pm in Punta Del Este, Uruguay.
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I CANNOT DISTINGUISH BETWEEN IMAGINATION AND REALITY. CAN I ASSUME THAT I DO NOT KNOW REALITY YET, SO WHY NOT ENJOY WATCHING THE WHOLE MOVIE WITHOUT TRYING TO DISTINGUISH? OR, IS IT NECESSARY TO BE AWARE OF THE DIFFERENCE BETWEEN IMAGINATION AND REALITY?
There is no question of making any distinction between imagination and reality.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Laughter is the highest spiritual quality</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 12
Laughter is the highest spiritual quality
1 June 1986 am in Punta Del Este, Uruguay.
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I HAVE JUST READ AN ARTICLE BY STEPHEN JAY GOULD, A WARM, AMUSING, OPEN- MINDED SCIENTIST WHOSE FIELD IS BIOLOGY, AND PARTICULARLY EVOLUTION. IT SEEMS PROBABLE THAT ABOUT FIVE TO EIGHT MILLION YEARS AGO THE CHIMP-HUMAN ANCESTRAL LINE SPLIT INTO WHAT WAS TO BECOME MODERN CHIMP AND MODERN MAN.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 Boots, flesh, marrow, and\...,</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part13/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 13
Boots, flesh, marrow, and...,
1 June 1986 pm in Punta Del Este, Uruguay.
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
YOU WERE SAYING THE OTHER NIGHT HOW MAHAKASHYAP BROUGHT HIS OWN UNIQUENESS TO BUDDHA’S RELIGION. WHEN DID THE PATRIARCHS OF BUDDHA STOP BEING UNIQUE AND BECOME BUDDHISTS?
Gautam the Buddha is one of the most unique expressions of human consciousness. It is difficult to conceive of someone going beyond him, but Mahakashyap, his disciple, really did go beyond him.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 The greatest surgery possible</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part14/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 14
The greatest surgery possible
2 June 1986 am in Punta Del Este, Uruguay.
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
YOU HAVE TALKED MUCH ABOUT DEATH AND DYING. I UNDERSTOOD YOU TO HAVE SAID THAT PEOPLE ARE AFRAID OF DEATH ITSELF BECAUSE THEY CAN’T REALLY CONCEIVE THAT IT IS GOING TO HAPPEN TO THEM.
AM I FOOLING MYSELF WHEN I FEEL TREMENDOUSLY EXCITED AT THE THOUGHT OF DEATH?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 : There are times when you need the open sky</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part15/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 15
\ There are times when you need the open sky
2 June 1986 pm in Punta Del Este, Uruguay.
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I HAVE DONE OR HAD EVERYTHING OF THIS WORLD THAT I HAVE EVER WANTED. I SEEM TO HAVE RUN OUT OF AMBITION TO ACHIEVE ANYTHING FURTHER. EVEN ENLIGHTENMENT APPEARS TO BE A REMOTE AND IMPOSSIBLE GOAL, OUTSIDE THE REALM OF MY UNDERSTANDING.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 When it is ripe, the heart opens</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 16
When it is ripe, the heart opens
3 June 1986 am in Punta Del Este, Uruguay.
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHAT IS THE DIFFERENCE BETWEEN THE MASTER-AND-DISCIPLE RELATIONSHIP NOW, AND IN THE DAYS OF BUDDHA AND BODHIDHARMA? IT SEEMS THAT THOUSANDS OF YEARS AGO A NEW DISCIPLE, UPON MEETING A MASTER, OFTEN HAD A SUDDEN, DRAMATIC REALIZATION THAT OPENED HIM UP TO A STATE OF AVAILABILITY – UNKNOWN IN THE PRESENT TIME.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 If you live totally, once is enough</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part17/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 17
If you live totally, once is enough
3 June 1986 pm in Punta Del Este, Uruguay.
Question BELOVED OSHO,
A FEW DAYS AGO I WAS FEELING FULL OF ENERGY AND A LOT OF LOVE FOR MYSELF.
THE OPPORTUNITY AROSE FOR ME TO LET MYSELF FACE MY NUMBER ONE DEVIL: JEALOUSY. I WENT FOR IT WHOLEHEARTEDLY, AND THE RESULT WAS TO SEND MYSELF EVEN HIGHER: I FELT EUPHORIC AND SO GRATEFUL.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 You just have to gather courage</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part18/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 18
You just have to gather courage
4 June 1986 am in Punta Del Este, Uruguay.
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHEN I HEAR YOU TALK ABOUT THE INTERDEPENDENCE AND INTERWOVENNESS OF EVERYTHING THAT EXISTS – THAT NOBODY AND NOTHING IS AN ISLAND, SOMETHING IS DAWNING IN ME WHICH I CAN HARDLY PUT INTO WORDS. WHAT SO FAR HAS JUST BEEN AN INTELLECTUAL PERCEPTION SOMETIMES CRYSTALLIZES AS MOMENTS OF AWE AND ADMIRATION FOR EXISTENCE’S INTELLIGENCE, WHICH GOES SO FAR BEYOND OUR OWN LIMITED THINKING.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19 Don\&#39;t miss the head</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 19
Don’t miss the head
4 June 1986 pm in Punta Del Este, Uruguay.
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
A VERY REVEALING INCIDENT OCCURRED RECENTLY. IN THE WAKE OF THE SO-CALLED “GIANT STEP FOR MANKIND,” WHEN THE FIRST ASTRONAUT SET FOOT ON THE MOON, THE AMERICANS HAVE CONTINUED THEIR SPACE EXPLORATION, NOW WITH THE REUSABLE SHUTTLE.
SUDDENLY, A LITTLE WHILE AGO, THIS 2.3-BILLION-DOLLAR SPACECRAFT BLEW UP IN THE SKY, KILLING ALL SEVEN PASSENGERS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 A whole glass of water</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 2
A whole glass of water
27 May 1986 am in Punta Del Este, Uruguay.
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
IN THE OLDEN DAYS IT WAS CALLED MELANCHOLIA; TODAY IT IS CALLED DEPRESSION, AND IT COUNTS AS ONE OF THE MAJOR PSYCHOLOGICAL PROBLEMS OF DEVELOPED COUNTRIES. IT IS DESCRIBED AS A SENSE OF DESPAIR OR HOPELESSNESS, A LACK OF SELF-ESTEEM WITH NO ENTHUSIASM OR INTEREST IN THE SURROUNDINGS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 The revenge of the pygmies</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part20/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 20
The revenge of the pygmies
5 June 1986 am in Punta Del Este, Uruguay.
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
IT SEEMS THAT THE IMPLICATIONS OF GURDJIEFF’S WORK WERE AS REVOLUTIONARY, AS THREATENING TO THE STATUS QUO, AS YOURS. MANY OF HIS METHODS WERE UNEQUIVOCALLY OUTRAGEOUS, YET IT SEEMS HE WAS NEVER REPORTED IN THE LOCAL RAGS AS RUNNING A CAMP FOR SLAVE LABOR, DISRUPTING PUBLIC TRANSPORT, BEING A MENACE ON THE ROADS OR BEING THE INSTIGATOR OF RIOTOUS BACCHANALIAN ORGIES.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 Spice in buddha\&#39;s pot</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part21/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 21
Spice in buddha’s pot
5 June 1986 pm in Punta Del Este, Uruguay.
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
BODHIDHARMA ADDED A SPICE TO BUDDHA’S COOKING, WHICH EVENTUALLY BECAME ZEN.
WHO ELSE HAS THROWN SPICE IN BUDDHA’S POT?
The number is really vast. Buddhism in itself became a world of philosophy – not just a philosophy, but a source of many philosophies because it spread all over Asia, meeting with different cultures, different people, different philosophies.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22 Man has suffered enough</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part22/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 22
Man has suffered enough
6 June 1986 am in Punta Del Este, Uruguay.
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
EACH NEW ERA OF THE LAST FEW CENTURIES HAS AFTER A SLOW START EMERGED VERY SUDDENLY – THE INDUSTRIAL REVOLUTION AND THE ERA OF COMMUNICATIONS ARE TWO OBVIOUS EXAMPLES.
BEING WITH YOU I ALWAYS HAVE THE FEELING THAT WE ARE SITTING AROUND A WARM COSY FIRESIDE, AT THE FEET OF THE MAN WHO INVENTED FIRE, WHILE ALL AROUND ARE THE HOWLS OF AGONY AT THE ICY WORLD EVERYBODY ELSE IS ENDURING.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23 Nothing but a dead skeleton</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part23/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 23
Nothing but a dead skeleton
6 June 1986 pm in Punta Del Este, Uruguay.
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHEN YOU WERE TALKING ABOUT THE WAY THAT DIFFERENT BUDDHIST MASTERS HAVE BEEN ADDING THEIR OWN FLAVOR TO BUDDHA’S TEACHING, I STARTED WONDERING WHETHER THERE WILL EVER BE ANYBODY ADDING A NEW FLAVOR TO YOUR POT. IT LOOKS ALMOST IMPOSSIBLE TO ADD A NEW SPICE TO SOMETHING WHICH ALREADY CONTAINS ALL THE SPICES WHICH CAN BE FOUND ON THIS EARTH.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 Souls are not male or female</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 24
Souls are not male or female
7 June 1986 am in Punta Del Este, Uruguay.
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I LOVE HEARING THE STORIES OF THE OLD MASTERS AND THEIR DISCIPLES. IT IS SO BEAUTIFUL TO FEEL THE ESSENCE OF THOSE SMALL OASES OF CONSCIOUSNESS – WHICH CENTURIES OF RELIGION HAVE SINCE COVERED IN THE DUST OF DOGMA AND DECEIT. BUT STILL, AS I LOOK AT US SITTING HERE, FEELING THE JOY, THE SILENCE, THE TEARS, THE LAUGHTER, I SUSPECT THERE IS SOMETHING PRESENT THAT NO MASTER MAY EVER HAVE EVOKED BEFORE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25 Bravo, America!</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part25/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 25
Bravo, America!
7 June 1986 pm in Punta Del Este, Uruguay.
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
MAHAVIRA WAS THE TWENTY-FOURTH TIRTHANKARA OF THE JAINA RELIGION. DID THE JAINA RELIGION START WITH THE VERY FIRST TIRTHANKARA OR WITH MAHAVIRA? AND WHAT IS THE MEANING OF THE WORD ‘JAINA’?
The word ‘Jaina’ has a very beautiful meaning, just like the word ‘Buddha’. Buddha means the awakened one.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26 Cut the social crap completely</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part26/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 26
Cut the social crap completely
8 June 1986 am in Punta Del Este, Uruguay.
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
YESTERDAY I WAS TOLD THAT I AM INTELLIGENT. I FELT AS IF I HAD BEEN CALLED SOMETHING TERRIBLE... AS IF IT WAS EVEN DANGEROUS.
WOULD YOU PLEASE SHED SOME LIGHT ON THE FEAR OF INTELLIGENCE?
Avirbhava, to feel terrible for being called “intelligent” proves you really to be intelligent.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27 Go on, go on!</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part27/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 27
Go on, go on!
8 June 1986 pm in Punta Del Este, Uruguay.
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
IN HOMER’S GREAT EPIC STORIES, THE ILIAD AND THE ODYSSEY, HE DESCRIBES ULYSSES’ VOYAGE HOMEWARD WHEN HIS SHIP SAILS NEAR THE ISLAND OF THE LOTUS- EATERS. THE SIREN’S SONG WAFTS ACROSS THE OCEAN, HYPNOTIZING THE SAILORS AND CAUSING THEM TO STEER OFF THEIR COURSE TOWARDS THE SENSUOUS SOUND.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28 Unless your feet are holy\...</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part28/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 28
Unless your feet are holy...
9 June 1986 am in Punta Del Este, Uruguay.
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
IT SEEMS SO IMPOSSIBLE: SO MANY COUNTRIES HAVE SAID “NO” TO YOU IN THE WEST. BUT EVEN IF THE SO-CALLED DEMOCRACIES ACCEPTED YOU, WHAT CAN BE DONE ABOUT RUSSIA AND THE OTHER COMMUNIST NATIONS? UNLESS THERE IS A GREAT AWAKENING THERE, IT LOOKS LIKE THE WORLD IS DOOMED.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>29 Just like ripe fruit</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part29/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 29
Just like ripe fruit
9 June 1986 pm in Punta Del Este, Uruguay.
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
A SOCIOLOGIST HAS A THEORY THAT WESTERN CIVILIZATION IS TAKING OVER THE WHOLE WORLD. ALREADY THE WAY OF LIFE IN ALL THE BIG CITIES OF THE WORLD IS THE SAME, AND WHEREVER THERE IS PROGRESS, IT IS ACCORDING TO THE WAYS OF WESTERN CIVILIZATION.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 True balance</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 3
True balance
27 May 1986 pm in Punta Del Este, Uruguay.
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
YOU ARE UTTER SILENCE AND SO STILL, AND YET I SEE, WHEREVER YOU ARE, A MAD CYCLONE SURROUNDS YOU. IS THIS JUST YOUR LEELA, OR DOES EXISTENCE ALWAYS BALANCE SO PERFECTLY?
It is neither. I have nothing to do with it. It is not my leela, my playfulness; nor is it nature balancing itself.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>30 This chair is empty</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part30/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 30
This chair is empty
10 June 1986 am in Punta Del Este, Uruguay.
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
IN THE FACE OF THE HUGE MYSTERY OF LIFE, SINCE THE EARLY AGES HUMANKIND HAS CONSULTED ORACLES. IT’S VERY FAMOUS THROUGHOUT HISTORY – LIKE THE ORACLE OF DELPHI. PEOPLE ASKED THE ADVICE OF THE STARS TO KNOW ABOUT HUMAN DESTINY; WITCHES OR WISE WOMEN USED TO READ DESTINY IN THE TEA LEAVES OR EVEN IN TORTOISE SHELLS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>31 I am an adamant optimist</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part31/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 31
I am an adamant optimist
10 June 1986 pm in Punta Del Este, Uruguay.
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
THE PHRASE “A BROKEN FAMILY” IS USED TO CONJURE UP THE ESSENCE OF A DISASTROUS CHILDHOOD.
BY THE TIME I WAS AT UNIVERSITY, I HAD HAD TWO FATHERS AND THREE MOTHERS; AND IF YOU INCLUDE MY GRANDPARENTS – WHO ALSO FUNCTIONED AS PARENTS FOR A GOOD WHILE – A GRAND TOTAL OF SEVEN, INSTEAD OF THE CONVENTIONAL TWO.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>32 Water into wine is not the real miracle</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part32/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part32/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 32
Water into wine is not the real miracle
11 June 1986 am in Punta Del Este, Uruguay.
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
IT STILL PUZZLES ME HOW, FROM THE TEACHINGS OF JESUS AND MOHAMMED, TWO RELIGIONS COULD EVOLVE THAT WOULD BRING SO MUCH DEATH AND UGLINESS TO THE WORLD. THEIR INTOLERANCE AND VIOLENCE SEEM EVEN DARKER AS IT IS COVERED BY THE IMAGE OF THEIR ALMIGHTY GOD, ALLOWING ONLY THOSE WHO BELIEVE IN HIM AND HIS SON, HIS PROPHET, TO ENTER HEAVEN.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>33 I need your intelligence, not your surrender</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part33/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part33/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 33
I need your intelligence, not your surrender
11 June 1986 pm in Punta Del Este, Uruguay.
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
LOOKING INTO WHAT IS MY ENEMY NUMBER ONE, I REMEMBERED THAT AS A CHILD WHEN MY FATHER USED TO BEAT ME WITH A BELT OR SOMETIMES EVEN A WHIP, I WOULD NOT CRY OR IN ANYWAY SHOW HIM I WAS HURTING. AS SOON AS HE WOULD LET ME GO, I WOULD SING, THINKING OVER AND OVER AGAIN, “I WOULD RATHER DIE THAN SURRENDER.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>34 Truth cannot be humiliated</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part34/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part34/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 34
Truth cannot be humiliated
12 June 1986 am in Punta Del Este, Uruguay.
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
THE OTHER NIGHT WHEN YOU WERE TALKING ABOUT THE DECADENCE AND SUICIDAL TENDENCY OF WESTERN SOCIETY, PEAKING NOW IN THE USA, I WAS WONDERING WHY THE WESTERN LIFESTYLE IS CAPABLE OF PENETRATING OTHER CULTURES AND SPOILING THEM IN A SHORT TIME.
IT AMAZES ME AGAIN AND AGAIN HOW EASILY ABORIGINAL TRIBES ON ALL THE CONTINENTS, WITH, BUT MOSTLY WITHOUT FORCE, DROP THEIR MILLENNIA-OLD CIVILIZATION AND CULTURE AND START IMITATING THE WESTERN WAY OF LIFE – OFTEN IN QUITE RIDICULOUS WAYS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>35 Worship may be a worse crucifixion</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part35/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part35/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 35
Worship may be a worse crucifixion
12 June 1986 pm in Punta Del Este, Uruguay.
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
IN INDIA THERE IS A PROVERB, “VASUDHAIVA KUTUMBAKAM: THE WHOLE EARTH IS A FAMILY”. PERHAPS THIS PROVERB IS ONE THOUSAND YEARS OLD. OSHO, WERE THERE REALLY PEOPLE ONCE WHO LIVED LIKE A FAMILY? OR WAS IT A VISION OF SOME MYSTIC, A VISION WHICH YOU ARE GOING TO BRING TO REALITY?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>36 And if the song bursts forth\...</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part36/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part36/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 36
And if the song bursts forth...
13 June 1986 am in Punta Del Este, Uruguay.
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
IN AMERICA, MANY PEOPLE – FROM MEDITATORS TO MANAGERS – ARE USING A TECHNIQUE CALLED “POSITIVE THINKING.” THEY ARE TRYING TO CHANGE DESTRUCTIVE THOUGHTS AND CONDITIONINGS ABOUT THEMSELVES, OTHERS, AND EXISTENCE, INTO POSITIVE ONES, AND IN THIS WAY HOPE TO BE MORE SUCCESSFUL ON THE LEVEL OF THEIR LIVES THAT THEY ARE CONCERNED WITH.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>37 There is no power which is higher than love</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part37/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part37/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 37
There is no power which is higher than love
13 June 1986 pm in Punta Del Este, Uruguay.
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
YOU HAVE DESCRIBED HOW THE ABILITY TO COMMUNICATE HIS EXPERIENCE IS THE ESSENCE OF THE MASTER. YET IN YOU SOMETHING EVEN MORE BEAUTIFUL HAS HAPPENED.
BUDDHA CONVEYED HIS MESSAGE TO A SELECT FEW THOUSAND MEN IN THE LOCAL PALI LANGUAGE – IN RESPONSE TO THE FAILINGS OF BRAHMINISM.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>38 Base humanity into golden humanity</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part38/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part38/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 38
Base humanity into golden humanity
14 June 1986 am in Punta Del Este, Uruguay.
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
RICHARD WILHELM, THE MAN WHO TRANSLATED THE I CHING FROM CHINESE TO GERMAN, CAME BACK TO VIENNA VERY DISTURBED AFTER SPENDING THIRTY YEARS IN CHINA. HE CONSULTED HIS FRIEND, CARL GUSTAV JUNG. JUNG’S DIAGNOSIS WAS THAT WILHELM WAS IN A DANGEROUS CRISIS. HE HAD PUT ASIDE THE GERMAN CULTURE AND ADOPTED THE CHINESE ONE, THE WHOLE PACKAGE – RELIGION, EDUCATION AND WHATSOEVER.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>39 Donkeys carrying great scriptures</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part39/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part39/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 39
Donkeys carrying great scriptures
14 June 1986 pm in Punta Del Este, Uruguay.
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
IF THE WHOLE HISTORY OF THE WORLD WERE CONDENSED INTO ONE YEAR, WITH US STANDING AT THE END OF THAT VAST YEAR, IT WOULD LOOK SOMETHING LIKE THIS.
THE EARTH IS FORMED ON THE FIRST OF JANUARY. IT IS ONLY IN DECEMBER THAT THE CONTINENTS START DRIFTING INTO THEIR PRESENT POSITION.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Spreading a net of perfume</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part4/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 4
Spreading a net of perfume
28 May 1986 am in Punta Del Este, Uruguay.
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHENEVER YOU TALK ABOUT MUSIC AND DANCE, IT TOUCHES SOMETHING REALLY DEEP IN ME, AND MY WHOLE BEING IS ABSORBED IN EVERY WORD AND GESTURE, LIKE A SPONGE. WHEN YOU TALKED ABOUT AWARENESS AND BEING TOTALLY LOST IN THE MUSIC, I SUDDENLY UNDERSTOOD WHAT AN INCREDIBLE GIFT YOU HAVE GIVEN ME BY LETTING ME DANCE AROUND YOU – WHERE NOTHING WAS SAID, BUT AWARENESS HAD TO BE THERE, AND IT CAME NATURALLY, TOGETHER WITH BEING LOST IN THE DANCE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>40 In this mood of festivity all rules are put aside</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part40/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part40/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 40
In this mood of festivity all rules are put aside
15 June 1986 am in Punta Del Este, Uruguay.
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
IT IS SAID THAT WHEN BUDDHA ACHIEVED ENLIGHTENMENT THE WHOLE UNIVERSE BECAME BLISSFUL – FLOWERS SHOWERED FROM THE SKY, DEITIES BEGAN TO DANCE AROUND HIM. INDRA, HIMSELF, THE KING OF ALL THE DEVAS, CAME DOWN WITH FOLDED PALMS AND SURRENDERED AT BUDDHA’S FEET.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>41 The salt of the earth</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part41/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part41/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 41
The salt of the earth
15 June 1986 pm in Punta Del Este, Uruguay.
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
I HAVE ALWAYS FELT A GREAT LOVE FROM YOU FOR JOHN THE BAPTIST. IT SEEMS THAT THE MAN WHO IS REGARDED AS THE PROPHET WHO HERALDED THE COMING OF JESUS WAS OF GREATER STATURE THAN JESUS HIMSELF. WOULD YOU PLEASE COMMENT?
John the Baptist is not much known.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>42 Reality is far richer than imagination</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part42/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part42/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 42
Reality is far richer than imagination
16 June 1986 am in Punta Del Este, Uruguay.
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
IN RESPONSE TO ANANDO’S QUESTION THE OTHER EVENING ABOUT YOUR PLACE IN HISTORY, YOU TOLD US TO FORGET HISTORY AND HISTORIANS, TO SIMPLY LET THEM DO THEIR THING. BUT SO MUCH OF VALUE IS CONTAINED IN YOUR BOOKS WHICH IS BEING MADE AVAILABLE TO CONTEMPORARY PEOPLE, AND WHICH COULD BE PART OF A RECORD OF A WHOLE DIFFERENT DIMENSION FROM THAT WHICH IS CONVENTIONALLY REGARDED AS HISTORY.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>43 The monkey is dead</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part43/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part43/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 43
The monkey is dead
16 June 1986 pm in Punta Del Este, Uruguay.
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHAT IS THE DIFFERENCE BETWEEN BEING ONESELF AND BEING EGOLESS?
There is no difference between being oneself and being egoless. The difference is only in the expression. If you see it from the negative standpoint, egolessness will be the expression because ego disappears.
If you see it from the positive standpoint then being oneself will be the expression.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>44 The very perfume of love</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part44/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part44/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 44
The very perfume of love
17 June 1986 am in Punta Del Este, Uruguay.
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
EVERY TIME YOU TALK ABOUT TRANSFORMING PASSION INTO COMPASSION, SOMETHING IN MY HEART GETS TRIGGERED; BUT STILL, I DO NOT UNDERSTAND WHAT IT MEANS.
COULD YOU EXPLAIN IT TO ME AGAIN?
The energy called passion is always addressed towards someone. It is possessive, and because it is possessive it is ugly.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>45 I am the only challenge</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part45/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part45/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 45
I am the only challenge
17 June 1986 pm in Punta Del Este, Uruguay.
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
THE VATICAN HAS JUST ISSUED A STATEMENT IN WHICH THE POPE SUGGESTS THAT CULTS, SECTS AND “NEW RELIGIONS” SHOULD BE SEEN AS A CHALLENGE TO CHURCH AND SOCIETY.
THE STATEMENT SAYS THAT DEPROGRAMMING OF CULT MEMBERS IS MISGUIDED. THE VATICAN MADE THE STATEMENT AFTER CONSULTING CATHOLIC EXPERTS IN SEVENTY- FIVE COUNTRIES.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>46 Energy moves better when it is warmer</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part46/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part46/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents
‌CHAPTER 46
Energy moves better when it is warmer
18 June 1986 am in Punta Del Este, Uruguay.
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
YOU ONCE SAID SOMETHING LIKE WHEN WE TAKE SANNYAS IT IS EITHER TOO EARLY OR TOO LATE.
I HAVE OFTEN WONDERED WHAT YOU MEANT BY THIS. WOULD YOU PLEASE COMMENT?
Man is so unconscious that he does not know what he is doing, or for what he is doing it, or when the right time to do it is – so perhaps someone takes sannyas too early.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 The very foundation for one world</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part5/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 5
The very foundation for one world
28 May 1986 pm in Punta Del Este, Uruguay.
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
IN THE JAPANESE LANGUAGE, THE WORD FOR LOVE IS A PICTURE OF A PERSON WITH A FULL STOMACH, KNEELING, WITH BOTH HANDS RAISED IN OFFERING. THE PICTURE MEANS, “I AM SO FULL; PLEASE ALLOW ME TO SHARE, PLEASE TAKE FROM ME.” OSHO, IS IT POSSIBLE THAT THE LANGUAGES OF CULTURES THAT USE SYMBOLS ARE MORE PROTECTED FROM DEPRECIATION IN VALUE, AS HAPPENS FOR EXAMPLE IN ENGLISH WITH THE WORD ‘LOVE’?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Pure consciousness has never gone mad</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part6/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 6
Pure consciousness has never gone mad
29 May 1986 am in Punta Del Este, Uruguay.
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHEN I WAS A BOY, BETWEEN TWELVE AND FIFTEEN YEARS OLD, I OFTEN HAD, LYING IN MY BED IN THE DARK, STRANGE EXPERIENCES WHICH I LOVED VERY MUCH. IT STARTED BY MY IMAGINING THAT MY BED DISAPPEARED, THEN MY ROOM, THE HOUSE, THE TOWN, ALL PEOPLE, THE COUNTRY, THE WHOLE GLOBE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 The caravan became bigger and bigger</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 7
The caravan became bigger and bigger
29 May 1986 pm in Punta Del Este, Uruguay.
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHEN YOU RELATE TO US THE STORIES OF YOUR STUDENT DAYS, OR YOUR TIME AS A PROFESSOR, I OFTEN WONDER WHAT IT MUST HAVE BEEN LIKE TO HAVE BEEN ONE OF THOSE STUDYING WITH YOU OR UNDER YOU – I KNOW I CERTAINLY WOULD HAVE HAD A CRUSH ON YOU.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 Change is the law of life</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 8
Change is the law of life
30 May 1986 am in Punta Del Este, Uruguay.
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
A COUPLE OF YEARS AGO, ALVIN TOFFLER WROTE A BOOK CALLED FUTURE SHOCK. IN IT HE DESCRIBED HOW THE WORLD AROUND US IS CHANGING FASTER THAN EVER BEFORE. AND NOT ONLY THAT: THE RATE OF CHANGE IS INCREASING ALL THE TIME. HE DESCRIBES HOW HALF OF ALL AMERICANS CHANGE HOMES AT LEAST EVERY FIVE YEARS; HOW PEOPLE CHANGE HUSBANDS, WIVES, JOBS, CITIES AND CAREERS WITH INCREASING RAPIDITY.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 Get in tune with the essence</title>
      <link>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://osho.lol/posts/the_transmission_of_the_lamp/part9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt; Previous | Contents | Next &amp;gt;
‌CHAPTER 9
Get in tune with the essence
30 May 1986 pm in Punta Del Este, Uruguay.
Question 1 BELOVED OSHO,
WHEN YOU SPOKE ABOUT DEVOTEES I WAS VERY DEEPLY TOUCHED BECAUSE THAT IS WHAT I FEEL FOR YOU: DEVOTION. IF THE PRICE OF ENLIGHTENMENT WERE TO STAY AWAY FROM YOUR PRESENCE, I WOULD GIVE IT UP GLADLY FOR THE BLISS AND CENTEREDNESS I FEEL RIGHT NOW JUST LOOKING INTO YOUR EYES.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
